So let me give you a little bit of my own background in history.
I've been working as an entrepreneur in the information technology sector since the early 1990s, and
I have done work for an awful lot of clients, including Thomson Reuters, a number of American and
Canadian banks, Hewlett Packard, General Motors and many others across North America, the Caribbean
and parts of Europe.
And I've also been teaching at the university level for more than 30 years.
And I do have a PhD in this field as well as a few others.
And I really enjoy teaching.
And one of the things that I like about Go is just how easy it is for people to pick this up and to
pick it up relatively quickly, even if they have no background in programming whatsoever.
So I don't want to spend a lot of time talking about myself.
I really want to get into the content of this course itself.
So let's get started.