So if you don't have go installed, you're going to have to do that before you can go any further.
Unfortunately, it's really, really easy.
Just go to this URL, go langue and click on this big button that says download go.
And once you get here, if you're on Windows, you're going to download this installer.
If you're on a Mac, you're going to download this installer.
And if you're on Linux, you'll download this and follow the instructions for installing it.
That way, if you want to, you can install it from source.
I don't recommend that you do because it's a lot more work and gives you no actual functional benefits,
at least for the purposes of this course.
So go download, go and install it.
And once you're done that, let's move on to the next item.