So if you've been working and go for a while, you probably already have an I.D., but just in case,
if you don't have one, here is a free, good option for you.
So just go to this URL, Coorg Visual Studio, dot com download with a capital D. and download the version
for your particular operating system.
I am on a Mac, so I've already downloaded it and I've already installed it, but I haven't actually
started it yet.
Actually, I uninstalled it just so I could record this lecture.
So hopefully this will work the way I expect it to.
Once you have it installed, start it up.
And there's a couple of things we need to do to make sure that everything is going to work the way that
we want it to.
So this is up and running now, but I need to install some extensions for go, so what I'm going to
do, first of all, is open the the extension's marketplace, which is command shift X UniMac or a command
shift X on a macia and command shift or control shift X on windows.
And once I've got that, I will search for go.
And here it is, very first one go as I record this is version zero point two two.
Oh I'm going to install it and it's now installed.
So now I will go to open the command pallet commandership on a Mac and control ship on Windows.
And from here I'm going to look for Go Kolan Install update tools right here.
And once it shows up, it'll show up again here in a second.
I need to make sure everything here is checked.
So I'll just click this to check everything and say, OK.
And it's installing them, as you can see, at the bottom of the screen.
And once that's done, just restart the idee and you're good to go, and this gives you code completion,
auto import, all the things you would expect from an ID.