So, as promised, let's have a quick look at how you test handlers, and I'm not going to test all
of the handlers in this lecture, but I will do a couple, one that just displays a page and one that
actually handles a form post.
And those are these two routes right here.
I'm looking at my routes files, so I'll test the login screen and posting to the login screen.
And there's a couple of things you need to do to make this take place, because we don't want in our
tests to actually run a real database in the background.
We want to have a dummy database and we want to have complete control over that.
So what I've done and this is a fairly time consuming process, so I just did it and will show it to
you is in my repository.
I created a new file called Test Dash Repco, and that file has every single database function that
exists in our postgrads repo.
So I just duplicated them all, but I changed them to make them as simple as I possibly could.
For example, all users returns a slice of pointers to model user and a potentially an error.
So I just created an empty variable and returned that and Nhill and I did exactly that for every single
function.
So just return the bare minimum to get this to work.
And the other change in the test repo is that I'm not using the receiver of Postgrads DB repo.
I'm using the receiver of a pointer to test DB repo and you'll find that in the DB profile.
That's the other change that I made.
So I'm not going to force you to watch me type all of this stuff out because it's fairly time consuming
and not terribly difficult in DB Repo.
We have a new struct, a new type of struct named test DB repo and we have a new function, new testing
repo.
So those are the only changes I made for the database.
OK, so now we actually want to start building the tests and the tests are pretty straightforward.
But as is the case in pretty much any programming language and certainly Engo, you need to establish
the environment in which you're going to conduct testing and then go.
We do that by and I'm doing this in the internal folder.
In the handler's folder, I'm creating a new file, a new go file called Setup Underscore Testico.
And that is exactly what it has to be named.
So what we're going to do in this file is almost exactly let me go back to our main package and go to
the main dutko, almost exactly what we do in this function setup app.
So let's have a look at that.
Now, I don't care about reading flags because we're not going to be reading flags, but much of the
rest of what we see in here, I have to to some extent duplicate and I need to set up the environment
enough that I can actually run the appropriate handlers.
So let's go back to set up tests are set up test go and start working here.
So the first thing I need is a session and I'm going to give it a name, a new name I could use the
one that's already in the package called Session.
But I like to keep things clean, so I'll create a variable called test session and it's of type six
session manager.
And that's exactly the same type of the variable session in our main package.
OK, so set that up now because I'm running setup test, I'm going to have a function which will be
named Tessmann, OK, and it takes a parameter and I'm going to call the name M, but it's a type testing
M.
OK.
And inside of here, I'll start by using that test session variable I just created, because one of
the first things I do in setup Dash Apptio is actually set up the session.
So test session is equal to exact new because I'm using Alex Edwards, ESCs session manager and I'll
give it a lifetime test session.
Lifetime is equal to 24 times time dort hour, which is more than long enough for our purposes.
I can make it a few seconds, but I'll just make it 24 hours.
We'll make the Kushkaki persist test session dout.
Test session cookie persist equals true, and I will make the I have to set the same site attribute
on the cookie, so test session that cookie, same site and I'll make that equal to the constant HDB.
That same site lacks mode.
And I don't want these cookies to be secure for our testing purposes, test session, the cookie DOT's
secure.
Equals false.
OK, so that defines our session now in our application, we're actually using a postgrads store, but
here you can use a cookie store because I just need the cookie in the session to exist for the duration
of the tests.
We also need a mail queue, which we're not going to use, but I'll set it up because we might do this
later in testing.
Try that again.
Male Hugh.
Is a sign the value of make Channe Channel data, adult male data or male job, not male data.
And this is, again, just copying straight out of the setup test function or set up app function,
and I'll give it a limit of five.
OK, and now we'll define our config and I'll just create a variable.
A is a sign the value of config app config and I'll put in the bare minimum, I'll put in a DB which
will just be a pointer to a type of driver DB just so I can satisfy the requirements and that's never
going to get used.
The session will be our test session.
Which we just to find up here in production is going to be called a false.
The domain will just be localhost.
And the male Q, which we're not using, but we would for subsequent tests, will be male Q.
And that should be enough for that senator to define that variable, A, I'll take the package variable
app which already exists and make that a reference to it.
So we have it in the correct type.
We also need a preference map, even though I'm not going to use it.
I will say preference map is assign the value of make a map, string, string.
I'm just doing that so I can stick the preference map in the app.
And if you ever needed to populate it with information, you could do so in your tests.
And if we set it up now, it's out of the way.
App dot preference map is equal to preference map.
I also need a push or client, which I'm not using for this test.
But again, I may as well set it up as client is a sign the value of pusher dot client.
And we'll give it an app ID, too many quotes there.
Try that again, APD will make it one the same as we did before, our secret will make exactly what
we had before.
One, two, three, ABC and the key ABC.
One, two, three.
And we also need secure, which I'll set to false.
And host, which will be localhost four thousand one.
OK, so we have our clients set up, let's add that to our map, to our config.
W.S. client is equal to W.S. client.
And there's a few more things we need to set up, we actually need a monitor map, which is a sign the
value of make a map into and that one is a Kronborg entry.
And again, we're not using it, but we might for subsequent tests, we might as well set it up right
now and set out in our app config.
And we also need to get the actual Chron stuff and just to save some typing, I'll go over to set up
app and I'll see if I can find all of that.
Right here, we need this stuff, so I'll copy that, and this is just the scheduler, so I'm copying
the local zone down to Aptos scheduler, equal scheduler, and I'll paste that right into my setup test.
Now we need to create a repository, and I'm not going to create a repository the way that we did in
the last time because I don't want a true database repository.
Instead, we'll take advantage of that new test handlers.
So in order to make the repository, we're actually going to have to have a new function.
So if you go back to set up app, for example, and we go back to the main, which is right here, let's
see if I can find that.
Now, it's not in there must be an set up app, just let me look for repo.
There it is, so here in setup app at line 106 in mine, I actually create a repository by calling new
postgrads handlers on in the handler's package.
But instead of test, I don't want to do that because I don't actually want to have a true database
running.
So what I'm going to do is create a function outside of the function we've been working on in setup
test.
And I'm going to call it new test handlers.
And it will take a parameter, a of type pointer to configure app config, and that's it.
Now, in the other case, back in set up app, the new postgrads handlers actually takes two parameters.
The database driver, which we don't care about in our case, but we do care about the app config.
So the function I'm creating right now, new test handlers is almost identical to this one, but it
doesn't have that argument for the database.
So let's go back to setup test and finish writing our new test handler's function.
So it's going to return a pointer to DB repo, just like the postgrads one does.
And we will return ampersand DB repo and will populate the app, the app part of it, which we're going
to use with a the parameter we're receiving and the DB will be a instead of going to the actual Postgres
database will call that function.
DB Repo, new testing, DB Repo, our new testing repo and it just takes one parameter.
Hey so now that I have this function available I can actually call it.
So up here, back in our test main function, I will say repo is a sign the value of new test handlers.
And just pass it, my app.
So now that I have that repo, I can actually call new handlers, just as we do back and set up app
here, we call handlers, new handlers that's in set up app, which is in the main package.
So I have to prepend the package name over here and set up test because I'm duplicating this environment.
I simply pass new handlers, the repo I just created, which has a dummy database and my app variable.
And the last thing I think I need to set up.
Well, there's actually two things they need to set up.
One is called is to actually set up the helpers.
And again, now that I have this this new repository, my new app variable with the correct repo, I
can just say helper's.
New Helper's.
And pass it, my app.
Now, there's one thing I need to put at the end here before I forget, whenever you have a test main
function, as I do in my setup, underscore testing, go file, you have to call OS X, which seems
strange, but os x it, and then you have to pass the parameter emerg run, which will actually run
the tests just before this, this function exits.
So there's one more thing we need to take care of here, and it's something you might not have thought
of because it's not immediately obvious.
And that is when we're rendering a page in our application.
We're actually calling a function in this folder Helper's and it's inside the Helper's Digo file.
And in this file helpers, Doug, we have this variable views and that's used when we actually render
our page views of type jet new set.
So it's the new set type.
And inside of that we have a hard coded value that points to our views folder where we have all our
templates.
And the problem is when we run our tests, that path name is not correct because we're not actually
running the tests from the root level of our application.
We're running them from inside the internal folder and inside the handler's folder.
So to get around that, I'm going to do what I usually do and that's just create a function, a mutator
that allows me to overwrite the value of this variable if I ever need to.
So I will call it func.
SEPP views, and it will take one argument path, which is of type string, and it will return nothing.
And all I do is copy this, paste it into here and get rid of this part var because I'm overriding an
existing variable and I'll replace this with path.
Now I have this set views function available.
Let's give it a comment.
Set views sets the views variable for testing.
OK, now, back in my set up test, after I call my helpers function, I can actually just say helpers
set views and give it the correct path, which would be the current directory slash up one directory,
which gets me outside of the handler's folder and into the internals folder, slash up one directory,
which gets me to the root level of the application and then the views folder.
OK, so now we've got our setup test ready to go and we're ready to actually write some tests.
Sorry, but I had to take a break to get some caffeine to get through the rest of this lecture, which
is turning out to be a little bit longer than I anticipated.
But this is important content.
So we're ready to start writing some tests.
So I'm going to go to my handler's folder and I'll create a new file.
And I will call it handler's underscore test go.
And it has to end in underscore Testico.
So I'm going to write some tests that will test only two things.
And if I look at the roots file, here are the two I'm going to test.
I'm going to test the login screen displaying the login screen and actually handing the post, which
of course tests these two handlers, login screen and login.
I'm going to write what many people do and go and I do all the time.
I'll write table tests so I can very easily run a number of tests using the same function.
So to do that, I'm going to create variable and I'll call the variable login tests and it will be a
slice of Starbucks.
And let's describe the contents of each of the entries in the slice.
I'm going to have a name which is just for me, it's the name of the test I'm going to run and that's
a string.
I will have the URL, which again is a string.
I will have the method which will be either get or post.
So that's a string.
Then I will have the posted data, and that will be any time I'm running a test that requires an HTTP
post, I need to post some data and that will be of type URL values, which is a built in type, as
you know.
And then I'm going to have the expected response code, for example, 200 for HTP status, OK, or 303
for status C other and that will be of type empt.
OK, so those are my members or what I'm going to have in each entry in the slice now less populated
with each of our tests and I'll do two.
So the first one will be the test that just displays the login screen.
So I'll open new parentheses and I'll put it on multiple lines.
So it's readable.
The name, which is for my purposes, is just login screen.
The euro and the euro for displaying the login screen in our case is just the root level of our application,
the method in this case will be get because I'm not posting anything.
Therefore, I can skip the next entry posted data and my expected response code will be 200.
But I'll use the constant built into the package HDP status, OK, which just makes it more readable.
So that's our first test.
Our second test will will be the one that actually posts information to that form on the login screen.
So name I'll call it login screen, post the URL once again.
That's just slash the method.
In this case it will be post and this one does have some euro value.
So I need posted data and that will be of type you URL values and I'll just populate what people actually
enter onto that form.
And if you recall, there's a field called email and it's value.
It has to be in curly braces because you can actually have more than one value for a form post, for
example, a bunch of checkboxes.
But in this case we just have one.
So I'll put me at here.
Dotcom, it doesn't matter what it is, as long as there's a value.
And then I'll duplicate this line and my second value is actually password.
And for that I can put anything.
So I'll just put password.
And finally, what's my my expected response code in this case, it's status C other and if you look
at the at the actual handler, you'll see that that's exactly what we're looking for.
So those are my test cases.
Now I'm going to write a function function and I'll just call it test login screen.
And because we're in the testing package, it takes a parameter T of type points to testing dog T and
let's write the actual tests themselves.
So what I'll do because I'm running table tests is range through all the tests for I don't care about
the index and I'll call the individual entries.
E is assign the value of range through log-in tests.
Now, what we need to do, first of all, is to build request, just as you would have in a Web browser,
so somebody in a Web browser hits a page and issues a request to a page that sends a request to the
server.
So let's build a request request and I'll ignore the second parameter is assigned the value of right
from the TTP package we're going to call new request and the method will be IDOT method.
OK, now this after the method, what are we calling URL?
That's our URL.
And I'm not passing in any case any anything in any data.
In the first case, no body.
So I'm not posting a Jason request.
I'm not posting you are values.
But of course we have one that requires no posted values and we have one that does.
So let's surround this whole thing in an if statement.
If Eatock method is equal to get, then do this, otherwise do this.
So we'll handle the get requests first.
Our first case just testing, displaying the login screen.
Now, the next thing we want to do is create a response are is going to be a variable and I'm not going
to create a true HTP response.
Instead, I'll create from the HTP test package a new recorder and then actually gives me something.
If you look at its signature, it gives me a response recorder and a response recorder satisfies the
interface requirements for an HTTP response writer.
So we can use that as our response and link between these two things.
There's something else I need to do.
I need to actually add the ability to manage a session to our code, because if we actually go back
to our roots file and look, for example, at the login screen, so we'll go to the login screen method,
this actually immediately checks the session.
Now, back in our setup test, we built up a session, but we actually need to add that information
to the request we just generated right, right here.
So we made this request.
We have a request now.
We actually need to add some session data to it so we can actually use the session in our handler that
we're trying to test.
So I'm going to add that method in my setup test.
So let me go here.
And right at the very bottom, just before test new handlers, I'm going to write a funk, which I'll
call get X for context and it will take as a parameter a request, which is a pointer to HTTP request,
and it will return a context, that context.
OK, and this is a very simple function, I'm just going to create a new variable called Sirtex and
potentially an error that's assigned the value of from the test session variable we made in our setup
underscore test go file I will load, which is a built in method using the context from this request
request context.
That's the first parameter.
And I'll get the header request dot header doget and I'm looking for exactly like this X dash session.
So that gets me the information.
I need to be able to use the session and I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, I'll just log it logged up print line error and all I do now is return.
OK, so that gives me a method of getting the necessary information into our request.
Hands back a context that I can add back into a request.
So let's go back to our handlers test.
And in between request and response here, I'll simply call that function.
Cortex is assigned get context, and I handed the request we just made, and then I add that context
back into the request.
So request equals.
Request with context.
OK, so now we've got our request, we've added the necessary information for the session and we have
a response writer, a response recorder, actually, so let's get our handler.
Now, the thing is, what I want to do here is I want to call a method that's available to us that requires
an HTTP dog handler funk.
So I need to actually create a new variable, which I'll call handler is assigned.
The value of Al I'm going to do is cast my handler to an HTP handler func HGP dog handler func and make
sure you don't choose this one.
You need the one with the AH and I'm going to call the handler that displays the login screen, which
happens to be in my case, repo login screen.
Now that I have this handler, I can actually call the handler itself with the response recorder as
my response writer and the request so handler because it's been cast to an HDB handler func.
I have this method serve HTP and I hand it out and request and all I do at this point is test to see
if the response code I get back is the correct one.
So if our code is not equal to what my expected code is, my expected response code, if I'm not getting
back in this case and a 200 status, OK, then I have an error.
So I'll just write an error tag error.
I'll use it on error actually, and I'll put in percent s, which will be the name of this expected
percent D, which is the response code.
I expected to get back but got percent D and now I put in my substitutions for those placeholders idot
name and my expected is idot expected response code and when I got back is Irda code.
OK, so now I should be able to run this test.
Let's give it a try.
I'm in the correct directory, so go test dot.
And it passed.
That's great.
OK, so now let's handle the other case where I'm actually testing a post request.
The logic is very, very similar.
We still need to create this request.
So I'll just copy this line and modify it as necessary.
Actually, we need these lines as well and we need this line.
So we copy all of these and paste them in here and I'll just modify them.
In this case, we're not passing nothing in the body of the request.
We're actually posting data.
So we'll get rid of the Nhill and we'll substitute strings, that new reader, and we'll put in IDOT
posted data and will encode that.
And all this does is it takes are you rld up values and turns it into the format that's necessary to
satisfy the request for new request.
As you can see, it requires a method which is a string.
Are you Earl.
Which is a string and the body which is an IO reader.
So we just converted our posted data into an eye, a reader that gives me the request.
We still need to get the context for the session.
So we do that and we still need to create a response recorder.
And after this, we need to do pretty much what we did before.
So let me copy all of this these lines and get it pointed to the correct handler, which is not login
screen in this case, if you look at the actual routes, it links to log in.
OK, so that should run our second test.
So let's try this.
Let's come up here, open our terminal, clear the screen and go test.
This time I'll put Dash V for verbose and run it.
And there it is that actually passed the test, so those are our two test cases that I want to handle
for testing handlers.
Now, obviously, there's a few more things you might want to do right now.
I'm just passing this dummy data like me out here, dotcom and password.
And because we're actually using and if I look in my repository, we're using this test DB repo right
here.
The method that's being called when we post to our login screen is authenticate and all I'm doing is
returning a one and nothing and nil.
So it's not actually testing whether or not a login would work.
If you want to do that, you have two options.
One is to actually modify your test to use a real database, which is not great because we're testing
the handler, not the database.
A better solution would be to use these to pass parameters, email and test password and just put in
something like this.
If email is equal to admin at example, dot com and test password.
Is equal to password, then I'll put comments here, return valid login
ELT's, return invalid login so we would actually not need the statement here.
We could just get rid of this altogether and delete this line.
But you get the concept, so you use the data you're passing to your your Stubbe database methods to
determine what kind of response you send back.
Now, I'm not going to bother doing that.
I'll leave that as an exercise for you and I'll just put this back exactly as it was.
So there is how you test handlers.
And I was just a review and I intended this lecture to be much shorter than it actually turned out to
be.
But there you go.
This is an important thing to do and to know how to do so in the next lecture will look at how we're
going to test our WebSocket handlers.
And again, I'll just do one as an example.