All right, the last test I want to write is one that tests something that interacts with our pusher
client and I thought or push your server and I thought I would just use this one in the routes file.
The simplest one to use is the pusher off route.
And that calls this method pusher off.
And what that seems to look for are some parameters and it builds a response or builds a member data
object that it's called presence data and pushes that off to the server and gets some kind of response.
OK, so let's go look at our application.
I have this running and I have my pusher server running IP and I suggest you do two or nothing's going
to work.
And I'm going to open the JavaScript console.
I'm going to look at the network tab and I'm going to look at all the responses.
And now I'll reload the page.
And then what I'm looking for is called off right here.
The file.
It says file, which is a strange name, but anyway, it's off.
And that's the one that's actually making our request.
And if we look at this, the request has a socket ID and a channel name.
OK, so I'm going to leave that open and I'm going to go back to my ID and back to my handlers test.
And I've already created an empty method here to test the pusher off method.
And I'm going to copy everything from here, everything that's in the method named as a test to test
login screen.
And I'm getting the part that tests a post request because we are in fact making a post request.
And I'll just paste it in here to save some time typing and I'll modify it as necessary.
So because this is not a table test, these E's aren't going to work, but we'll fix that in a minute.
First of all, if you look back here in our Web browser, I'm making a form post and I'm passing two
pieces of information.
So let me create a variable, which I'll call posted data.
And it's going to be of type orld values, same as before.
And I'm going to put in there the two things that I see are being posted.
So one is socket ID and I'm going to copy this socket ID.
OK, I'll copy it and I'll call this socket ID, which is exactly what it's called in the Web browsers
console.
And then I'll put in the value that I just copied and pasted.
And the next one is called Channel Name and it's just private dash channel dash one.
So private dash channel dash one.
And it has the value of actually Erith at the wrong spot.
So I'll delete this, try that again.
This is called Channel Dasch name, right, channel underscore name.
Channel underscore name, so this is actually using our off to serve the private channel to connect
to the private channel, and this needs to have princes around it, curly braces.
Let's try that there.
I finally got that right now.
I do.
So I've got my posted data.
So what I'm going to do here is get rid of this E and instead just post the variable that I created
right here so that we'll post it.
And I'm posting it not to slash.
I'm pushing it to push her off, which is not actually being used in our case.
But I like to have things accurate.
So when I'm reading this in six months, I'll have some clue as to what I was doing.
OK, so we create a request.
We put in the session stuff, we create our response and then we call the appropriate method.
And the method we want to call here is not login.
It's pushed off.
OK, now what we're getting back.
Let's go back to the Web browser.
What we're getting back from this request is the response.
And we're actually getting some Jason and the Jason has this format.
So we have OTH and we can actually look at the payload to get a little closer.
Look at it, we have an off and then we have some scroll over here, an off apparently I can't do it.
And then we have channel data that comes after it right there and that's got some other fields in there.
So let's go back here.
And all I want to do is I want to first of all, check the response code, which should be here where
we want to get a status.
OK, so htp dot status, OK, and get rid of the extra E and here the error code should be.
I'll just change this message to make it really clean.
Expected response, two hundred, but got and I'll just put in a comma or a placeholder present the
pardon code.
OK, so we're going to check the status quo.
And that's great.
But I also want to check to Jason that's being fired back at us.
And the easiest way to do that, of course, is to create a new type, which I'll call pusher resp.
It will be a struct and I'm going to give it only one field off.
I could, of course, put all the necessary fields in to pass the entire JSON file, but I just want
to make sure that I get back something of value.
It's a type string.
And in JSON, I want this to be known as exactly it is as it is in a return JSON which is off.
So back here we actually have oth and I should get something back.
OK, so that's the only thing I care about.
I want to pass just enough of that Jason, to actually get our information.
So I'll create a new variable.
I'll call it P for Pusher and it's a type pusher resp.
And now I simply unmerciful the Jason that I'm getting back.
Jason Daudt, new decoder.
And I'm going to decode our body, which has the Jason response, and I want to decode it into Pete
check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I will say t dot fatele and I'll just pass in the error.
And assuming we get past that, then I should be able to verify that it actually exists.
So first of all, let's just log in print line, log, print line.
Got back and I'll just read that.
Peter off and then we'll read our test afterwards just to make sure this works, so I've got that test
going, I switch into my internal handlers directory, clear the screen and go test dashboard.
And I seem to get it back, so there we are, got back that string.
So what I can test for here is very simple if p dot off.
We'll say if Lenn of Peterhof equals zero, then we fail our test, if we get back nothing, if that
value is still empty, which it would be when I initialised it right here with this variable, I'll
just say Teda Şeref.
Arab works here.
Empty Jason response.
OK, and now we can actually run this test.
There you go.
So it's simply a matter when you're working with Pusher in WebSocket of looking at the JSON response
that you get in this case, and I think this is enough to get you started so you can start writing your
own tests.
Well, there we go.
That's all there is to that.