So this time around, we want to change our test, our test that interacts with handlers that connect
to our pusher compatible server, and we want to modify those tests so they no longer have to connect
to an external service.
And in order to do that, we need to make some changes to our code, but not very many.
And this isn't that difficult and it's incredibly useful any time you're writing tests that have to
interact with some external service because the procedure is basically the same.
So right now, I'm looking at set up dash app abogado.
That's what I'm looking at.
And I'm looking at in my code line 129, the part where I create a pusher client.
And what I'm going to do is look at that type pusher client.
So I'm going to roll my mouse over it and then I'll scroll down and look at the methods that it has.
If I create a type that has all of the public methods, all the ones that start with a capital letter,
the ones that are public, then I can actually replace what I have in my test.
I can replace an actual pusher client with one that seems to be a push her client, but doesn't actually
make an external call.
So let's get started doing that.
First of all, go over to my setup, underscore test, go file.
And at the very bottom, I'm going to create a new type, which I will call dummy WC and it's going
to be a struct.
Now it has to have some methods or some some members.
So let's go back to our setup app and look at what happens when we create a push or client.
And I'll just go straight to that code.
This is what I want right here.
I'm going to copy all of these members and close this and go back to my setup test and just paste them
in there.
OK, so now I have my dummy type in order to make this type satisfy the requirements of being a an actual
something that's compatible with a pusher client, I just need to go create those methods and then substitute
the return values of those methods to be whatever I want.
Now, there's quite a few methods here, and I'm not going to force you to watch me do all of them,
but I'll do a couple.
OK, so let's have a look again back at set up test and are actually the set up app and find that push
your client again.
And let's start with the first method that I see there, which is the first one with a capital letter
trigger.
So let's go look at Trigger.
I'll go in here and I'll find Trigger.
And there it is.
So what I'm going to do is copy this entire method.
And I'll go back to my set up test.
And I'll paste this in here and I'll change the receiver from client, which I can't find because it's
in a totally different package to my dummy WC and I'll just have it return nil because all it returns
is an error and I'll just have it return nil.
Now, that's one method, the method that we're actually using in our test, the one that the the handler
we're testing actually calls is a different one.
It's called Authenticate Presents Channel, and we know that because it tries to authenticate to a president's
channel.
So if we go back to our actual tests here, handlers tests and look at the pusher off, it's actually
trying to authenticate to private channel one.
So that's the method that I actually definitely need to put some different things in.
So let's go get that again.
I'll go back to here and find and I mean go, which is part of the push or package.
And I'll look for Authenticate Presence Channel right here.
So there's the method, I'll copy this and I'll go back to set up Testico and I'll paste this method
in here and all I'm going to do is, again, give it the correct receiver dummy.
We get rid of this return statement.
And in here I need to return some JSON.
So what I'm going to do and I'll do this when I'm actually copying all of the other things over and
modifying because you want to watch me do that for all these methods.
But you'll be able to copy and paste from the source code I put to this lecture.
And as long as I do a couple, you should have no trouble following along.
So what I need here is to create adjacent string, which I'll call J-Star, and then I'll just go copy
and paste the actual JSON that is posted from my Web browser.
I'll go to the inspector, find that necessary, JSON, paste it in here and then it's just a matter
of.
Saying.
Return a slice of bite's.
And what I'm returning is my J-Star, I got to put in a signed statement in their.
And Neil.
Because this returns a slice of bytes and an error, and as long as I return hard coded JSON and nothing
else, and I'll just move this up here so it's a little less ugly than this.
Absolutely will satisfy my requirements.
So what I'm going to do now is pause this video and go and copy all of the necessary methods that have
to be implemented and paste them in here and just make them return as little information as I possibly
can.
And once I'm done that, I'll resume recording and show you what to do next.
So I'll be right back.
So I'm back, I went and implemented all of the necessary methods that are visible, the ones with a
capital letter and as you can see here, I went to my Web browser and I opened the JavaScript console
and found what was sent back to me right here.
And just copy and paste that that Jason right into a string file and return it as a slice of bytes.
So now I have this type which actually will fulfill the requirements for being a a client pusher client
type.
So next, I need to open my model's file and I can put this anywhere I want, but I need to put it in
a different package, not in the main package.
And I'm going to put it in my models just to make things really straightforward.
And what I need to put in here is a type I'm going to define a new type called WSC Client, which is
a name I'm choosing, and it's WebSocket client and it is an interface.
And in here I need to put all of the methods that I defined over here.
So I'll copy Trigger.
And put it in here.
And then I'll copy Trigger Multi.
And put it on the next line, trigger exclusive and don't miss the return types, because that's an
easy thing to do.
And paste that there aren't very many.
So this won't take too long trigger multi exclusive copy.
And Paiste.
Then trigger batch copy.
Then channels Kopi.
And Paiste.
And channel singular and get its return types copy.
Then get channel users.
Authenticate, private channel copy.
Paiste.
Authenticate presence channel.
Kopi.
And Paiste.
Almost done.
Web hook.
Kopi.
And paste.
OK, so now I have this type, so what I'm going to do next is there's a typo here somewhere.
Oh yes, I didn't do my sports header.
There are fixes that so that just all that did was add the necessary import up here to net HTP.
OK, so I have this this type defined now and what I'm going to do is go back to my config file where
we define our application config and I'm going to change the type for W.S. client from pusher client
to the new type I just defined, which is model client.
Now if we go back to our setup test, no, our set dash app, we have an error.
And the error is if I roll over, it's a very simple one.
Cannot use W.S. client type Pusha because type does not implement models.
W.S. Client as trigger method has a pointer receiver and all I need to do is change that, put an ampersand
in front of it, make it a reference instead, and that makes that error go away.
So I've made that change and technically I should be able to.
Now where am I?
Yeah, I should be able to run my project.
And it starts without any problems and it starts because the pusher client type, we satisfied that
that necessary interface its interface requirements in the type we just created.
OK, so next step, let's go back to set up go and do a similar thing here where we set up our pusher
client.
So what we're doing right now is using pusher client and that's what's forcing us to make a request
to an external service.
So let's make some changes here.
I'll just do it right over here and we'll delete what we don't need after the fact.
So I'm going to create a new variable which are called DWC for dummy web sockets.
And I'll call it I'll make it of type dummy.
We and I will just put some values in here, RFID, and I can just copy this, because this is we're
never going to use them, but I'm just going to put them in there.
So it gives me some indication as to what it actually does.
Then I can delete the WC client we produced and make this a pointer to.
A reference to DWC, and that satisfies the necessary requirements.
So now I can go back to my actual test, which is in handler's test stock, go and get rid of this comment.
And what should happen at this point is I should be able to I'm going to if my application is running,
I'm going to quit.
It's not.
Good, I'm going to stop my IP server, so it's not raining at all, so I just stop that and I'll go
back to my test folder in CD Internal handlers and type Go Go Test Dashboard.
And everything passed, and that is a much cleaner way of writing any kind of test that depends upon
a remote service.
So that takes care of my example for how to test a handler that interacts with WebSocket using Pusha
or a pucher compatible client.