So we have our Mineo file system working as as expected, and it's time to turn our attention to secure
FTP.
FTP and to make that happen, the first thing I'll do is I'll open the dot on the file inside of my
app and I'll go down to the FTP section right here and populate the necessary values so we can connect
to our local Docker setup server.
And of course, the host for that is local host and make sure you spell it right or nothing will work.
The user we called FSF, FTP and the password was password not very secure, but fine for a local development
server and the port.
Normally, when you connect to SFO, it's Port 22 because it uses S.H. as its underlying transport method.
But Port, 22 is used in a lot of machines and we're listing on Port 2022 on our Docker installation.
So that's what we need for our set up in the.
And that's easy enough.
The next thing I need to do is to go to the celebrities package.
Open file systems and open the SFP file system.
And the file is as FTP don't go.
Now we have some stub functions in here right now, and of course, we're going to populate those and
we'll start with the put function.
But before we do that, of course, we need a client that knows about SFP servers.
We need to install that using Go Get.
So I'll open my terminal and I'll make sure I'm inside the celebrity's project and not inside my app
because we want to modify the government file for celebrities and not for my app.
And I'm in the right folder, so I'll just type.
Go get.
And this is a really good asset TV package.
GitHub dot com slash pcmagas FTP.
And if you go to that, you URL, GitHub, dot com slash, so on and so forth.
You'll see all the documentation for this, but it's really straightforward.
So let's go get that.
There it is.
And now we can use it.
Now I'm going to start with Typekit function, but just like I did with Mineo, I'm actually going to
create another function called get credentials because I have to get credentials for all operations
with the SFB server, and it'll have the receiver of S Pointer to FTP.
And just like I did in, meanwhile, I'll call it and get credentials and it takes no parameters, but
it returns two things.
The first one is a pointer to an FTP client right there, and the second one is potentially an error.
Now to connect or to get the necessary credentials and a client, I have to have an address to connect
to.
So EDR, it's just going to be a string and that's the address we're going to connect to.
And that will be a string using the format sprint package, which returns the string and my format string
is percent s colon percent s and the first value was the host.
And of course, I get that from the receiver I start host.
And the second value is the Port Start port again from the receiver.
So that gives me my connection string.
Now I need to build a configuration variable of type a pointer to SSA short client config because SFP
uses the underlying transport of secure shell or S-H, so we can just use a standard library for that
config, which is the variable name I'm choosing right now, is a reference to SSA H Don.
And eventually, it'll pop up there it is client config, and we'll just populate the fields that we
have to have, the first one is the user.
And that's easy.
I just comes in the receiver start user.
The second one is actually a slice of authentication methods now, because this is using SSA age, we
can connect using SSA keys or if the SSA servers configured to accept it, just a username and password.
And we want to keep this simple.
So we'll use the username and password, which are Docker image supports anyway.
So the field is called off and it takes a slice of SSA each dot off method, and we're just going to
put one in there.
But because it's a slice, of course, you could put multiple authentication methods in there and we
want SSA short password and our password again from the receiver, our pass.
So that's the first two things we need in our config.
And the last one is just to make things simpler for us.
Host key callback.
We're going to use SSA dot insecure, host key, insecure, ignore host key right there.
And that allows us not to get queries for unknown hosts and things like that.
So that's our configuration.
So that's all right.
Now, once we have that config variable, we get a connection.
Con is my variable name and we'll check for an error, and that is those are assigned the value of SSA.
Don't dial.
That's how you connect to an SSA SFTP server.
And our method is TCP, which is standard for the internet.
We're going to ADR the address, which is the host and the port.
And we're using the config values stored in config and we'll check for an error if error is not equal
to nil.
And I'll return nil for the client because we don't have one and the error.
But if we get past that now, we can get our client client.
And again, checking for an error there assign the value of from the SFO, S.F. TP Package Dot new client
and that requires a connection which we just made called Con, and we'll check for an error again.
So I'll just copy and paste this error.
Check
and paste that in here.
And now, once we're connected, we want to find out what the working directory is, what's the current
directory on the server?
So I'm going to store that in a variable called S.W.A.T and I'll check for an error and those come from
Client Dot, get WD, get working directory, OK?
And I'm just going to print that out just so we can see what the directory is on the print line.
Current working directory, this is just for our information.
OK, and finally, I'll return the client and Neal, because there was no error.
So now I have a means of connecting to the server.
So now let's take care of our put function.
And that's the one will do in this lecture.
Now, Put takes two parameters file name and where do you want to put it?
The folder?
OK.
And it potentially returns an error, and we can't change the parameters because if we do, we will
no longer satisfy the interface for file systems fs.
So that's a limitation that we have, but it's not a big problem.
So right now, this stub function returns nil.
The very first thing I want to do is get a client and check for an error, and I get that by calling
ask, don't get credentials and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return the error.
OK, so now we have a client, but we want to make sure that client doesn't stay open because it will
actually keep our connection to the SFP server open and eventually we'll run out of connections.
So we have to put in a defer client.
Got close.
And of course, that will run when this function exits.
And at that point, our put operation should be done and we want that connection to be closed.
And this the rest of this function is remarkably similar to to mine, i o.
But of course, we're using type, so there are some differences.
So I'll declare a variable f for file and I'll check for an error.
And those come from the OAC package part of the standard library.
I'll open.
And I'm opening a file, and the file I'm opening, of course, is the parameter pass to this function
file name.
So it's open now and again we'll look for an error.
So I'll copy and paste this error checking right here because it's exactly the same.
But if I've opened it, then I need to close it when this function is done, so again, defer foreclose.
So now I have opened my client.
I've opened a file and I've deferred clothes for both of the client and the file itself.
Now I need to create a file called F-2.
I can call it whatever I want.
That's just a variable name I'm choosing.
And again, I'm checking for an error and I'll call client.
That's our SFB Client Dot create, and I'm going to create.
I want the base file name of what was passed to us in file name, so it might be slash temp slash,
whatever the file name, I just want the file name.
And again, I can use that path base.
So path to spell, right?
Don Bass and I give it filing.
And that gives me the name of the file that I want to create, which will be the same as the name of
the file that was uploaded and will paste in our check.
And now we again defer to foreclose because we don't want to leave that file open either.
Or we'll have a resource leak and bad things will happen eventually.
And finally, I want to copy F2 or F2 F2, so if we don't care about the first return value, but we
do care about an error and that comes from Io built right into the standard library dot copy.
Our destination is F2.
That file we created using the SFD clients.
So that's on the remote server and we're copying F..
And if error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll return the error return to Earth.
Otherwise, everything worked as expected, so that should do the trick for us.
Now is there anything missing here?
Well, one thing that I notice is that I have that variable folder that I'm not using.
And of course, that tells me where I want to put it on the remote server.
Well, let's just leave it like that for right now.
And when we start experimenting with this, we'll see if we need to make any changes.
But that's enough to get us started.
OK?
We'll move on in the next lecture to the next required function.
Let's move on.