So we have the put functionality for us ready to go more or less, we still have to think about this
folder parameter that we're not using.
We'll come back to that later on.
Let's move on and take care of list now.
List is pretty straightforward.
We're going to have our variable listing, which is a slice of types, file system listings.
So that doesn't change.
And we're going to return listing in nil.
It's all this stuff in between that we have to worry about.
So once again, we're going to need a client that's up to be client.
So client and error come from just like before they start.
Get credentials and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return the error.
So a return listing and we'll return the error.
And we needed to defer client closing once again, so defer client thought close just to make sure that
a safety B connection is closed.
Now, let's get our directory listing, and that's pretty straight forward with the SFO client will
say files in error are assigned value from calling client dot reader.
Read Dear right there and the direction we want to read, of course, is our prefix, the one parameter
we get in this function.
So that'll give us a listing for a particular directory on the remote server.
And we checked for an error.
So again, I'll copy my error, check right here and paste it right here.
And if we get past that, then we just range through the files.
So for we don't care about the index.
We do care about the current item, which I'll just call X. You can call it whatever you want.
Those are assigned values by ranging through files, and all we do is, as usual, create an item variable
and that will be a type file systems dot listing.
And again, we want to check to make sure that we're only going to show the files we want to show,
so we don't want anything that starts with a dot because that might be a hidden file.
So if not, strings Dot has prefix and we're looking at x dot name.
The name of the file, it's not called key by this package.
It's called name.
But that's exactly what we're looking at is the file name, and we're looking for a dot as a prefix.
So if it doesn't have that, then we want to actually once again calculate the size of the file exactly
like we did before.
B is assigned the value of float.
Sixty four, we're going to cast it to that exact size and that's built right into the item type that
we're getting back and we'll figure out what kilobits are.
Kilobytes is assigned the value of B divided by 1024,
and then we convert it into megabytes, and that's a sign of value of kilobytes divided by one thousand
twenty four.
And now we populate the various fields in item, which is a type file system dot listing.
So Item Dot key, that's the name that's going to be equal to extort name.
Item size is equal to megabytes MBIE.
Item Dot last modified.
That's going to be equal to extort mod time.
The modification time and now we want to see if it's a directory or not.
Item Dot is dear.
There's equal to export and it fortunately has a function called is dear.
And that tells me if the entry in the current entry is a directory or not.
And then we append our item to listing.
Listing equals append listing and item, and all we do next is return.
We already have that line, I think.
Yes, we do.
We return the listing and no error, and that should be it for the list functionality, and we'll test
this out at the end of this section.
But for right now, let's move on.