So we only have two more functions to complete in the S&P Go file in order for this to satisfy and be
functional, to satisfy the file systems interface.
Those are delete and get in this time around will take care of delete.
And the first thing I'll do is say some typing by coming up here and copying the client bit from list
where I get my client right up to and including defer client close and we'll come down here and put
it in the delete function.
We'll have to fix the return type and we return a false instead of what we were doing with a list function.
So.
Now, after we defer client clothes, it becomes dead simple.
All we're doing here is we're getting a slice of strings which have the full path name to all the files
we want to delete on the remote server.
So we'll just range through it for we don't care about the index, we do care about the current item,
which I'll call X again.
Those are populated by ranging through items to delete, and it's simple.
We get checked for an error delete error, which I'll call it, that is assigned the value from calling
Client SD as client got removed.
And that's what delete something and we're going to delete X if there is an error.
If delete error is not equal to nil, then as you say, return false.
OK, something went wrong.
And I have read dear when it should say, remove how I did that.
There we go.
That makes more sense.
And that is literally it.
Now, of course, I'm returning a boolean.
You may want to return an error instead.
That's entirely up to you, but a simple that's a simple enough change to make.
Of course, you'd have to change the signature for all of the required methods in file system start
ifs.
So the delete returns in error instead of a Boolean.
But I'm OK with the Boolean, so I'll leave it like that.
So that was delete that was dead simple.
And in the next lecture, we'll take care of get and then we'll try things out.