So the last functioning we have to implement in order to make this work is to get function, and as
was the case with Mineo, this is a function you may not use very often, but when you need it, it's
nice to have it, so we might as well implement it.
It's not that difficult.
So the first thing I'll do is get a client and I'll just copy the code here from the delete function
pasted here before the return.
And now I have a client and we're not returning false in this case or returning the error.
OK.
So now that we have a client.
Well, how do you put something up there?
Well, the thing we need to pay attention to is we might be putting more than one item up because we're
accepting a very adequate argument at the very end of the get function.
So we'll have one or more thing to get, so we'll range through that four.
Again, we don't care about the index and again, we do care about the item, which I'll call once again.
I shall call it item this time.
Why not?
And we'll range through items.
And what we have to do is, first of all, create a destination file.
So we do that the standard way I'll call it DST file and I'll check for an error.
And that's a sign those are assigned values by calling Osako create or just creating something on our
own server, not on the FTP server.
We're getting it from the SDP server and we have to have somewhere to put it.
So we'll create that file and we'll create it.
We need to build a string, so we'll use format as printouts as usual.
Yes.
Print, yes.
Give it a format string and that will be in the form of percent as percent s.
And the replacements for those placeholders are the first parameter from the call to get destination.
And then we want the name of the current item.
But again, that's coming as a full path name.
So we have to use Path Dot Base to get just the following half dot base again base and we're going to
use it.
So that creates the file potentially gives us an error.
So we'll check for an error if error is not equal to no.
Then we'll return the error return in the file system's full.
That path name doesn't exist.
Whatever the case is, we can't create the file.
We don't want to go any further.
Now that we've created that file.
Of course, we have to defer closing it.
Defer test file.
Duclos don't want to have a resource leak, and then we want to open the source file.
So source file and potentially here.
And we just call our SFO be client client open and we open open file open.
And again, if there's an error, we return it.
So I'll copy and paste.
Now we want a copy.
Copy source file to desk.
So copy source to Dest.
And that's easy enough.
We get the bytes and an error by calling Ioco Copy.
Dust file.
And source file.
And what are we going to do with those bites?
Well, first of all, we'll check for an error.
So let's just copy and paste this.
We actually don't need those bites, but we should have put this out to the long, so I'll say log dot
print line just so we know what's going on and we'll remove this later on and we'll say percent d because
we're getting bites as an integer bytes copied just so we can see things happening.
Put my substitution, which is bytes, and there's one more thing that we have to do, and this is kind
of specific to Asaph St.
What we need to do is to flush the in-memory copy.
Otherwise, things might not work as expected, and that's really easy.
Error is equal to test file sync.
Right there.
And again, pasting my error check.
OK.
And I think that will do it for us.
So if everything goes according to plan and we might have to do some cleanup here, but if everything
goes according to plan, this long, desperate line is not going to work that should be format as print
f.
And close this.
That's better.
OK.
So if everything goes according to plan, we should be able now to go and make the appropriate changes
to the handlers for our web pages and try things out and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.