So we have all of the necessary functions implemented in our executive go file, and now we're ready
to start trying things out with celebrities.
Now, to be clear, there are some things we're going to want to clean up, particularly this get function,
but we'll get to those shortly.
Don't worry about that right now.
Let's just see if we can get it working.
And of course, the first thing I have to do is to go to celebrities.
The celebrities project and open up celebrities don't go and find that bit.
Where I create the file systems in my code, it's right here in the file.
Celebrities don't go around line three hundred and eighty three, and the only one we have right now
is midnight.
So of course, we also want to add one for SFTP, and we can use the same logic to see whether or not
we should try to create that file system and add it to the map for celebrities.
We can say if OST don't get on and we're going to look for something I know that is in my own file and
that's s f t p underscore host.
If that exists, and it does exist, probably.
But if it's not equal to an empty string, which is what it will be if there's no value set there or
if it can't find that key in the data on file, if it's not equal to an empty string, then I want to
try to set it up.
So I'll create a variable called SFTP, which makes sense and will make that equal to S.F. file systems,
which it should find for me, SFTP and I did, and we'll just populate its fields.
And it needs a host, and we get that from the OS oes don't get on.
And that is SFTP host said TP underscore host as a t p there is.
And we need the user and that's.
Don't get on TPY user right there.
We want the password.
So pass.
And that's O.S., don't get on SFTP Pass.
And the last thing, of course, is the port.
Port, and that's equal to OS, don't get on SFTP port.
OK, so now we've created that variable.
We just added to the map.
So we'll add to our map file systems at the key SFP, which seems logical.
We'll make that equal to SFTP.
And that should be all we have to do to create their connect celebrities to that particular file system.
Of course, we still have to use it and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.