So now that we have our SFB file system connected to celebrities, the next step is to go to our handlers
over in my app.
So let's open up the file.
My handlers don't go in the handlers folder in my app project and right here at the List F's file system.
That's when I'll start with.
It should be easy at this point.
If you scroll down in this function called List EFS, we have this switch statement.
We're switching on FS type.
And right now we're only trapping for the case material.
So I'll copy all of this, but not the closing curly bracket.
Or we'll have a syntax error and I'll paste it here and I'll just change it.
I'll make this one SFTP and I'll make this as FPP and this as well as FTP.
And since we're grabbing the key of ESDP from this map file systems, we're not going to cast it to
mean I'll Filesystem will cast it to FTP file system FTP.
And that should be all I have to do.
Except before we run this, it'll be useful to have a file in R.S.V.P. folder to make sure that things
work, so I'll go to my desktop.
And I'll put this file, it doesn't matter what the file is, but I put it inside the folder SFTP,
which is, of course, in my app DV data SFTP.
And that should do the trick.
So let's go back here to our I.D. and start our application.
Make start.
So it's running, so I switched my Web browser.
And I'll go to local host 4000 right there, and I'll go to filesystems and see if we got it right.
So let's make sure that Mineo still works.
It does.
Now let's look at SFTP.
And there it is, their source dog zip now delete doesn't work and uploading doesn't work.
But at this point, that's trivial.
We're basically using the same logic.
We're adding something to our switch statements.
So we'll get started on uploading a file in the next lecture.