So we're getting closer, and the next step is to handle uploading something to our remote FTP server
so that can handlers start go?
Let's go down and find the post upload to Efes right here.
And basically the same logic as we applied last time around applies this time.
I'm going to copy this case for minute
and paste it right here and change this to S.F..
And again, I'm going to look at my application file systems field for the key SFTP and cast that to
an SFO file system.
SFTP.
And literally that should take care of it.
There's no other change necessary to make, and this is largely because we took all that time to make
sure that our file systems all conform to the same interface.
All right.
So let's stop her application.
Make stop.
Make start.
And see if this works actor or web browser, and right now, I have one thing on my SFB file system
SawStop Zip.
So let's try uploading something to that.
So we'll choose SFP and I'll find some file doesn't matter what it is.
I'll choose this way of image again, and I'll try uploading that and see how this works out.
And it says it's uploaded, let's go see if we can find it.
File systems, list files and I'm going to choose S&P and the whale should be there.
And there it is.
And that works really well.
Now one more thing to look at here.
If we go back to our I.D. and look at the console, you can see that little statement, I said to print
the current working directory.
It says current working directory is slash.
And of course, if I want to upload to another place on that file system, say a folder underneath the
root level, of course, that's where this bit.
And we'll find it here over insularity, us under filesystems, under SFTP.
We find the part that puts it up there.
Which is right here.
This is where we need to make a slight modification to our code.
We don't always want to upload to the root level of our file system.
Instead, we should probably modify this code right here where it says client create path based file
name.
We should change that, maybe to an s print f so format print f with a format string.
And that would be percent s slash percent s.
And then in here, we can take this first parameter or take this parameter out, cut it.
And our substitutions in now would be folder that parameter that we received up in the signature for
this function.
And now we can put the based file name in there, and that will allow us to upload to a specific location
on the remote file system.
So that was just a simple change.
OK.
All right.
Next, we'll take care of deleting something from our SFTP server.