So the last step in this process with her SFB file system.
Well, not quite the last step.
We have a bit of cleanup to do, but we'll do that in a moment.
The last major step is to permit deleting files from the remote as it SFB server.
And of course, that's done here in handlers.
Don't go in the Maya project in the handler named Delete from.
And it probably comes as no surprise that what I'm going to do is copy this case in a switch statement.
Paste it right here and change this to S&P.
Change the key to s f t p and cast everything to the appropriate data type, which is as FTB File System
S&P.
And with that one change, I should be able to say make stop.
Make start.
Wait for it to compile.
Switch over to my Web browser list, my SFTP file system, and let's delete, say, SawStop Zip, I
click the delete button and delete and it's gone.
And that's all there is to it.
OK, so S&P is mostly functional.
Actually, it's entirely functional, but I do want to do a bit of cleanup in one bit of code, and
we'll take care of that last little bit of housekeeping in the next lecture.