So the last thing I want to take care of with respect to SFTP is just so clean up to this get function.
And I deliberately left this function the way that you see it right now.
Just so I'd have an opportunity to talk about resource leaks that don't show up for a long time.
If you recall, what the get function does is it allows us to go to the remote SFB server and pull one
or more files down to the server, to the server where a web application lives, which is something
you're not going to have to do very often, but you do sometimes, and it's convenient to have this
function.
And if you actually look at this function in detail and you may already have noticed this, and if you
did good for you, there actually is the potential for one or more resource leaks.
For a couple of reasons to start with.
I'm ranging through here in line 127 right down to the line 153.
I'm ranging through items which we receive as one or more strings as the final parameters in the call
to the get function and my I.D. and probably yours also gives you this kind of warning.
Possible resource leak defer is called in the for loop, and that can be a problem.
And the other thing you might have noticed is down here, we open the source file, but we never actually
close it.
And the fact is, if you don't use this, get function very often, this is a resource leak that you
might not see for a very long time.
In other words, it's a problem in our code base that is really, well hidden.
We're not going to see it for a long time, possibly months, maybe even years.
But fortunately, it's pretty easy to fix.
So to start with, what I'm going to do is take the contents of this for loop and wrap everything between
Line 127 and Line 155 in a function.
So we'll look for an error because my function and I'll just use an inline function.
Which returns an error, I'll get rid of this closing parentheses and come away down here and close
it off and then give it the double parentheses that it requires.
And then we'll say return nil to get rid of the error that shows up now.
And now all I have to do is say, if error is not equal to nil,
return the error.
And the last step here is I'll get rid of this long because we don't need that anymore.
And I'll get rid of the bikes because we don't need that anymore and we never actually used it.
But that doesn't matter
is after I create this source file, I come down here and say, Defer source file, I'll close.
Now these two defers are really not in the loop as far as they're they're concerned.
That's why we don't have a warning for defer here.
We do have a warning on clothes that says this actually throws an error, but I don't care about that.
And almost nobody does in my experience.
But the important thing to note is because I wrap the entire contents of this for loop in its own function,
which returns in error.
I only have to check for error down here at the end of the four loop, and that takes care of the possible
resource leaks that you would have.
The nice thing about the first statement is it will always execute as soon as the function that it exists
in finishes.
And in this case, that's this function is inline function, not the overall function.
Yeah.
So that solves that problem.
And that's just a bit of housekeeping.
And I deliberately left that until the end of this section because because this is the sort of thing
you might run into now and again.
All right, let's move on to our next file system.