So in this section of the course, we're going to be working with databases and we're going to be working
with post-cruise and maestro.
We're actually MariaDB, which is a drop in replacement for MySchool and a bit later on in the course,
we're also going to be working with Reddit's.
And I think the simplest way to get these three things installed is using Docker.
And of course, if you don't have Docker installed, the first step is to install Docker.
So I have links to three resources here on the course resources for this lecture.
One is how to install Docker on a Mac.
And there's two big buttons here.
If you have an Intel chip like I do, this is the one you want if you're fortunate enough to have an
M1 chip or one of Apple's chips.
This is the one you want, so download that and install it.
And it's really, really straightforward if you're on windows.
Of course, this is the one you want.
And again, it's very, very simple to install it.
All of the instructions are here and there.
They're detailed very well.
And if you're on Linux, chances are you're not going to have any difficulty installing it.
Your favorite package manager for whatever your district is probably has Docker.
And if not, there are instructions here for Ubuntu.
But there's all kinds of resources out there for how to install Docker on Linux.
So get that installed in in.
The next lesson will use a Docker compose file to install Postgres, Redis and Maria DB as Docker images.