So now that we have Docker installed, we can use Docker Compose to set up an easy to use development
environment that has a copy of Postgres and read and read is running.
And of course, if you already have those installed, feel free to use those and just skip this lecture
and use your installed databases.
But I'm going to assume that you don't.
So the very first thing I'll do is I'm in my app.
That's the project admin.
I'm going to create a new folder at the root level of this project, a new folder.
And I'm going to call it VB Dash data, because that is where I'm going to have my Docker images store
their data.
We could just let Docker manage it and put it wherever it wants to, but I'd like to make these things
explicit.
And on the course resources for this lecture, you will find a file you can download called Docker Compose
Dot Wiimote, it's a YAML file and just copy that contents of that and create a new file at the root
level of your Maya project called Docker Dash, composed y and built, and make sure it's exactly that
name.
No uppercase letters, nothing like that.
Now I have a copy of this on my clipboard, so let me paste it in and we'll go through it.
This is a really simple Docker compose file, and it allows me to go get a copy of Postgres to specify
on my local machine.
I'm going to listen to Port five four three two, which is the default Postgres port, and on the Docker
network, it's going to port five four three two as well.
And I'm specifying a Postgres user named Postgres a password of password and a database called celebrities.
And the nice thing about this is that the first time I run this, if that database doesn't exist, it
will be created.
And I'm also telling it Use this for your volume store in the current directory.
Gabe Dash data create a folder called Postgres and link that to this directory on the container.
And we do the same thing with Redis and the same thing with MariaDB.
So now that I have that there and I just installed Docker, I uninstalled it and then reinstalled it
so we'd be able to start from scratch.
I just type Docker Dash compose up and away it goes.
It begins pulling all these things at the very first time you do it.
Of course, it has to pull these images down and it will take a while to start up.
I have a relatively fast internet connection, so it's not taking me very long.
It might take you a bit longer.
But only the first time.
And I got an error because apparently I need to go into my debrief dash data and create a new folder
called Postgres and what are the other two named?
It's a good thing I did this from scratch, so post-cruise Redis and MariaDB.
So I'll create another folder inside of DB data a new folder, Redis and a third folder new folder.
Where?
Yeah, DV.
OK.
So let's bring this back up and clear that screen and type Docker compose up again.
And there it goes.
Starting up databases, starting at MariaDB and of course, the very first time they start, it takes
a while to initialize this and you'll see warnings and things in the log file.
But just ignore those.
OK, I need to make sure everything gets started up before I try to connect to any.
Server started.
Let's try this, and it's still doing its thing.
And now it's ready to accept connections.
OK, so now I'm going to start up my favorite Postgres client and I'm back and on the Mac that happens
to be post code, which I have to pay for.
But it's not very expensive, and the free version works really well.
You just can't open that many databases at the same time.
So I'll create a new favorite and I'm going to call this celebrity's Dash Docker.
The host is local host.
The port is five four three two.
The user is Postgres.
The password is just password, which I specified in my Docker Dash composed, don't worry email and
I'll say, save it and I'll make the database celebrities.
So let's connect and see if this works.
There it is.
I'm connected.
No problem.
And you can do the same thing with Redis from the command line if you want to, or the same thing using
your favorite MySchool client to connect to MariaDB.
Now that's up and running.
So let's close it by hitting control C to stop it.
OK.
I can run this in the background by typing Docker Dash compose
up.
Dash D to send it to the background and it will run in the background.
So starting them all up and there it goes, and it always takes a few seconds after you start it, before
you can actually connect to the database, but not a terribly long time.
And to bring it down now it's Docker Dash compose.
Now what?
So whatever Makefile over here, my file and I'll close the terminal window and let's add a couple of
things here.
I'll put it right before the test.
OK, I want to make this easy for myself.
I'm going to add one called start, underscore, compose or whatever you want to call it, colon.
And it has one command Docker Dash compose, which I better to spell right up dashti throughout the
background and not surprisingly, start compose Docker Dash compose down.
So now if I save that and open my terminal window and clear the screen and type, make start, compose
and actually starts my network for me.
And then we go, and that will keep running until you actually tell it to come down.
And of course, while you're working in the project, you can start it up.
And while you're not working in the project, you can tear it down.
And the great thing about this, of course, is in lots of situations when you're working for a particular
employer or for a particular client.
If you happen to be a freelancer, they're going to want specific database versions in a lot of cases.
And Docker makes it trivial to install specific versions of whatever software you want.
OK, now that we have this setup and we have our database running, we can start writing the code necessary
to make our Celerity House package support different databases and we'll start with Postgres.