So in this part of the course, we're going to build a rather interesting little project and it's one
that is used to monitor external services on various servers out there.
So I'll just show you how it works.
I'll just log in here.
All right, I'm calling this vigilante, which is just a Latin word, that means watch, because the
entire purpose of this application is to watch remote services on remote servers and notify someone
when things go awry or when they go down.
So right now, you'll see that this is the dashboard.
I have to help these services.
And there's only one host on monitoring, which is Google, which is usually up, no warnings, no problems
and no pending services.
So let's go look at Google.
So we'll look at Google.
And you can see here we have some basic information about the server.
You know, where is it located?
What is the world to find it?
I can validate that this is a valid UFO and I connected to it successfully.
So that's good.
I can manage it services.
There's only two that I'm monitoring here.
Can I ping it and can I connect to to it using https and I can look at the settings, check this every
three and I can change minutes, hours or days.
How frequently do you want to check it.
So on and so forth.
What are the healthy services.
I can refresh it and that works great.
It just refreshes and stays there.
I can see any warnings, any problems or any services that are not being checked right now.
So I'm going to add a host.
I'm going to go to hosts and say add a new host and I'll call this local server.
And the URL is HDP colon slash slash localhost eighty eighty, which is a Web server I have running
locally and it's where its location is right here and its operating system is Mac OS X.
So let me test that to make sure I can connect to it.
I can.
So I'll save that.
I'll say save and continue and then I'll add a service so I'll add a service and I'll just add HlV there.
So Sanaz it's added it and I have not left this page and yet this appeared here.
I actually change the contents of this table based upon using web sockets.
Now I'm going to open another window here to show you how this works.
So I'll open the settings are not the settings.
I'll open the schedule window and I will drag this down and resize this window so that it's over here
and resize this window.
Make it a little smaller, too, and I'll just drag it over to about here and then this way.
OK, so now we can see two windows at the same time.
Now you'll see that this schedule, this is a list, this lists what is currently being checked.
I'm going to turn monitoring on and notice how this automatically refreshes.
I use Web sockets to update what's going on in that table.
And we're going to use this application.
We're going to build this from the ground up.
I'll give you some starter code so you don't have to write the boilerplate.
We're going to write code that uses Web sockets to update everything in real time without leaving the
page.
And we're going to do it using a pusher compliant server.
You can use Pusha if you want to, but I'm going to show you how to use a free version and we'll do
it all through Web sockets.
Now, there's lots of other things we can do in here as well.
One of the things that we'll be doing is under settings.
You can say you can determine how do you want to be notified.
So you have to specify the URL of this application because we're going to be sending email encryption
key may or may not make it to the final version, but it's here right now, notifications and scheduling.
How do you want to be notified of problems and recovery by email and by text message?
So email, I've put my information in here and for text messages, I'll just put in a fake phone number
555 one, two, one, two.
And I'll save and continue.
And if I go to mail settings, you can specify your mail server.
And for text message settings, I'm only going to bother with one provider.
I'll say yes, enable text message and the provider will be Twilio because it's really easy to use.
So we'll specify all of this information and then we'll test things.
So let's go back to our overview and you'll see right now I have one pending service I'm monitoring.
Let me go to that pending service and refresh it.
And I got a little message saying the servers, OK, and it automatically populated the healthy table
or the healthy tab at the table in the healthy tab.
Now, I'm going to go over here and I'm going to stop that application running on Port AT&amp;T and come
back here.
And if we look at our schedule, when's it next going to check it, it's going to check it at 11, 28
and it is 11, 27, 53, that's a whole minute.
I'm not going to wait a minute.
I'll just go back to overview and go to healthy services and look at local server and refresh that.
And it says there is a problem here and I can click on details and it would take me right to the problems
tab showing me that error connected.
So this is what we're going to build.
It's going to take a little while.
But as I said, I'm going to give you some starter code that will make things a little simpler for you.
We're going to focus on the WebSocket aspect and not the Web application aspect, but it'll be fun.
So let's get started.