So it's time to start working with the database and what we're going to do is install a database and
the one I'm recommending and the one I'll be using throughout the remainder of this course is Postgres.
There are other ones, of course, but postgrads is the one I'm going to work with.
And what we're going to do is install this, install a graphical client that allows us to connect to
it and we'll figure out how databases work before we actually get to the steps where we hook our application
up to postgrads and start persisting our data in that way.
So the install for postgrads is found at this early PostgreSQL Duggie download, and we're going to
do it slightly differently depending on whether you're on Windows or Mac.
We'll start with windows.
If you're on windows, click on the Windows button and what you're going to do is click download the
installer right here and that will take you to a page that shows all the various downloads.
And assuming you're on a Windows 64 bit system, which most of you probably are because 32 bit systems
are getting really old, download this version at the time I record this, it's thirteen point one.
Download that and run the installer.
Now, when you run the installer, when you get to the second or third step of the installer, it's
going to ask you, first of all, ask you to set postgrads, say yes, then step to choose a directory.
Just choose the default directory.
Step three is going to say select components.
And I strongly recommend you leave postgrads server installed.
You have to have that.
That'll be the first option.
The second option is called PJI admin for uncheck that.
And I want to suggest you uncheck that for a simple reason.
That is a client that isn't installed as part of the process that actually allows you to connect to
your database through a Web browser and manage the content that way.
So it's a graphical user interface that installs a server on your machine and allows you to connect
to your local installation of the database through Web browser.
The problem with that is every time I have tried to use that, it has grabbed all the system resources
from my computer.
Are there my Windows machine or my Mac machine to the point where things become unresponsive.
So I strongly recommend you don't install PJI admin for but leave everything else check to the postgrads
server, the command line tools and leave two of them unchecked.
PJI had been for and don't bother with Stack Builder.
That's of no value to us for this course.
So you're only going to have two things checked when you install on Windows Postgrads Server and command
line tools and then install it.
Now if you're on a Mac, it's a little easier.
So we're going to go back here to packages.
This is where we started off on the download page.
Choose Mac OS and scroll down.
Scroll down to this part PostgreSQL app, download this application and it's really, really easy.
It's just an application that you when you run it, you use double click on it to start it.
Your server is running and when you quit out of it, your server shuts down and you can't get any simpler
than that.
So that's how you install the database server on your local machine.
Then in order to connect to that server using a graphical user interface, we're going to go to this
place de Beever DB ver community.
So it's called DB Beavertail Slash Download and download the community edition.
So for Windows there's a 64 64 bit installer and for Mac here's the installer or the DMG.
Use whichever version you want, but install that and once you do, you'll be all set, will be able
to connect to our local machine and will be able to start doing things.
So get those things installed and when you're done, come back and we'll move on to the next lecture
and start playing with the actual database.