So it's time to install the starter code for our project, and you're going to get that by going to
GitHub, Dotcom, TESOL Vigilante Vigilante and I have posted a link to this in the course resources
for the this lecture.
And what you have here is an application, it's called vigilante vigilantes, a Latin word, in case
you're curious, that means watch.
And this is an application that will, by the time we're finished with this project or this course,
watch servers, remote servers and services on remote servers and notify people when something goes
wrong or when something gets better.
So it will notify users by email, by SMS if you choose to implement that.
So so text messages.
And this is the part that is of interest to us in this course in real time, using Web sockets while
you're in the Web application.
So don't install what you see here.
This is right now as you're looking at this, this is exactly the starter code.
But by the time I launch this course, this will no longer be the starter code.
This will be the finished code.
And you'll be able to look at the project in various stages as we go along by going to particular releases.
So if I go over to the releases tab here, the link right now, there's only one starter project and
this is what you want.
So download the zip file or the target file, extract that into your local computer.
And if you want to commit that to get or whatever your favorite repository is, I encourage you to do
so.
But don't just clone this project or you're going to have the finished project as we begin.
And that's not going to be very helpful for you.
So I've already downloaded this or I actually haven't downloaded this, but it's functionally the same
thing because this is where you're going to start.
And I've imported it into my favorite Edek.
And what we need to do, first of all, is to connect this to our database.
So there's a couple of files here I need to change.
One is called database y email dot example.
So I'm going to copy that just by opening my terminal and making sure I'm in the right direction.
I am.
And I will keep database dot y Amelda, for example, to database y amount.
And this is a file that's going to be used to manage our database migration's which I'll get to momentarily.
The second file you want to copy and it's different if you're on Windows or Mac, if you're on Windows,
you want to copy this one run batdorf example to run it back and we'll make changes to that.
I'm on a Mac, so I'll use the rundown, S.H..
So if you're on macro Linux, you're going to do this copy run, for example.
To run S.H. and then I need to make this executable on a Mac.
Now I can run it, first of all, let's make sure the contents are correct, so I'll start with the
database.
Open your database, why file and all you need to populate could ignore the bits down here.
All you need to populate up here is the name of the database, which I'm going to call vigilante.
The user happens to be, in my case, my username.
So use whatever username you have and I have no password, so that's fine.
Now the rundown, S.H. Let's look at that.
My DB user.
I need to change that to tax.
In my case, push your host.
I'm just going to put localhost in there right now.
This isn't going to be used for a little while, so don't worry about it.
Leave the key in secret alone.
Leave the app alone.
Leave the leave everything else alone.
OK, so now I want to actually populate my database.
So I'm going to start up my favorite database client connect to my localhost, which I'm on right now,
and create a new database which I'm going to call the gelati, just like I did in my database.
Dot, why am Alpha OK?
Now that I've created that, I'm going to open my terminal window, make sure I'm in the correct directory.
I am, and I'm going to run Sota now you don't have SOTA installed and SOTA is something that's very
useful actually.
It's actually part of a project called Go Buffalo and let's go have a look at it and I'll show you how
you can either install it yourself or you can use the binaries I provided you.
So I'm going to go to go Buffalo Io slash n slash dock's DB slash toolbox.
There it is right there.
And this is soda.
Soda is actually just a little command line utility that's built in to go Buffalo, which is a web framework.
Many of you may be familiar with it, but I just like soda because it makes migration's makes creating
migration's running them up and down really, really easy.
So to install this, if you're on a Mac and you have homebrew, you can just do that and that will install
it for you very easily.
And then you'll have soda right in your command line.
You can compile it from source if you want to on a Mac or on windows.
We're not going to use Silverlight three or any version of SQLite.
So you can just run these two commands and then you'll have it available to you.
Or if you want, you'll notice in the repository that you just downloaded.
I have a folder called SOTA Binaries and I have three versions here, one for a Mac, one for really
old Windows machines and one for current Windows machines.
So you can just extract that, the one that's appropriate for your platform, put it somewhere in your
path so you can find it from the command line.
And when you do come back to your application, make sure you've set up a database, which I did just
a moment ago right over here.
It's called Vigilante.
It's in my local Postgres install and all you do is type SOTA migrate and it will actually populate
that database.
Now, it's not a very complex database and it will become more complex as time goes on.
It has a preference table of remember tokens table that allows users to log in and have the system remember
them by setting a cookie and checking its valid validity against whatever is in here.
Schema migration is what SOTA uses to migrate things up and down.
The sessions table is just to store sessions, sessional information and you could do that somewhere
else.
But I just did it in the database so you don't have to install anything else.
And so it won't forget you every time you stop the application, which is what happens if you use in
memory sessions and the user's table and in the user's table.
I have one user, some admin with a username and a password.
OK, so now that I've installed the necessary database tables and content, I can actually run this
and I just go run S.H. and it will start the application.
On Port 4000 of the local system, so let's go over to our Web browser and have a look at it, localhost
4000 and it brings you to the login screen.
And the default user that's added to the database is admin at example, dotcom with the rather less
than strong password of password.
And I'll have it remember me.
And once I've logged in, you have basically the framework for a Web application.
There's only a couple of things that are functional right now.
This button at the top, for example, doesn't do anything, but it's there and it's something for us
to work with.
These are all hard coded values, but it will show you what you're going to do here is you're going
to be monitoring specific posts which will be listed down here.
And this gives you a dashboard overview of the status of any services for any given host.
And again, this is just HTML right now.
There's nothing being populated dynamically here at all.
On the right hand side, you can list your hosts and this doesn't do anything.
The new host button takes you here but doesn't show you a host.
This will list the events that take place when a server goes down or comes up that's recorded here.
A schedule when we're done will actually list all of the next checks with the time and date when they're
going to take place.
This part does work settings and first thing you're going to want to do is populate the user of this
application, which if you're using the same IBM is HTTP Colins localhost 4000 for notifications.
You can specify how do you want to be notified when some event takes place, a server goes down, a
server comes up, whatever it may be.
I'll just say by email right now and I'll put my name in here and some email address.
Treva at example dot com.
Since I'm not going to use a real mail server, I'm going to use a dummy e-mail server.
When we get to the part of the course, I can just put any valid anything that looks like an email address
in here.
And I won't bother with text message for settings under mail settings.
I'm going to specify and SMTP server of localhost with a port of ten, twenty five.
And if you want to follow along, exactly as I'm going to do a little bit later in the course, will
be installing something called Mail Hug, which is a local dummy e-mail server, which is great for
development, and it's written and goes well.
So it's a single binary to run.
It's very easy.
Mail sent from I'll just put a vigilante at example, dotcom, that's the name, but I'll use the email
address for both the name and the email and I'll leave these two empty and then I can save this.
So I will save and close and save the changes.
So settings actually work.
Now, one of the thing I didn't show you here is if you want to do this and I'm going to do it later
in the course, I'm also going to enable text notifications, text messages, and I'm only going to
do it for one provider.
But the logic is is very much the same for any provider.
And I'll use Twilio because I can get a free account there that will allow me to send text test texts
at no charge, which is very helpful.
So I would specify that.
And then I would give the information that I get once I create my Toilolo account, which I haven't
done yet for this course.
But I'll do it when we get to that point.
So let's cancel it.
The last thing that's in here are users right now.
I can I can look at myself.
I can't delete myself.
I can change my password if I want to.
I can change this information.
But because I'm logged in, I don't want to have complete control.
I don't want to accidentally lock myself out of the system.
So I'll just cancel that.
And if I want to have a new user, I can have another user, another user, last name, whatever it
is.
I'm going to delete this in a minute anyway, so it doesn't matter to me at here dot com with some password
and I'll make this user active and it's just a simple user management system so I can save that.
Now it shows both users and if I want to get rid of this one, I can just delete this user and the user
is gone.
That's not really gone.
I'm using soft deletes, but I'll talk about that when I go through the code review, which I'm going
to do right now.
And this is just a quick walkthrough of how this application works.
So I'm going back to my ID and I'm going to close these two files that I have open and we'll start at
the entry point.
Now, if you took my course in Web development and goaland, you'll be familiar with the format that
I use when I start most Web applications.
I put the entry point in a folder called CMD at the root level of the project.
And then because this is the Web application, I have a folder called Web and we have Mango.
So let's look at that.
Mango is dead simple.
I declare a few variables here that I'll go through momentarily.
I declare a few constants here that I'll go through when I get to the appropriate parts.
Well, the first ones obvious, it's the version of the application and then I call the Init function.
And all I'm doing in here is registering the type of models user, which is a type that I have defined
in this application, and it's the one that holds the admin user or the admin users if there's more.
And one and it lets me put that in the session, so I registry's using Godbout register, which means
I can store this data type in the session and then I set the time zone.
I have it set to America Halifax, because that happens to be my time zone.
You can send it to whatever you want or you can just ignore it.
It's really not important for this course in any case.
The main function is the entry point.
This is where we begin.
So I get the value of insecure port and potentially an error from a function called set up app, which
is over here at Setup Dash app DOKO.
And this is where I set up the basic information for the application.
So as you can see here, these are all flags.
Not all of them are required.
Some of them have default values.
But if you look at the run S.H. or run that file that we worked with a little while ago, you'll see
that I'm setting the bare minimum to get the application functional.
OK, so all I'm doing is reading the flags here.
I pass them and then I make sure that the required ones are actually there.
And if they're not just dye and print out that message, missing required flags, then I connected the
database.
Now, the only database I'm supporting here is postgrads, but it's actually set up using the really
common pattern known as the repository pattern.
So if you don't want to use postgrads, you want to use Maruja to be your MySQL or Mongo DB, you feel
free to go and write your own driver for this and drop it in here and use that instead of postscripts.
And it's really straightforward.
So there are two potential connection strings, this one and this one.
And the only difference is that postgrads, at least version 13 that I'm using, gets really upset if
you pass it an empty password and it refuses to start.
So in development, we often don't have a password and that's the case right here.
So I'm just checking to see if the password is empty.
Use this connection string.
Otherwise use this connection string.
And the only difference is the second one has a password equals some value and the first one does not.
Then I connect to the database using driver connect to postscripts, and that's in the internal folder
in the driver's package.
And it's dead simple.
All it does here is connected the database and ping it.
And this is the kind of code you would find in any of a million of tutorials out there online.
I'm just connecting the database, pinging it and moving on.
So once I ping it, I start the session.
And here I'm using a package called Developed by Alex Edwards called Alex Edwards says if you like gorilla
mux or gorilla sessions and want to use that instead, just go ahead and change the code.
It's very straightforward, but it's really pretty straightforward to use this this particular session
manager.
And I've used it for years and it works really, really well.
So coming down here a little bit further, I start my male channel, all I'm doing is setting up a channel
that I can send email to and then I start a dispatcher that listens to this.
So all I'm doing here is making a channel and giving it the Max Poole worker size or max worker pool
size.
I'm saying that was the constant set back in Mingo right over here.
And I'm saying only have five workers at any time.
That's Max worker pool size.
And we have the same thing for Max job worker, which you'll see in a moment.
So here I start up a new dispatcher and we can look at that one by clicking on it and it actually starts
up jobs are opens up jobs, Dasch, Moeldoko and all this does this is code.
And if anybody's worked with the gorilla WebSocket in the past or any of the gorilla packages, this
is a really common pattern to make sure that I'm never going to overload my channel with too many things
and everything will get done in an orderly fashion.
And the is you know, it's fairly long, but it's not that hard to read through.
And for the purposes of this course, all you really have to be aware of is that this is how I'm going
to send email.
And potentially because I might be watching a thousand servers, I might be sending a lot of email at
any given point in time.
So this ensures that only five will go out at a time because I'm just going to be doing this locally.
That's more than sufficient for our purposes.
Back to set up that app once I have the dispatcher started, I define a simple struct of type config
app config, which is over the internal internal folder and just called config.
And it's really straightforward.
It's just a type.
And these are things that I probably want to share across my application.
So there's more information in here that we're actually going to use.
But for our purposes right now, we're setting up these things.
What's the database?
What's the session?
Are we in production or not?
What's the domain name for our server?
What's our pusher secret, which we're going to get to in a while?
Right now, it's set to, I think, ABC one, two, three, or one, two, three, ABC.
But it doesn't matter.
We're not using it at the moment.
I share the mail.
Q So I have a place to send info, send my email messages to store the version information for the current
build of the code and this identifier.
We're actually not going to pay attention to it, but I tend to use that because quite often I want
to have more than one application on a given server and an identifier is just a way for me to keep track
of which one is which.
So you can ignore that.
But it's in there because I use it all the time and I expect to find it there.
Then I store the value a incap, which is a package level variable, so it's available to everything
in my main package.
I get my crate, my handlers and my handlers are everything in the handlers folders, so internal handlers
and this is where you're going to we're going to be working most doing most of our work.
Here's where we actually process specific requests to specific routes on our application that I just
create a map called preference map and I store all of the information.
I create the map right here.
I store all of the information that's in the preferences table in the database by looping through through
it right here.
I started my map and that gives me a quick and easy method of getting any preference right out of my
system wide or application wide app variable so I can read preferences and store them in their.
Now, down here, I'm actually creating a pusher client, and you'll notice if you look at the imports
on the top here, I've imported Pusher somewhere.
Where there is right there, pusher HDB go, and that's the official go library for Pusher, even though
I'm not going to be using Pusher in this.
Course you can if you want to, and I'll talk more about that when we get there.
I'm going to be using a local pusher clone instead because I like to have control over everything as
I'm developing and all this does is create that client and we're not actually doing anything with that
client right yet.
But I'm creating it and I'm storing it where it needs to be in my application abdelnabi client.
And then I'm done and I hand back the port and I hand back potentially an error.
If everything went well then there is no error.
So now we're back in the main routine and from here all I'm going to do is do my standard, defer clothes
for both the database and the channel because it's always important to defer clothes for those things.
Technically speaking, I wouldn't have to because the main function stops when the application stops.
But it's good practice and if I do it all the time, I never forget to that.
I just put a little print, a little message to the screen and create my web server and hand it some
roots.
And the roots are in a file called Roots in the main package right over here.
And for this course, I'm using the monks are sort of using the key router and it's a really dead simple,
easy to use routing package.
And if you want to go read about it, the URL is right here in the imports.
GOCE it's in GitHub.
Dotcom, Godus cheat cheap, simple to use and perfect for the kind, of course, that we're doing right
here.
Most of the roots are protected.
All I'm doing here is loading some middleware, loading the session, which I have to do for Alex Edwards
X so the session is available on every request.
Rickover panic if things go awry.
I don't want the application to die.
I want to recover from that and print a message to my log.
No surf ensures that I can use extra tokens so I can protect my forms against cross site request forgery,
dead simple and check, remember, is just a really simple middleware that actually verifies it's right
here.
It verifies if someone has checked that remember me on the login screen the next time they come to the
site, check, remember, looks to see if that cookie exists, if it's valid, and if it does, it logs
them in automatically.
Very straightforward.
Everything else here outside of these three routes, which are show me the login screen, handle the
post of the login screen and log user out.
Everything else in here is actually a protected route.
So you have to be able to logged in to see it.
And each one of these is tied to a specific handler.
So back to our application here.
When I go to the dashboard, for example, this screen is rendered using the admin dashboard I handler
and I can go look at that and it's very straightforward.
Right now.
I'm taking creating four variables.
No healthy, no problem warning impending, setting them all desirous of putting them into a variable
called var map because I'm using the template rendering engine and then I just render it.
So what we're going to have to do of course, a little bit later on is make these zeros actual meaningful
numbers that correspond to servers that we're watching and services that we're watching and get those
somehow and send that information to the dashboard.
And that's exactly how this application works.
It is dead simple.
There is nothing too complex in here at all.
For example, one thing that I did not mention was how do we how are we querying the database?
And I'm doing it by hand using my retaught repository pattern.
I have a file called Repository Dogo Go in the repository folder in the internal packages folder, and
here I list all of my database functions and there aren't very many right now.
There'll be more by the time we're done.
But each one of these is specific to or corresponds to an entry in DB Repo inside the repository folder.
So for example, if I look at preferences here, I have one function called all preferences of type
postgrads DB repo, and there's only one type for all of these handler, these database functions right
now.
And it's for postgrads.
It returns a slice of model's preference.
And I just do my query the standard way of connecting to a database engo.
I just write some SQL, do the query and return the result or an error.
So that's a thousand foot overview of our code and you'll be seeing more of it in more detail as we
go through the entire project.
But the simplest way to get familiar with this is just to start working with it and we'll start doing
that in the next lecture.