So the very first thing I want to do in this lecture is to connect to a pusher server.
I'm going to close all my windows here.
And as I said before, if you want to create an account on PUSHER and they have free developer accounts,
feel free to do that.
But what I'm going to do is run a local installation of a pusher compatible server.
And the one I'm going to use is over here.
It's found on GitHub, dot com slash DIMIA R.O., the number one IP and it's something called IPA.
And I'm pretty sure I'm pronouncing that right.
And it's not been updated for a couple of years.
And the author is actually said he's not working on an actively right now, but it is compatible with
the latest release of PUSHER.
I've actually fought this and I'm working on a new version of it that I might released to the public
when I get it done, which is going to take months.
But for the purposes of this course, this will work really, really well.
So if you go back to your source code, you'll notice that there's a folder called IP right here.
And inside of that there are two executables, one for a Mac and one for Windows.
And I would, of course, encourage you to use the local installation just to follow along with exactly
what I'm doing.
But it's entirely up to you.
So to run this, it actually uses a configuration file called Config AML.
And I'm going to listen on part four thousand and one.
I've turned off profilings.
All the detail and the information I've said here is absolutely appropriate for our use.
And you'll notice that I have a key of one, two, three ABC and a secret of ABC one, two, three in
production.
I'm going to use much longer, harder to guess keys, but for development, these are easy to remember.
And if you go back to the command set up app, you'll and scroll down to the part where I create to
push your client.
You'll notice that these are stored in here and they're read from when I run the application and run
such a run up that so the key and the secret are exactly the same here as they are in my configuration
for EPA and so is the port number.
So how do you run this?
Well, it couldn't be any easier.
I'm going to open a terminal window and I'm going to change to the IP directory and I'm going to run
IP.
And of course, on Windows it's IP with nothing else and it actually starts.
So that's running now.
As we go on in this course, you have to remember to start IP and if things aren't working, go check
and see if IP is running.
So it's running right now.
So what I want to do now is when someone logs in, let me go back to my application and start right
from the beginning.
So I'll log out.
And if I log in as me, like I called it medo no, I deleted that user right.
Admin at example dot com with my password.
At this point when I get to the screen I want to connect to Pusher and that's all I want to do is to
connect to my local pusher client.
So how are we going to do that?
Well, not surprisingly, it's very similar to this kind of logic we used when we worked with Gorilla
WebSocket.
We need to create a handler that listens for a connection.
So I'm going to go to my internal packages, find my handlers that will create a new file, which I
will call Pusha Duco,
and I will add it to my repository.
And the package is handlers.
I don't create any function and I'm going to call it pusher off because it's the very first thing I'm
doing is authenticating to make sure I'm allowed to use Pusher.
So I'll create a function and it will be of type repo or have the receiver of repo DV repo so I can
get to the database if I have to.
I might not actually I'm going to have to and then I'll give it a name, push her off and it's a handler.
So it's always, as is the case with all handlers, that has to take a response writer and appointment
request.
So they should be the response writer, which I'll call W an R pointer to request.
And inside of that I actually do my magic.
Now, nothing here is too complex.
The very first thing I want to do is to figure out is this user authenticated?
Well, the easiest way to make sure that that happens is to make sure that the route is protected in
our file and only available to authenticate users.
So let's open our reads file.
And right here, just before my slash admin, I'll create another mux dot route and prefix will be pusher,
which I better spell right.
And it will be a function of mux Qaeda reader.
And inside of that, let me spell everything right here, I seem to have difficulty typing today, that's
better inside of that, let's create a route to our off.
So, first of all, let's make sure this is a protected route.
Muxtape use off now.
Only authenticated users have any way of getting to the routes that are inside of this closure.
And I'll just create a new hand, a new route to a handler Muxtape post, because the authentication
will be a post request and then it will be upgraded just like it is with guerrilla web sockets.
So the route will be pushed off.
And I'll point it to the handler just created handlers repo dot, push her off.
OK, so now I have a route to it.
So let's go back to our handler and see what we're actually going to do in here.
The fact that I'm authenticated and the fact that I'm being passed through my routes file means that
I have access to certain things.
And I know if you go back to her authentication handlers, which you haven't looked at in detail, but
when someone logs in right here, so this is login attempts to log the user in this line.
Thirty of authentication handler Stocco.
One of the things that I put in there right at the end is I put the user in the session.
So I now have four authenticated users.
I have an object stored in the session that is the user, him or herself.
And I also have the user ID so I can go back to my roots here or back to my pusher pusher handlers.
So what I want to do with this handler, first of all, now that I know that it's a protected handler,
only available to logged in users, is I want to get the necessary information that allows me to authenticate
this user and connect that user to my pusher host, wherever that is.
And in our case, it's going to be a local server.
So back in our authentication handlers, I have a user ID and I stuck that in with a key user ID in
the session.
So let's pull that out of the session.
So we'll say user ID is assigned the value of app session douget.
It's not app, it is repo DB, the repo app session get and this time I want to get an ENT and I know
it exists because this is a protected route.
So I have to pass the context, our context and then I get the key user ID and this key absolutely 100
percent corresponds to this key right here.
So now I have these ready and from that I can go get the user.
So you and I'll just ignore the error for this case is a sign the value of repo db get user by ID,
user ID and now I have the user stored in a local variable and it's of type users, a model's user.
So if I look at my models and find the user, I have all of this information available to me right now
and I can use that to authenticate to push her.
So let's have a look at how we do this.
Well, the very first thing you have to bear in mind is that what I'm getting and we haven't written
it yet, but when we write the JavaScript to connect the user to our push host, we're actually pushing
a body of information.
And I need to get that information from the request.
And I do that as follows programs.
And these are parameters.
And I'll ignore the error or assign the value of IOU to not discard.
Read all, and I'm reading the body of the request, and with this information, I can now create a
type that is used by the pusher go client and it's called pusher member data.
So I'll call this presents data because it's my presence and presence on present on the server.
It's a sign the value of pusher member data.
And then I just populate its fields and I need to give it a user ID.
And in this case it will be it needs to be in a string format.
So I'll convert my int, which I have here, to a string with STR, convert it to A and I'm going to
pass it user ID.
So that's the first thing I have to pass it.
The second thing it wants is information about the user and that's in the form of a map of string string.
So this is called user info and that's, that's one of the members of the member data type.
And I'm going to give it a map of string string and that will be populated with the user's name, which
will be.
Yuda first name, which is enough and an ID, and that will be against her conv but a it in they're
really going to have to stir conv eye to a and again user I.D..
All right, so this is the necessary information.
This is the information I'm going to be able to use to connect to and authenticate with my server,
my Pusha server.
And I do that by getting a response and potentially an error.
And that comes from Apte client.
And now we're using that client.
We put it in our application config and the method is authenticate the president's channel pass that
the programs we just built, we grabbed up here in the line 15 and past our presence data and we'll
check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then for now I'll just say logged off print line error and return.
Otherwise, we're all set and we just write the information back to our user.
And what we're writing is a response which is adjacent file.
So we write it as Jason to our response reader header set.
We tell the client that what's coming is of content type
application, Jason.
So now the client knows that it's about to get Jason and we just push it the Jason file, and I'll ignore
both the response and the potential error and just say write and I'll write the response.
So that will allow us in theory, to connect to our push your client or push your server from our client.
But we haven't written any JavaScript to do that yet.
Now let's have a look at how I've arranged the templates for this particular application.
So when my project at the root level, I have a folder called Views, and inside of this I have one
called partial and one called layout.
So layout, if you look at that, this is just basic HTML and the template I'm using is just a free
one that I found online and a admin template.
And it's it's good.
It uses a an alpha version of Bootstrap five.
So if you're used to the beta version, the one that is currently in use of bootstrap five, there's
a few changes, but nothing too much to worry about.
And I'll draw them to your attention as we come across them.
But every page, except for the login page is based on this layer.
And what inside of this, we have a couple of places where I yield things so I can yield success.
So if I look at, say, the dashboard at the very top, there's a block access and that allows me to
populate CSC rules that are specific to this page and back in the layout.
I also have another yield for in the next one here, there's our navigation menu along the left card
content and that corresponds to on the dashboard DOGIT, everything that's inside here and the title
corresponds to car title and that's all that.
It works at the very bottom of the layout.
I have one where I'm saying, let's see here.
The lab, so I can't find it, I have include Parshall's James Jet, so this is JavaScript that's going
to be available to every page, every page that requires authentication to see.
So that seems to me to be a really good place to put our particular code to connect to the push your
client and push your server, because you need to do it on every page where you're authenticated, just
as you had to do it on every page with Gorilla WebSocket.
You have to do it with Pusha as well.
So let me just ignore this and think about how we're going to connect to this.
Well, the very first thing we're going to have to have is the actual push or JavaScript library.
So I'm going to put it line up here.
And I've actually in your static folder, under admin, under underuse, I put Pusher in.
So let's include that.
That's the official JavaScript library released by Pusher.
And you can use the one that that's hosted on a CDN.
But in my experience, the problem with using the hosted CDN version that PUSHER provides is they're
actually tracking a lot of information from users and sometimes ad blockers tend to disable the pushier
library entirely because they think too much information is being tracked.
So I just hosted a local copy.
So let's bring that in.
Script source equals slash static slash admin slash pusher mindgames and close that.
Now I have access to the pusher library.
So first thing I'm going to do on every page where a user is authenticated, which is the only time
people ever see the Jast Jett file, let's create a variable let pusher equal new pusher and it requires
a key, something like that, empty for a minute.
We'll get back to that in a minute and then it requires some options.
And the options would be what are your authentication endpoint?
Well, what you are do I hit to a to authenticate users?
And as you know, we just created that.
It's right here under Pusha and it's pusher's off.
So let's put that in there.
Auth endpoint has pusher off.
And it needs to know what's the host was host in our case, it's local host and port and our case is
four thousand and one.
That's what we specified both in the start up for our vigilante application and in the start up for
our pusher server.
We're not using to tell us.
So I'll say forestalls.
We're not using SSL certificates.
In other words, it's false.
And we need to say what transports are you using?
And will enable enabled transports?
And it's an array of W.S. for Unsecured Connections and WSC because this might be in production at some
point.
So a lot of that transport and disabled transports will just pass an empty array.
And that will connect to our server once we call it so we need to actually subscribe to the server.
So analysts say here is let public channel, I'm creating a new variable and I'll talk about channels
in a bit equal to Pusher Dot subscribe.
And I was going to subscribe to a channel called Public Channel, and if it doesn't exist, the server
will create it for me if I'm actually successful in my connection.
So let's see what we're missing here.
We're almost ready to run this and see if we can connect.
First of all, we have to get our key in there and we can do that.
If you recall, when we logged in and before we remembered, I don't even know if I showed this to you,
but let's make sure when I render something, let's go back to our roots here, any page.
So when I render a page like this admin dashboard, for example, if I open that up, I'm actually calling
a function in a package called Helper's called Render Page.
And the template system I'm using here is templates.
But you could use any templating system.
I just like Jet because it's very easy to use and it's easier to write, say, if statements than the
standard go library templates.
I use them both, but for this course I thought I'd use Jet.
When I'm rendering this page, the very first thing I do is to say, am I being passed variables, which
is right here?
And if I am, then I use those.
Otherwise I create a new empty jet via and call the variable first.
And then I have this function and default data and let's have a look at that.
It's just a little higher in the right here at default data.
One of the things that I'm adding in here in my template data, which is pass to every single template,
whether every single page is being rendered, I always have access to this app preference map and that's
in the app variable.
I have access to that so I can actually pull my push her key right out of the variable dot the preference
map and it's key is Pusha Dash key.
And then I close my quotes, close this and my double quotes are closed.
The only drawback to working with Jet is there is no plug in for my idea that knows about jet templates.
So it thinks things like this are in error, but I can live with that for right now.
So let's make sure we've got this.
All right.
We're creating a Pusha of New Pusha.
We're getting our preference map.
We're pulling the push or key out of it.
That looks right off end point.
Actually, that needs to be capitalized.
OK, push her off, localhost the correct part, perfect, let's try running this and see what happens.
So I will stop my application, make sure it compiles and it does all go back to my now let's reload
the page, actually open a JavaScript terminal, make sure I'm looking at the network, reload the page.
And there I have one on one.
Switch us to web sockets and connected to localhost four thousand one, which is exactly what I wanted.
Perfect.
So it looks like we've connected to our server now in the next election will make sure we're actually
connected to our server and authenticated properly.
And we'll try pushing some information from the server to our connected client and we'll see how that
works.