So let's try pushing an event from our application to our clients and we'll just make sure that everything's
set up correctly and we actually are, in fact, connected to our pusher server.
So I'm going to go to my roots file, which is in command web rootstock go.
And I'll just set up a test route right up here just before my actual pusher routes.
So much start get and we'll just use Pusha Dash test as the URL and we'll go to a handler that doesn't
exist yet but will create at the moment handlers repo and we'll just call it test pusher.
All right.
That doesn't exist.
So let's go creative.
So I'll go to my pusher's dog, go file and I'll create a new handler, which I'll call Funk.
And it has a receiver of Repo StarTalk DB Repo.
So we have access to the database if we ever need it, and we'll call it what I call it, an route's
pusher, test pusher.
So let's come back here and call it test pusher.
And because it's a handler, it has to take two arguments.
A response writer, which I'll call W.
And a pointer to a request, which I'll call our.
OK, so this exists now, so the error in my route should go away and it does good.
Now let's actually create the handler and have it send something to the client.
Now, the first thing I'm going to do is create a map and I'll call it data.
And it's a map of type.
Make a map.
Of string string, so the index is a string and the actual content of an entry in the map is also a
string, and I'll put a value in their data and I'll just call it message, which I actually have to
call it in this case equals anything I want.
Hello, world.
Now, all I want to do is push something using my WC client that I have set up in and it exists in my
application config, so error will check for an error equals and we'll call this repo dot app dot WC
client.
That's what I'm calling and I'm calling a method on this called Trigger and I'm going to trigger it
to a channel.
And we only have one channel which we call public channels, so I'll push it to that.
And the second argument it requires is an event name, which I'll just call test event.
And I'm pushing the payload of data, my map of string string and I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then just log in log print line error.
OK, so I now have a test route one that I can use to try to push something to our client.
And of course back in my JavaScript Jagjit, we need to do something to listen for that particular event.
So right here we subscribe to the public channel and we put it in a variable called public channel.
So now we just look for events, public channel.
Bind, we're going to bind.
Try that again.
We're going to bind to test event, which matches exactly what I have in my pusher go file.
I'm pushing test event.
So back to our jass.
When you get that test event, what do you want to do?
Well, you want to execute this anonymous function looking for data.
What are we getting?
And all I'm going to do here is call this routine right down here success alert, which exists right
in my I think it's in my leg.
Let's find out it mean.
Where are my views are they're LaserJet, public, personal, jet abcess somewhere in here, I have
my will just find it the easy way back to my jet, find success alert that exists in.
Oh, yes.
And attention jazz, which I've included.
And all that does is fire a.e alert.
So I'll just call that success alert and I want to pass it.
DataDot message.
So my map is converted into an object I can access in JavaScript and I'm looking for a message which
I've pushed right here, data message so I should get Hello world.
If this all works the way it's supposed to now, I'll tell you right now, I was a little sloppy when
I put some some of the files up in the repository.
So there are some problems, but let's just try it and see what actually happens.
So I'll stop and start my IP to make sure it's running and I'll go back here and stop my application
and run it.
And it ran and it looks like everything should work.
I'm here on one window, and if I reload this, you can see that I'm actually if I look at my network,
it appears that I'm connecting to my local host four thousand one.
So let me open a new window and I'll drag this down so we can see both windows at the same time right
to here, so we can see everything.
And all I'll do is go to localhost 4000 test dash pusher.
And what should happen when I press return here is this should fire a request off to my pusher server
iPad and that should handle the request and send it to everyone who's listening to the public channel.
Let's see what happens.
So I push it and it says Page not found.
So let me find out what I got wrong there.
I didn't call it test pusher.
I called it pusher test.
OK, there's my first problem.
Let's try that again.
Push pusher test and nothing appears to have happened, and if I go look at the log file here, it says
Hope posting to localhost for Colon four three and it's trying to push to localhost four, four, three,
which doesn't exist and doesn't seem to make any sense, because if I look at my random S.H. file,
Rondout S.H. or run but bad in your case, it looks as though I'm pushing to I should be going to port
four thousand one.
But if you notice here, I forgot to put the slashes and that didn't work.
All right, so let's stop.
Our application started again and see if that fixes everything.
So back here to my Web browser, I'll reload this to make sure I've got the correct page or the latest
version of the page.
And I'll go back to this window and fire off pusher test.
And again, it still didn't seem to work.
So let's go back here and look at our log files.
Not authorized.
What did I get wrong?
Well, here I have Pusher your said to ABC one, two, three.
And in my EPA file suit I have my key is one ABC one, two, three.
Let's find my I can figure out why I'm out my key.
Is one, two, three ABC.
I got this backwards, so this should be ABC, one, two, three and this should be one, two, three
ABC.
So let's go stop our EPA server.
Try to.
And stop and start our application just to make sure, OK, and return a few times, go back to my Web
browser, reload this.
And try this one more time, and there it pushed the request off to the server, so now we have things
set up properly and make sure you've got your key and secret set the same in your epic config file and
your config Oyamel and in your startup script, either Renderos or run that.
And it seems as though we can now push things to our server.
So let's stop for this time around.
And in the next lecture we'll start doing some more useful things because our goal here is actually
to monitor remote hosts.
So we need to get that logic set up before we can do too much else.