So in this section of the course, we're going to have a look at goal routines.
And chances are, if you've been working with go for any length of time, you've probably used them
to some extent.
But I'm going to go over the basics in any case and illustrate just how easy it is to use go routines
and why you have to be careful when you do it.
So what are we going to do in this section?
Well, to start with, we're going to have a look at what a go routine is.
And go routines are nothing more than a part of your program that runs.
You might think of it as in the background or concurrently, and you can have multiple go routines running
at the same time and they're incredibly easy to use.
You just have to type two characters in a space and suddenly you have a go routine.
But creating go routines, as we'll see in this section, it can create problems and there are multiple
ways with solving those problems.
We can use new taxes, we can use weight groups, we can use channels.
We'll have a look at weight groups in this section because they're the easiest ones to understand,
I think, and they're really easy to implement.
But in any case, let's get started.