So let's start looking at go routines.
I started up Visual Studio code and I've opened up the folder and I called my folder first dash example.
You can call yours whatever you want, but make sure you have a folder open and as is good practice,
I'm going to open my terminal and I'll type go mod in it and I'll call this first dash example.
That's the name of my project.
Okay, and that will create a government file.
So there now I have a go mod file.
Now over here, I'm going to create a new file, not surprisingly called Mico, and we're going to start
right from first principles.
So a lot of this will be review for some of you, but I just want to make sure that everyone's on,
as they say, a level playing field.
So this is my main doggo file and of course this is in package me and I'll create a function here,
my main function that I have to have.
And now that I have a main function, one of the things you should be aware of is that every go program,
even a simple one like this, if I just say format dot, print line hello world and run that that actually
has one go routine.
The main function itself is a go routine.
Now a program can have just one, as is the example here, but we're going to create one that has at
least two and one.
Our go routines will go routines are in effect very lightweight threads.
They run on very lightweight threads, not the built in hardware threads of a processor, but instead
ones that are specific to go itself.
They take very little memory.
They run very, very quickly, and they're all managed as a group of go routines is called core routines.
They're all managed by the Ghost Scheduler, and it decides what runs, when, how much processing time
one gets.
It schedules everything.
It takes care of all that magic for us in the background.
Okay.
Now, obviously this is not a very sophisticated program.
We're going to be building very simple programs to demonstrate how the important concepts in concurrent
programming actually work.
And then we'll start tackling some more sophisticated problems.
And I'll begin with classic problems from the field of computer science.
And then later on in the course, we'll actually build a real world example of the concurrent program.
Okay, so let's get started.
So I'm going to start here above my main function.
I'm going to create another function.
Okay?
Now I'm going to call this one, print something and print something will take one parameter s, which
is a string.
And not surprisingly, it's just going to print it to the terminal format or print line and the parameter.
S Okay.
Now down here in the main program, I'm going to delete this one and the first thing I'm going to do
is call print something.
So I'll call print something and I'll give it a string.
This is the first thing to be printed.
Okay?
And I'll hit return a couple of times and then I'll call it again, print something.
This is the second thing to be printed.
Now, if I run this program, you know exactly what's going to happen over my terminal.
I clear the screen and I type go run dot and it prints two things out.
This is the first thing to be printed.
This is the second thing to be printed.
And there's no surprises there at all.
I'm going to put in an exclamation mark there just to be consistent.
Okay.
So that's really, really simple.
Now, what I want to do this time around, the next time I run the program is I want this first call
to print something, this one on line 12.
I want that to run concurrently with the main function and all I have to do and go and this is what
makes it so easy to to write concurrent programs and go or at least it appears to be easy.
I just put the word go in front of it.
Okay.
So what that word go does is it tells the compiler when you execute whatever comes after this go command
executed in its own go routine.
So it spawns in Hugo routine, hands it off to the scheduler and the scheduler says, okay, I'll take
care of running this for you.
But when I run the program right now, if I clear the screen and type go run dot what you would expect
to see happen logically is you would expect to see, well, it's going to on line 12, it's saying spawn
a new go routine called print something.
Call that function and print out that text and then it'll print out, print something.
But watch what happens.
I only see this is the second thing to be printed.
Well, what happened there?
Well, what happened is pretty straightforward.
This program executed so quickly that there was not sufficient time for that go routine, the one I
spun on line 12 to actually execute.
So what happened to its output?
Well, it just died.
It's often the ether somewhere.
We're never going to see it.
But you'll notice the program ran with no errors whatsoever.
Okay.
Now, how do I fix that?
Well, there's a couple of ways of doing this.
And actually, there's three good ways of doing it and one really bad way, which is the way I going
to look at right now.
I could, if I wanted to go in between these lines, hit return a couple of times, and then just tap
over and say, time, dot sleep.
I'm going to put the program to sleep for 1/2, one times, time dot second.
Okay.
And hopefully that did the import for me.
Yes, it did.
So now I'm saying to the program, okay, start running.
Send off, print something with this string as its own go routine.
Then just go to sleep for a second and then print this.
And technically, that will solve the problem.
I can run the program.
So down here in my terminal.
Go run dot.
And a prince out the first one and then a prince at the second one.
Now, is that a good solution?
Absolutely not.
This would be a singularly awful solution, the kind of thing that if you try to do this in a production
environment and your manager sees you do it well, at best there will be some harsh words.
At worst, you're suddenly polishing your CV and looking for a new job.
Okay, so this is obviously not the best way to do it.
Now, in the next lecture will modify this program to introduce a concept known as weight groups.
And this will allow us to wait for certain things to happen and then continue once they've taken place.
All right.
Let's move on.