So last time around, we managed to figure out a rather bad way of ensuring that our single go routine
runs, and that's by giving the program one extra second here on the line 17.
And that's a terrible solution.
Now, let's find out just exactly why that's a terrible solution.
So what I'm going to do is delete this line entirely.
And instead, I'm going to spawn more than one goal or two.
So what I'll do, first of all, is create a slice of strings and I'll call that slice words, and that's
going to be equal to a slice of string.
And I'll just put some words in here.
So we'll use the Greek alphabet.
Alpha, beta,
delta.
Just some Greek letters.
Gama.
In no particular order.
Pi and maybe Zeta and ETA of Theta.
Theta, if you prefer.
And we'll give it one more epsilon.
Okay.
Now I have a slice of strings.
Now, what I'm going to do this time around is below that slice of strings.
Is, um, going to range through it.
So for I don't care about the index and X are assigned the values by ringing through words
and then I'll call principal.
So print something and I'll print and I'll use a format print f to create a string format that is pronounced.
And my format string will be saying, actually, I'm going to keep the index in here, so we'll call
the index.
So we'll say, ah, we should get percent D, that's my placeholder and then a colon and then the word
percent pass.
And my substitutions for those are obviously on an X.
Okay.
And now I'll put the keyword go in front of that.
So if I run the program right now, I have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine
things.
Okay.
So let's run the program and see what it looks like.
So could the screen and type go run dot.
And here's an interesting thing.
Look at that.
I actually got all nine printed, but they didn't come in any particular order.
And that's another important thing you have to understand about go routines.
It doesn't matter what order you spun them in.
As you can see here, I started at index zero and went right up to eight in my range statement or four
for loop here.
But they came out as 823456701.
And then 1/2 was long enough to get all of those printed.
But the problem is, you know, what happens if I change that one or this this slice of strings to one
that has a thousand words in it, or as is more likely, I'm querying the database and I have no idea
how big that slice is going to be.
How long should I wait?
Well, obviously you shouldn't wait using time, dot sleep.
That's a really bad idea.
And here's where weight groups come to the rescue and wait.
Groups are dead.
Simple to use.
So I'm going to delete that that time sleep.
And up here in the main function, the very first thing I'm going to do is create a variable Var and
I'll call it WG for weight group.
And it's a type right from the standard library, sync type weight group.
Okay.
So that could be important for me and important time, which I'll delete because I'm not using it anymore.
So now I have this variable weight group.
Now, the great thing about weight groups is they're so easy to understand.
It's one of three different ways of dealing with concurrency that we're going to look at in this course.
Really, those are the only three you ever have to worry about and go because they're the three main
ways of doing it.
And we groups, I think, are the easiest.
So the first thing you have to do is you have to add one entry to your weight group.
It's just an integer, one entry for everything you need to wait for.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do is say, well, I have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight,
nine things I need to wait for because I'm calling this this go print something nine times.
So I could down here just say WG dot ad and put in nine.
Okay.
Now I have to wait for nine things to finish before I finish before I'm done with that weight group.
And down here after the for loop, all I put in is WG dot weight.
Okay, so this on line 34 in my code, this WG the weight will wait until the weight group WG is set
to zero.
And I set it to nine here and I'm looking for a zero here, but at no point do I actually decrease the
weight group.
Well, of course, the place to do that is in the go routine for spawning, which means I need to have
access to that weight group in that particular go routine.
So what I can do is come up here to print something and say, I'm going to take a string test and I'm
also going to take a weight group.
WG Which is a pointer to center weight group.
And it's important that you use a pointer here.
And I'll explain that momentarily.
Now, down here in this way or in this for loop, when I call, go print something.
Obviously say I'm looking for it.
My second parameter was just WG MC group.
Okay, now I have an error because I'm not passing a pointer, so I need to put an ampersand in front
of this.
And there's a reason you want to do this.
Once you've created a weight group, you really shouldn't copy it after the fact.
And that's right.
And then the documentation for Go.
And it just tells you that you need to be really cautious with weight groups.
Don't go copying them and modifying them, just pass them around as pointers.
It's much simpler.
And of course, the last change I need to make here in print something is to hand this WG which will
be ignored as well.
And that needs to be a reference.
Now, the last step in this process, I'm now passing a pointer to weight group up to this function
print something I need to decrement by one.
And that's as simple as using the defer keyword.
And I'm sure you've seen this many times and go, but just to be safe, Defer says whatever comes after
this, don't execute it until the current function exits.
So what I want to do is say WG, dot, dot and that will decrement the weight group by one.
Now let's run this program, see how it looks so clear the screen and type.
Go run dot.
And I have a negative weight group counter now that is completely to be expected.
And I'm sure you saw this error coming.
Why?
Let's close the terminal.
Come back here.
When I started here in the function I declare in the main function and declare weight group.
Then I create my slices strings.
Then I add nine to it.
Then I call this function as a go routine with a keyword go nine times.
So by the time I get to this line 36 and get to zero when I get to the next one.
Of course, Weight Group is already at zero.
So to make this compile, I can just do this WG to add one.
And now if I clear the screen in my terminal and run the program again, everything should run as expected.
And it does.
And of course, if I run this many, many times, I'm going to get different results.
The first time around, the last word printed was number three, which is, of course, and position
four in the slice.
That's Gamma at the second time I ran it.
It's Delta.
So key things to remember.
Weight groups are really easy to use but never try to get them below zero or bad things happen.
And the second thing to remember is if you have multiple go routines running at the same time, even
if they're the same function, you have no guarantee as to what order they complete.
And that's entirely decided by the Go's scheduler.
Okay, so that's our brief introduction to weight groups will be seeing much, much more of these as
time goes on.
And of course, the last thing I can change here is if I don't know how big the slice is going to be,
I don't have to add nine.
I can just add the length of words, and that's a much more useful way of doing it, because in this
simple example, this is never going to change.
But if word is actually populated by calling a remote API, getting some Jason, putting it into a slice
of strings, you never know how long it's going to be and this just makes much more sense.
Okay, let's move on.