So we're coming along in our consideration of Sinking Weight Group and just as a review, it's very
simple to use.
It's the easiest way to deal with concurrency.
Not always the best way, but definitely the easiest.
So all I did was declare a variable of type sink weight group.
I added the number nine to it, which is the length of the slice of string words every time I call a
go routine that I want to wait for in the on actual go routine I call defer awake report done and then
I wait down here and it's as simple as that.
But what happens if somehow I get the wrong number in here?
Let's say I get I want to know 1212 is bigger than nine.
Now, logically, if I were to run this program, you might think that since I only have, I'm only
spawning nine go routines, one for each of these words and I'm waiting for 12 that my program just
stops here and waits forever.
But it won't actually.
If I run this go run dot, you'll see that I get an error fatal error.
All go routines are asleep deadlock and that is an easy error to run into.
And that's one of the reasons why you almost never use a hardcoded value like 12 as I did there, because
that's a bit of a problem.
Okay.
So I'm going to change that back to Len of words just so that things will work as expected.
And now when I run it, it'll do exactly what I expect.
Okay.
Now you're also at some point going to want to test to go routine that you have to wait for.
And I'm sure you can figure this out on your own, but I thought I can go through it quickly.
Okay.
So I'm going to write a test for this function, print something.
So I'll create a new file which I'll call main underscore test.
Don't go and it's in package main and I'll write one test just for that function.
So I'll write a funk and I'll call it test, underscore, print something and it takes one parameter
t a pointer to testing T and that did the import for me and we'll write this test.
Now I'm testing a function that prints something to the console and there's a little bit of magic you
have to implement in order to do that easily.
Fortunately, it's not that difficult.
First of all, when I run my program, it's printing it to O's dot steady or you T standard.
Okay, so what I'm going to do is create a variable char call STD or T and it's assigned the current
value of STD or UTI.
I'm just saving what standard out is before I run my test.
So I'll set it back to that when I'm finished and now I'm going to create my own standard out.
So I do that by getting a variable ah for read w for right.
And I'll ignore the third return parameter which isn't important to me.
And that comes from the built in Oscar type.
Okay.
So once I have that now, I'll set OSD standard out to this right pipe.
So I say, okay, STB out right from the standard library.
I'm changing that to be equal to w that's what I'm gonna write to.
Okay.
Now, since I want to test this function over here, print something.
It's expecting to have a weight group.
So I need a weight group.
That's no problem.
I'll create one.
Via WG.
Of sync weight group type.
Okay, now I have a variable.
Now I'll add one to it.
And in this case I can add the number one because this is a test and I know I'm only running one thing
wg to add one now I just call the function I want to test.
Go print something.
And I handed some text that I wanted to print.
See another Greek letter?
Epsilon.
And a reference to my weight group.
Remember, you never hand weight groups around.
You always hand pointers to weight groups around.
It's much safer.
So that executes the function.
Now I have to wait.
WG Don't wait.
Once that function print something runs, it has that defer statement in there.
So we'll wait until that's deferred.
In other words, we wait till this is finished running in the background as its own go routine and now
we close our pipe.
W So I'll ignore the error when I called WQ close.
Okay.
Now I want to get the results from that test.
In other words, I saved what was being written in my own variable.
And I want to get something out of that and turn it into a string so I'll get the result in a variable
called result.
And I'll ignore the second return parameter when I call I.
Okay.
Read all.
And if you're using an older version of Go, you'd have to use IOU.
Tilde read all, but hopefully you have the latest version installed because that's been deprecated.
So I'm going to read all her and that's the variable up here from line 13.
Okay.
I turn that into a string.
Output is a sign the value of casting result to a string.
Okay.
And now that I have my output and I finish with that, what I can do is say ost study out my variable
over wrote back up on line 14 that's now equal to the one that I saved online 11 STD.
I have to set things back as they were before the test ran and now I perform the test.
So I'll say if not from the strings package strings dot contains and I want to look at output and I'm
looking for epsilon.
If that's not there then something went wrong.
So I can say t dot rf
expected to find epsilon but it is not there and I can run my test.
So I'll clear the screen.
Go test.
Done.
And I misspelled Epsilon.
That's why it failed.
So let's copy it and paste it in here.
We said it worked.
Let's try it again.
Go test dot and it passes.
No problem at all.
So the key thing to remember is I'm expecting that goto routine to run in the background.
So when I write my test for it, I run it in the background.
And that, I think is an important point to keep in mind when you're writing tests.
So as you can see, when we're writing console applications like this, it's a bit tricky to capture
the output.
So I can test it, but it's not that difficult.
Okay, let's move on.