So let's put some of what we've covered so far into practice.
You can watch me do this over and over and over, and until you've done it yourself a few hundred times,
it's really not going to be of much use to you.
So I have a simple challenge for you.
If you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file you can download called challenge
dash one dot zip download that, unzip it and open up that folder in Visual Studio code and you'll see
a file called Mango that looks just like this.
And the challenge is pretty straightforward, and I don't think you'll have much difficulty with it,
but let's give it a try in any case.
So what I want you to do is to take this program.
I can run it right now.
If I open up my terminal and type go run dot, all it does is print out Hello Universe, hello Cosmos
and hello world in that order.
Okay, now what I want you to do is to modify this code so that every one of the calls to update message.
And in this example and on this example, it's on line 27.
I have a typo there, but it doesn't matter.
It's just a comment.
Lines 27.
Lines 39.
Line 33.
Every call to update message should run as a go routine.
In other words, it should run concurrently with the current go routine, which is main.
Okay, so that's the first change.
And I want you also to implement weight groups so that the program runs properly.
In other words, you run the program and it every time you run it, it's always going to print these
three messages in exactly that order.
Okay.
And I'd also like you to write a test for all three functions for this program.
So you're going to create a file called Main Underscore Test.
Don't go.
And you're right, three tests, one for the update message, which of course, is running as a go routine,
one for print message that's a bit simple and one for main.
So you're going to use the same kind of logic I used in that test I wrote in the last lecture to capture
standard out and don't forget to set standard out back to what it's supposed to be when you're done.
So this should not be too difficult for you.
It might take you a couple of tries to get it running properly, but you should have everything you
need at your disposal in order to complete this challenge.
And if you run into problems, don't worry.
I'll show you how I solved that in the next lecture.
All right.
Good luck.