So how did you make out with the challenge?
I suspect you didn't find it terribly difficult.
So our goal and I did play with this between lectures, so my line numbering is a bit different than
it was last time around.
But it's exactly the same program.
If I open the terminal and type go run dot.
There it is.
Universe, cosmos, world.
So it's exactly the same functionality.
The spacing is a bit different, that's all.
Now I want to make all the calls to update message run in the background.
And of course that just means putting the keyword go in front of all of the calls to update message.
And if you thought that was enough for this, well, you were sadly mistaken, because if I open this
up and run it a few times, so I'll type go run.
Dot You can see that I have three outputs, which is great, but it says Hello World, hello universe,
hello universe.
And that's not right.
So something went wrong.
And of course, that's because I need to put a weight group here, and this time I'll make it a package
or a little variable.
Okay.
So I'll put in a variable WG of type S'INQUIETE group and that should do the import for me.
And it did.
And of course, down here, because this is a little exercise to get used to working with Waker, I
can just go WG dot add one and then down here after hello universe I say WG Dot wait.
And of course that means up here in update message I have to defer WG dot done and I can call WG there
because it's a package a little variable, right?
So now I have the first one doing exactly what it should and it's pretty much exactly the same for the
next two.
So WG dot add one and I want to wait before I print a message.
WG Dot wait.
And down here, same thing.
WG To add one and.
WG Don't wait.
And of course, if you did this by creating a slice of strings that say Hello Universe, Hello Cosmos,
Hello World ended everything by arranging through that slice.
That's a perfectly fine solution, actually.
It's a bit more elegant.
So if you did that, congratulations.
Now, that was easy.
We can run this again.
And it will do exactly what I want every single time.
Universe, cosmos, world is run it again.
Universe, cosmos, world.
Perfect.
That does exactly what I want.
Now, the test might have been a bit trickier for you, but probably not that much.
So I have it pre-written here, so we'll just go through it.
So I open up my main underscore Tesco and of course I'm importing IOC strings in testing and those were
automatically imported for me as I wrote them.
So the first one testing update, a message.
I mean, I tested this by running it in the background because that's how my code expects it to run.
And any time I write a test, I try to simulate the actual production environment as closely as possible.
So here I used the package level variable WG, which is available to this test because it's in the package
main added one to it ran update message with some string as a go routine with the keyword go, waited
for it to finish and just made sure that epsilon equals or epsilon is the current contents of message
if it's not through an error.
So that went simple.
The next two required me to create a variable STV out and save the existing value of OST standard out
and then restore it down here.
But it's exactly the same logic I used last time around.
I set the package level variable message to epsilon called print message and then just captured my output,
restored state to what it was before the test ran and made sure that the strings that the output contained
the String Epsilon and I did exactly the same thing with Main, but I checked to make sure that Hello
Universe.
Hello Cosmos.
And Hello World were there.
And if I type now go test dash v dot to give a verbose output.
They all pass exactly as they should.
Okay.
Now, we'll be doing more testing with with concurrency as the course goes on.
When we look for race conditions, but we're not quite there yet, we have little ways to go before
we can start doing that.
So that's our overview of the Select Weight Group package.
And as I've said a couple of times now, it's the easiest way to deal with concurrency.
In a lot of cases, it's all you actually need.
But there are situations where weight groups just won't do the trick, which is why later on in the
course, we're going to look at two other methods Mute Hexes, which are almost as easy as the weight
group, but not quite.
And then finally, channels will be looking at that.
And that is the most sophisticated way of dealing with concurrency, but it's also the most powerful.
So we'll go through those in some detail as the course goes on.
In any case, that's it for this section.