Hello and welcome to the gold and programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about installing, go learning and preparing vis code I.D. in Windows.
Guide Tool Kit is a version control system.
We need it for two reasons.
First, many components of go land are distributed via gate.
And second, the Windows installer includes the terminal that makes it behave more like Unix operating
systems.
So download and install mice escaped from mice, escaped the gate hop that I or vending installer asked,
make sure to select use gate from the Windows Command prompt.
The terminal windows comes with a terminal called CND Dot X Z.
You can start it by click on the window button in typing CMT and then selecting its terminals are a
text drive interface to your computer.
You can enter commands by typing the comment and hitting into your computer will then execute the command
and display any results.
Go ahead and close it as we will be using a different terminal that comes bundled with my CS kit.
Clique is soft.
All programs guide and select Keith Bash Tina's answer allow you to manipulate files and folders on
your computer.
Your terminal starts in the working directory where you can release.
The folder contends with less change directories using CD, make directories using the air and remove
files using are.
Go Lanc in this style, going is a compiled programming language.
So we need to install the go toolset, download and run the installer from Go Lang dot org slash dial
2's Windows Dash AMD64 dot MCI for 64 bit or Windows Dash 386 dot MSI for 32 bit version.
You'll probably want that 64 bit version.
Confirm that it worked by opening a new terminal and typing go version.
Now you should see the go version you installed.
Environment variables now set the environment variables right click on my PC and select properties,
choose the advanced system settings from the left side and click on environment variables as shown in
the below screenshots.
Click on path from the system variables and then click Edit.
So click new and then add the path with being directory where you'll have paste the Go folder.
Here we are editing the pack see column Baccus.
Let's go back to the screen and click OK, as shown in the below screenshots.
Now, create a new user variable, which tells Go, Come in, Virgo Lang, libraries are present.
For that, click a neon user variable, as shown in the below screenshot.
Now feel the variable names as go routes and variable value is the part of your Go Lang folder.
So here variable value is C column Backus.
Let's go after filling, click OK.
After that, click OK on environment variables and your setup is completed.
Now let's check the Golang version by using the common Go version, uncomment prompt and see the Golang
version.
So after completing the installation process, any idea or takes editor can be used to write goals and
codes and run them on the IED or the command prompt with the use of comment.
In this case, we want to install this code and write our courts and it.
Install visual Estadio code and extension download and install VSCO from the following link code dot
visual Estadio dot com slash download.
After the installation launch, VSCO opened the extensions marketplace by the Council Plus Shift, plus
its short key and then search go extension and install it.
After it opened the comment, followed by the control plus shift plus P Short G and run they go install
update tools comment.
And select all the go extensions listed here and install them.
Start coding.
Create a file like name.
Hello Dot.
Go in this code either by the following by default auto completion and formatting for quote saving or
enable.
That's great.
After created the fine, save it and go to the terminal and execute the following command Go run hello
dot go and you can see the Hello World message.
Now it's ready to writing our courts in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.