Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about install the Go programming language practically inside the Windows operating system.
First, install the Gear tool in the Windows environment.
So go to the M6.
Get the guitar that I or U R A M CS Guide Dot Guitar, Dot I or.
And now we enter the gates of download page.
Press the download button and wait until the download starts.
Press the start a lot.
OK.
Download complete it now, go to install the application.
Right click and run as administrator.
The first page of the application was opened, this page provides us jianyu general public license information.
Press next and continue in this space, we should select an application destination location by default
here.
Destination location is C Program Files Gieat Folder.
You can change this destination, but here we don't change it to continue.
Click Next.
In this page, ask us what components you want to install.
We can accept the default settings and we can select on the desktop option as additional icons.
Press next and continue in this page, we select the Start menu folder.
By default, it is gieat select, eat and click next to continue in this page, ask us what text editor
you want to select by default.
Forget, depending on the type of editor installed on the operating system, the desired editor can
be selected here.
The Notepad Plus Plus editor is installed on my system, so I select it as the default text editor for
it.
So I choose Notepad Plus Balance as default editors are used by G8 tool to continue press.
Next, here we want to adjust the name of the initial branch in new repositories.
As default, we select Let it decide to continue.
Press next.
In this case, we want to define your pad environment.
By default, we selected from the command line and also from third party software to continue press
next.
Here we want to select which SSL or TLS library would you like to use for SD connections?
By default, we select Use the open SSL library press.
Next, continue.
In this case, we want to configure how should we treat line endings in text fonts?
By default, we select check out windows that's just commit unique, special style lines endings to
continue press NICS.
Here, we want to know which terminal emulator do you want to use with your Gwaith batch?
By default, we use Mean KTVI press next.
In this case, we want to choose the default behavior of gate pool as default.
We select Fast Forward or missed press next and continue.
Here we want to know which credential helpers should be configured.
By default, we selected Credential Manager Core to continue press next.
In this case, we want to configure extra options and to know which features would you like to enable.
Here we select Enable File System Catching.
To continue press next here, we want to configure experimental options and to know which bleeding edge
features would you like to enable in this case, we don't select anything and press in a start.
The program is being installed.
We are waiting for the installation of the program to be completed.
The software installation process is complete.
Now let's go to desktop and see the get software shortcut.
So first run the gate tool to test the soft fit, we want to see the least of files and folders in the
current part to do this.
We use the less common.
Now we see that the software is installed chronically.
And this comment shows the least of all files and folders for us in the first Test that we managed to
this to get completely in the following.
We checked the CND or command prompt software in Windows.
So click on a Start button.
Type C mode and select command prompt here.
As in the previous system, we can see the files and folders in the current path to check the software
in the Windows Terminal.
The DJR Command is used to view the files and folders, so we tidy I R and press enter.
Now we see that everything is correct and all the files and folders in the current pack are displayed
to us correctly.
Now it's time to move on to in the styling go language.
So go to the go blank dot org, slash the.
We entered the Gold Lange software download page based on the desired operating system, selecting installation
file and download it.
So we select the Windows installation fine, press the download button.
Wait until the download starts.
Now, start, download, the program is being downloaded, download completed, so go to the wrong application.
Right click on the program.
And in a star.
To continue, click next.
This page provides Ars with SOF, the license information, so we select I accept the terms in the license
agreement to continue in select next year, you will have to choose the part to install the go language.
We choose the default path as see backslash, go and continue.
Here, click on Install Button.
Wait a few seconds for the goal language installation to finish installation of the program is completed
and we click on the finish button.
Now we were able to install the Golang programming language.
In this time, you need to define a path as a workspace for the go link, which we usually selected
by default.
See Backslash User Package.
This username and package lets go and create three folders being SIRC pcgg in this part.
So go to my computer, select Drive.
See go to users.
My username here is Hamid Reza.
Go to Hamid Reza.
Create a folder.
Named Go.
Now in Go folder, we create these three folders.
First, create a folder name being.
Second, create a folder named PCGG and third create a folder named SIRC.
OK, here you want to examine it.
Challenge, open the CND program and check the version of the installed GO programming language with
the Go version comment, so click on the Start button.
Type CND and select command prompt.
In this case, we use Frank Go version common, so we tie.
Go version.
Here we see that the installed version of Golang is displayed.
But if the Go version command does not return any output, it means that we should set the environment
variables.
To do this, right click on the My Computer Select properties.
Select advanced system sitting from the right side.
Select the environment variables in this section, go to the System Variables unit and select part and
press, edit and press the new button.
Then set the C column back Yes, let's go back a splash being in this case, we have already set this
value here now to create a girl part right here, then at the top of the page in the user variables
section.
Press the new button in the variable named, then type the vote go pad in upper case and in the variable
value fill time percent user profile by upper case.
Percent back, yes, let's go.
Then press, OK.
By sitting environment variables in the system inside the terminal, we will have access to the go commands
in any part.
So go to the terminal, click on the Start button.
Right, Sandy said a comment from.
First chance, a directory and again, Ron, go urgent, come in.
Now we can see version of the installed GO program with the government comment in another directory.
OK, it's time to download and install this code program for these.
Go to the code that Visual Studio dot com you are so tied code that Visual Studio.
Dot com slash download.
Based on the desired operating system, select installation, file and download it.
My system is Windows 64 bit version, so Settings System Installer 64 bit.
Press the download button.
Wait until the download starts.
Click on the Start download button.
The program is being downloaded.
OK, download completed, so go to install the application.
Right click on the program and select Run as administrator.
This page provides us with SOF, the license agreement.
So select I Accept Agreement radio button and click next to continue on this page, you'll have to choose
the path to install the V escort set up will install Visual Studio called into the C Program Files Microsoft
Voice Code folder, so we choose it as default and continue.
Here you select the Start Menu Folder set will create the Programs shortcut in the following Start Menu
folder.
To continue, press next.
In this case, we want to select which additional tasks should be performed, so we set an app to pat
and created this stop icon as additional icons to continue.
Click next and click Install button.
The program is being installed.
Now, press finish button, the soft installation process is complete.
Now let's go to the desktop and run the escort program.
Now, it's time to configure the vs code in this time.
We want to install go extension, so first press control plus shield plus x key and select go extension.
In a start, it's.
Now, installation completed saw clear software and reopen it again.
Now, it's time to install the required Tools for Waskow program.
So press control plus shift plus p short key and select Go.
Install update tools and select all the check boxes for installing all required tools.
We are waiting for the installation of the required tools to be completed.
OK.
All tools successfully in a staffed, now closed school program and open it again.
Go to the project, explore open workspace.
My workspace is C users, Hamid Reza Go and select SRT folder.
In this case, we want to create a sample in this court, so we define a package like, hello.
And create a fine life main dubbed Go Inside It and set a package, for example, Pichai's main in this
section, we want to write a few lines of code and just we want to test the program and we will explain
these codes in the future.
So we write phone main and set the message for dysfunction, family, not prindle and.
Welcome to go.
Programming language.
Now, save the project, go to terminal and execute the program first clear screen, go to the project
folder and execute the program by the Command Go Run Main Go.
Now we can see the output welcome to go programming language.
Everything is ready for us to be able to write our courts.
We have reached the end of this session.
I hope you take full advantage of this session until next session.
Goodbye.