Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in this issue, and we want to talk about
G.R. PC concept.
What is your PC?
DRP is the modern lined with communication protocol that's implemented by Google.
GOPAC is a high performance, open source, universal RPG framework or remote process or code that can
run in any environment.
It enables the server and client applications to communicate transparently and build connected systems.
We are PC, you can utilize this STP two capabilities such as server side, the streaming, Clydeside
streaming or even bi directional streaming, should you wish.
Jill PC uses an interface description language for IDL to define a service contract and uses HTTP to
the latest network transfer protocol as the default transport protocol and G.R. PCs support only protocol
buffers to transfer data between server and client.
It can efficiently connect services in and across datacentres with plugging will support for load balancing,
threatening health checking and authentication.
The G in Group does not stand for Google.
It is a recursive acronym that stands for Siri remote processor.
Con G.P.S. originated from Google in 2015.
It was based on an internal Google project call as to the.
Which was an internal framework for GOPAC.
But just for Google services.
Nowadays, this tube has been rebranded DARPA and it is free open source project with an open source
and roadmap.
Google designed DARPA to be for and as efficient as possible.
The structure of the protocol itself is lean, with the minimal processing occurring at the marshalling
and on marshalling a stage.
Because of this genre is inherently efficient, made only better by building up an STP two, which enables
highly effective use of natural resources.
What you end up with is a lean platform using lean transport system to deliver lean bits of code an
overall decrease in latency and size.
Dear PC, modern.
G.R. PC provides four different ways of communication between client and server.
The four different ways are a unity server.
Streaming client is streaming and bi directional streaming so effectively in groups of both client and
server can talk to each other.
You know, this is the simplest one.
The client send the request and the server sends a response.
Client is streaming.
The client can send a stream of multiple messages via the server is expected to return on a single response
to all client requests server streaming.
The client will send only one message, while a server can send a stream of messages back to it and
bi directional streaming.
Both client and server can stream multiple messages.
The streaming will be in parallel in no order.
Also, it will no blocking.
Neither client nor server needs to wait for a response before sending the next message.
Performance.
Since you're picking her, Anthony uses HTP to so all the performance optimizations applied to keep
do automatically are available in Group C H two capital has introduced several performance optimization
over ATP one, such as duplex streaming multiplexing and further conversion.
Plus, GOPAC uses political warfare inherently, and since political parties are binary data and have
less sides, there are transferred over network fast.
Since GOPAC is built on top up political power, it provides automatic code generation.
In fact, with political office generation is a mosque.
Things to use your PC.
Your PC can utilize each TCP connection very effectively.
Due to these two reasons, GRC is very fast.
There to use G.R., PC microservices.
G.R. shines as a way to connect servers in service oriented environments.
One of the original problems its predecessor has to the aim to solve was wiring together microservices.
It is well-suited for a wide variety of aeronauts from medium and large enterprises systems on the way
to the very scaled e-commerce and SAS offerings.
Client server applications.
Europe is it works just as well in killing server applications where the client applications run on
desktop or mobile devices.
It uses step two, which improves on S30 one in both latency and network utilization.
Integrations and APIs.
DRP sees as a way to offer opinions over the internet for integrating applications with services from
third party providers.
Petty requisites, let's get Assad installing the petty requisites of the development go version 1.6
or higher for installation instructions.
He goes getting a smart guy.
So use the following year end political warfare version three.
Install the port The compiler that is used to generate job is a service code.
Now, use the following commands.
And GOPAC.
Use the following comment in a song G.R. PC requirements in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.