Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the pit of U.S., we could define the
flag and switches between return values, and in this session, we want to go to implement the Iran
GOP server function.
Go to the GOP server function
first display, a message that the server is a starting sold right off the list, starting
Sarah.
We must tell Server to be ready to listen to a port to do this because the lease and function from the
NYT's package, the lease and function announces on the local network address and accepts two parameters
as network and address and returns to venues and leasing around it all.
So define two variables like leasing, render and invokes the listening function
listener and adult callers because in walk listen function from that package, let's dance.
Listen function
sit TCP as network parameter t c p.
Vorticity networks, if the host in the address parameter is A. or literal on a specified IP address,
this information listeners on all available Unix and any guest IP addresses of the low cost system.
And said at perimeter.
Hundred into an incident, darts 0.0 dart one column for the example port.
Eighty eighty five.
First, check our status if they're not equals name
calling, fat and functional from like packages fatter and all
that
now display another message that indicates the server is listening now.
So we right if PPI
server is listening.
Now we'll be calling a new survey from G.R. PC Package, new search function creates a G.R. PC server,
which has no servers registered and has not to start to accept request.
Yet this function accept a list of DDR option as the input parameter and return a server from G.P.S.
package.
So before invoking this function, we create a variable as array of server options.
So we write options
ray or G.R. PC Dot server option.
Now, Connie, new server function from G.R. PC package, first defined and variable for return value
like new server, new server calling equals and calling new server function from your PC package.
He said that new server function and set options as parameter.
OK, now it's time to call the G.R. PC server initialize a function from the server package so that
we can set the necessary values for our jobs service connection to the database.
This function accept two values for connect to the database, first driver name and second data source
name that we create.
Then to Jason fight and reads from the Jason file and set to the object from configuration as struct.
This function returns true values for us first and object from the IPC controller and second and Arrow,
a student server and roll call in equals connect your PC's server initialize there from server package
server dot.
John PC server initialize a set driver name from conf object.
Com dot driver me and set data source name from Com stored data.
Source name from the data source name.
First check or status, if they're not equals ne lot fatter and without a roof.
Now it's time to connect the server in the G.R. PC package to the server we created in this case, the
name of the server we created from the G.R. PC package is new server and the name of the server be created
using your PC server initialize there is a student server.
We can establish this connection by cutting the register of student service server method from the protocol
package.
This function, I accept two parameters.
First, and no object from service register of the job is the package that registers a service and its
implementation to the concrete type implementing this interface.
And second and object from a student service server of the protocol package.
So we write Protocol Dot Register of Student Service Server set up new server object as service register.
New Senator.
And said a student server object as a student service over the student server.
Now we were able to register the service together.
It's time for the created server to be ready to listen to the request to do this.
We can't serve metal from server package this function, accept the parameter as listener and return
an error value so cunning server methods from new server.
First, define a variable like ETL equals new server.
And calling serve Mitchell and said, Listen, Ralph Nader, parliament, to listen.
Said function accepts incoming connections on the listener, creating a new server, transport in service,
good routine for each.
The service go Reuters read GOPAC requests and then call the Register's handlers to reply to them.
Listener will be closed when this method returns, so check our status if it will not equal.
Large got fat on.
There or there are no.
Now we were able to implement the Iran GOPAC server function in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.