Hello and welcome to the Go programming language course in the previous session.
We were able to implement the Ron GOPAC server and run GOPAC client functions and indecision.
We want to run the program for this purpose.
We use two separate terminals to execute the client and server methods.
To do this, right click on the one off the package of the project folder and select the Rilwan Ford
Explorer.
For the example, right click on the main package.
And select Ribbon in foreign experience.
In the window that opens, hold down the shift key and right click and select the open PowerShell option.
Now, a new PowerShell terminal opens for us and do this again.
Now, another terminal opens for us, reassigning the two open terminals inside the skin so we can see
both at the same time.
Now we use this command to run our program once we the surf league and once we the client flat for the
server, we write, go wrong, go to main package and Maine that go Fong Dash admin server.
Now we can see the server is running and go to another terminal and wrong clients, right?
Go run, go to package main and main that go find Dash.
That means by the flag clients and run
when you run the client side program, we are asked which option you want to select.
There are two options.
Number one and number two in option number one based on the name.
It is supposed to show us the least of all students in the database that have that name and in option
number two based on an I.D. number.
Displays the student information whose ID is equal to the number received.
For example, we want to select number one.
So right one and press enter.
For example, we enter the name David and press enter date after entering the name David.
The program will show us the list of S2.
Then whose name is David?
Once again, we do this on there.
Another name?
Select one and press enter now into another name for exemption, Jack,
and we can see the program is show off the list of a student whose name is Jack.
Once again, Rod declared side program and in this time, select the number two.
Select number two and trace, either in this case, we are asked to enter an I.D. number.
For example, we enter five for I.D. value on press enter after entering the I.D. by the five value
the program is shown, the student information whose idea is equal to number five do a gain.
Select number two and enter your I.D. for the exam, press three and enter now we can see I.D. equals
three named David and Age Terrifying.
In this tutorial, we succeed to implement a G.R. piece of service based using protocol partner, and
we were able to connect to the database through the G.R. PC service and run our queries on it.
First, we created the part related to the database.
Then we launched our job jobs a service, and then we designed the methods related to the server and
client part and established their connection with the job service and the database.
We have reached end of decision.
I hope you have taken full advantage of this session until next session.
Goodbye.