So before we can do much coding, we need to set up our project.
And if you look at the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file called Source Dot Zip.
Download that and then create a new folder somewhere on your machine.
It doesn't matter where you put it, as long as you can find it easily.
I created a folder called Cell Dash Dev and then extract the contents of that zip file into that folder,
and you should wind up with a folder named something like Cel Dash Dev your overall folder.
And inside of that, you have a folder called celebrities.
Now, if you did the first part of this, this creating a go version of Laravel, you probably already
have some source code that you could use if you wanted to.
But I encourage you to use Source Dot Zip, download that and use it instead.
And then you can apply whatever changes you want to your own code as you go along or after you're finished
this course or whatever.
But it will be simpler for everyone if we're all starting from the same place.
So I encourage you to do that.
And once you've done it, once you have an overall project folder and inside of that folder, name celebrities
with all the appropriate source code in there and start up visual studio code or whatever your favorite
editor is, and open that folder the celebrities folder.
So I'll open from my desktop or find my cell dash dev and open celebrities.
OK.
And I'll open it now.
This is the code as it existed at the end of part one of this course.
So if you look for example at the make file right here down here on Line 18, this is how we build the
celebrity's executable and we're going to do that in just a moment, but I need to make one change first.
So if you go to the CMT Seelye folder and find the new Dot Go file and open that.
This is the line right here that I want to change.
When I did the first half of this course, I used C to get the necessary skeleton's hilarious application
repository, and I'm going to change that to use TDPs instead.
So what I'm going to do is just duplicate this line, comment the first one out and change the URL to
this.
I have a copy to my clipboard.
We're using HTTPS instead.
And as you can see, the URL is pretty, pretty similar, but it's HTP s colon slash slash GitHub dot
com slash t Solr slash celebrities dash app dot get.
OK.
So that's the first change I want to make.
Now, once that's done, I'm going to go to my terminal window and I'll just type make build.
And this will build a new version of the celebrity's application inside the this directory.
So now if I go inside the this directory, I can type dot slash celebrities.
And if you're on windows, it'll have Dot X at the end, of course, new and I'm going to create an
application folder called my app and please use the name my app for now.
This will clone the repository and everything is ready to go.
OK, so now I have a new application inside that folder.
So over here, if I go back to my finder or my desktop inside of celebrities inside of the dist, I
have a new folder called my app, and I want that to exist beside this hilarious folder.
So from the command line, I can just say move my app up one level that gets me inside the celebrity
folder, then up another level which gets me beside the celebrities folder, I think.
Let's find out.
So I'll go up to levels and do an else.
And there they are.
Now we're not quite done.
Let's close this window entirely or just create a new window that'll do the trick.
And let's open that celebrity's folder.
So I will make this window bigger.
What we're going to do here is create a new workspace in a minute and I'll open that my app folder I
just created.
So on my desktop, inside a cell, dev my app, I'm going to open this.
And then I'm going to open go dark mode, and I want to add the replace line that we used last time
around.
So at the very bottom of this file, I'll simply add a line that tells Go, we're going to replace GitHub
dot com slash t Solr slash celebrity's
version zero point zero point zero, which I don't think matters, but I was at it with dot dot slash
celebrities and say that, OK, now I'm going to close this window and close this window and create
a new window.
And then I will say add a folder to a workspace.
Now I'll add those two folders that we just created on my desktop.
Cell Dev.
I'm going to add celebrities and I'm also going to add another folder to the workspace.
Which is my app that now if I look at my files, you'll see I have my app here.
I have celebrities there.
And now I will save everything as a workspace safe workspace as and I'll put that at the root level
of my cell dev folder, which I'll call just workspace.
OK, now that we've done this, it will make it much easier for us to work on our project because I'll
be able to make changes in celebrities and have them reflected very quickly, much faster than last
time around.
Because the last time I tried this, when I recorded the first half of this course, this didn't work.
But it appears to now, OK, so we have our workspace set up.
Let's move on.