Before we go too much further, let's just make sure that everything works.
So I'm going to start up Visual Studio code right here, and I will say open a workspace.
From a vial, and I'll find my workspace, which is inside my desktop folder right here, workspace,
that one.
So we have it open.
And the first thing I want to do is I want to make sure that it actually works, so opened my terminal,
make sure I'm inside the My App folder and I am.
And I'll just take make start.
OK, so it started it on Port 4000.
Let's go to our Web browser and make sure we can actually hit that file so localhost four thousand perfect.
So it works.
Now let's stop the application.
Make stop.
And let's make sure that if we make a change here in celebrities, that it's reflected when we use that
change in my app, and we can do that by going to the celebrity folder and creating a new folder inside
of that cold test folder and inside of that look pretty good file.
And I'll just call it test, go go.
And the package is test folder.
And I'll just create a handler here, func test handler.
And it takes the standard two arguments for any handler, a response writer, which I'll call W Response
Writer and a pointer to a request which I'll call our HIPAA request and I'll just write some text to
the browser window so you don't write as a slice of bytes.
It works.
That's enough.
OK, so that exists now.
If I go to the Roots Dog Go file inside of my app right here and I add a test route.
Read like this a dog get test route.
And I want that to point to the new package called Test Folder inside of celebrities.
So I should be able to just to go test folder dot test handler.
OK?
And it looks like it worked really quickly for me.
Sometimes there's a few seconds of delay, but down here in my terminal now I should be able to able
to type make start.
And it's now running, and I can go back to my web browser and try going to this route.
So I switch back to Firefox and I'll click on my user over and paste that to the end of it.
And it works great that is ever so much faster than the old way of doing it, the way I was forced to
do it in the previous section of this course.
So that'll make our lives a lot easier.
OK, so now that we know that everything works, let's get rid of this test route and get rid of this
test package.
Delete that and move to trash.
And we're good to go and I I'll stop the application.
Make stop.
All right.
Let's go do some actual work on our project and we'll get started with file systems in the next section
of this course.