Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about some important things about a race.
One, if an Ari does not initialize explicitly, then the default value of this attack is zero.
Two in A..
You can find the length of the array using land function.
Three in an area.
If ellipses become visible at the place of length, then the length of the array is determined by the
initialized elements.
Fold in an attack, you are allowed to iterate over the range of the elements of the array.
Five in an ad, if the element time of the era is comparable, then they're at a time is also comparable
so we can directly compare to and he's using equal to operate or.
Now go to a school program and do some exam pit about these, some important things.
14.
First case, you find out, does not initialize explicitly then the default value of this value is zero.
First, creating an array of ian type feature stores two elements.
Right.
My Ray lengths to try this, and we don't initialize this any and display the very either.
FP, my Paris, save the project and execute.
We can see that output, so the value of daddy is zero because compiler assign different value for every.
OK.
Go to the next case in an array, you can find the length of the array using the land function first,
clear the last go
and creating two arrays using shorthand creation for the example array.
One column equals length three time and clearly rockets one comma two comma three, and in the next
line, array two column equals length scythe by the ellipses and time is end and initialized by one,
two, three, four and five.
Now, finding the length of the array using land function, go to the next line FP length of a one column
land function and set the value.
It had a well.
Go to the next line and read this call for the either way, even if he brings
up a two and set the land function and array to save the project and execute.
Now we can see the output.
The length of at Avon is three and the length of three two is five.
Now we could find the length of +8 by land function.
Go to the next case in an array.
If ellipses become visible at the place of lengths, then the length of the array is determined by the
initialized elements.
First, clear the last court.
Create an add a whose size is determined by the number of elements present in it using ellipses for
the example array column he calls ellipses set for the length type is estrange and initialize by the
values for the example girl
Java
Seashore,
C++
and OK.
Displayed at a well, it's up against.
Oh hey, Colin.
On September 18 at.
And in the next line displayed the length of the alley that is determined by using land function, FP
length of a column and learn function and set the variable.
I saved the project and execute.
Now we can see the output and the length of play is five
and the next case in an array, you are allowed to iterate over the range of the elements of the array.
First, clear the last code,
creating an eddy whose size is represented by the ellipses.
For example, again, any equals sets and it says for the lengths type is it and initialize value by
10, 20, 30, 40, 50 and 60, Iterate added.
Using for loop four.
I call an equal zero I less than Len of anybody ever.
I + + now displayed to each element of every variable by the comment, if this person, the back is
less in and a square market index, I save the project, then execute.
Now we can see the output and we could iterate between any elements.
Go to the next case in an area.
If the elements time of the attack is comparable, then to at a time is also comparable, so we can
directly compare to arrays using equal to operator
first clear.
The last code
defined three arrays at a long calling equals five
and initialized by the values one, two, three, four and five.
Go to the next line and define another variable at a two Hallen equals set.
The last by the ellipses and type is end and initialized by the values one, two, three, four and
five.
And go to the next line and create another variable like add a three column equals set the length five
and type is eight and initialize the value for the example six to three, seven and nine.
Now comparing arrays using equal to operator for the example to compare, arrival in at A2 had a tool
by at eighty and eleven point eighty three if p at a Y equal to at a two.
And in the next line, if P
had a tool equal to at eight three and in the next line
had a one equal to a three, save the project and execute the code.
Now we can see the outpour first conversion is two and the other conversion is false.
We have reached the end of this session.
I hope you have taken full advantage of this session until next session.
Goodbye.