Hello and welcome to the kulang programming language course.
In this session, we want to talk about the others concurrency concepts.
Channel as Fonctionne, are you man to go?
There are many ways in which it can and can be passed as a function argument.
The direction of the arrow for a channel specifies the direction of flow of data channel bi directional
channel.
Both read and write channel channel operator on the writing channel channel operator channel on the
reading from the Channel, the input channel, Asterix Channel Channel Pointer both read and write.
BI directional channel signature of such a bi directional channel will be light below, then pass to
a function as an argument.
Now let's go to a school with program to illustrate by of Shannon Channel.
First, create a function that accept the channel as argument.
Solve you right?
Find, for example, process.
Set a variable like search by the time of each.
Sent a value to Channel C H channel operator, for example, send a value like 10.
Received value off channel and display, it defines a value to like value calling equals channel operator
and CSI event and display it FP
Value now go to main function and create a channel and positive process function.
So define a value like search Collins equals and consummate function channel for you to come in and
sit.
For example, try a second argument now counting process and set channel as arguement go, process and
sit c is a channel are human to process function.
Now go to the next line and put a time asleep.
Time to sleep.
For example, one multiplication time.
The second reform that the court said the projects and execute the program go from, that the bank is
dismaying that quote now we can see the output, we could send a value through a channel and receive
its value in a gold routine by the buffer China in order not to prolong the time of decision.
You will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.