Hello and welcome to the godowns programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about the orders concurrency concept.
Anonymous girl routine.
In good language, you can also sort go rooting for an anonymous function or, in other words, you
can create an anonymous glow routine simple by using go keyboard as a prefix of that function.
Now you can see the syntax.
There is no difference in behavior through when calling an anonymous function using go writing or calling
a normal function using gold.
Now, let's go to this school program to illustrate how to create an anonymous school routine.
First, write a message for interim main function.
If hello, hello to name function, now creating an anonymous call written for the example.
Go find open and close parentheses, curly braces and end of closed braces.
We sit and order open and closed practices and in the between open and closed curly braces, we sit
as statements.
For example, FP Welcome to Girl Rules
now set a sleep time and statement for exit from main function.
Time does sleep.
One Multiplication time start second.
And so the message is that, for example, if the good by.
Reformat the code, save the project and execute the program, go wrong.
Back this made that go.
Now we can see the output.
Two main function.
Welcome to go routine and goodbye.
So we could define an anonymous score routine in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.