So in this section of the course, what we're going to focus upon is making it easier for developers
using celebrities to write their tests.
And a lot of people overlook writing tests.
They think it's too much work.
They don't see the benefit.
But anyone who's written them realizes that writing good tests makes maintaining your code ever so much
easier and actually cuts down on development time as time goes on.
So let's get started, and we'll focus on is writing tests for the most difficult part of most web applications.
And that, of course, is the handler's package.
So what I'm going to do is write the necessary tests that we want to include right in my app, and then
we'll just add those stub test files to the repository that we clone when someone types celebrity's
new whatever the project name is.
So over in my app, inside the handlers folder, the very first thing I'm going to do is create a new
go file and it has to be named.
This setup underscore test, not go.
And of course, what this does is set up our testing environment, and we're going to do it using a
function called Test Me that was introduced to go, I think, around version one point four or five.
But it's incredibly useful.
So let's read a function thunk that has to be called test me exactly like that, and it takes one parameter
which I'm going to call em up type points or two testing dot in thirties.
So everything we do in the test main function will execute before the actual test suite runs, and I
need to set up things that are going to be required in order for our handlers to function.
So things like the session, the celebrity's variable, our views are renderer things like that, and
it will seem like a fair bit of duplication of code from the main application itself.
And it is, but we this allows us to isolate our tests and to only test the things we want to test.
So a couple of things that I'll put in, we may not use them, but someone writing tests down the road
with more complex handlers probably will.
I'll set up an info log.
Actually, let me declare a few variables first.
So I'm going to declare a variable called self, and that is of type celebrities, not celebrities.
OK.
And I'll also declare one called test session.
And of course, that's going to be a pointer to a session manager, and I'll declare another one called
handlers.
Test handlers were test handlers, and we'll need these in order to run our handler tests of type handlers.
OK.
Now, what are some of the things that we need to do in here?
Well, to start with, let's set up some loggers.
We might not use them, but it's nice to have them info log and that's a sign the value of long up new.
And it writes to us, don't stand out.
And will prefix it with info and a tab and will include in it logged date and a python and logged time.
OK, now duplicate that just to save some typing and make this one error log.
And this will be prefixed with error and we'll put in log l date log l time and also will pipe log dot
short l short file.
OK.
Just to give us line numbers when there's errors.
So those are the first two things I'm going to need.
I'm also obviously going to need a session because any web application out there is going to use sessions
of some sort.
So test session variable we declared right up on Line 12.
That's going to be equal to new and we'll just use the default cookie based session and we'll set up
some reasonable defaults test session, dart lifetime.
And I'll make that again lifetime.
And we'll make that equal to twenty four times timed out.
OK.
And cookies.
Test session, cookie.
Don't persist.
Oh my God, good true and test session, not cookie.
That same site will make that equal to HGTV Dot same site lax mode.
And test session, the cookie that's secure will make that equal to thoughts.
Those were just running tests here.
So we need that there's our session variable.
Now let's create our views, our Jet Dot news set, so I'll create a variable.
Views equals jet dot new set.
And I'll put this on separate lines, so it's more readable.
The first line will be Jet Dot New OS file system letter, and we'll give it the correct path to where
our user store, which is actually up one level views.
OK.
And we'll have Jet Dart in development mode.
All right, there's our views now I can use that to create a renderer which I'm going to need to use
to render pages.
So I'll just call this my ringer.
And that will be a sign the value of from the render package in our Celebrity House project or our project
don't render.
And I'll specify the things that we want.
So renderer that will be equal to jet and route pass and that will be assigned the value of up one level
slash.
And the port has 4000, which isn't going to be used, but I'll just specify it anyway.
Now, of course, that's a string.
And jet views.
And that's the sign, the value of use, the variable we just set out.
And our session, of course, that's going to be test session, which we defined just a few minutes
ago.
So now I have my render.
Now, I can use this to specify what celebrities is going to be the sole variable and that will be equal
to celebrities.
Dot celebrities and we just populate its fields, so apni, we don't need this, but I'll put my app
in there.
And debug, I'll make that trip useful during testing.
Version immaterial, but I'll put it in any way.
One point zero point zero Error log.
And that's going to be equal to the error log we defined right at the start of this function.
Info log will be the info log we defined.
Route path.
This is important.
Dot, dot, slash or nothing will work.
Roots.
I'll make that deal for now, and we'll set it up later on, my renderer is a reference to my renderer
because it has to be a pointer session is test session.
And it does require some kind of debate, so in here, I'll just put an empty, solicitous dot database
like that, and that's sufficient for our purposes.
Jet views will be equal to views encryption key.
I can just make that a random string.
It doesn't matter because it'll change every time we run a test.
So I'll make this around.
No random value.
Sell the random string that needs to be exactly 32 characters long, so that'll suffice for our purposes.
Cash will make nil.
It could just leave that empty.
But you know, people will want to change this as they're writing their own tests scheduler.
I'll make that Neal as well.
Mail, I'll make an empty mail or mail.
And server and that will be celebrities.
Dot server, and we'll leave that empty as well.
OK, so now we have that set up, the next thing we need to do to be able to test our handlers is to
make test handlers app equal to a reference to celebrities are so variable.
And now the magic in Test main, of course, is when you call Osaka exit and we exit M run.
And what this will do is run all of the tests that are in this directory after these values are set
up and then it will exit when things are finished.
OK, so that's the first thing we're going to do is set up this test main variable.
In the next lecture, we'll set up a couple of functions that will make our lives easier as well.
One to set up the roots, they said.
We're not going to use the actual rootstock go file.
We'll just put in the roots we want to test and also managing the context so that we have access to
the session in the tests when we need to have that access and we'll get started on that in the next
election.