So we have our test main function set up that actually establishes the environment in which we want
to run our tests and how we're going to add two functions to the bottom of this file.
The first one is going to be called simply get roots, funk, get roots.
And it takes no parameters, but returns in Eastport Handler.
OK, and we'll write that in a second.
The second function I want is because it's going to be called get C.T. X and it's going to take one
parameter, which I'll call every cue.
And it's a pointer to HTP Dot request and it returns context, dot context.
OK, now we'll populate the values in these functions of the body.
These functions right now.
The first one get roots.
This is a substitute for the root start go file that exists in our project, in my app, and I'll we're
going to do here is create a router.
So Max is a sign the value of from the chip package dot new router.
And then we'll say mucks don't use, and the only middleware I'm going to put in here right now is sell
dot session load to manage sessions, OK?
And I must specify a route and I'll just put one in four right now, Muscat and everybody has a home
page, so slash.
And that's going to go to test handlers.
The Hunt, the one handler that we're worried about right now.
We might do more later on, but this will get us started.
And now we just return Max.
So that is where we'll specify our routes that we're going to be testing and get CTCs or get context.
This is just so we can use sessions, and there's just basically one line and an error check that we
have to add here.
And it's very simple.
So Seat X is a variable, I'm declaring, and we'll check for an error come from test session dot load
and we hand it the context which we get from the request Erica context.
And then the second parameter is just wreck dot header, don't get.
And we just have to use this header and it's a very specific format x dash capital s session.
OK, without that, we can't we can't actually access any values from the session, and I will check
for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll just log in logged our current line.
The error down here, we just say returns KCTCS.
OK, now we're not using either of these yet, but in the next lecture, we'll write one very, very
simple test that developers can use as kind of a starting point, and we'll get started on that in the
next lecture.