So we have our test main and the get roots and get KCTCS functions complete, so let's write a test
and see how it works.
So I'll do that by going over to the handlers folder in my app and creating a new Go file, which I'll
call handlers underscore.
Test don't go and it has to end and underscore test don't go.
Or as I'm sure you know, it won't actually be recognized as a test.
OK, so I have this file.
Let's write our first test and we're going to test the home page.
So --, test home seems like a logical name, and it takes one parameter, as most tests do te pointer
to testing dot t and it doesn't return anything.
Now, very first thing I need to do is to get my roots, so I have access to the necessary route to
test a handler.
And I think that by declaring a variable rates and saying that's assign the value of just call a function,
get roots.
Now I need to start up or define a testing server.
And we do that using Go's built in and rather robust testing functionality.
So tips for test server is a sign the value of each type test dog new test server right there and we
hand it roots to now has some roots to test and we'll defer closing this defer to start close.
So it'll close once we get out of the once this function exits.
And now let's get a response and check for an error.
When we call from the test variable, we just defined online.
Can we define a new clients, a Dot client dot account request?
And you were all I want.
It's not just the home route slash.
We have to put in T-s dot URL because that URL for the test server, it'll be a different port every
time you run it.
So yes, and then we just attend Append Plus Slash at that to test the homepage and we'll check for
an error if error is not equal to nil if something went wrong.
I'll just say long before.
So T dot log beer and T dot fatal error.
We'll do it twice once would be sufficient.
I actually don't need this long, but I'll leave it like that.
It's not going to hurt anything and now I'll just check all I'm got to check.
Here's to say is the response status code equal to status?
OK, which is 200.
So if DOT status code that is rest bright Respect Status Code is not equal to 200, then I'll write
an error.
So this test will fail keyed on error and I'll use error string.
Four for home page expected status.
Two hundred, but got actually I'll change that to an era of.
But got.
Present day, because it's an integer and the substitution is respect status code there.
So in theory, I should be able to run this test.
Let's give it a try of my terminal window.
Make sure I'm in the Maya folder and go to the Handlers folder and type go test dot.
And it passed perfect.
So there is how we write a simple test.
Now, obviously, I don't want to stop here.
This would be a great start for developers if we did nothing else, this would make development and
writing of tests for handlers ever so much easier.
But I don't want to stop here.
I want to add some additional functionality and we'll get to this in a little bit.
But for example, one of the things that Laravel offers is Laravel Dusk, and it has a nice feature
when you're writing tests for web pages.
If a test fails, you can actually take a snapshot of the page as it appears in the browser when that
test fails.
And that makes it much easier to look at the results of your tests when something is not behaving as
expected.
So we'll get to that before too long.
But before we do that, we'll just write a few more tests just so we can see how these things actually
work over time, because not everybody writes tests exactly the same way.
OK, we'll move on and write a couple of additional tests in the next lecture.