So let's write another test using a slightly different approach, and this time let's test the session
as well.
OK, so back in the file handlers underscore Tesco, let's just create a new function and I'll just
call it test home to T pointer to testing tea, and it doesn't return anything.
Now, last time around, we actually got our roots, and then we use the HTP test new tell us server,
but this time let's do a little bit differently.
Let's build a request manually.
So a variable RFQ for request, and I'll ignore the error that comes from http dot new request.
We just created a request.
The method will be get the URL doesn't matter.
You can put anything in there and we're not going to pass.
Anything is the body.
OK, so we have a request.
Now let's get a context using that request so we can play with the session.
So this is my variable I'm creating.
I just comes by calling or comes from calling.
Get context and handing it the request we just made.
And now my request is going to be equal to request Dot with context, and the context is just KCTCS.
Now I have a request that is aware of the session.
And just like I built the request, I'm also going to build a response.
But I'm going to use.
I'll call the variable R for response recorder because I'm going to get it from calling HTP Test Dot
New Recorder.
And that's a response recorder, which takes the place of a response writer.
Now, let's put something in the session just so we can test to see if it's still there after we run
our test sold-out session Selby in the variable that we created, that's our sellers house darts alert
horse type and we'll put in that session using this context.
We'll use the key test underscore key and some value hello world.
And that should be in the session now.
Now, rather than spinning up a new a server like we did before, we use a different approach will declare
a variable called H, and that's assigned the value of casting it to an HTTP dot handler.
Func handler, func make sure you get the right one and we just call our variable test handlers dot
com.
OK.
And now we make a call to that by going to H Dot surveys.
And it requires a response writer of some sort.
We can use our and our request, which is our HQ.
Now I can test to see if we get the correct status code.
So I can just say if our code is not equal to two hundred and I have an error.
So I'll just error on error.
F error f
returned wrong response code got percent d but expected two hundred and my code would be our code.
So that's one test.
So this is a except for putting something in the session, it's functionally equivalent to the one we
wrote last time around.
But now we'll test to see if something's in the session.
If cell dont session the server session, don't get string using the context ATX looking for test key
if that's not equal to Hello World, then wrote T dot error, I'll just say did not get correct value
from session.
And of course, you can put whatever you want in there.
Now, obviously this is a highly contrived example, but hopefully it shows you how you'd work with
a session.
Normally, you would call some handler that would set some sessional variable.
And then after you've called that handler, you could look to make sure that the sessional variable
you expect to find is in their end of the correct value.
But the steps to make that happen are virtually identical to what we have here.
We just wouldn't put it in this session online.
32.
Instead, we just check to see what was in the session after we've made the call to serve HGTV or our
request.
OK, let's run this test and see if it worked the way that we expected.
So I'll put my terminal window.
Make sure I'm inside the handlers folder.
I am go test dot.
And everything passed perfect.
So in the next lecture, we'll get started on working on some Laravel dusk like functionality, specifically
taking a screenshot from the web browser.
When something doesn't go the way that it's expected to and we'll get started on that next time around.