So over the next few lectures, what I want to do is to implement some of the functionality, not all
of it, but some of the functionality that you see here in Laravel Dusk.
And this is, of course, testing using a browser rather than you doing it yourself with a web browser,
it automates and starts up a browser in the background and runs whatever test you want.
And the part I want to focus on right now is just grabbing a screenshot of the page as it exists at
some point during a test.
Normally, of course, when something goes wrong and you want to look at what the browser sees when
an error takes place, so it was a bunch of ways we can do this.
There are several packages that actually drive web browsers in the background available in the go world.
But the one I want to use is this one.
It's go rod, goldenrod slash run.
And what I like about this is that it actually works really well.
There is another package out there called Chrome DPI.
I think it is.
I've never been able to get that one to work properly, but that could just be because it wasn't trying
hard enough to.
In any case, this one works really well.
It came out last year and it's actively developed and it works really well.
So this is the GitHub repository, and there's a link to this in the course resources for this lecture.
And this is the documentation, and there's a link to that in the course of resources for this lecture
as well.
But let's go install it.
And so I'll go back to my idea and I'll open a terminal window and I'll go up to levels and then into
this hilarious package because I want this to be important in this hilarious package and not in my app.
And I'll type go get and paste in the appropriate URL, GitHub dot com slash and go dash run slash run.
And I'll go get it.
OK, so it's installed it for us, and that means we can actually use it.
So to get started in the next lecture, we'll create a new go file in this hilarious project that just
grabs a screenshot and we'll give it a try.