So this time around, what I want to do is to write a helper function in this whole art house project
that I can call from my tests in whatever test I'm writing in my my app, for example, and just grab
a screenshot.
And fortunately, it's really easy to do so using the rod package.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go to my Solaris House project and at the root level or create
a new go file and I'll call mine DuckDuckGo.
You can call it whatever you want.
I'm calling it dusk because I'm going to be implementing some of the functionality that you find in
Laravel Dusk.
And just as an aside, you can actually, as far as I can tell, implement pretty much all of the functionality
you have in Laravel Dusk using pretty much the same logic that I'm going to this time around because
the Rudd package has an awful lot of control over a given browser, but we'll just do a few.
So package still our task that was hopefully filled in by my I.D. and I'll create a function with the
receiver see pointer to celebrities.
I'm going to call this one.
Take screenshot, OK?
And it takes a few parameters.
First of all, a URL, so page URL that seems like an appropriate name.
Also, the name of the test that I'm going to be running this from.
Both of these are strings and also width and height.
How big a browser window do I want to capture?
And these are of type float 64, which seems odd because their whole numbers, but that's what they're
using in the wrong package.
Now I'm going to create a variable called Page, and you can see this, this is just taken and modified
from the example code that you find right on the home page of the GitHub repository for Rudd.
It's really simple.
I'm going to create a variable called page, and that's a sign the value of rod drive to spell right
rod dot new with no parameters and that imports are on for me.
And then it must connect.
Dot must connect.
Then Dot and this one's important.
Must ignore certain errors and set that to true.
OK.
Because when we spin up our test, tell us server, it's actually an SSL encrypted server, but it generates
its own certificate.
And if we don't put must ignore cert errors true there, then the test will fail every time simply because
it says, I don't know what the certificate is, I'm not going any further.
So we'll set that to true then must page singular.
And the page I want is page URL, the parameter I've got as a call to this function.
And then finally, must wait load.
Wait until the page is loaded.
OK.
So as you can see, they actually use what's known as the fluid syntax Enron, where you can chain function
after function, after function, and it works pretty well.
So there's my page variable.
Now I just want to get a screenshot from that page.
I'll store the result in a variable called image, and I'll ignore the error, which I probably shouldn't.
But I'm going to for right now, and I call Page Dot screenshot.
And here it requires a few parameters.
First of all, full page, I'll say true.
And now the second argument is actually going to be written this way as a reference to Protocol Dot
Page Capture screenshot, which should be showing up here, capture screenshot things and we fill in
its fields.
And I want to say format, which is one of the required fields, and I'm going to make it a ping image.
So Kroto Dot and I'm looking for page capture screenshot ping.
You can do it as JPEG or Wimpey, but I'm going to go with PNG.
OK?
And the second thing I'm going to specify is how much of the page do I want to clip?
And that's why I put the width and height in there, so I'll put in clip.
And this is a reference to Kroto Dot Page Viewport.
And I'll specify its fields.
So x start at zero.
Top left is where we're going here.
Y started zero with.
I'll make that W, which I received as a parameter to this function.
Height will be h, which I received as a parameter, this function and the scale, and I'll scale it
to one.
In other words, don't scale it at all.
Then put a comment after this.
And now from surface, if you read the documentation for Ron, it'll tell you this is an experimental
feature, but use it, it works really well from surface is true, just makes things a little bit faster,
as far as I can tell.
OK, so that gives me my image variable.
Now I'll create a file name.
The name of the file where that I'm going to use when I save this to disk.
So filing is a sign.
The value of that.
I'm going to use time dot now
dot format.
And then I'll just use a file system safe name using the date and time.
So using goes rather unusual syntax for formatting dates and times.
Twenty six, excuse me, the year Dash zero one gives me the month Dash zero two, excuse me, the day
and then a dash.
And I'll just go with the time 15 and I can't use columns.
It doesn't work on a Mac.
It might work on windows I've never tried zero for.
Zero five.
And then just to be safe, because it might have to test feeling very close to each other only include
milliseconds, so I'm going to put one two three four five six zeros.
OK, so that's the first part of my filing.
And now I'll ignore the error when I use the Utils package to put a file.
And again, that's right from Ron Simmons protocols, and I'm going to put it to a now.
I'll build a string format as per death and my format string will be percent s slash screenshots slash
percent s dash percent s s dot PNG.
And my substitutions for those r c dot root pass the root of my my app application, then the name of
the test test name, which I received as a call to this function.
And then finally.
And after that comma, I'm writing image by MGM.
And that should do it, so I should be able to call this from a test.
So, of course, we haven't written that bit of the test yet, but we'll take care of that in the next
election.
And we're also we may as well do this right now.
Notice that I'm writing this to a folder called Screenshots.
Let's go back to our celebrities and go file and make sure that folder is generated when the application
starts.
So celebrities don't go.
And somewhere in here, I have a place where I'm creating folders.
There it is.
It's right at the top of the new function in celebrities don't go folder names.
I'm just going to add to the very end of this screenshots.
OK, so that should take care of it.
The next time this starts, it should create the screenshots folder for us.
But since I'm going to be doing this running tests and I'm not an optimist, I'm going to go manually
create it too.
So at the root level of my app or create a new directory called screen shots, which I have to spell,
right?
OK.
In the next lecture, we'll actually try to modify a test to generate a screenshot and see how it all
works.