So we have this helpful function, take screenshot.
Let's give it a try, and I'll do that by going over to handlers, underscore Tesco, which of course
is in the Map project in the handlers folder.
And I'll just add another check here in the test home function.
Right now, all I'm doing is checking the response status code if it's not equal to 200 when there's
an error.
So what I'll do instead, or in addition to this, is to grab the entire text that I'm getting back
as part of the response and check to see if a certain string exists in there.
If it doesn't, we'll throw an error.
And of course, I'll pick a string that I know is not there.
So I'll declare a variable body text and I'll check for an error when I call.
I'll read All right there and I read rest on body, and that comes back as a slice of bytes or a bunch
of bytes.
We'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then just not fatal with the error.
But once I get past that, here's where I can do my little check, if not strings dot contains.
So let's convert body text, which is a bunch of bytes into a string string body text.
So that's what we're searching and we're looking for this text submarine.
I know that's not in there.
So if that doesn't exist, let's take a screenshot cell dot screenshot.
Take screenshot right there, and we need to pass it a URL.
So that's T-S done URL plus a slash, which might not be necessary, but I'll put it in there the name
of the test, home test and some screen dimensions.
I'll go with 1500 and 1000.
And of course, we need an error to error.
And I'll just say we did not find submarine.
And of course, you could put whatever you want there.
OK, let's run this test, so I'll open my terminal and clear the screen.
Make sure I'm in the right folder.
So I'll go up one level and over to my app.
And then in the handlers that'll run the test and go will probably tell me I have to go get my salary
to this project, but that's no problem.
Go test dot.
And it says, Go get some laptops, so I'll copy this.
The pasted in here to get the new function.
Clear the screen and try it again, go test dot.
And it should fail, and it will also give me a warning, I expect.
Now that warning you see there us handshake error that's going to show up every time a test fails and
screenshot is taken simply because it's an unsigned certificate.
Now it didn't find submarine.
Let's see if we have our screenshot.
So in the screenshots folder.
There is a file.
Let's double click on it.
And there it is.
It's a screenshot, but you'll notice that the image shows up as a broken icon and that's easy to fix,
and it was an oversight on my part.
If we go back to set up test, don't go, let me hide the terminal.
Right here, when we're getting the roots right here, we need to tell our router where the static assets
are.
And of course, that's very similar to what's in the roots.
So let's just open the roots file, grab the static roots right here.
Copy them.
Go back to set up test.
Don't go paste those in there and modify this to say go up one level to the public directory.
And of course, we need to change this to be MUX.
OK, so now I'll delete this home test screenshot that I have from the last time I ran the test.
Reopen my terminal.
Clear the screen.
Run the tests.
I should get an error and I should get a screenshot as well.
And there's the error.
Now let's look at our screenshot.
There it is.
There is the image as expected, and that seems to work perfectly.
So that seems to work pretty well, and it will be very useful when you're running browser tests and
just want to get a visual feedback as to what might be going wrong.
OK.
In the next lecture, we'll just write one or two more helper functions in the alertness package just
to make testing even easier.