So let's continue improving our testing functionality, and as I said earlier, basically all of the
functionality you find in Laravel Dusk can easily be duplicated using GO and the broad package we use
to grab a screenshot because it does more than take screenshots.
So in this lecture, what I want to do is get started, say, emulating a mouse, click so you load
a page with your your headless browser or the browser that's running in the background.
As a part of this test, you select a particular element on the page, which happens to be a button
or link, and you click on it and then you check to make sure that the expected action takes place after
you click on the button and we'll just do a really simple test here.
So to get started, if you look at the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a zip file called
Tester Jet Zip.
Download that and extract the zip file and copy the contents and then put them in here.
I'll just copy and paste what I have on my clipboard, in The View's menu, in my app, or create a
new file called Tester Dot Jet.
And of course, you'll just drag yours in.
But here's the contents of that file.
It's a dead simple jet template.
Basically, it displays a button that is labeled Click Me, and it has as in JavaScript void.
It's actually a link, but it looks like a button because we're using bootstrap.
It has the idea of clicker.
And down here in the JavaScript, I'm listening for the click event on that particular element.
And once it's clicked, it populates a certain div with the text clicked the button.
Very simple.
OK.
So we have that.
Let's now go over and add a handler for that.
So go over to handlers dot go.
It'll go to the bottom of that file.
Look at a handler, so func h is the receiver pointer to handlers, and I'll call this one say clicker.
It's simple enough and it's a handler, so we give it a standard two parameters.
And this is dead simple.
So we'll just say air is assigned the value of each dot rendered and we're going to render using W and
R, the file tester, which we just created and no data is being passed to a new angle.
And if the error is not equal to nil, then we'll do what we've done before.
Just say h start at dot error log dot print line, whatever the error is.
OK, so that'll render it.
Now let's go to our roots file right here and at a right to it.
And I'll put it right after the home page.
So I'll duplicate that line and I'll call the root tester and it goes to the handler.
OK.
So let's make sure that worked well.
Open up her terminal, go to the root level of the my app and take make start.
And I should be able to go to local host Colin 4000 tester just to make sure it works.
So it started, let's go to our browser.
And I'll go to local host, 4000 tester.
And there's the click me, and if I click on it now, I have some text.
OK, so that's exactly what I hoped would happen now that we've done that.
What I want to do next and I'll just hide this.
What I want to do next is update our tests so that I can actually emulate clicking on that button and
check the result right from a test.
You can go.
So to make that happen, what I'm going to do is rather than writing all the code right in our My App
project is welcome back over to my desk file.
So that's in this hilarious project.
It's called dust up, though you might have call it something else, but that's what it is.
We have one function in there right now, and that's just called take screenshot.
Now, any time I'm working with Roard, of course you have to wind up typing all this long text right
here.
So I'm going to make a really simple function just that just fetches a page and returns the appropriate
type.
So I'll call this func with the receiver of C Pointer to celebrities and the name of this, and I'll
capitalize it.
So it's exploded.
I'll just call it the fetch page, and it's going to take nothing more than page URL, which is a string,
and it'll return a pointer to Rod Dot page
and up here where I'm already doing this.
I'll just copy this bit, which takes a page URL.
So everything after the assignment operator, I return that we just say some typing, so that will actually
return a pointer to product page, which we can use in our tests.
And the other thing I'm going to do is write a really simple function folder, see pointer to celebrities,
and I'll call this one select element by ID.
And that will take a page, which is a pointer to Rodarte page as its first parameter.
And then we'll take it, which is a string, and it will return a pointer to a product element.
And this is as simple as saying return.
And this is straight out of the raw documentation, which I'm going to look at in a minute.
Page Dot must element by J.S. Now there's several ways to select things and share a number of ways to
select elements from a given page in run.
But I'm going to use the JavaScript approach because most of you are probably familiar with it.
And what I want to select here is I want to go use JavaScript to say, you know, document don't get
element by ID.
So I'll use the format Esperanto package for function and my format string will be Document Dot, Get
Element by ID. And then in single quotes, I'll put my placeholder percent as.
And then I'll close my parentheses.
And my substitution for that placeholder is I need in that should if I can find it, return that particular
element.
OK, so there's my two helper functions.
And of course, if I was actually going to try to duplicate Laravel Dusk entirely, I would have many,
many more helper elements because at the end of the day, for the most part, that's what dusk does
is it actually wraps other packages and just gives convenience methods to access whatever functions
you're looking for for your given test.
OK.
But we'll just do a few here.
So this is enough to get us started now that these are available in the celebrities package.
Let's go back to Handler's test.
OK, go.
And the first thing I'll do is I'll make sure my test doesn't fail this home test where I'm testing
the home.
So here I'm checking to see if the if I don't find submarine, then fail.
Now Submarine doesn't exist on my homepage.
But if you recall, it says, Go build something awesome.
So I'll just put the word awesome in there and that will solve that problem.
OK, so that test will pass now.
Now I'll write another test.
I'll put it right after the home test funk test clicker with the parameter of T pointer to test inky
and give ourselves some room.
So I'm going to get the roots.
So I'll say roots is assign the value of get roots now in order to test the one that we just created
that slash tester.
Let's go over to our roots file.
And that in our test routes must get tested and its test handlers dot clicker there.
Now it will be available to me because I'm going to need it in a minute.
So back to handlers underscore test.
I've got my roots and let's spin up a Telus server.
So that's as simple as tests is assigned.
The value of the GTB test got new TLC server with roots.
So now I have that and we'll defer to stock closed as we should.
Now I want to fetch that page from that new TLC server I just spun up named piece.
Now that I have that helper function, it's hilarious.
I can see my page is assigned the value of Cell Dot such page and I hand it to us dot URL plus slash
tester.
OK, so that gives me the page.
And now from that page, I actually want to make sure that the first time that pages are displayed,
and if we look at the tester file again, that this output deals the deal with the idea of output that
doesn't have any text OK or doesn't have the text that I knew shouldn't be there.
That's probably a better way to put it.
That means I need to select that element.
So I'll say output element because I want to select that element is going to be assigned the value of
from Cell Dot Select Element by it.
And I hand it my page page, which I just got to the previous line.
And what I'm looking for, I'm looking for the element with the idea of output.
So now I have my output element and I'm also going to, of course, I'm going to have to select the
button because I'm I want to click on it in a minute.
So that button, if you look at the test jet tester jet, while it has the idea of clicker, so I may
as well select that.
So I'll say my button is assigned the value of Cell Dot Select Element by it.
And again, it's page and I'm looking for a clicker.
Now I have both the things that I need.
So first of all, how do I check to see if that particular output element?
Does it contain the text that shouldn't be there?
And it's as simple as this?
First of all, I'll grab the HTML from just that element output element.
If I can do that by saying test HTML and I'll ignore the error, which I probably shouldn't, but I'm
going to.
I just call output element dot HTML built right into that package.
So now I have the HTML from that element.
And I can say if Strings Dot contains and I'm searching test HTML and I'm looking for clicked the button
because if we go back over to tester dot jet, if you look at the JavaScript, when someone clicks on
that button, I put click the button exclamation mark and I can just put a part of that text was sufficient
for my purposes, so I left the exclamation mark out then to error found text that should not be there,
which isn't a great message, but you get the idea you can put whatever you want in there.
So now at that point, if I pass this.
Then I know the first time that pages rendered before anyone clicks on the link, then this is this
is exactly as it should be, that text should not be there.
Now let's click on that button.
And that's as simple as saying Button, which I selected right up there in line four to three must click.
Now I click the button.
OK.
Now, after that happens, I can actually check the new version of the HTML because I'm working with
a pointer to that page and I'm working with a punch of the output element.
So once that button is clicked, the contents of that deal should have changed.
Let's make sure it did test HTML, and I know this is wordy.
I could make this shorter than it is right now, but I want to make it really readable.
Testing test H.M. And again, I'll ignore the error, and this time I use the up the equals operator
again as equal to output element dot html and I just write another test if strings dot contains.
But this time I want to put the nut operator.
So in other words, if it doesn't contain this and again, I'm looking at test html and I'm looking
for clicked the button.
If it's not there, then fail.
So I'll just copy this error message or this.
Error pasted here and say did not find
text that should be there.
So let's run the tests of my terminal.
I'll clear the screen.
Change into the handler's folder and right go test dot.
And all of the tests passed, now, let's make sure it's actually doing what it's supposed to.
Let's change that last comparison this this firm line 52 to 54.
Let's change what it's looking for and change this to say fish.
This time, the Teshie failed.
And there it is.
We got that little handshake warning, and you always get that, just ignore it.
But the test failed as it should have.
Perfect.
So let me change this back.
I'll just undo this.
OK, it's back to where it was before, and I just have a quick look over in my web browser at the kinds
of things you can do here.
So I'll go back to the raw documentation and you'll see here under, for example.
Selectors, you have lots of different ways of selecting things by text content, by experts, by JavaScript,
and that's the one we use.
You can select a list of elements.
You can traverse the tree and on and on it goes.
You also have all kinds of events you can wait for, so you can wait for an event.
You can get the details of an event.
You could handle multiple events, you can look at the list of available events, and there are many
to choose from.
Here's one You'll be using a fair bit input.
You can.
You can use most clicks, which we did.
You can also type text into a form.
You can remove text from a form.
You can do time inputs, checkboxes.
So basically everything you possibly want to use.
As far as I can tell after a quick look at it at all is probably available to you here in the RON package,
and hopefully the couple of things we implemented is enough to point you in the right direction.
It's remarkably easy to use.
All right, let's move on.