So now that we have our token functions set up, let's get started testing, but before we do that,
there's just one thing I'm really not happy with in the authenticate token function found in token.
Don't go in the data directory in the Myat project, and it's just something that's not really clear.
It works just fine.
I think I won't know for sure until I write the tests, but here in line 171, I'm declaring, I'm calling
get my token on the receiver T and storing the value in T, which is our receiver and it works, but
that's inconsistent.
We haven't been doing that sort of thing in any of these functions.
So what I'm going to do instead is call thatcan for token, and I'll copy that and I will put that down
here.
I'll call Tandoh expires, and the rest of that should be fine.
OK.
I'm just a little clean up, and it's not critical, but I like to be consistent whenever I can.
So let's get started writing some tests, and the first thing I'll do is create a file, a new file
in the data directory in my app and I'll call it models underscore test done go.
And I'll give it the package model's
package data actually error and I'll create another file in here.
New file called set up underscore Tesco, and we're not going to do much with that, but we might in
the future, so we may as well set it up right now.
We'll get that it's packaged like a declaration as well.
Now in setup test set up underscore test start go.
I'm going to because we're going to be writing integration tests before too long.
I'm going to put the first line of this file.
I'm going to put a build tag there.
Go build, go colon, build space.
And I call it unit because this will run four unit tests and only four unit tests and four hour integration
test, which will be getting to before too long, will actually have a different build tag for that
will use go build integration.
OK, now this one is dead simple.
We're not going to do anything except have a function called test main as usual, and that will have
as its parameter m a pointer to testing dot m and hopefully that did the import.
For me, it did OK and we'll have to run go on vendor in a minute, but right now, let's get this going
first.
OS x it and we'll call em up.
Run.
OK.
So that's just going to run our tests, but we might need this at some point in the future.
Now I do have an error here.
Can't import this because I need to open my terminal and type go mode vendor.
And that should make that go away.
So let's save this.
That error should go away any time now.
I'll just wait for that to disappear, I'm sure it will before too long.
So let's go to models underscore Tesco, and this one will be pretty simple, too.
We're just going to test the model style, so create function funk.
Test New will test the new function inside of the model's package of the data package, and it takes
one parameter T measure to testing T and in part for testing were tier and it went away in models test
being set up just as well.
So we're so testing it now.
This is really simple.
Now what I want to do, if you look at the new function in models, don't go.
It's pretty simple.
So here's the new function.
It takes one parameter a pointer to SQL DB, and it returns the models, and it makes a decision based
upon the environment.
Variable data database underscore type.
So that's pretty simple.
So let's go back to our models, underscore test and figure out how we're going to call this.
Now here's a situation when I'm running a unit test, I don't really want a live database.
I don't mind a live database for integration tests.
So what I'm going to do is go down to my terminal and import a new package.
So clear the screen and type go get.
And this is from GitHub icon gift hub, dot com slash and then all in all, caps data hyphen dodgy slash
go dash, SQL, MLC, SQL mock.
And this is a really simple package that allows us to mock a database so we can run unit tests without
having a live one.
So I've imported that, and let's go up here and use it, so I'll create a connection pool.
I'll call it fake DB because it is a fake database, and I'll ignore the second parameter and I'll ignore
the third return parameter, and I'll call by a site using the assignment operator SQL Mock Dot New.
And that probably will give me an error until I come down here and say Go mod vendor.
And come back up here and let's just try retyping sequel marked out new and see if it finds it this
time sequel mark.
Try that again, Mark.
Dot.
Hasn't found it yet, but it will eventually.
OK, so we'll just import it manually for now, just to get it working, the computer seems to be running
a bit slower than I.
So we'll wrap that whole thing in parentheses and just import
from here GitHub
dot com slash data Dash Dogs Go Dash sequel mark.
OK, so actually get fixed up at some point in the not too distant future.
I've created this fake DB and of course, I want to defer fake caught up to 50 vehicles.
So let's go down here now and set an environment variable, so ignore the return parameter and say equals
OS dot set on.
And also the database type.
So I'll set database underscore type, which is something that the new function expects to find.
And I'll set it to Postgres
and now I'll create a variable, which I'm going to call em for models.
And that's a sign the value of just new and I'll hand it fictive.
So I have my M variable, and now I'll do an if statement if format sprint s.
And the comparison I'm making here is pretty straightforward one percent to try that again, percent
t the type of M if it's not equal to and it should be equal to data models.
And I have an error tita error and I'll just say wrong type and I'll put in format dot print f if I'm
content, the type that I got, which is percent T.
OK, so there's the first one.
So that test test the first case.
Oh, just duplicate this whole thing and do it for minus two well and just modify it as necessary.
So this becomes an equal operator.
This becomes my ask.
You will.
And everything else should be the same.
OK, so let's try running that, let's type go test, get into the directory CD data go test.
Got.
And it passed.
Let's try coverage, go test, dash, cover dot.
Let's see what percentage of the models we have tested here and is pretty small 2.7 percent and that's
not at all surprising because we're not running any tests at all on token doggo or user account.
And in fact, we're not even testing one more thing that we should be that we can test very easily.
And that's over here.
Get Insert.
So let's try to test for that.
That's pretty simple back in here.
We'll try to function funk test, get insert ID, I.D. And again, it takes one parameter T of a point
or two testing dot.
And this is pretty simple.
I'll create a variable, which I'll call ID of type DB2.
And it should do the import for me here if it doesn't know how to do it manually.
Dot ID.
And it didn't need to be doing bad imports today, so we'll just do that manually.
We'll put it right in here.
DB2 is a reference to her an alias to GitHub dot com slash upper slash db slash v4.
OK.
There that's better.
So now we have our idea of the correct type, and let's just put a value on it is equal to sixty four.
And the value is one.
So we'll just cast that integer to an int sixty four.
And now we'll say returned.
It is assign the value of it.
We'll call get insert ID and hand it.
And I will run a test if format dot print f and then we'll just check the type.
Of percent tea and we put in returned it.
If it's not equal to.
And then Tina Air.
Wrong type returned.
And now we'll say ID equals one, just add it and we'll do exactly the same thing, so I'll copy this,
paste it here and this will handle the other case.
This becomes an equals sign.
Wrong type returned and that's all we really, really have to worry about.
So the first case handles what we get back from Postgres, which is in in sixty four.
And the second case handles what we get back from a b or minus MySchool, and that's just in it.
So now if I come down here and run these tests again and put a dash cover as the flag, which gets slightly
higher, no.
And both tests should pass four point nine percent.
Perfect.
OK, those were the easy tests, and that gives us basically 100 percent coverage of the models.
Don't go file.
Now we need to do the harder ones, the integration tests for tokens, token not go, and users don't
go or user account.
Now those will take a little bit more work because we need to.
As I said a couple of lectures ago, we need to spin up a new container, a Docker image that runs an
empty Postgres database.
Then we populate that database with no table structures.
And then we run our tests, and when we're finished, we get rid of that Docker container.
So it takes a little bit of work, but it's absolutely worth the effort and we'll get started on that
in the next lecture.