OK, let's try writing some integration tests and a word of caution.
It can be irritating to write integration tests that use build tags in visual studio code and only in
visual studio code.
It seems it's much easier in things like go land and other ideas.
But for some reason, Visual Studio code seems to have trouble with autocomplete when I'm using build
text.
But we'll get past this, and it's not that difficult.
So the first thing I'll do, and I mean my app right now is I'll go to the data directory and I'll create
a new file, which I'm going to call integration into.
Gration underscore test.
Don't go OK.
And I'm going to give it its package name, package data, and I'm not going to put the build tag in
there because sometimes when I leave the bill tag out, initially it's actually works better doing autocomplete.
So first thing I'm going to do, I have my package declaration is I'm going to create a variable because
we need to determine what are the values we're going to use.
We're going to pull the Docker image.
It's going to have Postgres, and we need to have some information about how we connect to Postgres.
So I'll create a variable like this host is equal to local host, low goal host, which I have to spell,
right?
Make sure you spell all of these right or you're going to have problems.
The user I'm going to use to connect to the database will just be called Postgres, and the password
will make that just secret.
These are all just strings.
OK.
And the DBI name will, I'm going to call mine Solara toss under test.
It doesn't matter what you call it, because this will be a Docker image that we use to run our tests
and then we get rid of right away.
OK, what port am I going to listen on?
Not post port.
Well, the standard one is five four three two, but I don't want that to conflict if I have my other
developed environment running.
So we'll just use a different port, say, five four three five.
OK.
And then we need a data source name, and this is going to be a format string and we'll populate the
various substitutions for the placeholders a little bit later on.
But we'll build the format string right here.
Host equals with no spaces percent as port equals percent.
As user equals percent as password equals percent S..
And this is the connection string for Postgres, of course.
DB.
Name equals percent as SSL mode equals false, you know, disable falsies for the other database and
will use time zone.
I'll use the same thing I did in my live connection strings.
UTC and Connect underscore time out will be equal to five.
OK.
So there's my variables I'm going to use to connect to the database.
Now, when we run our application or actually when we run our tests, we're going to pull a Docker image.
It's going to have an empty database with no tables or anything in.
It will create the tables which will get to before too long.
And then we'll try inserting a user and it would be convenient to have that user ready to go small created
here via dummy user.
And that's going to be equal to the type user, and I'll just populate the fields I want in there,
just the ones I need.
So I need first name, Colin.
I'll make that song, then a comma last name, and I'll make that guy some guy email and that will be
equal to me.
Not here, Gqom.
Long as it's a value, we'll make the user active one and we'll give them a password, which will make
password like that.
So there there's something I can use to insert into the database.
Now I'm going to create a few variables.
I'm going to need to run this test.
I'm going to need models, obviously of type models, and I'm going to need a test database pool, which
I'll call Ver Test DB.
And it's a type pointer to sequel DB, and hopefully it will do the import.
For me, it did good.
So I'm glad I left that build tag out.
Otherwise I'd be typing blindly and hoping for the best.
Now we're going to need another thing, another resource, and the resource points to our Docker image.
And what I'm going to do is open my terminal window and import a third party package that makes working
with Docker images ever so much easier.
That's a really simple one.
We'll look at the repository in a bit, but right now, let's just import it.
So I'm going to go get it from GitHub dot com slash or y slash Docker test slash V3.
And if there's a later version out, as usual, please stick with V3 for the duration of this course
and feel free to upgrade to a later version at your leisure.
But when you have major version changes, you have breaking changes.
And if you don't stick with me, three probably things won't work the way that they do for me.
It's all important.
I may already have it, but I'll go get it just to be safe.
I already had it, and now I'm going to hit the up arrow and just add slash Docker to the end of this,
OK?
And that goes and gets to things that we absolutely are going to have to have in order to run our tests.
So that goes and gets it.
And there we go.
So now that they're here, I'm going to go ver.
And I'll create a variable called resource, and it's going to be of type a pointer to Docker test right
there, dart.
And the one I want and it looks like it's not going to oh, it did do the option of the autocomplete
for me resource.
OK.
So we need that.
And we also need a database pool, VAR pool.
And this is a pool used by Docker, a pointer to Docker test
dart pool.
Now those are out of the way, so I'm going to hide this terminal window to give myself a little more
room.
And now we're going to have a test main function.
And this is why we're using build tags when you're running tests.
You can't have to test mains and we already have one over here in model or in setup.
Test dog under setup underscore test dog go.
We already have a test me.
And if I have to test means well, no test will run.
Bad things will happen.
That's why we're separating them using build tags so close that let's create a function test me.
And as usual, it has one parameter and I always call it Hammer Point or two testing.
Dot m.
And hopefully it imported testing.
For me, it did good.
Now, when we run these tests, of course, the code we're testing expects to find an environment variable
called database underscore type, and it's either Postgres or PostgreSQL or MariaDB or minus Q up.
So let's set our environment for.
I only care about right now testing Postgres.
OK, so I'll call the OS package and I'll use set on and hopefully it did the import.
For me, it looks like it did.
And I'm going to set the environment variable.
My code expects to have database underscore type two Postgres, which I have to spell, right?
So we've set that variable.
Now I'm going to use my Docker test package to go and get a darker image and run it.
And there's a few steps to make that happen.
Start with I need to create a variable called P, which I'm going to use just for a couple of lines
and we'll check for an error.
And those are assigned values by calling Docker Test Dot New Pool, and it requires one parameter an
endpoint which I'm going to leave empty and empty string will get me past the error.
And we check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then at this point, I really don't want to go any further.
So I'll say log dot fatal f and I'll just say could not connect to Docker.
And this will happen, of course, if the person running the test doesn't actually have Docker installed,
so we'll print the error message.
OK, now that I have a value in P, if I get past this, I'm going to set my package a little variable
pool equal to Pete.
That's the only reason I had a p there because otherwise I get into a whole problem with creating variables
and errors.
This is a simple way of getting past that.
Now, before I run Docker, of course I have to tell Docker test what image I need and what I want to
be in their versions and so forth.
So that's really easy.
You just create some options, which I'll call Ops Opts, and that's a sign the value of the type Docker
test run options right there, and I populate its various fields.
So first of all, what repository?
What image am I getting?
So repository not going to be able to equal to Postgres just like we did in our Docker compose y email
file?
So Postgres, and then we need to know what tag what version of Postgres do we want?
And I'll use the same one I'm using in my my code thirteen point four.
And I also want to set some environment variables, and this will tell Docker test what to use to configure
Postgres.
So these come in the form of a slice of string, and I'm going to put in there, first of all, the
environment variable Postgres underscore user.
And that will be equal to and I'll just use the Cat Nation operator user.
The variable we declared right at the top of this file and then we want Postgres underscore password
and that will be equal to plus password.
And then we want Postgres underscore DB.
What database are we connecting to equal?
And I'll use the plus sign and say DB name house underscore test in my case.
So that's our environment variables, and we'll put the comma it expects to find and we tell it, what
parts should you expose?
When I talk about ports here, I'm talking about the ports inside the Docker image.
So the port I want to expose is exposed ports.
And that again, comes as a slice of strings.
But we're only going to have one so slice of string.
And inside of that, I'll just put the standard port five four, three two, and that's inside the Docker
image.
And now we tell it to bind those ports to ports on my local machine, the host computer port bindings.
And we want that to be in the form of a map with a key of Docker port, and hopefully it'll find that
and the values.
Are a slice of dockworker pork bindings,
Docker pork bindings.
It's not showing an error, so hopefully that'll work.
Port binding, singular and in curly braces, we populated with one value.
Five four three two.
That part in binds to.
And then here I have host IP
0.0 0.0 all IP addresses and then host port is port.
I has to have a code in there
and I put a comma there, so we get rid of any syntax errors and I put a comma here and I put a comma
here.
Now it's not finding Docker.
Why not?
Because it didn't import it up here.
That's no problem.
I'll just duplicate this line and put slash Docker at the end before the closing quote.
And that should make that go away.
Port bindings should be port binding there.
That's much better.
So we have these options now.
We need to tell Docker test to run that resource.
So we'll use our variable resource, which we defined at the top of this file, and we'll check for
an error and we'll call pool the variable that we have declared that we defined on line 45.
So a pool is equal to P, so it comes from Docker test, new pool and we a pool dot run with options
and we handed a reference to ops, which we just defined up there in line 47.
OK.
And we'll check for an error.
So if error is not equal to nil
at that point, what do I want to do?
Well, I actually want to get rid of the the the pool variable, the resource that we actually got there.
I don't want that Docker image hanging around, so I'll ignore the return value, which is just an error
and call pool dot perch and I'm going to purge resource.
So I don't want that hanging around if it didn't work.
And I do want to also print some information out and stop.
So Logcat fatal f and my error will just be could not start resource.
And then the error and I put error in for the substitution.
So that will stop at this point.
It will clean things up and it will stop.
Now here's something to bear in mind.
We are using build tags to separate our unit tests from our integration tests because integration tests
take longer, a lot longer in our case, certainly the first time you run it and they take longer in
our case, because we're starting a Docker image and then we're starting a database, and it doesn't
take long to bring a doctor image.
But when you bring it up and actually has to create the database and start the base and get ready to
listen for connections, and what we need to do is we need to wait until that's ready.
Now we could run the Docker image and start a stopwatch and figure out how long it takes on average
and then make our test wait that many seconds plus, say, 10 percent just to be safe, but that seems
really awkward.
So instead, we're going to take advantage of something that we get as part of this Docker test package
that we import it.
And it's a back off retry function and it allows us to wait until the database is ready and it's pretty
easy to use.
So we use an if statement.
If error is assign, the value of pool has a function called retry it right there and retry takes as
a parameter.
An anonymous function which returns an error in what we put in here is will to define a new variable
error of type error
and we'll say Test DB, which is a variable we defined a while ago and we're looking for an error is
equal to cycle dot open.
So we open a connection to the database and here's where we use that format string called DSM that we
defined a while ago.
So it's a type PBX because we're using Jack C's PBX package, and I would just build our connection
string format Dot s print F. Right there, and we're using the string DSN that we defined at the very
beginning of this file and our substitutions, our host and port and user and password and even.
So we're trying to connect to the database.
OK.
And we checked for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we just return the error.
And here's where the retry thing comes in here.
So at this point, we're going to say return test.
Beekeeping,
so it'll keep going until that pinging of the database works properly after our closing curly bracket
and are closing parentheses.
And we say error is not equal to nil.
And here we want to purge everything out.
So again will ignore the return value and say Pool dot purge the not pulled up, purge the resource
and again printed error message so logged.
Not fatal.
Same as we did before.
And my message here will be could not spell it right.
Could not connect to darker
per se and the error.
So everything stops at that point.
But once we get past this, we're at the point where we can actually do something with the database.
Now this lecture is getting pretty long, so I'll stop it here and pick it up in the next one.
But what we want to do next in our test main is at this point, we've got Docker running.
We've got Postgres running.
It has a database called Celerity House Underscore Test, but it has no tables.
And that's not useful for us.
So our next step is to populate that database with the necessary tables, and we can use that same SQL
file.
I gave you a couple of lectures ago and just run that.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.