So let's keep going.
And right now, we're almost finished our test main function.
But of course, we need to create some tables.
So I'm assuming that and I'm looking right now at integration, underscore Tesco in the function test
main at the very end of this function.
By the time I get here to line 82, I'm going to assume and I think safely that our Docker images started
that Postgres has started and it's ready to accept connections.
So we need to create some tables and of course, we can use that same school.
We use just a couple of lectures ago, but I'm going to put it in its own function funk create tables
just because I can collapse it really easily.
That and it will take one parameter DB a pointer to sequel DB, SQL DB, and it returns potentially
an error.
And it's pretty straightforward.
So I've already copied to my clipboard the contents of that SQL file.
I gave you to download a couple of lectures ago, so a credit variable called for statement and I'll
use back ticks.
And inside of that, I will paste that simple file.
OK, so there's our variable, but of course we need to execute that SQL now.
And it's really simple underscore because I don't care about the return value, but I do care about
the error.
That's a sign the value of DB, the parameter.
We accept it in this function.
Dot exec.
And we're going to exec this TMT and we'll check for an error.
The error is not equal to nil, then return the error, otherwise return nil.
All right.
And I stuck this in its own function, largely because I can now collapse this and make it much smaller.
And of course, you could read that signal from a file if you wanted to, but I don't see any real value
in that.
So now online 81, I can't return and just call error equals, create tables and hand it to DB our connection
pool for our Docker image and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll log dot.
Fatal, if.
Error creating tables and print out the error.
That's near, and it stops at that point because we can't run any tests with our tables.
Now the last thing I'm going to do here is create my mark or assign my model's variable the value of
new test.
I need that to run my tests in the code below.
And I'm also going to create a variable called code, which is the return code we get from calling AMD
run running all our tests.
OK.
And down here, we're going to put something else between these two lines in a bit buffering now I'm
just going to say os x it os x it, that's code.
OK.
So at this point, if I run this, it should pull the Docker image.
Wait for Postgres to be ready.
Execute.
Create tables and create all of our necessary tables.
And life should be good.
So let's come down here after this func create tables and just write a really simple test, one that
we don't even need an integration test for, but one that we can at least run.
Funk Test User Underscore Table.
We're going to call that function that just returns the string users, in my case.
So of course, it takes one parameter t a pointer to testing data.
And all we have to say is s, which is a string is assign the value of models dart users dot table.
And we checked to make sure we get the appropriate value back if SE is not equal to users of the string,
then T2 error and will print out wrong table name return.
Yes.
OK, so now I actually want to try running this test just to make sure everything works the way that
it's supposed to.
So this is the point when I go right back to the top of my file and on the very first line, I put a
comment go call and build integration.
And I'm also going to put a comment here that reminds me how to run these tests.
Run tests with this command and the command is actually go test dot.
Then two hyphens, tags, integration and I'm going to put dash dash count equals one as well, so it
doesn't crash any tests.
So let's give this a try.
I will copy this command.
I will open my terminal window.
I'm going to switch to my Doctor desktop as well just to see what's running right now, so I have no
Docker containers running at all.
So let's come down here to our terminal.
Paste in that command and hey, return and see if everything works the way that we think it's going
to.
And it takes a little while because it's got to pull the Docker image and start the database, but hopefully
this will actually work.
So you can see that I have a Docker container running.
Which is good, and it's Postgres thirteen point four, which is what it's supposed to be.
It rather looks like I made a mistake in that backup function, but I'll give it a few more seconds.
Could not connect to darker reached retry deadline.
OK, so there's something wrong with my retry function or with the way I've populated the information
in my database.
Let's see if we can figure out what's going on.
So my database information is local host Postgres Secret Celebrity has underscore Test fifty four thirty
five and then I have host port user password DB name SSL mode.
The rest of it is just hard coded, so it's only these things and they come in the order of host port,
user password and dinner.
So let's get down here.
Postgres user is user post-cruise, password is password.
Postgres DB is D.B. name.
OK.
I'm exposing Port five, four, three two, and it should bind to host Port Port.
So the options all look OK, let's try to retry code.
Let's just add a log file here.
So Tea Party, log dot, print line your
error and we can at least watch that error message and see if any useful information comes out of that.
So let's go back to DR.
Let's get that container is gone.
Good analyst, tremendous again and watch the longer file.
So this time I'll say go test Dash V and I'll make this bigger so I can actually have room to see any
error messages that come there.
So clear the screen.
Run that command again.
Unknown driver PGS forgotten important.
Well, that makes sense.
OK, so let's stop this.
Hide that.
Go back and kill that Docker image if it's still running, it is kill that and remove it.
I'll go back up to the top where we have our imports.
And of course, this makes perfect sense.
We're testing Postgres and we've imported database SQL.
But at no point did we import the necessary things for Jack C's connection or Jack C's package, so
I'll use the blank identifier and say GitHub.
Dot com slash Jack C slash, and the first one I want is PG Con.
And I'll duplicate that line and get rid of PG Con and put in PG X version for duplicate that line and
add s t d l d to that.
OK, let's try that again.
STD IP.
So I open my terminal window.
Clear the screen and try this one more time.
Cannot find packaged dart in, so I've got a tape of somewhere.
Of course.
As I often do.
Jack, see, Jack, see, see.
Third time's the charm, so clear the terminal and run this again.
Cannot find package in Test August 16.
OK, maybe the fourth time is the charm.
16.
P g con, my typing is very bad today.
One more time.
Clear the screen up and run the tests.
So it should be pulling our darker image right now, and we have run, pass, run, pass, everything
past, OK?
And those messages from Upper are to be expected.
That's just some of their debugging code, and they can be safely ignored.
So our test actually works perfect.
We haven't done anything with the database yet, so let's go down here except create tables.
Let's see if our Docker image is still running.
It is.
So I should be able to connect to this Docker image and have a look at it.
Let's try that.
So open up my client and make sure those tables are actually there and I'll create a new connection
and I'll add a new favorite and I'll call this one test docker and the host is local host.
The port is five four three five.
That's what we specify.
The user name is Postgres, and the password is secret.
And I'll leave the database empty, so let's try connecting to that.
We connected.
Let's see if the celebrities test.
It does exist.
And that should have our tables in it.
And it does.
Perfect.
OK.
So that I know actually works.
Now let's go back here and delete that Docker image entirely.
Remove it.
And at the very end of my test, main function after I declare code, but before I call OS X it, let's
clean up our acreage.
They don't want that running after the test finish.
So we'll put a simple statement here that gets rid of it if error.
And that's a sign of the value from pool.
Don't purge.
And at this point, I want to purge resource.
And as you can see, now that I have mine go build tags at the top, it's not doing autocomplete for
me, but I think we'll be able to manage from this point on.
And error is not equal to nil.
Then I want to log double fatal f could not purge resource and the error per se on the air, and that
should clean up our Docker image, stop it and remove it after we're done running our tests.
So now let's write a real test, a real integration test, something that does more than just call test
user table.
So let's try the insert function.
So I'll recreate a function, and I recall it to test user underscore insert.
And again, it's a test.
So T pointer to testing dot t.
And what I want to do here is to try to insert that dummy user we created in the last lecture, so we
should be getting back an I.D. in the form of an ant.
We should not be getting an error and we're going to call models, dot users dot insert and I'll insert
dummy user logic for an error.
If the error is not equal to nil, then Typekit error.
My error is failed to insert user, followed by the error, and I should also check to make sure that
my I.D. is not equal to zero.
So if ID is equal to zero and something went wrong, we should be getting one back.
Error.
Zero returned as I'd.
After insert.
OK, let's try running that test.
So open my terminal window, clear the screen.
I'll get rid of the V this time because I only want to see if there's an error.
So Dash V is now gone and I'll run that.
And again, it should pull the Docker image.
And this is why we separate integration and unit tests because integration tests can take a while.
There it is.
OK, let's try.
Go test cover, dot tags, integration.
See what our coverage is now.
So we're at ten point eight percent.
We're getting there.
Let's try another test.
So now we've inserted a user, we know at this point that there's a user with an idea of one in the
database.
Let's try getting a user.
So funk test, the user underscore.
Get going again t pointer to testing T, and this was pretty straightforward.
We should be able to say you for user error for error there.
Assign values from models users don't get and I'm getting it and that should be in there.
So if error is not equal to nil, then thedoor error failed to get user error.
And that will make sure that user actually exists.
If you do, it is equal to zero.
If the ID field of the return user model zero, something went wrong.
T2 error ID of returned user is zero and the error, so we'll run that one in a minute.
We may as well just really quickly try to test get all.
And that's pretty much the same.
So I can copy this and modified copy paste and we'll make this get old and we'll get rid of the parameter.
And make that get all.
And all we have to do here is get rid of this.
And if the error is not equal to nil, you ignore the return value, which is checking for an error.
That should run.
So let's try running these tests.
I'll clear the terminal and run.
Go Test Dash cover.
Check our coverage and make sure there's no failures.
So we've gone from ten point eight to twenty one point six.
It's getting better.
Let's keep going.
So let's try getting a user by email, so I'll copy this one and paste it down here, and it's it's
called get by email, and in this point, I want to change this to get by email and that should return,
or it should accept as its parameter and email address.
And we used me out here talking.
OK.
And that should be simple enough.
Let's try running this test.
So we're at twenty one point six a moment ago.
And now we're at twenty eight point six with no failures.
Perfect.
So we've managed to insert a user and to get a user and to get all users.
And of course, we want to test updating a user as well.
And this is a little more code, but not much.
So funk and I will call it test user underscore update and T pointer to testing talked when parentheses,
sir and give yourself some room.
So first of all, we'll get a user.
You and Aaron are assigned the value of models.
Users don't get by ID one if error is not equal to nil.
I'll just copy this one and paste it here.
So now we have a user and we can update the users, so let's change the last name you last name is equal
to Smith.
OK.
It was guy a minute ago and I will say error is equal to Utah update.
And we handed a pointer to you and we paced for error.
Check failed to update user.
And now, just to make sure it actually worked.
Let's go get the user again, so we'll copy this, paste it down here, get rid of the assignment operator.
And failed to get users fine and now was checked to make sure that the last name is actually Smith.
If you don't, last name is not equal to Smith exactly as we typed it above and ticker error and in
here we can just put last name not updated in database.
OK, let's run that test.
So we were at twenty eight point six.
Let's see where we get now and make sure we get everything right.
Thirty one point nine.
We're getting there.
OK, this lecture starting to get a bit long, so we'll pick up pick it up in the next lecture and continue
writing tests for both user and token data models.