So we're coming along, we've managed to test getting a user by ID, getting a user by email, getting
all users, updating a user.
And before we delete a user, which is the next obvious one, we probably should try.
Maybe all that's testing that password matches, so that's pretty easy.
Funk test user underscore password matches.
And that's what the function is called and the parameter T pointer to testing the T, and this one is
pretty simple.
So again, we need to get a user, so we'll just copy this code and paste it here.
And now let's take the variable matches will declare that an error or assign the value of from the variable
you that we just got will call password matches and hand it a string, the correct password.
So this one should return.
OK.
That password matches, so we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil, then teed on error,
error checking match
and the error.
So that's one thing we're checking.
If an error took place took place, but we also need to make sure that the match actually is valid,
so if not, match.
In other words, if we get false back from the function then teed up an error password does not match
when it should.
OK, and now let's say, matches an error.
This time they're equal to you dot password matches and give ourselves some room.
And this time will pass it, say one to three.
That one should return false.
So we'll copy all of this code and just modify copy paste.
And if match password matches
when it should not.
So that was pretty straightforward.
Now let's test resetting the password and then we'll run the test to make sure we have these right.
So func test user and this one is called reset password.
He pointed to testing that to.
And again, we have to actually try resetting a user's password.
And this is as simple as assigning the value error by calling models Dot users dot reset password and
we'll make the password for user one, the only one in the database and we'll make the new password
new underscore password.
It doesn't matter as long as it's different.
So if error is not equal to no,
then teed up error, error resetting password and the error.
And now let's check to see if we get an error, say, for a nonexistent user.
So a copy all of this and paste it in there and get rid of the assignment operator change the one to
two.
And of course, that doesn't exist in our database.
Now we're checking to see if the error is nil.
And of course, there is no error to put the end of this.
Let's change the error message to did not get an error when trying to reset password for non existent
user.
OK, let's run these tests.
So opened my terminal window.
Now, bring it down a little because it doesn't need to be so big anymore.
That's better clear the screen, we're thirty one point nine, the last time we ran it now or what are
we at?
And we have an error undefined match integration test line 256, 256 matches.
OK.
It's matches that match some matches and matches.
I'm sure you noticed that.
I did not.
Let's run it again.
And now we're at 40 percent with no failures.
And that's pretty good.
OK.
But 40 percent isn't high enough, so let's keep going.
So now we can reset the password.
What's next?
Well, now we can actually test deleting a user.
So funk.
Test user underscore delete, delete that user t pointing to alternative testing dot t.
And it's as simple as saying error is a sign the value of models that users don't delete and giving
it the only one and checking for an error.
The error is not equal to nil.
Teto error failed to delete user and the error.
That's all we really have to do for that one, I think.
Except I'm a bit paranoid, so I'm going to check one more thing underscore an error are equal to models
that users don't get, and I'll try to get the user we just deleted.
OK.
And I'll say if error is equal to nil.
And I got that user and that's not good.
Don't error retrieved user who was supposed to be deleted.
OK, let's run that open our terminal clear run.
And we're up to forty two point seven now.
Let's move on to testing tokens.
We got pretty good coverage for users, but we need to work on tokens so funk and we'll test the table
function test token underscore table and that takes one parameter T pointer to testing Doty.
And this is dead simple.
So we scroll up and give ourselves some room once again.
Ask for string is equal to models.
The tokens don't table, and if S is not equal to tokens, then teed up error wrong table name return
for tokens and that's sufficient.
So that was an easy one.
Now let's test generating a token funk test token underscore generate token is the name of the function
T pointer to testing the dirty.
So we need to insert a user because we deleted one.
So it's insert user I.D. an error, our assign the value of models that users don't insert dummy user
put it back like he was before, and his I.D. won't be one anymore.
But that's OK.
If error and I don't know why I have those brace brackets, let's get rid of those.
If error is not equal to nil, then teed off error
error inserting user and the error, I could be using error after, but I've just got in the habit of
typing it this way and it makes no difference.
Now let's get a token so well stored in a variable called token.
We'll look for an error.
Those are both assign the value of models, tokens, DOT and we won't generate token and we need to
have it handed the ID of our newly inserted user, which is probably too.
But I'm not going to assume that from this point on and we'll make it expire.
Give it a duration for expiry of time to our times.
24 times 365.
Make it expire in a year.
And because I don't have that build tag or because I do have that build tag at the top of my file,
I probably need to come up here and insert time.
And yes, I do.
So I'll just insert time and that should take care of that back down to the bottom.
So we have our token.
Let's make sure things went as expected if error is not equal to nil, then teed off error, error generating
token and the error that should be enough for that one.
Let's go on to the next one and we'll look at our code coverage later on in the web browser just to
see how it's going.
So we've generated a token or we know how to generate a token.
So let's try inserting a token because that's its own function func test token.
And we want to test insert key pointer to test inductee.
And let's, first of all, get a user.
This time, I'll get that user by email because I don't want to assume that it's going to be too in
the database you an error or assign the value of models.
Don't users don't get by email and my email I know is me at here dot com, but I can just make it really
simple and say dummy user got the email and that's just cleaner.
OK.
So if error is not equal to nil, then teed up error failed to get user.
So we have a user now, so let's generate a token which I can do right here and copy the same code.
We're testing it twice, but I'm OK with that and paste it right there and scroll up to give ourselves
some room.
Now I have a token, but I can't pass I.D.
Need to pass Yudof, Heidi.
OK.
And now let's try inserting it.
Error equals models.
The tokens don't insert, and that requires.
Our token in the form of a pointer
and our user in the form of a pointer, and we check for our error, so I'll copy this.
Paste it here.
Error inserting token.
OK.
That's probably enough new functions to test.
So let's clear a screen in the terminal and run our test and see what we have.
And we have an error line, 300, line 300.
Where did that come from?
You go.
Try that again.
See if we have any other typos and we do, Token declared, but not used and that is on line three 08
right here.
We don't care about that.
We just want to generate a token.
OK.
Clear that again, third time's the charm.
Not quite.
Line three 08.
I should have seen that.
This is why that build tech problem with integration tests and autocomplete bothers me in visual studio
code, but let's try it one more time.
OK.
Looks like it's running.
Fifty three percent perfect.
We're getting much closer.
OK, let's keep going.
So we've inserted tokens.
What is next, let's say get user for token.
I believe that's the next one in the actual files.
So func test token, get user for token and parameter T pointer to testing to a T in a way we go.
So let's first of all, declare a string variable called token, and we'll make that equal to ABC.
A token I know doesn't exist.
OK.
And now I'll ignore the first return parameter, but pay attention to the error and I will call models
DOT tokens, DOT get user for tokens and I will hand it that string, which I could have hardcoded in
there.
But it doesn't matter.
And I will copy this error message and modify it because we should have an error here.
OK.
So at this point, I want to say if the error is equal to nil and I'll change the error message to.
Say you're expected but not received when getting user by too many spaces are getting the user with
a bed token.
OK, so as our first case next case, let's say let's go get a user by email and I can do that the same
way I did here.
So I'll copy that and paste it here.
I need to get the user in order to get the token.
So now I can say.
Ignore the first or hurt or turn primer.
Do check for an error that's equal to models, don't tokens don't get user for token.
And this time I use a valid token and that comes, of course, in the form of from our user variable,
the token field and plain text.
OK.
And I will copy this.
And this point, I will say, if the error is not equal to nil, then I will say failed to get user
with valid token and print out the error and get rid of that extra quotation mark.
Let's make sure we got that right.
So run our test again.
We were at 53 percent.
Now we're at 60 percent, so we're getting closer.
Now let's try test testing, get tokens for user, which is a function we might never use, but you
never know.
So func test token get tokens for the Capital F user T pointer to testing the T and scroll down and
fix that to a lower case because it bothers me.
This one's dead simple tokens in error or assign the value of models.
DOT tokens get tokens for user.
And in this case, if you look at the function, let's bring it up token and we're looking for get tokens
for user ID.
So let's find get tokens for user.
Really, the only situation I need to test here at the moment, I believe it's just passing an int say
one which doesn't exist.
That should cover most of the cases.
I could be wrong, but we'll find it when we look at our code in the browser.
So let's go back to our integration tests.
Just put a one in there.
That user doesn't exist, but I should be able to say if error is not equal to nil, it should execute
the function.
I'll just say Teagan error error.
OK.
And you can put your own description in there if you want to.
But if I now say if the length of tokens is greater than, say, zero, then I should be able to say
T.
The error tokens returned for
non-existent user.
Let's run that and see what happens.
I could be wrong, and it's almost time to look at our code in a web browser and see what's actually
getting covered anyway.
Sixty three point two.
Now let's actually take the time now to look at our code coverage in a web browser go test dash cover
profile equals coverage dot out.
That's where I'll put my data.
And I'm going to go dot and then Tang's integration, and I should create a coverage dot out file.
And it did OK.
And now I'll say go tool, cover Dash.
Football equals coverage and they should fire up my web browser and show me what's covered and what's
not.
And there it is.
So we have 100 percent under data models don't go, that's good.
Topanga is at forty point six percent.
That's quite a bit so we haven't done the get yet or get token, and we do have good coverage here and
get tokens for user, which is great.
OK.
And the rest of these, very few of them have we done much with what we're getting closer?
If we go back and look at user user Dongo, we actually have pretty good coverage here.
These little cases like this, I don't care about those are edge cases, and I would have to jump through
some rather difficult hoops for almost no reward in order to make those turn green.
But if you want to do that, you go right to town.
I am not a purist.
Let's keep going.
And the only thing we've done here, not covered here is compare, hash and password with some kind
of default error.
Again, that I don't really care about because it's an invalid password is the only one I really do
care about.
I'm pretty sure the compare hash and password in the standard library is a pretty good, pretty well
written function.
OK.
So we're getting good coverage here, but not perfect.
Let's just finish this up, and we might stop here shortly because this lecture is getting rather long
and finish at the next one.
But we can do one more anyway.
So the last one we did was get tokens for user.
Let's try testing to get function funk.
Test token underscore.
And what I want here is just named get T pointer to testing to a T.
So we will say you an error.
Look at a user by email.
OK, I'm going to copy one we've done before right here.
Copy that one and paste it here.
Save some typing and like I said, a user by email.
OK.
And now I should be able to say ignore the first return value, but to pay attention to the error.
Those are equal to models, DOT tokens, DOT get you DOT Token I.D. and we're getting a token by ID
here, something you rarely do, but you might have to get ahead of those price brackets and shouldn't.
So let's check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then to your error
getting token by ID and the error.
So that's that one that was so short.
Let's try testing, get buy tokens or copy this.
Not getting it by ID or getting it by plain text pasted in there.
And I will say this is get.
By token.
OK.
Again, we'll get the user in this time, we'll change it to get by token.
And here it's you token dot plaintext.
I think I have inserted a token by this point, we're about to find out.
So by token, let's try running.
OK.
We'll find out here in a minute.
Up three right there.
Go to cover.
And it passed, so we tested getting an existing token.
Let's try getting one that doesn't exist.
OK, so copy this, paste it here and change this to a token I know doesn't exist in the database.
So say one two three.
It doesn't matter as long as it's not in there.
And if the error is equal to no, that failed error getting nonexistent.
And it should be no error.
So let's try running that again.
Clear the screen.
We're at sixty nine point seven.
Clear the terminal.
Run the test again.
Seventy point three percent.
OK, that's enough for this time around because this lecture is getting fairly long, but hopefully
will finish it up in the next one.