So let's see if we can finish up the last tests for our users in tokens and I'm still in integration,
underscore Tesco in the Miami project, and the next thing we need to test is the actual authenticate
token function, and we want to test this one really carefully.
What we want to test everything carefully.
But this one in particular, because it's authentication.
So I'll create a variable around table test here and I'll call it off data, and it will be equal to
a slice of strokes and four fields I'll have name, which will be a string.
The name of the test doesn't need to column, and I'll have the token.
The token we want to test, which is also a string, and I'll have the email I want to use to look things
up, which will be a string.
And I also want to have error expected.
Are we expecting an error or not?
And that will be a Boolean, and whatever message we want to use for the error should also be a string.
OK.
And now let's populate that slice of structs with some values.
So the first one will be invalid.
That's the name of my test and I'll have a token and it will be exactly the right number of characters
long, which happens to be 26.
So I'll just use the alphabet a b c d e f.
So there's my token and I'll use a nonexistent email adhir dot com, which is not in my database.
I do expect an error and my message will be invalid.
Token accepted as valid and that would be a bad thing.
So you want to avoid that sort of thing and we'll duplicate this line and I'll make this one named invalid
length.
In other words, the token is not there the right length.
All I have to do is either add or subtract a character, so I'll subtract one.
Email doesn't matter.
And here I'll say token of wrong length accepted as valid,
and I'll duplicate this one and move up a little bit to give us some room.
This one will be no user, so I can't find a user.
So it doesn't really matter what the token is, but I'll add the Z so it doesn't catch that error and
adhered Akam and true.
Here I will put in no user, but token accepted as valid.
OK, and we may not use this string, but it doesn't matter.
When we write the test, we'll take care of it.
In the last one is valid and I'll have nothing in the token because I'm going to look it up and here
I will have me at here Accom, which is a valid user and I expect no error faults and the error message,
if any, will be valid token reported as invalid.
OK, so there's my date.
Now let's right to table test func and I'll call this one test token and it is authenticate token.
OK?
Pointer of a T pointer of testing to a T, and we'll run the test.
So we'll say for, I don't know, care about the index, but I'll call my table test tie and that's
from range of data.
So we'll start right away by saying token is going to be a string with nothing in it.
OK, I will say if ttot email is equal to dummy user Typekit email, which is me out here, Ekong,
then we'll look up a user user.
An error are assigned the value of models that get user, which has to have a capital.
G get user by email.
Now get by email.
That's what it's called.
There's no user in there at all.
That's better.
Get my email and we'll put in ttot email.
We'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Always have trouble typing for some reason, and I'm sure you've noticed that T2 error
failed to get user in the error.
OK.
Seemingly a past that we will now say go back up a line token is equal to you u user Typekit token dot
plain text.
OK.
Else, if it's not our dummy user's email, then we'll just say token is equal to Typekit token.
OK, so now we have a token we can use for our test.
So we need to build a request.
So request.
I'll ignore the error because it's a really good package from the standard library and I'll just create
a new request http dot new request.
And when we get a get request with any URL and we're going to pass now for the last parameter now because
we have that whole problem with autocomplete not working, we had better go up and add the HGTV package.
So right about here.
Net slash HD.
Thank you.
And we'll go back down to our function.
The very bottom.
So we have our header.
Let's add an authorization header to it, and that would be Rekt header ad. And we want it to be authorization.
Be careful how you spell that and the value is bearer with a space plus token.
So now we have a request with the correct token, and all we have to do now is ignore the return result.
Check for an error.
That's a sign the value of models, DOT tokens DOT authenticate token with a request.
Now, if we expect an error and the error is nil, if Typekit error expected and error is equal to nil,
then teed up Earth is error off this time I almost never do, and I'll just put it in two format strings
and those will be substituted for Typekit name and Typekit message to display the appropriate error
message.
OK.
Else, if not, ttot error expected.
And air is not equal to nil.
That's our second case.
Then Teodora
percent s.
Percent as.
And then we'll display the error percent s, and for that, we can put dog name Typekit message in the
air.
And finally, we'll just kind of catch all else T dot log f past.
Why not?
And I put two percent s in there and I'll put Typekit name
and that I think should work.
Let's find out.
So let's open our terminal window.
Clear the screen and try running this test.
And we have get by email type models, don't users,
let's try that and see what else there is.
Another one HBP, the new new request.
Where did I get that?
Now look at that new new request.
Try that one more time.
And then we have error expected, which I called her expected.
So let's just change that to error expected.
Try this again.
Clear the screen.
I really miss my auto complete.
And authenticate token with a capital O.
Which is right here.
You can see why I missed my auto complete.
You become very rather dependent upon it over time.
There it seems to have built.
Let's see if we pass our tests.
Good, we're up to seventy seven point eight percent, so that's out of the way, and we'll check it
out in the browser later on, but let's keep going.
So we've authenticated token.
Let's try deleting tokens, funk test tokens underscore delete and for that T pointer to testing Dot
T, obviously.
And let's scroll up.
This one's pretty simple.
We'll get to user user an error or assign the value of models to what users don't get by email.
And I want dummy users email, which will get me the user if error is not equal to nil, then teed up
error, I'll just log the next one.
So now we'll try this leading the token.
Error is equal to models, DOT tokens, DOT delete by token,
and we'll put it in here use token dot plain text and we'll check the error and give it a more meaningful
message.
Error deleting token.
OK, let's just write another one since we're at it anyway.
There aren't too many left.
We need to test for expired tokens, so func test token expired token.
That's why I deleted it, because otherwise we'll be waiting a year before the test can complete.
And that would be bad.
T testing the token, we'd be waiting so long because the expiry was set to a year.
So let's insert a token.
So we'll get our user and I can just copy this information
and paste it in here and scroll up.
Then we'll generate a token token, an error or assign the value of models, stock tokens don't generate
token and what we'll do is generate token that's actually expired.
We can do that user ID and we'll just set the duration to minus timed hour.
So one hour in the past.
So the token is by default, expired as soon as we generated.
So we'll copy this, paste it here
and insert the token.
Error equals models,
DOT tokens, DOT insert and we need to insert our token as a pointer and our user as a pointer and paste
our error.
Check and scroll up a bit.
And now let's generate a request again so I can do the same thing I did up here.
Just copy those request lines right here.
Copy that.
Come down here and we need to make that Typekit token dart or token dart plain text, because that's
what's going to go in the bear header and we'll just move this back over to format it properly and now
ignore the first return parameter check for an error.
Those are equal to models.
Dot token is to authenticate token, and we hand it the request if error is not equal to nil.
Then something went wrong.
Ticker error.
And we'll just say failed to catch expired tofu.
OK, that's enough test to right before we run it again.
So let's run our tests again and we have an error.
44 443.
Not testing token testing, Don T.
OK, let's try that again, dummy user has to be dummy user.
Did I mention that I missed my autocomplete?
Try that again.
Still have a dumb user must have copied and pasted it somewhere I did up here.
Copy and paste is great, except when you copy and paste and paste mistakes, obviously.
Try to get it seems to be running.
And it failed.
What did it feel with?
So failed to catch expired token.
And let's just see what we got here.
Oh, it's if error.
That should be if error is equal to nil.
OK, so it did exactly what I told it, not what I wanted to do one more time.
Because an expired token should return an error.
And that's what we want to check for, the situation will be handed an expired token and no air comes
back.
Very good.
We are up to eighty one point one percent.
But there's still more things to test, for example, and this will be a longer test.
We want the funk test token.
And one of my tests, something is not actually a function, but it's called bad header.
We want to test bed headers going in.
So t point or to testing dot t.
So let's create a request.
I can copy it from here.
And paste it in there, OK?
And what I'm going to do next is just call authenticate token with no authentication header.
And that should generate an error.
So that's equal to models, DOT tokens, DOT Authenticate token, and we'll hand it a request.
So if error is equal to nil, they don't get an error.
Then we managed to get past authentication without even having an authentication header, and that's
bound to error and we'll just say failed to catch missing author
next.
Now, request and an underscore at this time, I don't have to use the assignment operator.
It's equal to http dot.
New request again with yet again to any URL and again with nil.
And now let's add a header.
But this time I'll add a bad authorization header req dot header dot ad and we'll have the correct name
of Thor ization, but we'll just put ABC for the authorization header.
No bearer words, no space and no valid token.
OK.
And we'll copy this and paste it here, and we'll change the message to to bed off header.
OK, now let's add a user and a token.
Let's save the token and then delete the user.
That's a situation that can happen in the real world.
Somebody could have a valid token.
Then the administrator deletes that particular user and we should actually find no user found.
OK, so let's create a new user and I'll scroll up and give us some more screen real estate.
New user is a the value of type user, and we'll just put it in here.
First name will be the last name will be temp last.
It doesn't matter what it is, but I'm still going to try to spell it properly.
First name, last name, email will be you at their economy and active will be equal to one.
We're not doing anything with active, but I put it in the database because it's something people always
need.
Password will be equal to anything.
ABC OK.
So we created a user variable.
Let's insert that user ID and error, or assign the value of models that users don't insert our new
user and we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil, then teed up error.
And I'll just put error like that that's been tested.
So I know it works now will generate a token token, an error or assign the value of models tokens that
generate token.
And I'll give it the ID of our user, which is i d just got back from our insert and we'll make it expire
one hour, one times time dot hour and again we'll check for an error or copy this.
And again, I'm not going to worry too much about the error message because by this point, I've already
passed that test and I'll still see an error if something goes wrong.
And now let's insert the token.
Error equals models DOT tokens.
Here are
tokens DOT insert and we handed a pointer to token and a pointer to new user.
Actually, just new user is enough.
I think we'll find out shortly and I'll paste in my error message and change it to nothing because I've
already inserted tokens, so the error message by itself is probably sufficient.
Now let's delete the user error equals models.
Don't users delete my ID and I'll paste my error message.
And again, I've tested that already, so I'll leave just that as my error notification.
Now, in theory, what I'm expecting to happen and I'm verifying that it happens by writing these tests
is my database has a foreign key relationship with Cascade on update and delete.
So when I delete the user, that token should be gone.
OK?
But we're testing it to make sure that it actually works.
So now let's create our request and header again.
Let's copy these things.
Actually a copy the whole thing.
These lines, because I'm doing pretty much the same thing down here, and I'll just modify it as necessary.
So my authorization, let's make it a correct format bearer space plus token plain text, which I still
have.
I still have it in memory so I can put it there, and that will be a valid token.
And again.
The only thing I need to change here is to fail to catch a token for deleted user.
OK, let's see what we got wrong.
Chances are, since I don't have code completion, there's at least one typo.
But let's find out and we have an error on 479 and 514, and that was our easy 514.
This goes away and 479 right up here that goes away because they're equals not assignments.
OK, let's try that again, though.
Test cover.
And it failed.
Let's find out what it was now.
It's undoubtedly something that's fairly straightforward.
So the air is we're at eighty two point two percent.
Those are just messages from their test token bedhead or failed duplicate key value violates any constraint
tokens, PKI, so that's integration test five 04.
So it is right.
Here so this test starts bad hair, we create a request.
We get that we get our try to attempt to authenticate that token, that one passed.
OK, let's just run that test again.
So I open this up.
I'm going to look at the error message in more detail.
So I'll run this test
and see where the first failure is.
So.
We get a warning there in certain the tokens.
Duplicate key value violates unique constraint tokens, Peki, and what is it trying to insert in there?
It's inserted into the tokens, it's probably the IDs.
So one two three four five, you know what it is?
I bet you anything.
And if I go, look at this sequel, I'm inserting at the top the very top of this file.
I bet you I left amid empty out of one of the tables.
So where is my create table function?
So down here and I call create tables right here, let's look at these descriptions.
So I have that is fine.
And that is fine.
And this is the one, OK, it has a serial.
OK, now let's go look at our token's model here.
At the very beginning, there it is simple.
That's why we write tests.
So this should have karma on it.
Empty.
Now, if I save this and open my terminal and clear the screen and run the tests again, this is why
we write tests.
And it works.
Eighty one point six percent of these situations, or the code is now covered.
OK, well or near the end of this.
Let's just go a little bit further.
So back to my integration test and I'll rehired this function and I'll go to the very bottom and see
what we work on next.
So we did bad header.
Next, I want to check for a non-existent token.
OK.
So func test token.
And I want to test for deleting a non-existent token and T pointer to testing Dottie.
And this is a really an unnecessary test, but I like to get as much coverage as I can if I don't have
to jump through a whole lot of hoops.
So we'll just say error is assigned the value of models, DOT tokens, DOT delete by token, and the
token I'm looking for is ABC.
That doesn't exist.
So we call that and we say if error is not equal to nil, and the only reason I'm doing this is because
it covers an edge case to error error deleting token.
That's an easy one, and I'm going to close the terminal to give myself a little more room.
Here's one that's pretty important func test token.
And then we're testing here the valid token.
OK.
And it takes the parameter T pointer to testing Doherty.
So before we go any further, let's just run our test one more time to make sure that I don't have another
typo somewhere, because that will slow me down a lot.
So what we're going to do in this situation is we're going to get a user, we're going to insert a token
and and then check for the validity of it.
OK, so test passed.
That's good.
So the steps here are pretty straightforward.
Let's get a user by email you and error is high in the value of models.
Don't users don't get by email and I want to get dummy user dot email and I'll check for an error if
error is not equal to nil and I'll just print it out.
T dot error here.
OK now will insert a new token for this user, so will generate a new token and look for an error and
will call models DOT tokens, DOT generate token, gender, generate token and we need to pass it the
user ID
and make it expire at some point in the future.
Twenty four hours should do it 24 times timed out.
And again, copy and paste our error check
and now we'll insert the token error equals models, DOT tokens, DOT insert and we'll hand it our reference
to a new token or a pointer to a new token and a pointer to you, and we'll check for an error.
So we've inserted the token now.
Now we'll check the validity of it.
So, OK, an error are assigned the value of models, DOT tokens, DOT valid token, and we're going
to give it new token dot plaintext.
OK.
Because that's how it looks things up and we'll check for an error.
And what we're looking for here, first of all, if the error is not equal to nil, then we'll just
print out the message error calling valid token plus the error.
So a comma and the next thing we want to check is if it's not OK, if not OK, because this is a valid
token, then we'll say Typekit error invalid token reported as invalid and now we can do almost the
same thing.
Let's copy all of this and paste it here.
And instead of handing it a valid token, we'll send an invalid token ABC and we don't need the assignment
operator.
And we will check for an error, and all we care about here is the OK part.
We want to care if it is OK.
And we're going to change our error message to invalid token reported as valid.
OK, so that's the next case.
And now let's refresh our user just to get the current user from the database.
So we're working with data from the database now instead of data we have in memory.
So you and Eric are equal to.
I can just copy this right here.
Copy and paste it right there.
And now will delete all the tokens for the user error equals models, start tokens, don't delete you
DOT tokens.
You don't token ID.
So it should be gone and I'll copy this error message.
And I know that's been thoroughly tested, so that's enough.
And now let's try checking for a token that we know is gone now.
So, OK, an error or now equal to models Typekit tokens dot valid token.
And from our newly refreshed you variable the token field plain text with a capital T,
and we can probably paste in the same error message right here and not call it a key.
Let's call it OK, so we don't get a compiler error, and we want to make sure that if OK is true,
then we fail because that token should be gone by now to error.
No error reported when validating non existent token.
So that's that situation.
Let's run this test right now just to see if we have any more typos, which seems to be the norm when
I don't have a autocomplete.
And it fails and it fails because.
No matching user found integration test go 569.
Is that the only one?
So we've got a mistake here somewhere.
And it is on five 04.
So let's find one, five four and go see what we got wrong.
Five 04.
Let's just run those tests again and make sure I'm looking at current data, so I'll drag this up a
little bit.
I may have been looking at an old error message.
I don't want to waste time doing that.
So, but lots of spaces here just to make sure I know where is my results actually start and run the
test again.
And I should have a clear indication as to where my error is if it's in my code or in my test.
So it's no matching user found at 569, so I was looking at the wrong spot, so let's hide that and
go to five, 69 five.
69.
Right here.
And of course, it's in my test.
This should be checking for no error.
We're expecting to get an error back.
And we're also expecting OK to be false.
So let's open our terminal window clear screen and run that one more time, and hopefully it will pass
this time.
And it does, and we're up to eighty seven point six percent of statements.
OK.
I believe that concludes all of our tests for both of these models for the moment.
Now we're going to have to go back and add validation at some point, and we'll do that before too long.
But before we close this lecture off, let's make sure that we're have sufficient coverage.
So clear my screen, make sure I'm in the data directory and once again, I will type go test, dash
cover profile equals coverage, dot out and I want to run everything in this directory and I want to
use the tags integration and I should generate my own file.
And of course, it will take just as long to run as a normal test suite.
So seven or eight seconds is seems to be our average these days.
And now we'll run go to cover, and we want HTML and we're getting our data from coverage.
And I should fire up my web browser and open a window.
And we have 100 percent coverage here which we had before, which is good.
So let's go look at a token, don't go, which is what we've been doing most of the work.
So don't care about that edge case or those ones, that's 100 percent coverage.
Forget my token, which is great.
Deleting looks good.
All of this looks pretty good.
All right.
So if user token plain text is equal to nothing, we're not catching that, but we are catching invalid
tokens, which should be exactly the same thing.
And here we didn't get our expires before this in get user for token.
You know, I can live with those two edge cases.
They're trivial.
They're not that difficult to go and implement.
But for now, I think we've got pretty good coverage and we might improve this a little bit later on
when we add a authentication.
But for now, I'm relatively happy.