So before we leave the section on testing our data models behind, there's just a couple of typos that
I had and I'm sure you noticed them and you probably don't have them, but I do.
So I'm looking at integration underscore test.
Don't go inside the data directory in the My App project and add line 478 in my code right here near
the top of Test token bed header.
I misspelled authorization.
And that's not good because it's not going to do the test, and I think it's going to do so.
Let's just fix that one.
And then probably because I copied and pasted it right at the end of this function.
I have the same problem.
And that's a bit of a problem.
Now one other thing I just want to draw to your attention and that's that line five hundred and fifty
two or so and it is right down here.
This isn't the test token invalid token here.
My ID is given me a warning, saying the value of error is never used and in fact, I don't want it
to be used because it's going to throw an error.
All I really care about here is the OK, so I'm going to just ignore that response.
OK.
So now if I opened my terminal window and make sure I'm inside the data directory in my app what I am
and I can run my test coverage in the browser against, so I'll type go test dash cover profile equals
coverage dot out just to generate the data I can use to display it in the web browser.
And that will take just as long to run as our normal test to normal integration tests because it's actually
running, those tests is just saving the output into a file.
And once it finishes, everything passed and you notice these warnings here, it says it's an upper
log level equals warning in effect that in the moment too.
But right now we have our output, so let's type.
So let's clear the screen and type go tool cover dash HTML equals coverage dot out and they should fire
up our web browser and show us the most recent results of our test.
And it does.
So let's go over to authorization.
Are tokens right here and see what we have now?
That's looking pretty good.
It's eighty eight point five percent, so it's more than it was before, and it's looking pretty good.
OK, so that was that.
And of course, these tests can be improved, but we've covered the vast majority of the cases, and
I'll leave it as an exercise to you if you want to make any improvements or changes.
Now the other thing I want to take care of is that warning from upper slash and DB where it gives us
warning logs.
I don't want to turn those off, and I actually went and looked at the source code for this project
for upper slash DB.
And let me show to you over my web browser, so I'm on upper slash and DB on GitHub dot com.
Here's the source code.
And if we scroll down to the longer bit right here.
And we look at this source code.
You'll notice that it has these potential settings log level trace debug info warning, the one I want
is error.
I don't want it to be warm, which is what it defaults to.
OK, so let's go back to our setup integration tests where we set up integration tests, right?
Very tall.
And let's just do what they do so right?
Near the very top.
Here we are.
So we set an environment variable database, which we're using in our code, but it turns out that upper
DV is also using an environment variable, so we'll set it on and then when we want to set is upper
underscore DB underscore log, we want to set it to error, so it'll ignore the warning messages and
that just cleans it up and makes our tests ever so much easier to run.
OK, let's move on.