So in this section of the course, I want to separate API roots from web roots.
In other words, I want to have one file where I put all of the URLs for all.
You can see it right here in our roots file in my app.
All the ones that are just for standard web pages to display a page, to handle a post request, all
that sort of thing.
And then I want to have a separate file for API.
And there's a very specific reason I want to do this.
If you go back to this letter to this project.
And you open up the middleware file middleware doggo, we have this one right here called no serve.
And because we have the no serve middleware enabled by default, what happens is anytime someone makes
a request using post, we look for a cross-site request forgery token.
And that's fine.
Now we do have one line in here CSR of Handler Dot Exempt Glaube, and that will exempt everything from
the API.
And this will work really well.
It will allow us to make sure that anything we want to call and exclude the CSR of token check.
We just prepend slash API slash at the beginning of that route and we'll be fine.
But it might be really helpful just to keep things absolutely clear and separate things up.
Unfortunately, this is really easy to do.
So what I'm going to do is I'll close this letter to this project and I'll create a new file in my app,
a new go file, and I will call it Roots Dash API.
Don't go.
OK.
And in here, I'll put it in a function funk with the receiver of a partnered application, just like
Roots Don't Go has been, I'll call this function API roots and I'll put all of my roots for API in
here and it returns in a sheep dog handler.
And hopefully that'll find it on the import.
It did good.
OK.
And what I'll do is declare a brand new router, and this will be a subreddit that will mount in our
roots file.
So our forever is of Typekit dot new rhetoric and hopefully they'll find it here.
It did good so that imported that for me.
Now I'll create a root root, and I'll match everything that begins with API, and I'll have an inline
function with one parameter mux, which is a Typekit Auchterarder right there.
And in here, I'll put any ruse that I want, so I can just put a comment like this and any API roots
here.
But I want to test it, so I'll put one in our target and I'll just use it in one function.
So it'll be slashed Test Dash API.
So to call this, I would go to local host 4000 slash API slash test Dash API and we'll just do it inline
function here.
Thunk and it'll be Whv beat out response writer as usual and our pointer to HGTV request as usual.
I don't here.
I'll just create a variable VAR payload.
We'll send some JSON back.
It's a struct with one member or one field called content, which is a string.
And in JSON, I'll call that content.
OK, now we have that variable as populate its field payload content is equal to Hello World.
And now I'll just write some Jason to the end user.
I can use my built in function from celebrities to do that.
So the receiver a dot app dot right, Jason.
And that requires the response writer some status code issue status.
OK?
That'll be fine right there.
And the payload, which I call payload.
So now I have this API roots function, which is actually a sub router in order to use it.
I have an error here somewhere.
Oh yeah, I got to return or return or otherwise.
Nothing will happen only when compile.
Now let's get back to our roots file and we just need to mount that route.
So I'll mount it right here.
A Dot app, dot roots, dot mount and I'll Mount Slash API to a Dot API roots and I should do it.
So now if I start my application, make stop in case it's running, make start.
And we go back here to our web browser and we make sure it's working.
It is.
Now we'll go to slash API slash test Dash API, and I should get some JSON back and I do, and that
is dead simple, and it's just an easy way of separating web page routes from API routes, and that's
exactly the sort of thing they do in Laravel.
So that was simple.
Let's move on.