So the next thing I want to look at in our kind of grab bag of miscellaneous application updates is
a function that exists in Laravel, which is kind of useful and it's called maintenance mode.
And right now I'm logged into a server that's running a application.
And if I want to bring the application down, I type up artisan down and that puts it in maintenance
mode and to bring it back up.
Of course, I type partisan up and while it's in maintenance mode, anybody that goes to any page on
the site just gets a page that says this applications in maintenance mode will be back soon and we're
going to do a similar thing in our application.
Now, the way that it works in Laravel is it actually generates a temporary file and there's some middleware
that says every time a request comes in, it looks as if that file exists.
If it does, then the applications in maintenance mode, and if it doesn't, then it's not.
And that's pretty straightforward, and we could do it like that, but we're actually going to take
a slightly different approach.
Instead, we're going to use remote procedure calls in our command line application.
We'll actually make a call to the running application and say either put it in maintenance mode or take
it out of maintenance mode.
So it's pretty straightforward.
Now here in the files alertness, don't go in the celebrity's application.
The very first thing I'll do is I'll come over here and create a variable called meet in this mode and
it'll be a Boolean.
OK, so we've created that variable.
And of course, we actually have to do something with it.
So we need to set up in this Alatas package some code that allows us to use the command line application
to communicate with the running celerity app.
Now we could if we wanted to simply make a route and a handler and make sure it's protected and turn
things on and off that way.
Maintenance mode.
But instead, we're going to use our PC because we've never done that before, and it's kind of useful
and it's not that difficult to implement.
So the first thing I'll do is I'll go to the bottom of this file very bottom and we'll start writing
our code in here, and I'll start by defining a type which I'll call our PC server.
And it's just an empty struct, OK?
And you have to have something like this in order to use our PC and go.
And now I'll develop a function called Frank with a receiver pointer to the type we just created, which
I'll call our a pointer to our PC server and I'll call this maintenance mode.
Make sure you spell maintenance right, and it's going to take two possible parameters in maintenance
mode, which is a bool and the response, which is a pointer to type string.
And you have to use this format and it has to return potentially an error.
And we'll put a simple if statement here, if in maintenance mode, if that's true, then we'll set
our package level variable maintenance mode to true.
And we'll set our pointer to a string a response to server in maintenance mode.
And there has to be an equal sign there, obviously.
Otherwise, if it's false else, then as you might expect, maintenance mode is now equal to faults
and error.
Return value is going to be or a pointer to a string is going to be response equals server alive and
down here.
We'll just return nil.
Now there's no situation where we're not going to return now.
But when you're making functions like this and this is a function that can be called using our PC,
some of them might return errors.
So you have to have the return nil there.
So that's easy enough.
And now here we need to have another function, which has a point or two celebrities and this one is
going to be called Listen, our PC and this will run and listen for our command line application to
send commands merely going to send one potential command.
But of course, you can have more than one.
So.
First of all, we're going to have to have some pork that we have to listen on because we're not going
to be listening on Port 80 or 0.4 for Port 443.
This will be a secret port which lives behind our firewall and can't be accessed from the outside world.
But we need to listen on some kind of port.
So we need some kind of our our PC port to listen to.
So let's make that right now, let's go to our arms in the solicitous application.
And right at the top of this file, where we're listening to a particular port, let's put another value
here.
We'll call this one our C underscore port.
And that's going to be equal to.
I would just think mine one, two, three, four or five.
Because I know nothing is listening on that port.
So there's a part that we're going to actually listen to.
So back in celebrities.
In this function, we need to have access to that variable, our PC underscore port.
Now, if that's not specified, I don't want this particular function to do anything, so I'll say if
nothing specified in or for harpsichord, don't stir.
So we'll say if OAC don't get on and the key and looking for is our PC port, if that's equal to an
empty string, which is what it'll be if nothing is specified and do nothing, actually listen to it
this way.
If it's not equal to nothing, that's clear.
If it's not equal to nothing, then let's print it a message.
So we'll say see dot info log dot print line that again info logged on print line
starting our PC server on port and then off start.
Get on our PC port, so we'll just print a little message.
Then we need to use the built in package, our P.S., and register our type, our PC server.
And that's pretty simple.
We checked for an error and we'll call our PC dot.
And we want to register.
We want to register a new PC that, again, our PC server.
And if error is not equal to nil,
then we'll print it out, say, see that error log dot print line error and will return.
We can't go any further.
Now we need to start listening on that port that we specified in our door on file, so I'll create a
variable called listen and I'll check for an error when I call from the net package built into the standard
library dot.
Listen, and we're going to listen using TCP and our address will be the local host 127.0.0.1 colon
plus OST.
Get on our PC port.
And again, we'll check for an error, so I'll copy all of this error checking logic.
And paste it in here.
And now we want this function to go forever, so we'll use a for loop for an inside of this, we'll
say our PC can choose the variable.
I'm declaring an error are assigned the value.
Oh, listen, dot except.
I will check for an error if error is not equal to nil, that in this case, I don't want to stop.
I want to continue.
OK.
And now?
We use the go keyword to run this in the background as a good routine.
Our dart serve com.
And we're going to pass it on.
And that literally should be all we have to do in the celebrity file itself.
Scope.
Now we're going to need to add some middleware that will do certain things if maintenance mode is set
to true, but we'll take care of that in the next lecture.
And of course, we'll also have to make some changes to our command line application.
We'll take care of that before too long.
But that's enough for this time around.
Let's move on.