So before we go too much further, let's make sure everything works.
Now here and celebrities don't go.
We have this function.
Listen, APC, but at no point do we call it so we're not actually starting our listening on the PC
port and we can fix that.
Let's go up to the function, listen and serve, which is right here.
OK, so listen and serve.
And down here at Line 286 in my code are simply type.
Go see dot.
Listen, APC, OK, and that will start it in the background.
Now open my terminal and Typekit make start, and I should see that message saying it's listening on
port one, two, three, four or five, and I do.
So that's great.
So in the next lecture, we'll get started on the middleware and make sure that when the package level
variable maintenance mode is true, that we give a an appropriate message to the user saying the is
currently in maintenance mode, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.