So this time around, we want to write some middleware that will check for maintenance mode, and of
course, we're not going to do that middleware here in my app project.
Instead, we'll use the middleware file inside the Solaris House project, so let's open that up.
Now this, of course, is in package celebrities, so that package level variable maintenance mode is
available to us for any handler we write or any middleware we write in this file.
So let's write one, write a function and it will be middleware with the receiver.
See Pointer to celebrities and we'll call it check for maintenance mode.
And because it's middleware, it'll take next HGTV dot handler as its function, and it will return
an HGTV dog handler.
And what I'm going to do here is return an HTP dog handler, funk handler, funk, make sure you get
the right one and it will have an inline function funk with W issue top up response writer and are a
pointer to your request HTP.
Don't request.
I find that really difficult to say for some reason.
And inside of that function, we'll just say if maintenance mode.
So if that's true, then we want to actually return an HMO file.
Now, if you look at the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a zip file called maintenance
dot html zip.
And what you're going to want to do is download that file and put it inside the public folder in my
app.
So inside a public, I'll create a new file.
A new file not to go file and I'll call it maintenance tried to spell right maintenance, not HTML.
I spelled that right.
And you can put whatever you want in there.
But if you download the file that I put on the course resources, it looks like this.
It's a very simple message that just says under maintenance.
Check back in a few minutes and gives you a link to click on to try things.
So make sure that's in public HTML in your My App project.
So we have this if statement and we'll say, if not because I want to make sure that the only page they
can see and I better still maintenance right here.
Main Amy in maintenance note that's better, if not Strings Dot contains.
We'll just use the strings package to see if the ardoin URL path.
That's what we're looking at.
If that does not contain slash public slash maintenance dot HTML.
So if they're trying to hit anything other than that page, we're going to send this back.
W Dot right header will set a header first of all, and we'll set it to 8TB Dot status.
Say service unavailable.
That seems like a good one.
And then we'll w dot header dot set, as you're supposed to do when you have this and we'll put in retry
dash after with a colon and we'll put 300 seconds.
So check after five minutes.
And I will say, said another header cash control w dot header that said and will set cash control.
And we'll set that to no Dash store, no Dash cash, all the ones that say, just don't keep a copy
of this must revalidate, validate, post-test check.
But to put this in the right spot, post-test check equals zero and predict check equals zero.
And that will just force the browser not to keep a copy of this page and then will serve that file public
HDMI out for maintenance studies.
HTML.
So HTP serve file.
We want to serve server with our and we want to put in.
We use the format as print printouts to build a string for my string will be present as slash public
slash maintenance HTML.
Make sure you spell it right and our substitution for that will be set off route path, the path to
our application to the Maya, and we'll just return at this point.
We don't want to go any further.
Otherwise, down here next, don't serve HDB opener, so that should be the necessary middleware.
But of course, we want to add that middleware to our middleware middleware chain.
And again, we're not going to do that in my app.
We'll do it up here in the Roots file.
We'll just say, must start use, see dot check for maintenance mode.
There.
Now, if everything went according to plan, I should be able to go over to celebrities ago and in the
listing and serve function right here, I can just say maintenance mode equals true.
Set that package level variable.
So now if I come down here and say make stop and make start.
So it's running now, she'd be able to go to my web browser and try going to localhost four thousand
and I get my maintenance mode message perfect.
Now, if I go back to my celebrity's package and get rid of this line, just comment it out.
Restart the application.
Make restart.
And of course, what I'm doing here is simulating sending a command from the command line application.
Now, when I go back to my web browser and reload the page, I should get my application and I do.
Perfect.
So the next step is to go to our command line application and add the functionality to talk to the PC
port, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.