So now that we have the server a bit finished, it's time to implement the client application and of
course, we're going to do that in our command line application stored in the Solaire Trust project
in CMD Seelye and we'll start with may not go.
And what we want to put in here, of course, is the ability to handle something like Solaris toss up
to bring the server out of maintenance mode, ancillary tasks down to put it in maintenance mode.
So I'll do what I've done before right here in the function main right in the Switch statement after
the first case help, I'll put a case up and I'll call a function that doesn't exist yet, and I'll
call it our PC client.
And because this is going to be calling the server and saying, take it out of maintenance mode, we
want the parameter for our client to be false.
In other words, is not in maintenance mode, and we'll also have a case down and then we'll also call
our client.
This time will find it true.
Now, of course, we need to define this function RPG client.
So I'll do that by creating a new file in Seelye and I'll call it our pickup, which seems appropriate.
So let's define the function funk, our PC client.
And it takes one parameter in maintenance mode and it's a Boolean, and it doesn't return anything.
So the first thing I need to do is to actually call the method dial from the built in package or PC
that's part of the standard library and get a client.
So see for client and we'll check for an error when we call our PC.
Dial right there in our transport will be TCP and we're going to call one two seven zero zero one colon
plus and I need their PC port.
So why don't I just store that in a variable?
Right now, our PC port is assigned the value of Dot get on.
And we're looking for the key.
Our PC port and now down here, I can just put our PC port.
Of course, I could have made this.
The OS don't get on, but I think this is more readable.
So we'll check for error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll just exit gracefully with the error.
But assuming we are past that, then let's just prints a message out to the user.
Format dot print line connected dot dot dot.
Now, this is the part where we're going to use that client, see, we just created on the line 11 and
we're actually going to call a function that's registered in our PC server.
And that's really straightforward.
So we'll check for an error and we'll use Seacole, a method built right into that variable.
And the way that this works is we're going to pass the first parameter as a string and we're going to
use the type we registered with our server, which was type our server dot.
Whatever method we want to call, there's only one maintenance mode and behind the scenes go, we'll
use reflection to get the appropriate method and call it.
Then we pass it.
The one parameter requires in maintenance mode that will be either true or false.
Depending how this is called, then we're going to store the results.
Now that comes as a pointer to a string, so let's go up here and create a variable for result, and
that's going to be a string.
And now down here, we can actually read the results from that call into results and we'll check for
an error.
So I'll copy this error checking code and paste it here.
And if we get past that, we'll just print out the result.
Color yellow just to make it look nice result.
And in theory, that should be everything we have to do.
And as you can see, our PC is actually pretty simple to use and it's very, very useful.
OK?
In the next lecture, we'll try this out.
But before we do that, let's just make one last change.
Let's go back to Mango.
And find the help function right here, show help.
Let's update that.
So right here, I'll just put it up.
Take the server out of maintenance mode, and before that will put it down.
Put the server into maintenance mode.
So in the next lecture, we'll give this a try.