So let's give this a try and see if our maintenance mode functionality works as expected.
So I have a terminal window open and I'm in the solicitor's project and I want to build the new executable
and copy it over to my app.
So make build underscore seal.
And there it's built the executable.
Now I'll go over to another terminal in the My App folder and make sure my application is running.
Make start.
There, so it's now listening and running, so I should be able to go to my web browser and I'm already
on this page.
Let's reload it and make sure it works.
It does.
Now let's go back to our terminal in the Miami project and Typekit slash salaries horse.
And of course, for Windows users, there's a Z at the end and that's all you need to use.
And we'll put down and actually put it in maintenance mode.
Well, we got the right response back from our PC, so that's good.
Let's go see if it worked and we'll reload this and it's in maintenance mode.
And now I can go back to my terminal and Typekit slash Celerio toss up and it should be live.
So I should be able to click on this or refresh the page and everything works as expected.
Now there are some enhancements we could make to this, and I'm not going to do it, but I'll talk about
them a little bit if we go back to our code right now.
If the servers in maintenance mode, it doesn't matter where I go.
I'll always get that maintenance mode message.
But there may be situations where you want certain functionality to still be active and available,
for example, perhaps a login screen or any URL that begins with slash admin or something like that.
Well, we've actually fixed that, and we could make that something that's actually editable by the
user.
So if we went back to our code and say in the dart on file in my app, we put something like this.
And as I said, I'm not actually going to do this, but I might be able to.
I could put something like this allowed the URLs equals.
And then as a string, I could put slash log in comma slash admin and whatever else you want to do anything
separated by commas.
Well, if you recall over here in middleware, in the celebrities project, which is right here, we're
actually doing a check here in the check for maintenance, for middleware.
We're actually saying, if not, strings contains the URL path, which is whatever the user is trying
to get to and then something that's permitted.
OK, we could actually read that string allowed URLs from dart ons when celerity starts up store, that
is a slice of strings.
And then just make sure that in this if statement, if we can check for anything that's in that slice
of strings and actually if it's not slash public slash maintenance dot html, but it isn't allowed URL,
we can allow an allowed path.
Then we had a permit that page to be displayed.
So what that would allow us to do, for example, is something like any page on the site.
That's a public page will display the servers in maintenance mode message unless it's one of the allowed
URLs.
So, for example, if you had all of your admin functionality for a certain web application stored in
you URLs to begin with slash admin, then you could put the public site into maintenance mode, but
still do some maintenance in the admin back end.
And that's an exercise I'll leave to you if you so desire.
All right.
Time to move on.