So things look pretty good so far, we can start our application, we can sign in using social authentication,
we can do all sorts of things.
But one thing we haven't taken into account is stopping the application right now when we stop our application.
If I type make stop at the command line, for example, it just stops.
It doesn't matter what's going on, it just stops.
And in a lot of cases, that's not a good thing.
You may want to take your your application off line for some reason, but you probably don't want to
interrupt things like mail that's about to be sent, but never gets sent because the application stops
and forgets about it.
So what I want to focus on for the next little while is graceful shutdown, giving our developers the
option of having certain tasks execute when the application receives some kind of signal to say, stop
running and we're going to do that by working on this function in celebrities don't go called listen
and serve.
And right now, all this does is it defines a server.
It defers some clothes.
It starts, are R.P. solicitor.
And then it starts the web application, listening for requests.
And that works really well.
But we're going to make it a little bit better.
I'm going to do that by, first of all, going into the Celebrity House project at the root level and
creating a new file, a new go file, which I'll call Server Go.
And here is where I'm going to have my new version of the listing and serve function, so I'll define
a function.
I shall just copy this to make it a little simpler.
Copy this.
I'll copy the whole function.
Comment it out.
Go back to server, doggo and paste that in there.
OK.
And it didn't do the imports for me, but that's no problem.
HTP Dot server and then clean this bit out and that'll take care of that.
So to start with, I'll have this return an error potentially error.
And down here, instead of doing this, I'll just changes to a return statement.
OK, so now it's off in its own file, and I can get rid of this comment I don't want.
And that's just to make things a little bit cleaner.
OK.
So we have this function and means I can go back here and delete this, and that just makes that file
a little bit smaller.
OK.
So so far, so good, but nothing interesting has happened yet.
All I've done is move one function from one place to another and have it return a potential error.
So now the next changes I want to make are actually going to be in the Myat project.
But what I'm going to do is open up Maine and go right here and I'm going to put a couple of additional
functions here.
OK, I'll have a function called, say, while the receiver of a pointer to application, and I'm going
to call this one shut down and it doesn't return anything.
OK?
And I'll have another function.
Also, with the receiver, a pointer to application and I'm going to call this one.
Listen for shut down.
And here's what we're going to listen for anything that might stop our application from running, and
we're going to do that by creating a channel and having that channel listen for.
Interrupts to kind of interrupts a seguinte and a second term.
A SIG interrupt and a SIG terminate.
Those are signals.
OK.
There are a bunch of signals that exist in most operating systems and some we can catch and the two
are interested in in this case are significant and SIG term.
So let's make the listen for shutdown function, which is assigned the value of make a channel and the
channel is a type of sports signal right there.
And one that's that's how big the channel is.
OK, and now we're going to use the signal package built into the standard library signal dot notify
and for parameters.
The first one is the channel quit, and the second and third are what we're going to listen for.
We're going to listen for Cisco built into the standard library dot SIG int right there.
And we're also going to listen for Cisco Dot SIG term, and that will send the appropriate signals to
that channel quick.
And now we just wait for that to receive something as is assigned the value of whatever comes from quit.
OK.
And now just so we can see what's going to take place here.
Let's right to the info log a dot that info log right there.
Dot print line.
I'll just say received signal and whatever the signal is that start string.
OK, and then I'll call the shut down function eight off down the one up there that doesn't do anything
in the moment, and that's fine.
It exists.
And then I'll fix at how I start it with the status code of zero.
OK, now this function listen for shutdown is here, but it's actually not being yet.
So what I'm going to do is here.
After I finished the application and before I call, listen and serve, I'll simply say, Go see Dot.
Listen for shutdown now since listen and serve returns an error.
Let's try out for that just to avoid the warnings in our I.D. and we'll print out whatever error we
get.
See the app in full of the print line.
We'll make the analog analog dot print line, whatever the error.
OK.
OK, now this doesn't really seem to do anything at the moment, but let's try our application.
Let's run it.
So make start.
There it started and listening.
Now a clear the screen and type make stop.
And you can see the received signal terminated, so it's doing what it's supposed to do when the application
stops before it actually exits.
It actually prints out this message and we're also calling a shutdown, which means up here in this
empty function, we can say, put any cleanup tasks here.
And if you want to make sure that things actually finish before you exit the application, you can do
something as simple as this.
In our application struct, we can put a variable called W.G. for weight group of type s'inquiete group.
And then down here, all we have to do is say AWG, don't wait.
So for example, if you're sending email in your application, you might every time you send a message
out.
Add something to the wait group.
And once it's finished sending you just say, Wait, W.G. done, and that would decremental.
So this AWG, don't wait.
This will block until the wait group is empty.
And just to avoid the irritating warnings will make it this way way through.
So that's a pretty simple way of giving our developers people using celerity as a means of putting cleanup
tasks things that have to finish or should take place before the application completely shuts down.
And that's pretty simple.