So this time around, we want to implement the same sort of thing that we did with Mineo and that is
connecting to an AWB bucket compatible server.
But this time we want to use Amazon's actual libraries because a lot of people will find themselves
in situations where they're working for an employer and that employer says, no, you're going to connect
two buckets using Amazon code.
So let's get started.
I'll open my terminal and I'll make sure I'm inside the celebrity's project folder, and I will, first
of all, go get the things we have to get.
So there's the first one.
Go get GitHub dot com slash IWC slash IWC Dash SDK, dot go slash NWS.
So I already have that one installed, I think.
Yes.
But now I want to do the same thing and put some credentials after it.
OK, so it's got those and now let's open up the file S3 don't go from inside the ESSARY File Systems
folder inside the file system folder inside celebrities.
OK.
And I want to do the same sort of thing I've done before.
I'm going to start.
I mean, hide the terminal window.
I'm going to start by creating a function to get credentials.
Func with Receiver s pointer to S3 three.
And I'm going to call this.
Get credentials,
and that's going to return one type, and let's hope that my I.D. finds it for me.
Sometimes it has trouble finding things from Amazon credentials.
Dot credentials right there.
So I did the import for me, but it did the wrong one.
It chose Mineo and that's not what I want.
So I'll delete all of this and replace the middle part with a s slash NWS Dash SDK, Dash Go slash IWC
slash credentials there.
So make sure you get the right import because my I.D. defaulted to the Mineo one for some reason.
OK, so that's what this is going to return now.
I'm going to get all of the necessary credentials right from my receiver, so I'll create a variable
called see, which is credentials and that's assigned the value of credentials dot new static credentials
like that.
And that requires the ID, which is actually the key in our case, ASCII, and it also requires a secret
escort secret.
And the third one is a token.
We're not using tokens, but that's where you put it if you're using a token.
OK, so that gives me my client and I will return.
That returns.
So now we have a means of getting Amazon credentials, and as you can see, that part is pretty straightforward.
It only took one line to get a client, but just word of warning.
Most of the functions we're going to be writing will take far more code than the equivalent functions
in SFP or Mineo or WebDAV.
For some reason, Amazon's code tends to be a bit longer, but it's not that difficult.
So we'll start with the list function.
OK, we may as well start with that one.
And it requires just a prefix.
OK.
So we're going to start pretty much the same as we did before by getting some credentials.
So down on my list function after my VAR listing.
Let me get client.
So I'll call this one see, and it will be assigned the value of s get credentials.
OK.
So that's my client.
I call it.
See, this time I'm not sure why.
Now, Amazon expects me to start something called a session, which I'll call CSC now.
This is not the same as the session we're using for web applications.
This is an Amazon session.
OK.
And for that, we're going to call Session Dot must.
And we'll see if it did.
For me, it did good.
Let's make sure it did the right session.
It did a WC session.
So Session Dot must and then it's parameter is going to be a variable of the type session dot new session.
Straight out of Amazon's own new session and it requires a config and it requires a reference to an
eight of you asked dot config.
OK.
And we'll fill in.
It's necessary fields.
So for our purposes, we need to specify an endpoint, which will be a and it has to be given as a pointer.
So we'll use a reference to from our receiver s dot endpoint.
And it requires a region and again a reference to our Pointer R Receiver s dot region.
And it also requires the credentials which in this case is a C.
It's not really a client so much as it is a credentials object, but in any case, there it is.
So we defined our session.
Now what are we going to do with it?
Well, we're now going to create what Amazon calls a service, so I'll create a variable called SBC
for service and that's assigned the value of S3.
That's lowercase s three dot new.
And that requires a session, that's SS.
And let's see if it did the correct import for me.
It did good.
And now we need to provide a variable called input.
I'm going to call my input and it needs to be of the type a reference to the three dot list object object's
input right there.
And that requires a bucket.
We know what that is.
That will be typically you, would you say it's a string from a receiver s bucket, but Amazon being
Amazon, we have to do things their way.
It was not straight and we give that escort bucket.
OK.
Amazon wants thing in the wrong format for some reason, and our prefix will be s dot string, and that
will be the parameter prefix that was handed to this function prefix.
So now we have a service and we have an input and we have a session and we have our credentials.
And finally, we can say.
Get a result while checking for an error by calling SBC Dot List objects.
And that requires our input.
OK, now we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And this is slightly different than the kind of logic we've done before because we want to check to
start with what kind of error do we have?
So.
Is it an error?
That's an Amazon error, or is it some other kind of error?
OK, so I'll just do an statement if I'm going to store this in a variable called a e r for Amazon error.
And OK, and those are assigned values by calling Error Dot, cast it to an NWS r error.
There it is.
And OK.
So if we have this kind of casting taking place will switch on the air code.
And this is sample code taken straight from Amazon's documentation air dot code right there.
We're switching on that.
So the first case will be is this an S3 dot error code?
No such bucket code, no such bucket.
Okay, if that's the case, let's just print out that error format or print line.
And we'll print out as dot error code, no such bucket, and we'll actually print out the error as well.
Our dart error.
OK, so that's our first case and the default case.
If it's not that, then we'll just print out the error format dot print line.
We are taught error.
OK, so that's our instinct now if OK is not true.
Else?
And we'll just print out the error, so I'll copy this one.
Say some typing, paste it in here
and print out e are not error.
And then at the end of this, I'll return nil and I'll actually return the error as well.
OK?
Something went wrong.
So that's our first big check.
We're getting that result.
Now that we have the result, we can actually populate the variable listing.
Sit down here, let's give ourselves a couple of lines and scroll up a bit.
So let's range through our result for four.
Don't care about the index.
Do care about the key is assigned the value of ranging through result dot contents.
That's the part we can iterate through.
So let's calculate some sizes like we did before.
Bytes is equal to float 64, and I'm going to get a pointer to key dot size.
OK, and now we'll get the killer kilobytes KB is of the value of bytes divided by a thousand twenty
four and megabytes is assigned the value of kilobytes divided by a thousand twenty four.
And finally, let's create a variable.
Current or current iteration is equal to file systems dot listing and populate its fields.
So in this case, we do in fact have the E tag, which we haven't used yet.
We might have used it in many, many.
Oh, I can't remember, but we're going to use it here.
OK, so the tag, which is specific to the current item in the bucket, and that's a pointer to key
E-Tech and we want last modified, which is going to be equal to a pointer to key to last modified.
And we want the key, which is the file name, which is a pointer to key dart key, and it could have
called this item.
And finally, size, which is megabyte.
And then we spend our listing, are we a current to listing listing as equal to append listing and Kirk?
OK.
And then down here I return listing and nil.
And that there's a lot more code than the Mineo equivalent, but it's the Amazon way of doing things.
All right.
We'll move on to the next method in the next lecture.