So this time around, we want to implement the put function for our S3 bucket file system.
And obviously that's done here in the S3 go file in this stub function put.
Now what we're going to have to do, first of all, is the same thing we did in list and that is to
get some credentials and create a session.
So I'll copy this code to say some typing and paste it here before the return statement.
So at this point, I have some credentials.
I've created a session and now I need to create a new uploader, an Amazon S3 uploader, and I'll call
my variable uploader, which seems appropriate.
And that's a sign of the value of calling S3 manager, which should show up.
It did start new uploader, and I just handed my session.
OK, so there's my uploader.
Now I'll open the file system that I received or open the file that I received as a as the first parameter
to this function file name being a the full path name to the file that I want to upload as three.
So I'll open the file, which I'll call F and I'll check for an error when I call OAC.
Don't open.
Violent, and if I have an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll just return the error.
OK, so we have our file opened.
Scroll up a bit.
Next, I want to defer closing it, defer if close, just to say some resource leaks or avoid resource
leaks.
Now I'm going to get the size of this file, which is something that we're going to be using here in
a moment when we create a buffer.
So I'll call the variable file info and I'll check for an error.
Those come from folks that built right into it.
OK?
And again, checked for an error.
So I'll copy this code.
If we can't open the file, we can't upload it.
We may as well just return the error.
And I'll create a variable size versus and that's going to be equal to file info dot size.
And that gives me an N64.
OK, so now that we have the file open and I know how big it is, let's create a buffer because this
is what our uploader wants.
Buffer is a sign of the value of make, and I'm going to make a slice of bytes of size size.
OK.
And I will read that buffer.
So if don't read, which actually returns two things.
After Reid offered let's see what Reid returns.
Reid returns an inch, which I don't care about and an error which I do, so I'll ignore the first return
value but do check for an error.
And then after I do my read, I will check for the error.
OK, now two more variables file bytes.
Is a sign the value of bytes Typekit new reader right there, and I'm going to read Buffer.
And file type, which I also need to know, and from this, we can use the HGTV HTP package that's hard
to say, don't detect content type and I'm detecting the type of buffer and that should give me the
file type.
And if HDTV detect content type can't figure it out, it just uses octet stream, which is fine for
our purposes.
OK.
Now we actually do the upload, so I'm going to ignore the first return value, but I will check for
an error when I call from the variable uploader that we created right up there in Line 38 upload or
upload.
And that requires, as its first parameter is only parameter, the S3 manager.
So we use in reference to because it has to be a pointer S3 manager right there.
Dot upload input.
And that requires a bunch of information.
The first thing is a bucket bucket and that we get from our receiver, but we have to convert it to
a W.S. dart string and we hand it bucket.
So that's our first field.
The second field is the key, and this needs to be in a particular format.
OK, so eight of us string again, that's the format, and I need to write the full path of what I want,
where I want to put this on the remote file system on my S3 bucket.
So I use Format Desperados
and my format string will just be percent s slash percent s again percent s.
And the substitutions for those two placeholders are the folder which I received as a parameter in the
call to this function.
And then we need the file name, which we'll just use our standard path dot base and we'll use file
name and that gives me just the file name.
OK, so that's our second field.
Our third field is what's the body of this upload?
And in this case, it's just a file bytes.
Then what's the access control string ACL?
And for my purposes, I want to put this so it's publically readable A.W. Stream and I'll call it public.
Oops that are put it in a string public dash.
Read so people can read it, but they can't change it.
And that's perfect for my purposes.
What is the content type?
Well, we got that just a minute ago content type right there.
That is again.
And they tell us not string.
And the parameter for that is just file type, which we got what we called HTP detect content type.
And finally, what's the metadata which isn't actually critical, but I'm going to put it in there.
OK?
Map string pointer to string.
An unpopular one value in there, so I'll put it in key.
And that's just going to be A.W. escort string metadata value.
Now, the only reason I put that in there is if you will look at the sample code from Amazon's documentation.
You'll see that you can actually include extra mated metadata with your upload.
But I'll just put that in as an example as a placeholder, and it won't hurt a thing by being there.
So we check for an error if error is not equal to nil and we'll return the error.
Otherwise, we're actually done.
So that should be unless there's some typos in there, a functional put function.
So now we need to move on to the next one.
And if we scroll down, the next one will do is the delete function right here on Line 126 in my code.
All right, we'll do that in the next lecture.