So we have two more functions to complete to finish off our SE three file system and the one we're going
to do this time around is delete right here.
And as usual, with Amazon code or code for Amazon, it's going to take a lot more lines of code to
do this than it did with our other file systems.
But the first thing we need to do is to get our credentials and create a session.
So I'll copy this code from the list function and go back down to my delete function and paste it here
before the return statement.
OK.
So we have our credentials.
We've created a session.
The next thing we need to do is to create a service just like we did when listing files.
HSBC is assigned the value of from the S3 package, not new, and we're going to pass it session, which
I have to spell, right?
OK, so now we have a service.
The next thing we'll do is range through that parameter that we receive a slice of strings listing the
files we want to get rid of, so we'll save for and we don't care about the index, but we do care about
the current item, which I'll call Adam.
Those are populated by calling range items to delete the parameter we receive as a call to this function.
Now we need we need to create a an input for S3, which is of typer calls the method delete objects
input.
OK, so we do that by creating a variable input and using the assignment operator and then using a reference
to S3 Dot Delete Object's input right there.
And that just requires some fields.
What bucket do you want to delete it from?
Well, you know how to do that bucket AWG dot string
and we're going to give an escort bucket from my receiver.
So that's our first field.
The second one is delete.
That's a field.
And that has to be a reference to S3 delete and we populate its fields.
So objects, those are the objects we're going to delete, and that is a slice of a pointer to S3 object
identifier right there.
And we have to populate its fields, which fortunately are pretty easy like this.
So in curly brackets, the key is A.W. s string and then just item our current item in our current iteration
in our range statement.
OK.
So that's our delete the first part of it.
So the object is the first field.
The next the next one is quiet and we want to be noisy if something goes wrong.
IWC dot bool it's a Boolean, but once again, Amazon wants it to be its own Boolean thoughts.
OK.
So don't be quiet if something goes wrong and then our closing comma here.
And that's it for our input statement.
No, something's wrong here.
Objects should be plural.
It's delete objects, input there.
That was messy or sloppy of me.
But in any case, it's correct now.
So we have our input to find.
Now we actually have to try to delete the objects.
So after the input statement or the input variable is declared, let's ignore the first parameter,
but pay attention to an error when we call from our service variable.
The method delete objects.
Delete object.
It's plural.
And we it in play.
OK, now again, we'll do our fancy error checking to see if it's an Amazon error or something else.
So if error is not equal to nil, then if a E are an OK are populated by calling error.
And of type IWC are error, and if OK is true, then we'll switch on the error code.
And our expression in this case is we are decode and our first case, actually in this case, I just
want a default case.
I'll put a switch in there in case you want to look for specific Amazon Air codes, but in our case,
I'll just go with the default and it's going to be returned.
False?
OK.
And then down here else, we'll just return calls again.
And you might want to put some logging statements in here, for example, in this one, I might put
format dot print on Amazon error.
And then just print out a R error.
And down here I might put another log instead.
Format dot print line.
Other error.
And then just the error.
OK, so that should take care of it.
Once we get down outside of this for loop, we just return true because everything worked as expected.
OK, so last, functioning to implement is the get one, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.