So the last function we have to implement for our SRT file system before we connected to celebrities
is, of course, the get function little used but nice to have when you need it.
And of course, the first thing I'm going to have to do is get some credentials and create a session.
So I'll copy that from the other function, delete and just paste it down here before the return statement
in the get function.
OK.
So I have my credentials, I have my session and now all I'm going to do is loop through my very attic
parameter items and process the get function for each entry I find there.
So four.
Ignore the index.
Pay attention to each individual item comes from ranging through items.
And now I'm going to check for an error when I and this is an inline function which returns an error.
And I'm doing this because of course, I'm going to be deferring file clothes periodically.
And this is exactly what we did before.
So I'll get a file and check for an error when I call OAC stock create and I'm going to create and this
will be a format string so formatted as print f, my string will be percent as slash percent s and the
substitutions will be destination, which I received as a parameter to this function and the current
item.
OK.
And I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return the error.
And down here I have to add my closing double parentheses, of course.
So once I have the file, I'll defer closing it, which is why this is all wrapped in that anonymous
function, and I'll create a variable called downloader, which is assigned the value of.
And they should have filed in front of the clothes.
That was sloppy and there should be a capital C..
Apparently, I can't type today.
My downloader is an S3 manager, dot new downloader.
And it requires my session, and now I'll ignore the first return parameter, but check for an error
when I use Downloader to download the file, and that requires the file and the second parameter, and
I'll put this on another line, so it's easier to read is a reference to S3.
Three.
Get object input.
And that takes two fields the bucket, which, of course, is an AWOL string from my receiver escort
bucket.
And the second thing is the key.
And then, of course, that's just A.W. Asked String the current item
and looks like I already have an error variable.
So this should not be an assignment operator and I'll format this.
So there's my downloader.
We check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll just return the error.
Otherwise we'll return nil.
OK, and then outside of this inline function, we do our last error check if error is not equal to
nil, then return the error.
And I think unless I have a typo somewhere, that should actually do it.
So now we have all of our necessary functions implemented to satisfy the file system FC interface.
So the next step is to connect celebrities to our new S3 file system, and we'll get started on that
in the next lecture.