So now that we have all the functions completed, our S3 file system, let's connect it to celebrities,
so I'm back in the files.
Larry Telesco at the root level of the Celebrity House project near the bottom of that file in the function
called Create File Systems.
And I'll put it right here after I declare the file system variable doesn't matter where it goes.
So once again, I'm going to check for the presence of a value in my thought on file to determine whether
or not to try to instantiate an S3 file system.
So if O's don't get on and I'm going to look for S3 key, that's as good as any.
So if that is not equal to an empty string, then I want to create this file system.
So I'll create a variable S3, and I'll make that equal to the type S3 file system, which it should
find for me S3 and populate its fields.
So we have the key, and that's OK.
Don't get on.
S3 underscore key right there.
I'll duplicate this, and the second field will be the secret like that.
And that's S3 secret duplicated again.
The next one is the region and that is S3 region
and duplicate that.
The next one is the end point, and that's S3 endpoint and the final one is the bucket.
What's the bucket name?
And that is S3 bucket.
And then I add that to my file system is a variable file systems at the key of S3, and that's equal
to S3.
OK, so that should take care of that.
And the next step, of course, is to actually go create a bucket somewhere out in a remote system and
then fill in the appropriate values in my own file.
And we'll do that in the next lecture.