So in order to test out our Amazon S3 bucket compatible file system, I need to create something now
I could use minimal because it is by default, an Amazon S3 compatible server.
But honestly, I've never had much luck trying to use straight Amazon code with Mineo, and that's largely
because I didn't put much effort into it.
I like to use the correct driver for the correct file system.
So what I'll do is create a bucket online note.
Now you can do it on digital oceans.
You can do it on Amazon if you want to, or any provider that gives a compatible S3 bucket compatible
file system.
So online mode, it's pretty straightforward.
I've logged in and this is what I see when I log in and it's just that lynda.com line ODI dot com and
you can create an account there if you want to.
But you might have to spend real money, typically very often at least know offers a $100 credit for
new sign ups.
So you can use that and then just cancel your account after the fact if you want to, or you can just
follow along and try this when you actually need to connect to a remote filesystem.
But in any case, Lenard calls their S3 buckets object storage.
Digital ocean calls them spaces.
Amazon calls them S3 buckets, but other object storage.
And as you can see, I have quite a few buckets already, but I'll create a new bucket.
OK, which I will call over here, celebrities and I'm going to select my region.
And what I'm going to choose is Newark, New Jersey, which is relatively close to where I am physically
located.
OK.
And I'll create the bucket.
So that creates a new bucket called celebrities, which I'll see somewhere along here.
Right there.
OK, so it's created now I'll click on celebrities just to see what we have.
And you can see that there are no files here right now.
And I can look at access.
And I'm going to leave this private or I can leave it authenticated, read public, read public read,
right?
I'll make my public read OK.
And I'll also leave cause enabled to turn on and share for sale.
Tell us, let's see what this is.
I could put my own certificate in there, but I'll use the default TLS certificate, which is fine.
OK, so there we are for that.
Now, if I go back to object storage.
I need to create access to it, so I'll click on Access Keys up here and I'll generate an access key
and I will call this one celebrities.
OK, and I'll just leave everything turned on.
I'm not going to give it limited access at all.
So I'll create the access key.
Now, at this point, don't close this window until you copy this information, so I'm going to copy
this first one called Access Key, and I will switch over to my I.D. and I'm going to open the door
on the file in my app.
And here we have a key for streets or paste that in there, and I'm going to revoke this after I finish
recording the course.
So don't bother trying to use mine and I'll copy the secret key and I'll go back to my I.D. and I'll
paste the secret in there now because I chose New Jersey.
I'm going to put U.S. Dash East Dash one in there as my region.
And if you create yours in a different region, of course, you'll have to put a different region in
there.
And if you get the region wrong, you won't be able to connect at all.
And my end point for this, it's pretty easy for a with us Dash East Dash one, whatever your region
is, dot lynn odd objects dot com.
And my bucket name, I call celebrities.
I make sure you get all of this right.
Because one of the most frustrating things is doing something like reversing this secret in the key
or misspelling the endpoint or leaving an extra character in or out of the bucket name.
So make sure you get all of that right.
OK.
And I can go back here now to my web browser and closes and I'm all set.
So there's my celebrity key, and I'm all set.
And if I ever want to revoke that key, I just revoke it right here.
OK, so now that we have celebrities hooked up to our file system and we've created a bucket we can
access, it's time to go, update our handlers and then finally try things out.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.