So before we can try things out, we obviously have to update our handlers for S3, so I'm in the file
handlers thought go in my app and I'm going to scroll down till I find list f's right here.
So obviously here I need to copy one of these.
I don't have to copy and it's just simpler and paste it here and change this to S3.
And our file systems will be at the key S3 from H Dot APT file systems that map and we don't want to
cast it to a WebDAV.
We want to cast it to end as three file systems.
Three Enter a first type is a street, so that was easy enough.
So let's keep going.
That was for listing a file system.
Now, upload to a file system that displays the page, this is the handler we want right here.
So again, we'll come down here and copy WebDAV and paste it here and change that to S3 and change this
to S3 and cast it to.
That's three file systems Dog S3.
Are there any more?
There should be get files.
Upload is fun delete from file system.
That's the last one, I believe, so we'll copy WebDAV.
Paste it here.
Change that to S3.
Change this to S3 and cast it to the correct type.
S3 File Systems S3 and I believe that's it.
Perfect.
OK, so now we're ready to try things out, and we'll do that in the next lecture.