So we seem to have everything hooked up correctly, and it's time to give things a try.
So I'll open up my terminal and I'll type make start, and when I hit return, it's going to start up,
but you'll get a warning saying you need to import the appropriate S3 file system from your celebrity's
project.
Just copy and paste the go get command and then you should be able to start it up.
So it's running out and I'll switch over to my browser and we'll give it a try.
So I'll go to local host 4000 and I'll go to file systems and list files.
And first of all, let's make sure the other ones work.
So there's Mineo that still works.
Let's try SFTP.
That works.
And finally, WebDAV and that should work as well.
And if I go to S3 Bucket, which is our topic of the moment and hit list, there should be nothing up
there and there's not.
That's good.
OK, so let's go over to our file systems and upload something to our S3 bucket, so I'll browse.
And I'll choose this ping.
This little image and upload it.
And it says it's uploaded great.
Now let's go back to our systems list files.
Choose SFTP now S3 bucket and list.
And there's still nothing there, which seems kind of weird.
So I introduced a little bit of a problem, and I confess that I did so deliberately, but if I could
to my Lynnwood account.
And go to object storage.
And look at celebrities, you'll see that files actually there, so it uploaded it properly, but it's
not listing it properly.
And fortunately, it's a really easy fix.
So let's go back to our idea and I'll just hide my terminal and find the list command in S3 right here.
And the problem is this value that's being passed prefix when we pass a slash, which is the default
parameter.
If you haven't clicked to a lower level folder, when we we submit that form, it actually passes a
slash and Amazon doesn't like that slash.
So what we have to do here is just add a little check.
If prefix is equal to slash, then prefix is equal to an empty string.
And that's one of the differences between Mineo, which takes care of the slash automatically and Amazon's
code or or library, which does not.
So now if I go make a restart or mix it up and make start.
And go back to my Web browser and get to the correct the page list files.
Now, when I choose S3 Bucket, it should show me that file.
And it does.
And let's try deleting it.
Yes.
And it's gone perfect, so that all works as expected.
So in the next section, my goal is to take all of this logic that we've just figured out.
Maybe just make sure all works and we'll build a file system agnostic file upload tool as part of celebrities,
which will make uploading files really, really easy for any project that's using our celebrities package.
And we'll get started on that in the next election.