I'm excited to have my friend and colleague and fellow venture fellow adventurer and start ups Daniel
here with me and Daniel has the advantage and benefit of being a practicing professional coder so I
already explained this but in academia I spend all my time kind of teaching the same classes and that's
different than being a professional dad where you're working on all kinds of different parts.
I'm really excited to have you here Daniel and I'm looking forward to going through this material and
learning some new things myself and kind of exemplifying pair programming.
So we have a little bit a wider lens on now you could see a little bit more of the room and the first
thing we're gonna do is just kind of go in to some get stuff and so it gets stuff that I notice a lot
of my students whether they're undergraduates or graduate students they don't always have these skills
and even when I teach people who are in industry sometimes I find that some people don't have these
skills and so this is going to be we're going to end this section here you could see from the outline
we're going to look at get we're gonna setup our get repo in this video and and so you know you'll have
a link to that and of course resources where the code is and then we're gonna work with branches a little
bit so we're going to go through understanding branches and working at branches and doing def master
branch you could see the videos coming up as a little bit of a preview of what's coming in this section
and then merging a branch into leading a branch.
So we're just laying the foundation and I really believe in being thorough because nothing is more frustrating
when you're trying to learn something than watching somebody do something and not understanding what
they're doing.
So if you already know all of the things that are mentioned there this is your course for your benefit.
We're here to help you if you already know this stuff feel free to skip over this section but if you
don't know this and I really believe in providing too much rather than not enough.
And so along with that philosophy I'd rather you have material if you need it and that way it's there
for you so you can go through it and if you don't need it you could step over it.
And so that's why we're including this information it's kind of like the next step up of what I've covered
in my previous courses which was an introduction to get.
And so if you don't understand get at all you want to step back to one of my earlier courses.
So that's what we're going to do in this section.
But I've been doing all the talking do you have anything you want to add.
No not really.
So the the skill set here and any good team and you get partnership you have complementary skill sets.
And so my skill set is teaching.
I've spent a lot of time talking in front of other people and sharing ideas and learning how to convey
ideas thus I have part of my brain that's really well developed do that doesn't mean I don't completely
screw it up at times I went to New York this summer to do a presentation and just the tension of life
the pressure the high level I was operating out back there I wasn't happy with how it turned down I
got nervous sometimes still happens so I'm good at presenting and professional DAB I just don't have
that experience whereas Daniel complements that and say you're gonna we're gonna have that benefit of
both of us here where he has professional experience it's been working with go professionally for wow
many years now and so that's what we're going to do and that's what we're looking at in this first section
and you got anything else you want to say looking forward to teaching.
He'll be talking more when we get into the coding and I'll make sure that I'm slowing things down to
you know make sure all things are under well understood.
All right.
So we'll jump in to get in the next video.