I'm just going to ease Daniel in here and I'm going to take the lead on this first part.
This first video.
This video right now.
And that's just create our get repo and I'm just going to briefly just review a few things and then
also maybe Daniel you could show windows and so how you get bashed commands on windows and again all
this stuff ah is in my previous court previous course is what we're going to cover here.
So this is just f y.
Maybe you're still new to this and you need a little bit of reinforcement or review or maybe your completely
new to it in which case it's just convenient for you that it's right here but to set up a get hub repo
the first thing you want to do is you want to make sure that you could clone using SS H.
There's many ways to skin a cat.
I don't know where that phrase came from.
Probably some hillbillies out in the boondocks who like skinning cats but there's many way different
ways you could do things and and so I like using SS H I just find it easier is that your preference.
Yeah this searches easier you do have to remember your password and it's more secure too.
Well there you go.
That's why I'm excited to have a pair programming pair teaching because you get additional perspectives
so SS age.
Those are all really good reasons to use it.
But if you're on Windows creating SS age can be a pain.
And so what's easiest is to use bash shell terminal commands on Windows.
So there's two main types of operating systems.
Windows or posits Unix Linux Mac right to families and then the terminals the command line interface
and the the the commands which I think are primarily used in programming are going to be Unix Linux
terminal shell bash as opposed to the DOS prompt command prompt which is Windows right.
Correct.
Yeah.
What you've experienced in programming too.
Yes.
Yeah.
The thing is most of those Unix bash command line commands are also available on Windows.
You just have to dig and find them and install yourself.
Yeah.
So hassle.
So it's just easier.
So one way that you could setup get.
Yeah I'm sorry.
One way you could set up a bash shell terminal commands on Windows just install it get ACM and I think
that's the easiest way to do it.
And when you install get SVM again you can check out my course on VSO code.
I just went through this in detail.
It will it will ask you different options but you just want to make sure you're selecting the right
options when you select the right options.
You'll be able to use and just read through the choices and some are like recommended choice.
You'll be able to be able to use Linux shell bash terminal commands on Windows.
Alternatively there's one other way you could do it and on Windows machines you could enable windows
to do Shell bash terminal commands.
Yeah when Windows 10 has a Linux subsystem for Windows which basically gives you an a boon to command
line with all the boon to commands that can run when X commands directly.
So if you want to do that I just google that here when the windows linux subsystem you can enable that
and then you can get back going on your machine to do these commands.
Once you've done all that you can then run SS H to create a SS H.
Public and private key and so SS H on Mac is what I'm gonna Google and I'll give you a command.
And so how to SS H on mac with native SS H client and so I'm just going to scroll down until I find
the command.
And that's not it.
And so I'm just going to search for another one.
How to create create create.
SS H key Mac.
Let's try that one manually generated your SS key.
SS each key in Mac and so the command here is this one right here.
And so if I go to my Mac and again intermediate course so it's going to actually take me a minute to
kind of drop into that mode and not try to teach everything from the beginning.
So I'm trying to find that right place of showing too much vs. too little.
And so if this is going too fast for you.
Drop back to my earlier courses and go through those classes.
So here I'm just going to search for my SS H folder and you can see it right there and I'm gonna drop
that in.
Well I could see what's in that SS H folder first into into SS H C D dot SS H.
Go and I could see in there I have a public and I have a private key and so this is public private key
encryption.
It's asymmetric encryption is referred to as asymmetric encryption because there is a public key and
so this dot pub you could share this with anybody in the world.
And then there is a private key and this private key you want to keep for yourself.
And so I would think it's a good practice to generate like I'm generating as the search key forget I'm
only going to do that.
Like get Hubble have its own unique public key is that good practice.
It doesn't matter it's public key.
Anybody can have it right.
Anyone can have the public key.
So if you want to be extra secure you can have separate private and public eats but then you have to
flip between them while you're using it.
But when you go to a place that's kind of different.
So different Web sites if they want my SS HQ it's totally fine to provide this Publix as Publix for
everybody.
You get invited to.
So never mind on that.
So you just want to create this and to do that you drop that command in right there as you could see
on my terminal I hit enter and now it says enter the file in which to save the key.
So that's going to fall to idea underscore RSA and I could say I'm just gonna create tab creating temp
and no passphrase if I wanted extra security create a passphrase and now if I look at what's in there
I've got my temp and temp pub and so the pub I'm gonna cap that right.
So temped up pub and they'll print out what that is this is everybody can see it including you.
I'm going to highlight all of that and then I'm going to go to get so I'm going to go get an ID get
a job I'm going to go into my user settings so settings and I'm gonna go to SS H and GP keys.
I'm going to add a new SS H key and this would be like What.
You know my home desktop or whatever and I drop that in so that key gets dropped in and then I add that
SS HQ I'm not going to do that.
I already have one but now what that enables when get hub has my public key is they could encrypt a
message and send it to me and nobody else in the world could decrypt it to decrypt it.
You have to have the private key.
So only I can decrypt it when I decrypt that message what GitHub would've sent me is usually some code
which I have to send back to them to let them know OK you know intended recipient was an actual recipient
and then they'll also send me a key they're gonna send me a symmetric key.
It's this symmetric key we'll both be able to encrypt and decrypt.
So we're gonna establish communication with asymmetric encryption public private key It's asymmetric
is the public key and the private key are different.
We're gonna establish communication with that.
And then once communication is established we're going to switch to symmetric key and a symmetric key
is going to be able to both encrypt and decrypt because you could only encrypt with the public key you
can't decrypt and you could only decrypt with the private key when we have symmetric.
We're going to be able to both encrypt and decrypt but only get hub and myself will have these keys
and the passing of that key was passed securely through encryption so nobody else could have intercepted
it.
Because we use asymmetric to pass that key and a code phrase.
And then I decrypted that the public encryption sent me the key in private encrypted private key decrypted
it and now we have what was decrypted what GitHub sent me is that symmetric key where we both have the
same key.
So now I can encrypt something to get hub send it back to get hub and we're being we're able to communicate
and secure encrypted fashion using cryptography encoding our messages and then decoding them when they
receive and nobody else can encrypt or decrypt encode or decode those messages because nobody else has
the same key.
There's only two of them.
And so that's kind of I think interesting and not all that widely known about asymmetric and symmetric
encryption asymmetric encryption is public private key and then symmetric encryption I guess maybe you
call private private key.
There's a saying shared secrets shared secret.
So that's my understanding of how that process works.
Do you have anything to add to that.
No.
Did that sound accurate.
Yeah.
All right.
For the most understandable.
Good.
So.
So now that we have that that set up we're gonna create a repo for this course.
I'm going to go to my profile.
I would also like to point out if you just search GitHub SS h the very first result you will get is
a guide for SS H including like how would you create a new stage key if you go to any of those it will
have tabs for whatever operating system you're on which will tell you the command for that operating
system which is both the same.
Yeah.
And if you're on Windows it's because it's still a safe kitchen.
It's just might be saved in a different location.
OK.
I thought it was much more complicated.
Yeah well installing a safe kitchen is a little more complicated but the command itself is the same
command across.
And if you have the emulator on windows where you could do Shell bash terminal commands you could just
use the Mac I put there.
So now we're gonna create a new repo for this course and to do that in and click new repository.
I think I'll save this for the next video.
I'd like to try to keep these videos short.
We're already coming up on LIVE minutes has had some good stuff in here about encryption and so all
understanding SS age is what I'll call this video and the next one will create or get a repo.
See you next video.