OK.
So you could see here in our course outline just keep you on point.
So you're tracking what we're learning where we're learning it.
We just went through understanding SS H encryption working in Windows on the terminal which is also
called Bash which is also called Shell and as opposed to command prompt prompt or CMT or DOS prompt.
I've heard it called all those things.
Yeah.
Windows also has power shown imitates but it's basically it's a superset it seems the power show.
All right.
So now we're going to create our get repo for this course and we'll clone it.
So I'm going to go to get hub click new repository it's going to bring me to this screen.
I'm going to name my repository.
So I'm going to call this go laying project and going project.
I think that's good.
Going project.
Yeah.
Yeah that's fine.
And I'm not going now to get ignore anything like that I'm going to create the repository so click Create
repository.
And now this is created quick setup if you've done this kind of thing before.
I have SSA reached.
Yes I want to make sure I've got SSA H.
I'm going to copy all of that man.
See.
And then go to my terminal and somewhere in my terminal I think I'll put mine in and we're going to
get into modules because modules is new.
And so as modules are is new we wanted to provide you know some teaching on that so that you can use
modules will be using go modules in this course if you don't know.
That is great.
We're going to teach in a second.
But what that means is the old way and go creating a workspace was that you actually had to go workspace.
There was a go path environment variables set to your go workspace inside your go workspace he had a
source been in package folder inside the source folder usually had some sort of name spacing that would
separate my code from somebody else's code and then namespace and usually when domain user name some
sort of repos something along those lines and and so insofar as it might be source get hub dot com my
username goes to 11 and then forward slash the repo name is where I'd create the repository but now
I could create I could create folders where I work on go projects anywhere on my computer and we just
have to create go modules to work in that and so we'll cover how to do that in a second but the point
of this is all that I could do is on the point of this is all to say that I could put my repo wherever
I want on my computer it no longer has to be in that go workspace defined by the go path if you have
legacy projects go pass still works but go modules you can put it anywhere so I'm just going to go to
documents and in documents I'm going to create this project.
So we're just going to do get clone and I guess before I do that I'll just l s kind of so I could see
what's in there and then we'll see how things have changed and so I'll do it.
S L.A. and that's it's in there and I'm going to do my get clone and clone this project that you are
all a copy and so that's coming down and it's going project get and says you've cloned it into your
repository and if I do my SLA now I've got going project right there.
So if I go into that C.D. going project and I create a file test start t t and I edit that file opening
the editor and just text whatever its name spelled right control X to save it yes save it to that and
exit.
And now if I do get status right I've got that test.
I'm just making sure that I actually switched in the building project LSA L.A. I've got my get folder
I've got to text files I don't know why to create it seems like when the test wins text test and text.
All right so I'm going to get rid of test.
There we go.
And thank you.
That's where pair programming is awesome.
And now I'm going to do a get add Dash I saw and get commit dash first commit test file and then get
push.
And so I should see this show up over on my repo now.
So if I come back to my repo and just hit this it's gonna refresh and now everything's connected in
my files getting pushed up.
So it's good.
And that's establishing a repo.
This will be the repo for the course.
So if you wanted to add to this or first of all you probably want to clone it down your machine.
So you have all the code by the time you clone it there's going to be a lot of code in there we're just
getting started and.
And then if you want to add to this repo or if you even want to contribute to the course in a larger
way by what do they call it being an administrator of a repo at length that 0 collaborator a collaborator
Lord of War.
Seth a jet I have this repo whatever you want to call it if you want to be somebody who else review
pull requests and accept those we're totally open to that because life gets busy but if you know you
have time you want to be able to sort of contribute to community.
That's awesome.
Or if you want to make pull requests like oh here's another thing or contribute another example another
file like here's another way to do it for everybody in the class.
Take a look at this way.
Feel free to add to this repost that pull requests and we're totally going to monitor that as much as
we can and we welcome additional help if anybody else wants to contribute to the monitoring of that.
So that's all I have to say about creating the repo and the next video we're gonna jump on branches
but I've been doing all the talk and just kind of get things warmed up get Daniel warmed up and in the
next video we'll jump into looking at branches so that we cover that.
That's never been covered in my classes because I want to make sure that's covered you have anything
you want and know.
All right sweet see in the next video.