So now we're going to add Daniel as a collaborator to this get hub repo.
I thought we'd be jumping into branches next but then Daniel said hey how about we show this and I was
like yes absolutely.
So how do we add a collaborator.
And I have to do it on my machine because obviously you don't have access there.
So you tell me what to do.
So.
So there's a settings tab there at the top.
That's where the repo not for the entire account.
Yes.
And then on the left there there will be collaborator collaborators.
So you have to confirm your password so that if you're pre logged in for to get hub you will.
It wants you to reconfirm your password.
If it's been a while since you've been passwords that someone just coming across your laptop that you've
left unlocked can't change something vital to your project
so.
So while Todd goes and looks up his password.
So the collaborators have access to the brief on the same way the Creator does which is separate from
most open source projects you're allowed to fork or basically clone a project and you can do your work
and then you have to request that your changes get pulled into the original repo.
A collaborator has full access and can just directly write to the other repo.
So I think I think we're almost here now.
It is all right.
I stopped my screen recording to log in there and get my password because that's super sensitive stuff.
And we'll see if there we go we're logged in.
So you're saying that isn't this fun.
First of all I should have seen this fine.
Like I'm telling you I'm fun.
So we're so much alike.
Life can be like particularly encoding like you're there by yourself you're learning that your I don't
know your code in it right.
Like you spent a lot of salt solitary time just go go go.
Yes.
And like it's totally like back when Barnabas was here like when you're kind of Barnabas.
That was awesome.
Yes.
And it's fun to have company doing this together.
I'm having a good time.
So you're saying Jump in anytime you can talk fast.
Yes.
You were saying collaborators versus somebody else but it could be a collaborator versus just anyone
in a for an open source project a collaborator has access to the original repo whereas anyone else has
to fork the repo into a copy of their own and then request that one of the collaborators pulls their
changes into the original repo.
Yeah.
So when I was talking about somebody being a what's a set that's the dark knight.
Right.
Yes.
Jed I want to talk about somebody.
And my my lack of Star Wars knowledge to show through when nice talking about somebody being a Jedi.
They'd be a collaborator if they wanted to be open and accept pull requests.
I'm going to type in your username here and get yes there it is.
Or Lord knows and I liked that name it sounds.
I just invited you it sounds it sounds like powerful and mysterious and like some esoteric piece of
knowledge like Dungeons and Dragons or something.
I think that's a good good name.
My user name obviously comes from maybe not so obvious now.
An old movie in the 80s by Rob Reiner called Spinal Tap.
You could You could YouTube goes to eleven Spinal Tap and watch where my name came from.
All right.
So Daniel is going to accept the invitation.
So when I got invited I got an email saying I was invited and that brings me here where I can accept
the invitation to be a collaborator.
And now that now I am now.
I now have push access to the goes to 11 going project repository.
So now I am capable of doing all the same commands as Todd is with the exception of I can't rename the
project.
I can't just collaborators they can't delete the project.
There may be a few other administrative things that only the owner can do.
You're giving me a lot of credit there that you could be able to do all the same commands I could do.
Daniel's got it on me when it comes to get.
He knows a lot of good get.
All right.
You have anything more you want to say about all that.
We've got the collaborator set up to be a collaborator requires the owner to get set up forking is just
anyone can go to the repo and just hit the fork button the upper right mean that they'll create your
own copy which you can work on and then you can go back to the original one and create a pull request.
Yeah.
So that's that's great.
And starring is just keeping track of the ones you like and you like and watching Latino and there's
changes sweet.
All right.
I think that's good.
We'll see in the next video where we're going to do something.