So do we want to for the first bit demonstrate why branches are a good idea.
Having us both make commit and try to push like both of us try to change this text.
Yeah.
So that's good on your screen recorder's gone.
Yes.
I'm just going to say that stuff like a pilot my screen records go on this go on and we're recording
audio recording video recording all that.
Just a moment.
Yeah sure.
Yeah.
That's got the red record gone all right.
So another great thing about pair programming pair teaching is that Daniel just had a suggestion and
in the sentiment that effort the vein providing too much information rather than not enough.
True to what I said in the last video we're going to do something in this video.
And Daniel suggestion was to show how you clone.
So we're going to see that how somebody else clones it as a collaborator or anybody could clone it the
way you're to do.
Yes.
All right let's do it.
Yeah.
So.
So I can just go to the project which I can if I know the full year old project that's there or from
the email from last time or I can just go to get hubcap and you can search for a repo so I can just
search for it goes to goes to 11:00 if I can spell slash going project I think my goes to Levin is with
bashes.
There we go.
No it's not.
Surprise me.
So that goes straight to it culturally if you are a collaborator for something it will show up over
here that's your list of your repositories so you can hit show more if you want to see all the repositories
that you have access to so either way once you are on the project page again if you're not a collaborator
you can fork it whether you are a collaborator or not if you can access the page you can hit close and
you can close that sage or if you're not using a sage there's HP s version but a sage is usually better.
Anybody could fork it too.
You don't have to collaborate correct and forking it would then make it a repo.
That is exactly like this one.
But under your account.
Correct.
So.
So if I hit a fork here I would now have an oral auto slash going project.
Yeah.
Copy and then anybody can also clone this contract.
Yeah bring it down to the machine because it's public.
Yes.
Right.
So once they clone it I can get the clone button here.
They've got a couple different options.
But what you want is the cloning.
You are all here.
So I want the sage cloning.
I can spent to copy it or I can click this and it controls see either one works and then I can go to
my command prompt and I'll just do it on my desktop get cloned and then I put that you are all and that
clones it onto my own machine and and this is one because I cloned it through this particular clone
button.
It is cloned off of it goes to eleven going project.
If you are forking it you will be cloning off you off of your fork not the original project whatever
you clone off of that's what you're.
That's what you're by default.
That is what you will try to push back to you.
And if you do if you're not a collaborator or pushes will fail
so that's just adjusting the volume if you see me do stuff like that.
So so.
So if I was not a collaborator I could clone like this.
But then if I tried to write back to this repository the when I do get push it would give me an error
message and it wouldn't actually go through.
So instead what I would do in that case is that I would fork it.
I would clone that I do my work there.
And I could push to my fork and then I could come back to and try to request that my changes get pulled
back to the original repository.
So let me just make sure I understand this.
And we have goes to Levin going project and let's say that I am James Bond.
I've got my James Bond github account and I'm really realizing the power of coding that this entire
thing and run around guns and dynamite fistfight with people.
It's not the way to make things happen in the world.
You really want to be powerful you've got to be a coder so that I can then go to goes to Levin and go
and project you're actually looking to see some he's got James Bond account.
That's great.
I think somebody has to grab that username.
It's already taken one and that makes sense.
And then if I clone my.
That goes to Levin Go line project if I make changes to that I can tell to make changes locally.
But then you know there's no way for me to save those changes on GitHub because unless I'm submitting
it to goes to Levin whereas if I fork it it's going to be under my account I can make all the changes
I want I could submit it to my account.
Right.
So all add files work on files as you go through the project with a fork.
You could do this and then send all those up to your fort Go Go line project under your account name
and then if you ever create something that you want to add to the goes to Levin you could select that
one thing you can make a pull request so I've made 10 things I'm keeping under my username my repo my
fork of it 10 things.
But then I'm like oh I want to send seven and add that to the project.
I could do a pull request.
I want to know the poor request does not go by the command.
It goes by the branch which is what we'll be getting into next.
So if you make 10 changes on the main branch you can make a pull request have that branch merged into
the original.
Okay.
So and that's and that includes all the changes that you've made on that bridge.
So to get that version I was talking about we really need to be able to use branches.
And then I'll make branches as I'm doing stuff.
And then if one on one of those branches and like this would be good for everybody's to see I could
smell that one branch.
I like that anything more.
No.
So I now have I now have it set up on my.
I've now closed it on my system so I couldn't have a go link project which on windows you don't have
lets you use DIY R for direct for directory.
And so I've got that text that text on my system.
Awesome.
All right.
So in the next video we'll start working with branches.