Wait.
No I do.
I told you I'd throw away get hub accounts.
I mean I guess I do have access to our greater company.
Awesome.
Oh really.
Yeah.
We had one.
Oh yeah.
And we just see that.
Let's just see that this is how most people will see it right.
Mm hmm.
Let me know if you're thirsty.
Me.
Are you thirsty.
Water
maybe came to me.
Probably.
So now Daniel has logged in to and we're looking at Daniel's screen here on Windows.
But Daniel is logged into a kind of you know just get hub user account and and the user account here.
So this is he's no longer a collaborator from this user accounts.
This is the way most people will experience this repost we've kind of wanted to do it from get Hub Repository
where the person individuals not collaborators.
So if you could go to your username here you could see its greater Common's font.
Awesome is the name of this account and now he's also gone to ghost eleven go Lang project.
Now he's gonna fork this we're gonna do it as a fork and we're gonna start working on branches so take
it away.
So yeah.
One thing to note is this is what it looks like as a non collaborator versus as a collaborator.
There's very little difference here.
All the all the same tabs and such.
I could turn off my.
Yeah you say one looks like it's night turn I can turn off my dark dark appearance there.
So as you can see the changes are tiny.
My the one that's a collaborator has a suggestion to add a read me and that's about the only difference
there.
So that's because this project is public so old all the same options are available and I can clone this
but I wouldn't be able to push if I closed in this way so I can fork it by clicking this work button
and that will tell get hub to fork it.
So it's working the project can take not it's fairly fast and so now I've got very common spot awesome
slash going project.
And it knows it has a little note here.
It was forked from goes to heaven project and then at the terminal or you're going you're going to work
from the command prompt but you have to bash shell commands enabled there correct.
I've got to get installed to get SBN.
OK so so I've got all the standard get commands and so we're going to start to create a branch.
So you could you know maybe add your own file so let's do one where we add a file on a branch that's
just going to be pushed Uri Po and then let's do one where we add a file that will then be submitted
as a pull request to the main Ricoh.
And so for this first one let's just add a file and push it to your repo and we'll compare that to the
repo under.
So first let me delete my googling project folder here because I was the one under your other that was
that was the one clone dwarf.
If the goes to 11 again.
So now it's gone.
So if I do dir it's no longer there.
How did you delete that.
I just went to my death is on my desktop so it's like that was fast.
So we're on Windows to delete a folder from the command line is an incredibly well it's not incredibly
complicated but it's different enough.
I don't actually remember off the top my head.
The arm.
RF Yeah.
Lizzy It's the ads.
It's a lot easier.
So I'm not going to go with that stage because it goes to heaven because the greater common so far awesome
account does not have my s h set up some screens HD yes which allows me to use my username username
and password instead.
So get a clone.
Yeah the HD.
Yes you are.
Because this is a public this is a public project it does not require credentials to clone it.
So even though I didn't have to type it in at this point.
So now I need to create a file of some sort.
So I can if I just open up a text editor here and I just create a new file with it.
This is a sample file I say.
Over in the test coding project here they call it text to
now I can run the commands get status and I can see what I have to be in the actual folder get status
I can see the new file and I can get add Dutch capital a.
So now I get status it's ready and I can do.
Get a mint dash and added a new file these are your commands by the way it's like I get ad get come
and get push and get ad dash a or dash dash all in the passive use get ad dash dash on Daniel.
Be like why you just do dash capital they both work.
So now they've added If I get status I can see there's nothing to commit but your branch is ahead of
origin master origin just refers to wherever you cloned it from.
So in this case it's greater common off the Golden project by one commit.
And so now I can get push this this commit and it's through and I can refresh the page refresh or wherever
and there's the new file and this is this is under greater Commons font awesome going project.
Yes if I go to yes thank you if they go back to the original.
No they're not there.
And so if we wanted to add something to the original under goes to eleven then you need to do that on
a branch you can you can do it on this you can do it on this master is a branch.
So type in it technically.
So if I want to have this pushed over to the original I need to create a pull request.
And so I think I go to the pull request tab hit you or request
and so you can see it says base repository goes to eleven going project and head repository you can
see it's got a little error here.
So stuff from this end greater comments my awesome master is going to great goes to eleven master but
if you'd made a whole bunch of changes on a master then it's going to try to send them all over and
now where you want the individual branch you send one little thing over so that's one of the benefits.
So yeah I can get more than just master branch you can see you can select which one and you can also
select which one you're pushing it over to two if the head if the original has multiple branches.
That's pretty cool.
All right so go ahead and so.
So yeah once once you've you can see a little preview of what's being moved over and then when you read
each that create pull request and it'll ask you to describe your request if you are doing a poor request
to a public to an actual public open source project one as much detail as you can in here.
So here I to say I added in there example file.
So usually one more detail than that but this works to integrate or best now because he goes love and
great going project is that poor request has one pull request and as a collaborator I my system just
got an email saying there is a new poll request Todd probably also got an email saying as much just
now.
But now Todd can now go to this pull request tab and you'll see my new pull request and he'll be able
to say that you're you're a collaborator under this account.
Yes I'm a clerk so yeah I can go to my account where I'm logged in as me and I can refresh the page
I can see the poor request you can see here it is by Greer comments.
Awesome I made the comment there I can check what the permits were added a new file I can see the file
changes and then when I'm ready I can then go to merge port request which accepts the changes or if
I say it's if I say it's done just close the port request you send a message if you're close you can
you can cut out a comment closing comment do.
This makes no sense closed for class.
All right let's close it next.
Yeah.
Close it was close it.
Next we'll show we'll show branches everything you want and this is meaningless.
Those records that adds that this is meaningless and it close it.
And the original person my the greater comments can now see this comment with the closed.
All right great.
Next video we'll start working with branches.