Hello and welcome to the go lines programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about VIPs who get the concept.
What is that, Sujit?
Let circuits provide a bi directional, full duplex communication channel that operates over HDTV through
single TCP IP circuit connection.
At its core, the Vets Get Protocol facilitates message passing between the client and server in contract
with FTP request and response connections that sockets can transport any number of protocols and provide
server to collide message delivery without poulenc.
We have two kits are exciting for developers because they allow for bi directional, real time communication
between servers and clients.
Website kits are available on many platforms, including the most common browsers and mobile devices.
They are often applied to solve problems of millisecond, accurate state synchronization and promptly
subscribe messaging, and that sucha is attracted by making the common HTC prerequisites to that server
been an upgrade.
Heather we used to server should confirm in its response.
After this, the connection remains established between that physical client's repair if at some point
the service needs to be redeployed or load redistributed.
It's better to get connection needs to be reestablished.
Why that, Sujit?
The idea of that suggests was born out of the limitations of today's technology with HDTV, a client
requests a resource and the server responds with the requested data.
HDTV is a uni directional protocol.
Any data sent from the server to the client must be first requested by the client.
Land pooling has traditionally act as a workaround for this limitation, with land pulling a client
makes its Typekit request with a longtime attorney, and the server uses that long time out to push
data to the client.
Land pooling works, but comes with a drawback.
Resources on the server are tied up throughout the length of the lined pool, even when no data is available
to send.
That suggests, on the other hand, allow for sending message based data.
Similar to UDP, but with the reliability of TCP that Sujit uses HTP as the initial transport mechanism,
but keeps the TCP connection alive after the initial response it received so that it can be used for
sending messages between client and service.
That suggests allow us to build real time applications without the use of long pooling.
When China lets at get used.
Realtime Web application.
Real time application uses a vets widget to show the data at the client end, which is continuously
being sent by the bank and server in wet Sujit data is continuously pushed or transmitted into the same
connection, which is already open.
That is why that's to get this faster and improved application performance.
Gaming application.
In a gaming application, you might focus on death data is continuously receiving by the server and
without refreshing the UI, it will take effect on the screen UI gets automatically refreshed without
even establishing the new connection.
So it is very helpful in a gaming application.
Chat application.
Chat application uses vets looking to establish the connection only once for exchange publishing and
broadcasting the message amount to subscriber in reuse the same.
That's a good connection for sending and receiving the message and one to one message transfer.
Creating events will get server events, we get connection.
It starts with a handshake.
This is the legal dance the client and server do to a soft connection.
The client to start out with the norm on the practice that contains two special headers upgrade calling
VIPs who get in connection, call an upgrade lounge with any other required request data like authentication.
The server then sends back an issue to be a 101 switching protocol, the status code indication to the
client, which basically says We used to talk an issue to be, but we will use something else in the
future along with this issue, be 100 inbound response.
It also sends the upgrade, calling VIPs care in connection upgrade.
Hey, there's a game after this.
The handshake is complete and the VIPs a get connection is in place in order not to prolong the time
of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.