Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous sessions.
We were able to implement this sorted server and client layers.
Now it's time to run the project.
It's is important to note that the server layer and the circuit layer must be executed seamlessly.
To do this, enter to the terminal and execute the following comment.
So time go run first.
Go to server that Google server layer server that go and comment gets wet and go to the socket that
Google Socket surgical and present.
OK, now server is right.
We need to execute the client layer for this purpose.
We use two separate terminals to execute the client and server methods.
To do this, right click on the client that go and select Revel in File Explorer.
In the window that opens, hold down the shift key and right click and select Open PowerShell window.
Now in new policy terminal opens for us.
Hold down the shift key inside the same page again, right click and select Open PowerShell window here
again.
Reassigned the tool, confirming those inside their screens so we can see both at the same time.
First term in the second term.
Also in the window that opens open the index file by double clicking on it.
Okay.
Raises these broader.
Much.
Now we use this command with some communication between client and server in each client, in publisher
in.
Go round the back slash client, go first terminal is running and go to second terminal and do this
command again.
Go round.
The back is last line that go.
And second terminal is running now.
It is important to note that first the server and socket must be started and then the client file must
be a start after its execution.
We now have three clients running to clients in two separate terminals.
And one client on the web.
It's time to exchange data and messages between them.
Once sent the message from each client to the server, the sent message must be visible on all planes.
For example, we sent the Hello message in first time in our.
Hello.
OK.
Now we see that this message is seen in other clients first terminal, second terminal and Prosor.
And they do the same from another client, for example, in the second terminal.
We send the welcome message Well, come OK.
We see that this message is also visible to other clients.
And now we want to send the message from our client.
For example, we said goodbye.
Send data.
OK.
We see that the message sent is visible to our clients.
In this session, we were able to implement the simple chat program using David Sujit and go like we
have reached end of decision.
I hope you have take full advantage of this decision.
Goodbye.