Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in the preview session.
We could define methods for implementing channels.
Indecision.
Finally, we will define our handler that we listen to the events of the channels.
The Loop keeps running infinitely and said it's the appropriate action based on the channel's event.
So we designed in metal to control this behavior named like wrong socket.
So we right fine set a receiver like config pointer of config
run socket.
And create a loop as a permanent listener for.
Now we manage the channel's behavior using the select comment, but different cases, so we try to select
and define our cases earlier.
We implemented a few methods for different channel behaviors that we will now use from them.
For example, suppose data is transferred to the registered land channel to implement it.
To the following case Set a name register
client colony equals send data to channel.
Config
dot register client now icon the corresponding method for each case in this case, for the registered
client chase.
The invoking registered line methods saw the right config dot register clients and set registered client
as argument for it, alleges the client.
Okay, now right case related to remove client
JS set and name like remove client calling E calls and send data to channel config dot.
Remove client calling and calling.
Now remove Client Smith for this case.
Config dot remove clients.
And said Ring of Clinton's argument for this method to remove plans.
And right Chase related to Message Exchange set a name like message data, message data he calls send
data to channel config, that message data caller and colleague message data's method for this case
config dot message data for it and set message data as argument for this message date.
Reformat the code and save the project.
Now you were able to manage channels control using Select.
In this case, we could make all the configuration for implementing the circuit layer in order not to
prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.