So in recent years, it's become increasingly common for different Web applications to allow people
to log on using not an account that's created on a specific site, but instead to use what's sometimes
called single sign on or social authentication.
There's lots of names for it, but the premise is simple.
I have an account on, say, Google or GitHub, and I'm going to use that account to log on to some
other website.
Now, obviously, there's a fair bit of magic that takes place behind the scenes in order for that to
happen, but it's pretty convenient and there's a lot of advantages to doing it.
For example, if someone signs onto my web application using their Google account, I know they have
a valid email address.
They haven't just made up a fake email address like Bill at Microsoft.com or whatever.
It's a real email address, and it's also very convenient for end users.
They don't have to remember a whole lot of passwords.
They just have to remember one password for whatever account they're using to sign up.
Now, single sign on or social authentication is very popular, and it's actually a little bit challenging
to implement.
Sign on for different services because most, most services have their own API and there's lots of similarities
between them.
But there's also little differences.
Configuration parameters The actual URL you call the API endpoint might be a little bit different.
So it can be challenging to implement them for lots of different services.
Fortunately, most programming languages go included actually have packages that make this a lot simpler,
and we're going to use a package in this course.
And the more we're going to use, it's right over here.
Let me go to my web browser.
It's called Murt Bates Slash Gothe, and if you scroll down, you'll see he supports or this project
supports lots of different providers, some I've never heard of.
But clearly there are lots to choose from here, and there's actually more supported than are listed
in the read me.
I think at least the last time I checked, but we're only going to use two.
We'll use GitHub and we'll use Google and the steps required to implement sign on using one of the other
providers support it.
There are very, very similar.
So let's get started.
Let's go down and look at how we install this package.
So what we have to do is use this go get command.
So I'll copy that.
And I'll go back to my I.D. and I'll open a terminal window.
And I don't want to be in the silver toss folder, which might seem counterintuitive to you because
we've been putting as much as we can into this hilarious package rather than the My App package.
But in this case, if you were following along, you can make off at the end of the last lecture and
tried things out.
And when we did that, it actually installed some views, for example, logging in jet and reset password.
But it also installed handlers and the handlers are right up here.
So handlers, we have this off handlers and this is where signing logs logic actually lives.
Celebrities actually installs that handler for us.
So what we're going to do is add that package Goss not in this alert householder, but instead right
here in my app.
So let me clear the screen.
Make sure I'm in the right folder.
I am, and I will paste that command and I'll go, get it.
And that adds the necessary entry in the gold mod file for my app, so that's installed.
And now we can start using it in the next lecture.
And as I said, we'll start with GitHub and Google, and I'll do GitHub first and Google after the fact.
So let's get started in the next lecture.