So before we can actually try a Single Sign-On, there's a fair number of things we have to do.
None of them are terribly difficult, but there's a lot of steps.
Now, if you're following along the same way that I'm doing things right now, one of the things you
did at the end of the last section was run make us.
And that command installed some views like, for example, the log inkjet file and the reset password.
Yet and it also installed the auth handlers file up here and some models inside the data folder.
Now, if you didn't do that, please do it right now.
Just run the existing celebrity's app as it existed at the end of the last section, and that will create
the necessary database tables and put the handlers file and all those things in there.
And once you have that done, or if you already have it done, go to the course resources for this lecture
and download the file called Log In Jet Dot Zip and open it up in your favorite text editor and copy
the contents and then come back here to your I.D. and inside the My App folder.
Inside The View's folder open up Log Inkjet.
This is the default login page, and it's a very simple form that asks for an email and a password allows
you to check or remember me, and that's pretty much it.
And what I'm going to do is delete the contents of this file and paste in the contents of that one you
just downloaded or you're about to download.
But in any case, this is almost the same, but it actually adds a couple of buttons in a left hand
column.
One here log in with GitHub, and that's one we're going to implement first and then one that's labeled
log in with Google.
And of course, both of these buttons are calling routes that don't exist yet, but they will before
too long.
OK.
So get that set up, and what we'll do next is we'll go over here, back to our web browser and look
at the Mark Bates Dot Gothe repository is an example folder, and inside of that, we have one file
called Mean Don't Go.
And if we open it up and look at it, you can see he's got a very, very long import statement because
he's importing all of the sub packages that support individual providers like We Pay and Yahoo and Yandex.
Of course, ours will be much shorter because we're going to use Google and we're going to use GitHub,
but we're going to have to do that kind of import to start with.
And if we scroll down.
He seems to begin in this one function named Main.
He begins with something called goth, don't use providers.
Then he lists all the providers he wants to implement, and each one has some information.
For example, if you were doing Google, which we will before too long, you need a key and you need
a secret and you need some endpoint to call back.
And of course, this URL is what Google will call after someone successfully authenticates.
So that's a world that have to exist on our system.
So we're going to have to do that at some point and a little bit further down.
He creates a map here.
So this map actually has one entry for each of the providers he wants to support, and that's probably
just for his demo.
So we're probably not going to have to do that, but we'll find out before too long and then down a
little bit further.
He actually does the implementation, so he sets up some routes using the Patriota reason the cheerless
or ours will be a little bit different, but the basic logic is the same, and down here he has some
kind of template that he sends back to people.
So we use this as a starting point for our application and we'll get started on this with GitHub in
the next lecture.