So at this point, we have a new version of our log in jet page that will allow users to authenticate
using a standard username and password for our application or at some point in the not too distant future
to authenticate using GitHub or Google.
So we may will set up some routes just to make sure that everything displays the way that it should.
So let's go to our roots.
Don't go file inside the Maya project, and let's just add a few roots just to display that page and
to call the in handler.
So.
So we'll put them right here at the top right after the home route.
And it's as simple as calling a Dot app dot roots dot.
Get it to display the page and I'll use users slashed log in.
And that's going to call the handler aid dot handlers.
And this is the one installed by celebrities user log in.
Then I'll duplicate this and changes to a post request when someone submits the form.
We're not going to call user log in.
We're going to call post user log in.
OK.
So assuming I have mine Docker images running in my My App folder, I should now be able to type it
make stop just in case the application is running.
It wasn't, and I'll take make start and it looks like I have to run a couple of go get commands, so
it wants this one, so I'll copy that.
This is not unusual when we're working on two packages at the same time, so I'll run that one first.
Then it looks like I have to do this one as well.
So I'll copy that while the other one's working.
We'll start in.
And the last one it seems to want is this mini oh, go.
For whatever reason, you get used to doing this when you're working on two projects at the same time,
and it's not terribly onerous.
The paste in the last one.
And now I should be able to clear the screen and type make start, and hopefully that's all it needs.
And I have an ear here, models DOT tokens.
Oh, yes, OK.
So I need to come up here to my data folder and open models dot go and I'll just hide the terminal.
So it's this part here, I need to add something to the model struct that I need to return something
down here, probably.
So up here, I'll add the three things that were installed by the make off command.
I'll call the first one remember token, and it's equal to remember tokens and tokens, which is token
and users, which has to have a lowercase asked users, which is of type user that will take care of
the first part.
And then down here where I'm returning my models, I'll add remember token, which is a type remember
token empty and I'll add users, which is a type user empty.
And finally, tokens tokens plural is a token, and it's an empty token format that and that should
take care of that problem.
All right.
Third time's the charm mixture.
And there it goes.
It's running.
So let's go back to our web browser.
And let's just go to local host, 4000, local host, 4000.
And at this point, I should be able to go to my users menu and choose log in and see the log in screen.
And I can't perfect how these buttons don't do anything, but clearly they're where they need to be.
So at this point, I don't have any users in the database, so I can't actually log in, but I don't
care about that right now.
We already know that works from the last course.
These are the things I want to work on.
So we'll get started with GitHub in the next election.