So let's get started updating some of our code to support social authentication or single sign on.
And I'm going to start by going over to my my art project, looking inside the Handler's folder and
bringing embossed handlers.
Now, if you'll recall one of the first things that we saw in that example application on Mark Bates
slash goth on GitHub is basically initializing social authentication.
He does so by calling the goth don't use provider's method.
So what I'm going to do is create a function here right at the end of off dash handler's dot go, a
function with receiver of h point and a handlers as normal.
And this is not going to be a handler, but it might use some information from the handlers package.
So what I'll do is name this one in it social off,
which seems like a reasonable name, and it's not going to take any parameters and it's not going to
return anything.
But what it's going to do is be called by other handlers that need social authentication.
So the first thing I'll do is declare a couple of variables.
One is called scope, and that will be the scope for connecting to, say, GitHub.
OK.
So when I make a request to GitHub saying I want to log in to this third party application, not GitHub,
but I want to use my GitHub credentials.
One of the things we have to send is what kind of information do you want from GitHub?
When you log log, these are in and you get to request all sorts of things.
So I could on GitHub, for example, say I want the user information and I want all that users repositories
or all that users stars, whatever it may be that in our case, we just want to log in.
We want to make this as simple as possible.
So I'll use the assignment operator and say, here are the things I want, and it goes to GitHub in
the form of a slice of strings.
So a slice of string and all I want is the user information.
OK, so that's all I'm going to use right now.
And later on, we'll have another one for Google, which I'll call GESCO or something like that.
We'll worry about that when we get to Google.
So right now, I need to tell the goth package what providers I want to use, and I do that by using
the goth package that we just installed a couple of lectures ago and I'm going to call use providers.
And that takes, as you can see in a little preview here in my I.D., any number of providers.
So I'll put it on multiple lines just so it's more readable.
OK.
And the only one I'm going to put in there right now is GitHub.
So GitHub dot and hopefully it'll show up.
It does a new GitHub provider.
OK.
So GitHub does new and that requires the GitHub key, the GitHub secret and our callback URL, plus
whatever scopes we're providing.
So for possible things more than for if you have more scopes that you want to offer, but we're only
going to offer one.
So I'm going to assume I'm going to get these things from my dot on file, which makes it really simple.
So OS don't get on and I'm going to call an entry that doesn't exist yet called GitHub underscore key.
That's my first parameter.
Then I'll put in OS, get on GitHub, underscore secret and my third one will be OS.
Don't get on and I'll look for GitHub underscore callback.
And my final parameter is just my scope.
All of my stops.
So scope, dot, dot, dot.
And it will read all the values for my scope and give it its trailing comma.
And we should be good.
So that sets up the providers.
OK, now when you're going through the associate authentication steps.
With golf.
It actually requires a cookie store, any kind of store will work, but by default it uses a gorilla
cookie store.
OK, so what I'm going to do is set up the necessary store for golf, so we're going to have a key.
And that's just some random key, and we can just use the one right in our own file.
Okay, don't get on.
And we're looking for key.
So that exists in there already.
OK?
And we have to set a maximum age for this cookie.
So I'll say Mac's age is assign the value of the number of seconds in a day.
Eighty six thousand four hundred times.
30 30 days.
And we also need to actually set up the Sessions new cookie store into a variable, so I'll create a
variable for store and that's a sign of the value of sessions, not new cookie store.
Wait, you didn't find.
Try that against Sessions.
I guess I have to go get guerrilla sessions.
I thought I did that, but apparently not so with the my app directory.
I'll just type.
Go get GitHub dot com slash guerrilla slash sessions.
In the map directory, so it goes and gets that perfect.
Now I should be able to import sessions.
Sessions dot.
New Cookie Store right there.
And that requires the slice of votes.
And we're just going to cast our key to a slice of votes.
And that gives me a story.
Then we said it's max age, Startraks age, and of course, that's max age, which we defined just a
couple of lines ago.
And options stock options will use the route path of her application, so it's good for the entire application.
Listed options dot HTP only we're going to set that to true, so it's not accessible from JavaScript
because it shouldn't be in the last one is secure.
Stock options dot secure and I'll that defaults for development equals false just to get it up and running
and in production.
Of course, you're going to have some variable that sets that to true when you're live and false when
you're in development.
But that's easy enough to implement.
So now we just tell Gothe and the key for this is Gothic.
Don't store.
Is equal to T.
And it looks like I have a typo here as well.
I don't know why I do that so often, but I do sometimes equals
and its options pass.
A really sloppy to that.
There we go.
So this session store, which is actually using a cookie, it only exists for the duration of the logging
process.
And that's not made abundantly clear in the documentation for Gothe.
But that's something you need to be aware of.
We need a session and we can use some other session, but this only needs to exist for the duration
of the time that the user is attempting to log into your site using Google or GitHub, or whatever it
may be, and then we don't care about it anymore.
So this is sufficient for our purposes.
So that's the first step.
The next step is actually to implement a handler which will call something like social login, which
will attempt to log the user in using some kind of social media account, and we'll get started on that
in the next lecture.