So in order to get things working, I mean, so far, we have the in its social off and we're going
to have to use that every time we log into some, some social sign on service, we'll be calling this.
But obviously, we need a handler to start it.
Let's put a stub handler in here for now.
So a function with the receiver of H pointer the handlers and we'll call this one social logging OK.
And like any handler, requires the response writer, which I'll call w the response writer and a pointer
to a request right there.
OK, so we're going to have to have that.
And if you recall, one of the things we specified up here was the callback for whatever provider we're
using.
So we're going to have to have another handler function here.
It will be a handler, in fact, and I'll put a stubborn h pointer to handlers and this one's called
social took out to spell right?
Social media callback like that.
And it requires a W Dot response writer and, erm, as a pointer to HDP request.
And we'll deal with that one later on, but we're going to need it before too long.
So what'll happen is the user will attempt to log in by clicking on, say this button over here, log
in in Log Inkjet, logon to GitHub so they click on this and that calls this route.
Slash author slash GitHub question mark provider equals GitHub, so we're passing along a URL parameter.
And, of course, that you, Earl, will link to this handler, social logging and social logging,
of course, is going to have to in its social auth and then do some magic so we can get started with
this part anyway.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to grab that parameter right over here again in logging
yet.
I'm going to grab this parameter GitHub.
The value is GitHub.
The parameter is called provider because I'm going to need that later on when I try to log someone out.
Because when I log someone out of my site, if they've logged in using social off, I want to log them
out of my site.
But I also want to log them out of, say, GitHub in this case, OK?
Log them out of this site on GitHub.
So back here, all handlers.
Let's get that parameter.
Now, if you'll recall, we're using the Chy router, so I'll get a variable called provider and get
the value from G.
Our router package.
Dot URL per annum.
Which should show up.
There it is.
And I'm looking for a provider and I need to save that somewhere.
I need to give it its other parameter, though, which of course, is the request.
That's better.
I'm going to save that provider in the session.
So each Dot app dot session, whatever session this application is using, I'll put in using our context
as the first parameter, and I'll call this one social underscore provider, so I'll need that later
on to log, the user wrote.
And I'm putting provider in there.
OK.
And now in it, my social authentication, and that's easy.
It's just h dot in its social life.
We're done OK with that part.
Now, what happens when I call in its social life is I've set up my providers and now I need to call
a method in the gothic package called complete user authentication, and I'll do it using an if statement.
Just to make sure that I check to see that things work as expected.
So if I don't care about the first return grammar, but I do care about an error, those are populated
when I call Gothic, which is the God's package complete user off.
And that requires the response writer, which I call W and the request, which I called, erm.
And then I'll check to see if the error is equal to nil, not not equal to nil.
But if the if there is no error, then I want to do something because in fact, what's actually happened
here is user is already logged in.
So they've already logged into this site using this and and we have no problem letting them continue.
So we'll just say a redirect.
And we'll give them W and her take them to the home page, wherever you want to put them, you just
take them there and we'll say about status, see other.
OK, so things are good, but if there is an error, then we have to attempt to log it, so we'll attempt
social login.
Those are the two possible cases, either they're already logged in on this site using social authentication
or they're not, so we have to try to log them in.
And we do that by calling Gothic don't begin off handler, and that requires the response writer and
the request.
And that's it for this social login function.
Now this will all work really well until the point when GitHub in our case tries to call this.
You are all back and saying, Well, here's my callback results of what happened when the user tried
to log in, and we need to implement that.
And of course, we need to set up some routes as well.
But we'll get started on this bit.
Social media callback in the next lecture and then we'll take care of the roots after that.