So this time around, we want to work on the social media call back handler.
And just as a reminder, this handler is called after someone attempts to log in on GitHub or Google
or whatever the social provider happens to be.
So someone comes to the login screen, they click on log in using GitHub, and that calls the social
login handler, which checks to see if they're already logged in.
If they're not, then this method begin Auth handler gets called.
That takes them off to the login sequence for GitHub or Google or whatever the provider is, and the
results of that are sent back to this handler social media callback.
And this is the one we want to handle.
Now this will take a little bit more work, but the very first thing we have to do is call each dot
in its social life.
OK.
We need to make sure that initialized and ready to go.
So we do that.
After that, we call something called complete user auth from Gothic.
So we get the results from that.
The Gothe user, which I'll call G.G. user like that and potentially an error.
And those come from calling Gothic Dart complete user off, and that requires the response writer and
the request.
OK.
And we checked for an error if error is not equal to nil and something went wrong.
So we'll put an error message in the session.
Each app dot session dot put and look good in using the context or context.
We'll call it error, so it'll be picked up by our nice error message logic in the templates and we'll
put in the error.
Error dot error.
OK, so we put it in the session and we redirect the user back to the login screen because that's almost
certainly what the error is.
HTP don't redirect and we'll just redirect using an error.
Take them back to the login screen, which is users log in with a message status issue, repeat status.
See other OK.
And at that point, we don't want to go any further, so we'll return.
But assuming we get past that, we now have this variable user.
So.
We have a user, but the user may not exist on our system yet, and if they don't, we need to create
a user on our system that has the email address associated with whatever account they use to try to
log in.
So what I'll do, first of all, is try to look up the user look up user using email address.
That's how we track our users.
So I'll create a user variable value of Typekit data, don't user, and I'll put a test user variable
as well.
And that will be a ver test user.
That's what I'm going to call it, and it will be a pointer to data user and you'll see why at a moment.
So those are my two variables.
So my first one is actually my second one.
But you get the idea is to just use it that is now populated and we'll check for an error when we call
you the variable that I created on line three hundred and twelve.
You don't get by email.
That's the only reason I created that variable is so I can call the method on it.
And the parameter to that has to be an email address.
And I get that from G user what was given back to me by whatever my provider was, G users email.
OK.
And I'll check to see if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil in this case, the error may
just be that the user doesn't exist.
So just to see what's going on?
I'm going to say long, dark print line.
Now print out the air just so I can see what it is.
And then we'll get the provider from the session, OK, so provider that is assigned the value of each
Dot app, dot session, dot get and I'm going to get using the context or context as usual.
And I'm looking for the key social underscore provider.
And if you recall, we set that, I think it was last lecture.
OK, and we're going to get that in, then cast it to a string.
And at this point, I can assume we don't have a user, so add one better put a space in there.
Otherwise that would bother me endlessly.
So will create a new user, ver new user.
Of type data, don't user our own type.
And we'll put some information in here.
Now I need to actually check what the provider is.
So we'll know what information to put in because as I said, we're going to be supporting two social
logins in this course.
GitHub, which gives me information in one way.
And Google, which gives me information in a different way.
And right now, I'm just going to check for GitHub and we'll take care of Google later on.
So I'll see if provider is equal to GitHub and do something otherwise do something else.
OK.
And we're going to leave this one empty for now, but we'll take care of GitHub right now.
So what I'm going to get from GitHub when they give me information back, they're not going to give
me first name in one field, in the last name, in another.
They leave those two fields, which exist in Gothe data type but don't exist in GitHub dictator type.
They just give me one field code name, and sometimes that has one name.
Sometimes it has two names, but I'm going to just try to make it as simple as I can.
I'll explode what they give me, so I'll splitting.
In other words, that I'll split it on spaces, so I'll create a variable called explode, which I have
to spell right.
And that is assign the value of from the strings package.
I'll call Split.
I'm going to split the value in the user name on spaces.
OK, so now I have that and now I'll just populate my first name and last name field in my data dot
user type.
Based on the values I get from exploded, I know I'm going to get at least one.
OK.
So I can say new user first name will be equal to exploded at position zero, the first value.
And then I'll check to see if the length of exploded.
If that's greater than one than we have at least two.
OK.
And just for simplicity, I'll say new user.
Typekit last name is equal to exploded one.
So the second position index one.
That we all have a first name and a last name in there somehow.
Otherwise, I'll just leave this empty for now and we'll deal with that when we get to Google.
Now let's populate the rest of the information we need.
So after this if statement, I'm going to say new user active is equal to one.
It's an active user.
And I'm also going to specify a password, and I'll tell you why in a moment, but let me do it first.
So new user password is equal to and I'm just going to generate a long random string of characters each
dot random string and I'll make it 20 characters long.
OK, now the reason I'm doing this is we finally got a user in our system and I don't want to lose them.
So they registered using, say, Google or something like that.
And then they decide to delete their Google account down the road and then come back to your site and
say, I want to get into your site, but I don't have my Google account anymore.
Well, this way they can actually recover their password and reset it to whatever they want.
So they're not recovering their password, they can initiate a password reset request and reset it to
whatever they want so they can log in either using their Google account or using the account we're creating
right now.
OK.
That's just a simple way to get around this problem.
Other things I need new user created up, and that's equal to time Dot now the current time and date
and new user dot updated at that school.
Updated at.
That's equal to time dot now as well, OK?
And now I'll try inserting a user.
I don't care about the idea that I get back, but I do care about the error that comes from new user
dot insert.
And I'm going to insert new user and I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then something went wrong.
So I'll just say 8GB the error.
W with the error, error, error and HGTV status, bad request, which is sufficient for our purposes
and of course, you can do whatever you want in there and I'll return, you might want to put an error
in the session, redirect them back to the log in screen, whatever the case might be.
So assuming we get past this, I can now say test user and potentially an error which I'm going to ignore
and you probably don't want to.
But it's almost certainly not going to be an error because we just inserted the user successfully get
by email and that would be G user dot email.
And the only reason I'm getting that is because once I get outside of this if statement.
I actually want to lug the user into my system, so I'll delete this blank line.
Come outside of this if statement and now log the user in.
And if you recall, that's as simple as setting a few sessional variables each dot app dot session dot
put out context.
The first thing I'm going to put in there is User ID, which will be test user ID.
And then I want to put in the social token, and I'll talk more about that later.
But we do need this, OK, so I'm going to put in something called social underscore token that goes
into the recession and that's actually coming from the user variable.
This is the the fourth token we get back from GitHub or Google G user access token.
OK.
And the last thing I want to put in there is their social email, which I'm going to call social underscore
email, and you'll see why in a little while.
For right now, let's just go with G User's email.
So now I have their User ID in the session, which makes our application know that they're logged in.
We have this social token, which will have to use later on.
Not right now in this lecture, but later on we'll be using it.
And we also have their social email, which we stuck in there as well.
OK.
And after all that happens, we do a redirect issue to redirect and redirect using W and our goal.
Just take them to the home page.
You can take them whatever you want with A2DP status.
See other and you might want to put a success message in the flash of using the flash keyword for the
session.
But this is sufficient for our purposes.
OK.
So with all of this, I should now be able to go and create the appropriate values on GitHub.
Get the secret.
Get the key.
Specify the callback URL.
Once we do that and add a couple of routes in our roots, file that point to the correct locations.
We should be good to test this out and see if we can log in, and then we'll have to figure out how
to log out, which is surprisingly much harder than it seems if you read the documentation on the Gothe
GitHub page, but we'll get to that shortly.