So before we go over to GitHub and set up our secrets and key and all that sort of thing, let's set
up the routes necessary to hook our handlers up to the appropriate URLs that are offering.
So if you look at log in, check those two buttons that we have here have very similar URLs.
It's slash off slash GitHub and then some query parameter, and this one is slash author slash Google
and then a query parameter.
So let's go over to our roots file.
Let's add a couple of routes here, so we'll add, first of all, the one that the button is hooked
up to.
So we'll put in eight app operates Dot, and yet this is what happens when they click on the button
and the URL is slash off.
And then some provider, then we could just use Cheez Placeholder like that so that URL will link to
a dot handler's dot social plugin.
OK.
And then of course, we need one for the callback when we go or take it off to GitHub, GitHub authenticates
users and calls back to some.
You are up.
So that's 8Ot app dot roots.
Don't get.
And it's a get request, do you think it was a post request, but apparently it's not slash off slash
and then provider again and then just slash colbeck.
And that is connected to Adolf Handler's social media callback like that?
OK, now before too long, we'll be adding another route here to log users out.
But for right now, we can just work with these two and try logging people in.
All right.
So the next step is to go over to GitHub and set up the appropriate things to get a key and a secret.
And we'll start that in the next lecture.