So the next step is to go over to GitHub and get her key and her secret and that sort of thing, so
we can actually try out logging in and then add that information to our on file.
So I'll go to my web browser and I'll go to GitHub dot com and make sure I'm logged in and then I'll
go up here to the top right and click on my profile or icon and go all the way down to settings.
And that takes me to a long list of possible menu items here, and then what I want is near the bottom.
And it's called developer settings, so I'll click on that.
And there are three things here.
GitHub apps, we're not using that, OK?
We're not going to build an app for an iPhone or Android device.
We want an off app because we're using authentication and you will click new or app.
And you can see I have several here that I was use for testing and so forth.
I've already created one.
You cook a new one and we'll ask you some questions and you would just want to authenticate using a
web page.
And when it comes up, it'll look something like this.
OK.
And what you're going to do is generate a secret, and it may have a default secret here, depending
on how your account is set up.
But if doesn't just generate a new client secret, so we get two things we need here.
The first one is this our client ID.
I'm going to copy that.
I'm going to switch back to my I.D. and I'm going to open the doors on file in my app, so I'll open
doors in my app.
I'll go to the very bottom of the file here and I'll add a new entry.
And the first one is going to be called GitHub.
Make sure you spell this right.
GitHub underscore key.
And that's the value I just copied.
OK.
And then we'll have GitHub.
Try that again.
Git Hub underscore secret.
I'm not going to show you my secret because I don't want to reset it, but I'll put it in there in a
minute.
While you're not watching and then GitHub underscore callback.
Now, if you recall, these three values are read by our application when it's when it creates the providers
list for Gothe.
OK.
So my callback, I can put that in here.
It's a deep colon slash slash local host port four thousand so colon four thousand slash auth slash,
GitHub slash callback and double or triple.
Check your typing to make sure you don't have any typos in there.
OK.
So those are the three values.
Now you only have to come over here and get your client secret.
I can't see mine anymore because it's protected that way, and I can't delete it until I generate a
new one.
But I already have mine copied and put into a secure password manager, so I have it and I'm going to
put that in there.
So once you have all that set up up here, you're going to have to give your application a name and
give it a home page URL and its callback URL.
And you can put that in here exactly as you have it in your development application.
And of course, when you go live, you would change that to a different URL, one that presumably is
using GPS and doesn't begin with the word local host for development.
This will work perfectly.
So get that all set up.
Make sure you put your secret over here in your own file and just check the typing very carefully to
make sure you have everything right because one little typo will make sure that nothing actually works.
OK, so once you have that set up, it's time to try logging in and we'll do that in the next lecture
and see what we got wrong.