So we should be able to try our log in process right now.
And there's a couple of things I need to set up before I do that.
If you recall over here and off handlers, we're actually using the session, so I should probably try
to configure the session before I try to do anything.
Now I already have in my Docker compose reddish running, so I use Redis for the session.
And if you don't have that, you probably should enable it as well just to make sure things will work
properly.
So I'll open the door on file and that's in my app and I'll specify my retest hosts, which comes right
out of the Docker, compose its local host port six three seven.
Not the default Redis port and down here at Line forty two in my dot on file or specify when I read
my session type to be read us our ideas.
OK.
So that's the first thing I'll do.
Now let me go over and look at my database and make sure I have nothing in the user's table.
So in the Solaris host database under users, I have nothing.
Perfect.
And the last thing I'll check is over in my web browser, in my GitHub account, I've looked at my oath
applicant application for this and I have no users at the moment.
So now I should be able to go over here and see what we got wrong.
So I'll go back to my I.D. and I'll open my terminal.
Make sure I'm in the My App folder I am and take me make start.
Well, we.
That's a good sign.
So let's go back to our web browser and try this out, so I'll go to a new tab and I'll go to localhost
four thousand and I'll go to the users menu and choose a login.
And now I should be able to click on login with GitHub, and something should happen.
So it took me over to GitHub, that's so far, so good, and it says, should I authorize this?
Now I've recently entered my GitHub password when I revoke tokens, so it already knows I'm, I am who
I say I am.
But if you haven't done that, it'll probably ask you to log in.
But I'll click, authorize and see if our callback works as expected.
So here.
You did the redirect, and everything seems to be the way it's supposed to be.
But let's see what we have in our log file.
So I have an error somewhere in the air is.
Invalid memory address or null pointer D reference, that's one of the worst errors you can get because
it's pretty much a catchall, but it says it takes place online.
Three hundred and forty four of art handlers.
Let's see what that is.
So this is what I'm trying to put something in the session.
Now, why is it doing that?
Social media callback as the handlers pointer as its receiver, and it is a handler, so there's no
reason why it shouldn't be doing that.
Now this calls in its social office and in its social office is up here.
And it also has the handler.
We're not storing anything in the session there.
That seems a little odd.
I'm not sure why it's doing that.
Well, let's go back and look at our report on file and make sure we type things incorrectly there.
No, that looks OK.
So let's go back here and look at both handlers again, see if we missed anything, I'll just close
my terminal.
So let's just go through this logically, social media callback calls in its social life.
I know that works, or I never would have seen that authorized user screen from GitHub.
And then I get my big user, which should be fine because it's calling it back.
And then I check to see if the user exists in the database and the user doesn't exist in the database.
The first time through because I'm on my database was empty.
So let's look at our database.
And I'll refresh this, and there I have Trevor Salter.
No email address.
Well, that would cause it.
So somewhere here, I forgot to put the user's email address in when I insert the user.
So I'm setting new user active.
I'll just put it right here.
New user email, you're going to be equal to and I'm going to get it from G User Dot email.
OK, so the problem was since we didn't actually insert a user with a valid email address when I tried
to get the user down here at line three hundred and forty two couldn't find that user at all.
So I'll stop the application make stop clear the screen, go back to my database, delete that one entry
that's in there.
So that's gone.
And then I'll go back to GitHub on my web browser and revoke any tokens that are there will refresh
that.
Revoke all user tokens.
Yes.
So that should go back to zero and git.
All right.
Now let's go back to our I.D. and start the application again.
Try it one more time.
Make start.
OK, so it's running back to my Web browser.
Go to local host four thousand.
And let's try this again.
Users log in, log in with GitHub, authorize that user.
That's better now when I go over here to my old North applications and refresh this screen, it should
show one user and it does.
When I look in the database, I should be able to refresh this.
And there's all the necessary information.
Perfect.
So now we can log in.
But of course, we also want to be able to log out.
We'll get started on that in the next lecture.