So we've managed to log in successfully using GitHub, and that's really good and everything seems to
be working properly.
In fact, if you go to the users menu now that I'm logged in, I have that log out showing up.
And of course, that links us to logging out of the application, which isn't enough.
We also want to log the user out of GitHub.
So if we go back and look at our ID and we look at the based git, which is found in the My App application
in the Views folder under lands, this part right here, around 150 or so this does a little check.
If the user is authenticated, then it shows the dropdown item which links to users.
Log out.
If we go to our roots, file over here.
We don't have a user log out, so we probably should put that in there.
So Ada app dot roots don't get.
And the pattern is slash and users slash log out and that links to ADA handlers dot log.
OK, so the next time I restart the application, I'll be able to log out.
But if we actually look at that method, which is in the art handlers don't go, all that does is it
checks to see if there's a Remember token.
If that exists, it deletes it.
OK, then it deletes our cookie if that exists.
And, you know, if you're logging out, presumably it does.
And then it removes some things from the session and it does the renew session, which you're supposed
to do any time you're changing authentication status and redirects the user to the log in screen and
it doesn't log us out of GitHub.
So let's go back over to our web browser and look at that gothe package.
And I'm on Mark Bates dot goth right here, and I'm going to go to the Examples folder and I'm going
to go to Maine Dot Go and I'll search for a logo.
See how you do it here.
Hello.
Oh, you two right there.
So it says all I have to do is call Gothic Dot Logout with a request of the response and the request
response writer and the request.
I can do that.
So let's go back to our I.D. and I'll do it right here after I check to see if the user is logged.
If the user has a remember token, so I'll call Gothic dot longer than that wants the response writer,
which I call W and the request pointer to HCV request, which I called her OK.
So that tells me it throws an error, so I'm his will handle here, so error is assigned the value of
that, and then we'll check to see if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll just say Logcat print line.
I shall use the built in error logging eight short app error log dot print line.
Try that again.
Print line and I'll just print out the error.
OK, and I'll keep going.
Because if there's an error logging out, I still want to actually log the user out of my application.
So in theory, this should all work.
It's not going to, but in theory it should.
So let's try to make restart and see what happens.
So their application has started.
Let's go back to your web browser and find the celebrity's tab and reload the page.
Make sure I'm still logged in.
I am OK and if I look at my GitHub a settings and refresh the page for that particular application,
it shows me I have one user logged in.
Perfect.
So let's log at log.
And now in theory, I'm logged out and I am logged on to my application because I don't see the log
out menu item anymore.
And if I go back to my GitHub page and refresh this, I'm still actually logged in.
So if I log in with GitHub again.
It just takes me doesn't take me to GitHub.
So you're already logged in, so what's happening there?
Is it's checking with GitHub to see if the user is currently authenticated and yet you're still authenticated,
so you're good.
So apparently this code right here, gothic log out doesn't actually log me out of the system out of
GitHub.
Now, if you actually download that example code that is provided on Mark Bates Goss and run that application
after removing all the things that are not GitHub in the sample code and try that it'll actually work,
it will log you out of GitHub.
At least they did when I tried it.
But it does that because it's actually using that temporary cookie, that gorilla cookie gorilla session
that uses a cookie store and any serious web application is not going to be using a cookie store.
It's going to be using something else.
So we actually have to do some more work.
We actually have to look at GitHub API and figure out how do I longa user out of GitHub without relying
upon Mark Bates slash goth guerilla sessions cookie, which we're not actually using.
As far as we're concerned, it's only exists for the little period of time when someone is actually
authorizing their GitHub account to be connected to our application.
And then it's gone as far as we're concerned and we have no access to it, so we'll actually have to
read a little bit of code.
Now it's not terribly difficult and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.