So this time around, what we want to work on is logging the user out of GitHub when they log out of
our application.
Now when I say log it of GitHub, it's not actually logging you out of GitHub in your normal GitHub
bbc.com web browser, you visit GitHub.
After logging out, you'll still be logged in.
If you were logging in before, but you'll no longer have access to the web application using your GitHub
account.
So we tried it this way.
Using Gothic don't log out in our log out function.
That handler inside auth handler stuck out and it just doesn't work.
So what we need to do is to use the GitHub API and we need to do this for a couple of reasons.
So I'm over here in my silver toss application.
I'm currently logged in using GitHub, but if I log out, it does log me out of the application.
But if I click again, it immediately logs me in without having to authenticate through GitHub.
And that's a bit of a problem.
It's not a big deal if it's on your personal computer inside your house.
But what if someone accesses the site using GitHub from a shared computer, something in a library or
something like that?
Well, the next user that comes up and clicks on that button will automatically be logged in, and that
is a bit of a security nightmare.
So to fix this, what we're going to do is look at this documentation, which I've already read, and
I'll put a link to this in the course resources for this lecture, and it gives you all the information
you need for how to make calls to GitHub and do certain things.
And all I really want to do is to log out.
So let's go back to our code and let's delete this function or these lines of code entirely and call
a function that doesn't exist.
So I'll call one that's not exported, called social logout, which doesn't exist yet, but rather to
make it.
And that's going to take a response writer and the request.
OK.
And it doesn't return anything.
So we're just going to call that.
So now we'll go to the very bottom of this file and I'll create this function.
You can put it anywhere in this file, but I'm going to put it at the bottom.
So I'll create a function with the receiver of H put in a handlers and it's going to be called social.
Log out like that and it takes W, which is initiative response writer and error, which is a pointer
to each CDP to request just like any handler.
OK.
So that should take care of the air at the top where this function didn't exist.
Now we need to do something.
So the first thing I need to do is determine what kind of provider we used to log in.
And of course, if you recall, we stored something in the session called social underscore provider
and we just a string.
So let's get that.
So we'll call the variable.
We're going to build provider and we'll check for an error.
OK?
Just by calling each Dot app dot session.
Not yet.
And we give it the context and context as usual.
And then we're looking for social underscore provider, make sure you spell it right.
And when we get it, we want to cast it to a string.
OK.
And if OK is not true, so if not, OK, can't find that in the session, just return.
So when someone's logged in the normal way using a username and password, when they try to log out,
it'll call this function, can't find social provider in the session, so it just returns.
So things just progressed as they should.
But assuming we do have an OK set to true, then we need to call the appropriate apple for our provider.
So remember, we're going to be supporting two.
And what we want to do is we want to revoke the auth token.
OK?
Each provider has different logic
for doing this if it exists at all.
And I strongly suspect that some of those various social authentication providers that are supported
by Gothe don't actually support this, but I'm only going to implement two and both of them do.
So what we'll do is we'll switch on that variable provider, which should only have two possible values.
The first one is the only one it's going to have right now.
Case GitHub.
OK.
So we're going to do something if it's GitHub, and then we'll have other cases.
But one other case at the end of the day.
So I've already dug through the documentation and figured out how this works.
And it's pretty straightforward.
First of all, I'm going to need the client ID. So I will call that Client ID, and I'm going to get
that from the dot on file.
OS don't get on.
And this is simply the GitHub key.
That's the client I.D..
OK.
And I'm also going to need the client secret, the GitHub secret.
So I'll call that client secret.
And this is just so we can authenticate against the API.
OS, don't get on GitHub secret.
So I'm going to need those two things, and I also need the token that the user received from GitHub
when they authenticated and we stored that in the session as well.
We called it social underscore token.
So token is assigned the value of each stop app.
That session doesn't get out of context, and the key is social underscore token, and we cast it to
a string.
So at this point, we have the client I.D. We have the client secret and we have the token that was
issued to the user when he or she logged in.
Now we just need to make a request to GitHub API Impasses and Jason.
So let's build the payload for the JSON, and it's dead simple.
I'll create a variable, which I'm going to call payload, and it's going to be a struct, and it has
one field access token.
OK, I'm type string and in JSON, that's going to be called access underscore token.
So there's my variable now it's populated with some content payload, the access token is equal to token.
Now, let's create a JSON request.
Joe called Jason RFQ a potential leader, which I'm going to ignore, and you probably shouldn't, and
I'll just mercial my value into Jason request.
So Jason Marshall?
Marshall right there, and I'm going to hand it payload.
Now I'll create a request, and it should be request and they'll check for error when I call FTP the
new request.
And this requires three parameters.
First of all, what's the method?
Well, GitHub API documentation says it has to be method delete.
So I'll use the constant from the HDD package called Method Delete, and it also requires the second
argument to be in the form of a string.
What do we call it?
And here's where we put our credentials in.
So I need to build a string, so I'll use the format as printouts function and my format string is t.p.s.,
colon slash slash.
And then my credentials, which are two strings, a placeholder and a colon and another placeholder
both of type string, then add API dot GitHub dot com slash applications slash.
Then another placeholder shall be my client ID, then slash grant.
And the substitution is for those are Client ID, Client Secret and then Client I.D. again.
OK, so that's my second parameter.
And the last part, of course, is the body.
And in this case, the body must be in the form of an Iowa reader, so will this create a bite start
new buffer and will hand it Jason e Chew?
And then I'll put my closing parentheses up on that same line, so it's a little more readable.
OK, so that builds a request that we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
I'll write it to the Log H Dot app dot error log dot print line.
The error and I'll just return can't go any further.
OK.
But if we get past that now, we'll create an HTP client.
So Client is assigned the value of a reference to agitprop client and we'll just make it empty and then
we'll use that client to make a request.
So don't care about the return value, but I do care about potentially an error that's equal to client
don't do.
And I just handed my request a review, which I built right up there in line three hundred and seventy
nine Chuck Vernier in error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll say print out the air.
The app error log dot print, one error logging out
of GitHub, and I'll put the error and I'll return.
Otherwise, we're pretty much done.
Now we'll obviously have another case here for Google.
We may as well put that in here right now and just leave it empty.
Case, Google.
And do nothing because we're not writing that right now, we'll do that later on.
But this should actually work for us now.
So in the next lecture, we'll try logging out and make sure that we got everything right.