So let's see if we got everything right.
Right now, we have our logout function and that's called when someone chooses, log in from the dropdown
menu on the web app and that will of course, delete a remember token if it exists.
And then it calls social logout.
And that is the one that will actually check to see if social provider exists in the session.
If it doesn't, it just returns.
And if it does, then in our case it should call GitHub API.
Let's see if we got everything right.
So I'm going to stop my application, make stop and restart.
It may start and I should still be logged in because I haven't logged in yet and my token doesn't expire
for 30 days.
So everything compiled.
Let's go back to our Web browser, and I'll just refresh the page to make sure its current look under
the user's menu.
There's my log in.
But first, I'll go to off on GitHub.
Refresh this page.
I have one user right now and I'll go back to my application and I'll try logging it and see if I got
it right.
OK, so I've logged out in my log out button or menu item is gone, so that's good.
But now let's go refresh this page over on GitHub.
We have zero users, and now if I try to log in.
It takes me back and asked me to reauthorize Perfect.
Now, just so, you know, the only reason I don't have to enter my username and password here is because
I'm already logged in to GitHub and another window.
And that's still active.
But if I do this back and forth, back and forth, logging in and logging out eventually, and it doesn't
take very long.
GitHub will say there have been an awful lot of requests to authenticate for your account, so I'm going
to ask you to enter your password in right now.
And that's just, you know, what's going on here.
All right, so let's move on and implement some of the similar functionality for Google.