So let's implement this similar sign on functionality for Google.
And you do that, of course, on the Google Cloud platform.
Let me go to the dashboard.
So if you don't have an account here, you can create one for free that just Google, the Google Cloud
platform and create an account.
And then, of course, you'll create a project I call mine blender because I haven't had to call it
something right here.
So create a new project if you don't have one.
And then, of course, you want to find the.
Both consent screen right here, OK?
And once you've got to the oath consent screen part.
You're going to want some credentials because without credentials, you can't actually do anything,
so over here on the left hand side, you'll see credentials, create some and you'll create some new
credentials.
Now I created some already and they're listed right here, and what you want are Oath 2.0 client IDs
and the one I want right here.
So I have this one.
And in here, you need to specify a few things.
And the way that Google handles things is a little bit different than the way that GitHub handles things.
So on GitHub, we're only allowed to have one callback URL or, as Google calls it, an authorized redirect
URL.
So of course, in development, you create one set of credentials for development and in production,
you just go to GitHub and create new credentials with a different callback URL, and you use that one
for production.
But Google allows you to have multiple you arise here, so you create one for a live site like this.
And one here like for development.
And this is the one we're going to use.
And I've already entered mine and you should enter something pretty much identical to what I have right
here.
OK.
And then up here you have your client ID and you have your client's secret.
And these are the things you're going to need to pay attention to.
Now there's no point in you trying to use this because I'm going to revoke this particular Client ID
and secret once this course is over.
Just go create your own mind will be useless to you in any case, because they won't exist by the time
you take this course.
But in any case, this is the information I need.
So I'm going to copy this big item here to start with.
Client ID and I'm going to switch back to my I.D. and I'm going to open my dot on the file and I'll
put three entries in here for Google.
Google underscore key will be equal to that value.
One.
Just copy, OK.
And Google underscore secret, let's go copy that and spark over here in my web browser.
The secret, I'll copy that value.
Paste it in here.
And get rid of the extra spaces, because that will mess things up.
And the last failure I need is Google underscore callback.
And that will be equal to a cheap, clean slash slash local host port, four thousand slash or slash
Google slash callback.
OK, so that gets the necessary values into our account.
And as I've said, I'll just say it again to avoid any potential confusion down the road.
Anything you see here next to GitHub qui secret and callback or Google key in secret?
These are my values, and they exist only while I'm creating this course.
And as soon as this course is over, I'm going to regenerate keys and have entirely new values and these
won't work anymore.
So don't try to use mine because it just won't work for you.
Initially, I said I was going to hide my GitHub secret, but after thinking it over.
That's actually not right because it undoubtedly appeared on the screen for a frame or two at some point
during this course, and it takes 10 seconds to generate new keys.
So I'm going to do that.
OK.
All right.
We'll move on and start modifying our code to support Google in the next.