So let's make the changes needed to implement logging in with Google, and we'll just worry about logging
in for this lecture and worry about logging out in a bit.
So right now, if you go over to your web browser and you have your application running this button
on the log in screen, logging with Google that appears in this file logging chat.
And it's this button right here with the label log in with Google and the route for that is slash auth
slash Google with some query parameter and then our roots file.
We already have that route covered right here that calls social logging because the provider bit in
curly braces can be anything.
So let's go over to social logging.
And here we grab the query parameter.
We store its value in the session.
And then we call in its social off.
And here this is where we need to uncomment scope and specify what kind of information we want to get
from the log in with Google.
And it's a bit different than it is with GitHub, but it's still a slice of strings.
In this case, we want to get email, which we absolutely have to have.
And we also want to get the profile just so we can get the users first and last name.
And then we need to add that a provider here in the U.S provider's method.
So we'll change this one from GitHub to Google.
I just duplicated that line to say some typing, and we don't want the GitHub key.
We want the Google key.
So we'll get that from the dot on file.
And same way we'll get the Google secret and the Google call back, and we'll change the scope here
to scope.
And that really should be it.
So now we should have a means of logging in using Google because there's nothing else required here.
When we get down to the social media, colbeck bid instead of getting the value of first name and last
name by exploding user name, instead, we just get the value right from user first name of new user.
The first name is equal to G User Dot, first name and new user.
The last name comes from User Dot, the last name and there shouldn't be anything else required.
So in the next lecture, we'll try logging in and see what we got wrong.