So let's try logging in with Google and see if we got everything right.
So the first thing I'm going to do is make sure my Docker images are running and mine are.
And then I'm going to log on to my database with my favorite Postgres client, look at the user's table
and just make sure it's empty.
I deleted the one entry that was in here before this lecture started, just so I know I'm starting from
a known location or known status.
Then I'll open my terminal window and type, make stop and clear the screen and make start.
And it looks like I have to do a go get, which is no problems long copy that
and paste it here.
We have to do that once in a while when we're working with multiple packages at the same in the same
project.
And I will type start.
So my application is running.
Let me go to my Web browser and I'll go to the home page just to make sure everything is current, go
to users, log in and I'll try logging in with Google and this should take me to the Google authentication
screen.
And it does, and I'm going to log in using this account and I logged now in theory.
There it is.
And if I go back to my database, we should see that I have my Gmail account, my first name and my
last name.
And we do everything looks great, so that works really well.
So the next step is to implement logging out of Google because I can come up here and choose a log out
once again logging out.
And then if I click Log in with Google, it takes me out again.
Now it appears that that might have worked.
But you know what?
I'm not an optimist, so I'm actually going to make sure that I manually call Google's API and say,
revoke that token because I just don't trust it.
It didn't work with GitHub, and it's not very difficult to implement.
So we'll take care of that in the next election.