So as I said last time, it appears that the logging out using Gothic, that the logo for Google actually
logs are set.
But it just appears that way, and I am not an optimist.
I always air on the side of caution.
So here are not handlers go in the function social logout.
I'm going to go all the way down to the case for Google, and I'll implement it, and it's just a very
few lines of code.
So the first thing I need to do is to get the token from the session, and I can just copy this code
from up here.
So I'll copy this.
From the case for GitHub and pasted here, now I have the token, and literally logging out of Google
manually is as simple as ignoring the return value, checking for an error and calling HDP right from
the standard library post form right there.
And that requires a URL.
So we'll use formatting as printout and the format string is GPS colon slash slash accounts dot Google,
which I got to spell right?
Dot com slash oh slash oh off to slash revoke with a question mark and a placeholder and a substitution
for that placeholder is the token.
OK.
And we pass nil as a second parameter like that, and that should do it for us there.
Now let's check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll just say H Dot App Dialog Dot Print Line and we'll print out
error logging out of Google and we'll follow the arrow and that should take care of it.
OK, now as far as I can tell, this should absolutely work, so we'll give it a try in the next lecture
and then move on.