So as I did last time before I test this, I'm going to delete the one value I have in the database,
so my users table is empty.
OK, then I'll come back and open my terminal and I'll stop the application and I'll start the application.
And this should compile without any difficulty.
Here we are.
It's running.
I go back to my Web browser and reload this page just to make sure everything is absolutely current.
There we go.
And now I'll try logging in with Google.
As you can see now, I'm not logged in.
And if you are, log out first, OK, so I'll log in with Google and I'll choose my Gmail account.
And I'm logged in.
Yes, I am.
And I'll look in my lawn file just to make sure everything is as it should be.
So back to my terminal looks good.
OK, now let's log it.
Users log at.
Now, let's go back and look at our log file.
No errors here, everything seems to be going as it should.
OK.
And now I'll try logging in again, and it should actually just take me back to the authentication screen,
the consent screen.
OK.
And everything seems to work as expected, and we'll sleep better at night knowing that token is revoked.
I may not have to do that, but as I said, I'm a bit paranoid when it comes to authentication and security.
All right, let's move on to the next section of the course.