Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about Jason concept.
Data exchange.
Then you start a project which interacts with the outer world.
It requires data exchange to make a project successful.
This interaction must be simple and efficient.
Data exchange is the process of taking data structured on the source Eskimo and transforming it into
data structures on a target.
This schema so that the target data is an accurate representation of the source data.
In simple terms, convert the data in the form at which the receiver understands there are many data
exchange formats like X-Men, Jason Ashjian and et cetera.
Among all, JSON has become ubiquitous for web applications.
What is Jason?
Jason, or JavaScript object notation is a lightweight format that is used for data interchanging.
It is based on the subset of JavaScript language and object isn't on older set of name and value pers.
It is mostly used for communication between backhands and JavaScript programs running in the browser,
but it is used in another kind of application as bill.
Now you can see an example of Jason.
Hard to use, Jason in Guoliang.
Golang Pearl Wines, multiple encoding and decoding APIs to brought with JSON, including from built
in in custom data points using the encoding JSON package data times, the default global and data times
for decoding and encoding J songs are as follows mode for Jason Boleyn's Int and load for JSON numbers.
Listening for JSON strings mean for JSON non value array as JSON array and map or restaurant as JSON
object.
Pass, Jason in Golden, Jason, is JavaScript object notation and goal and cannot use it in its original
format for this go and has provided an encoding JSON package in the standard library in goal language.
We use Extract to represent Jason, for example, in goal, and we create this right by the following
code.
You can see it light type employee extract, and in JSON, we create by the following code.
Now you can see these Sampat.
So we will use anchored in Jason Package to convert Jason into asteroid and asteroid into Jason.
For this, we will use two functions motion or encode convert golonka struct into JSON formats on Marshon,
or they could convert JSON into gold struct.
It is more like mapping the parameters, then conversion only data structures that can be represented
as valid JSON will be encoded.
JSON objects only support strings as keys to encode a go map type.
It must be of before map by the key type is read only the exported fields.
Those that begin with an uppercase letter of the airstrike can be encoded in JSON.
Cyclic data structures are not supported.
They will cause more side to go into an infinite loop, and pointers will be encoded as the values they
point to or not.
If the pointer is needed in order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish.
Then we will continue the content in the next session until next.
Mission goodbye.