All right so so far in this class we've done a welcome video where I commended you for embarking upon
the noblest of all endeavors you learned about my credentials I gave you course resources and then you
learned that there's going to be two teachers in this class and that I'm going to be learning alongside
with you and making sure that it's all taught well.
So it's clear to all of us which is is built for humans and we also had a big piece of you know including
humanity in everything you do.
And I'll just add an anecdote to that and the anecdote is the Harvard Adult Development study so you
could YouTube it.
It's a TED talk.
And so you know Ted Harvard Adult Development study and I spelled adult with an E.
Google probably fix it for me.
Thank you.
And so here it is.
It's a great TED talk and.
And that really emphasizes the importance of humanity and human relationships it's actually the number
one factor that correlates with longevity and fulfillment and meaning is having strong human relationships.
So we emphasize a lot of humanity.
Now we're going to drop into this new section learning tools and we're going to take a look at what
it takes to be successful as a student.
So we'll do that the next video I'll make this the introduction video and then we're gonna see how you
could change the speed on videos.
That's what the acceleration is going to be about.
You can speed him up slowing down.
Show you that if you don't know it probably a lot of you do but just in case there's somebody out there
that doesn't get students who say to me you know you talk too fast and I get other students say to me
You talk too slow for the same video.
So I'm gonna show you how to get the speed just the way you like it then well I'll show share with you
how to ask questions the best way to ask questions and where to go you know for a community of people
to answer questions.
We'll talk about some principles.
I'm not quite sure what that video is gonna be about.
I wrote it but right now I'm spacing on it and collaboration and exercises and anecdotes.
I'm going to share all that in here.
This will give you a basis for what it takes to be a good student.
How this class is going to be run I know is quite a bit of introductory material.
Feel free to skip it if you're not into it.
Maybe you're enjoying it and finding an interesting.
I think there's value not only in getting down to the nuts and bolts the brass tacks but also in thinking
about all of this material just from a philosophical humanitarian perspective.
I think that that adds value and will be a benefit to you.
This is stuff I've reflected upon for my entire life.
My father was a professor of sociology and I was steeped in this material and all kinds of interesting
theories grew up around the university.
And so you know I've got a lot of interesting perspectives.
You know I'd love to share with you about the continuum of ethics spirituality and maturation which
to me are the same thing that would be a cool thing to talk with you about at some point because nobody
else sees it the way or articulates it the way that I see it.
And I think it's you know much more intuitive and palatable than than Colbert's Theory of Moral Development
anyhow.
So that's that's where we're gonna be learn in this section.
And right now I guess I'll just share that piece since I did it.
So if you think about the maturation or if you think about spirituality or if you think about ethics.
Right.
A great framework for thinking about ethics is that it's a continuum.
And at one end of the continuum you have self-absorption you're only thinking of yourself you're completely
egocentric you are an anti anti-social right.
They call this actually anti-social personality disorder.
You only think about yourself you'll kill someone for your for their watch.
Yeah I like that watch you'll kill him take it and wanting you think twice about it.
You don't think of others right.
That's one end of the spectrum.
The other end of the spectrum is you think so much of others who don't even think of yourself.
So Gandhi it's OK if I die.
Martin Luther King it's OK if I die just so long as everybody else.
It helps everybody else right.
Buddha Jesus right.
Like spiritual figure is often way out here not thinking of the self thinking of others.
And often many spiritual pasts are about releasing the self so southern Pentecostal background.
My father my grandfather was a Pentecostal preacher you know in Christianity they say releasing my will
for Thy Will right and giving up the self giving up my will for thy will.
And so this is the path this continuum the spectrum from self-absorption to selflessness.
And it's the path of ethics and so the more that we make pro social behaviors the more we're thinking
of others the more we come out this way the more ethical we are not aligns with all of the ethical research
and theory and also actually aligns to the Harvard Adult Development study which says that when you
do things for other years others you're aligning with your nature and that makes you feel good that
makes you gives your life meaning and fulfillment that helps you live longer.
Like literally helps you live longer be healthier.
Right.
Taking pro social behaviors not just leaving trash but picking up trash even if it's not yours and throwing
it away not just leaving your shopping cart in the middle of the parking lot.
Hey somebody else can do it.
I'm giving people a job right.
Somebody else can deal with it right.
But pushing your car away like contributing to the social tribal community to which we all belong as
humans we're social animals.
So when you align with that social nature when you do pro social behavior you're aligning with your
nature when you line the nature.
Nature makes you feel good because nature wants you to do it.
Eating feels good.
Sleeping feels good right.
Reproducing feels good because nature wants you to do it.
Being social pro social when you're like that nature makes you feel good.
So that's the continuum of ethics right from self-absorption anti-social personality disorder to selflessness
taking pro social behavior.
That's ethics.
That's also maturation when you're born you're you know others have to take care of you.
You know you're not thinking of others so much but as you've grown mature you actually later in life
with the general timidity phase where you know you're just thinking of others because you realize oh
I'm not going to be here forever and I'll leave this nice for the next generation.
How can I help out others and leave this world as a kind good person who was beneficial to the pro social
the tribe.
And so that's that's the path of ethics.
That's the ethics that's math maturation it's also spirituality.
Any spiritual system worth its salt is going to teach you to focus more less on the self including psychology.
Right.
And that you'll be happier for it.
So that's a little bit about that.
That's an introduction to the section.
Learning tools in the next video we're gonna see what it takes to be successful as a student.