All right.
Sweet.
How do you.
We had this nice introduction I just wrote this little summary.
The spectrum of ethics maturation and spirituality from self-absorption to selflessness.
Now we're gonna talk about what it takes to be successful as a student.
And this is really important to know because you know it can feel overwhelming like there's this huge
mountain in front of you that you've got to climb and it can feel like I don't know if I could ever
get there.
I remember when I was young four years of high school seemed so long.
Four years of undergraduate and seemed so long.
Right.
And then owe me two more years in graduate school.
I don't know if I could do that.
I'm done with school so long it just seems too long now as I creep up on 50 you know it's like 10 years
to get a doctorate.
Nope no problem right.
Put me in solitary confinement.
Give me some books I'll see and give me a computer I'll see in ten years you know like I could do that
I could do it you know.
And and so it doesn't seem as as big as you get older but when you're young that mountain can seem big
such a big mountain to climb so much to learn.
And so how do you climb that mountain.
By the way I used to have teachers and you know this if you'd been in my other classes I've had teachers
like one teacher used to say drop by drop the bucket gets filled drop by drop the bucket gets filled.
And so every day this is how you succeed as a student.
You need to have grit and you need to have persistence.
And every day you just add a drop to the bucket.
So drop by dropped out buckets and get filled.
And after three days there's not going to be much in the bucket.
You've only added three drops.
And after three months you'll look in the bucket and you'll see man there's not much in there I've been
at this three months and I'm not that good.
I'm learning the guitar right now.
Maybe at some point I'll play some for you and it's slow going right.
But drop by drop.
I'm getting better.
And after three years you look in that bucket you guess what you're going to be like Wow.
There's there's some water in that bucket I filled that bucket some I've gotten some skills and so it
takes time.
But the way you get there is just drop by drop drop I drop you add you drop by drop the bucket gets
filled you fill the bucket drop by drop you fill the bucket and also had a teacher who would say persistently
patiently you are bound to succeed persistently patiently you are bound to succeed.
And so if you just keep with it and this is the research of Angela Duckworth and this is what makes
a student successful and what makes a student successful doesn't matter where you're born It doesn't
matter whether your parents were or we're not educated doesn't matter if you come from the good side
or the bad side of the tracks what makes a student successful is grit it's grit it's just sticking with
its purse persistence perseverance it's not giving up it's dedication and devotion to what are you going
to devote your life right.
You devote your life to something if you chew if you don't answer that question you are answering that
question.
It's much better to choose something to devote your life to what are you devoting your life to.
Right.
So when you devote your life you say I'm going to do this and then you do it every day and you add those
drops persistently patiently with perseverance and persistence.
Right.
You add those drops you keep going you get better and you get better and you get better and that's how
you succeed as a student.
You just have grit.
You don't quit.
You just keep going.
You don't give up and over time you're gonna get better and at times it can feel overwhelming at times
it could seem confusing but you keep working with the material.
I keep playing the guitar right.
And over time you start getting better.
You start getting better.
So that is research backed.
It takes grit to succeed as a student.
That's what makes students successful is whether or not they have that grit.
You just keep going.
So that's good to know.
Since you're a student you need to understand what makes students successful and it seems like there's
one more thing that I want to share about that.
So this is it.
I want to share an anecdote.
So one point in my life I was very interested in learning what enlightenment was.
And I'd read a lot about it and I realized that to get there from everything I read you know you needed
to meditate.
And so I decided that I was going to I was a bachelor I was gonna make this the number one priority
in my life.
And so every day I decided I was going to meditate one hour and then I also decided that if I missed
it one day I was going to make it up the next.
So if I missed meditating one hour one day on the next day I would meditate two hours and I did that
for seven years every day sitting for an hour with my eyes shut.
This is also that really destroyed period of my life whereas about as low as I think I could have gotten
without dying literally people were saying to me at that point in my life do you have cancer.
And so every day I meditated for an hour and I did that for seven years and is my number one priority
and come hell or high water if nothing else happened on that day I meditated.
And if somebody called me up at 7 o'clock and I had to meditate yet and they said hey I want to go to
the movies I would be like why I gotta meditate.
How about tomorrow.
Right.
And so I was just fiercely committed to every day adding that drop and that type of focus that type
of commitment if you have that focus if you have that commitment you could get through all kinds of
obstacles.
So if you make it your number one priority and then every day I'm going to do it I'm going to do it.
I'm going to do it.
You add those drops persistently patiently.
You are going to succeed.
You're going to succeed.
So Bill Gates and Warren Buffett were asked What is it.
In one word more than anything else independently they were asked this by Bill Gates his father and
both Bill and Warren responded.
The one word that's contributed the most to their individual success is they both chose the word focus.
Being able to focus on something.
So that's that's what it takes to be successful as a student.
I think it's important for you to know that as a student that you just have to keep doing it every day.
Right.
You do it every day and 10 minutes a day an hour a day is better than 70 minutes a week or seven hours.
You know on one day.
So a little bit every day is better than a lot.
Every now and then a little bit every day is better than a lot.
Every now and then.
So that's how you succeed as a student is just checking my clock.
Make sure this camera's not going to stop.
And I've put some resources here.
This is a little little picture I put together of Seven Habits of Highly Successful People.
And so this is a book by Stephen Covey and I just kind of paraphrase a lot of this stuff in my own words.
This is what Stephen Covey says it takes to be successful.
And then here's a link to the journey class so you can look on this platform from my course on leading
a successful life.
And it's called The Journey.
So if you're interested in more life skills to succeed in life just search on this platform wherever
you're watching this course for the course the journey or search the journey.
Todd MacLeod.
And that will bring up that course so you can enroll in that course to learn more skills to be successful
in life.
Because I've had to learn those skills and in a lot of people don't have them and the more you know
them the better you're going to be able to do.
All right.
So number one takeaway from this video is that to succeed as a student you just need to do it every
day and not give up.
You've got to have grit.
And if you do that you're going to get better and you're going to succeed.
That's what it takes to succeed as a student.