So now I already spoke to this.
But you're going to see how you can speed up or slow down these videos so if I'm talking too fast for
you you could slow this video down.
And if I'm talking too slow for you you could speed this video up.
I will often watch videos on to X and then you know if it's something that I need to slow down then
I slow it down.
After a while you're I'm a really good listener.
I'm not such a good reader but after a while you know.
Yeah right.
After a while your brain starts to figure out how to listen quickly so that works for me.
So I'm just going to open up this video here.
She opened this one because this is like the trailer for the journey and you could see it there and
if I wanted to I'm going to like my own video.
How do you like that.
And if I want to speed this video up I would just come here and I would click that and then I would
go to playback speed and I could go hey plays twice as fast or hey slow this down.
So that's how you speed up or slow down these videos which can be useful to you if you didn't already
didn't already know that that can be totally useful to be able to do that and you can go check out this
course healthier wealthier happier.
Right.
Who wouldn't want that.
All right.
See the next video.