So now we're going to see how to ask questions in this course.
And there's two resources I want to give you for asking questions and so the first resource resource
is the go Ling bridge forum.
And so the going bridge forum is a form of people who like to go programming language.
And this is the best place to ask questions.
So come in here and ask your question.
And there's many highly experienced top of the field go programmers who hang out in this area and and
it's a great place to ask questions.
So I'm going to add here.
Right.
Best great place to ask questions place to ask questions is the going bridge forum and we'll just put
that as a bullet point and drop in your.
So that's my number one recommendation for asking questions.
And then if you need to reach me so try to get your question answered first on the going bridge forum
or somewhere else and if the question isn't answered then you can reach out to me.
But these courses I've taught like literally two hundred thousand people on one platform and ninety
thousand people are you know like over two point six five.
Last time I added it all up million people have taken my courses and so when there's that many people
it's really hard for me to answer you know 100 questions.
That takes me all day I can't do it.
There's just not enough time in the day and I'm also you know tenured professor and I'm also a father
so unfortunately I wish I could sit down with each of you and answer each of your questions but unfortunately
I just find myself running out of time and then I feel bad that there's all these unanswered questions
and that's not my wish.
It's just the reality of the situation of teaching at scale like this.
And so really try to get your question answered in the Goodling bridge forum and then if that doesn't
work you could always hit me up on Twitter and there's a lot of people who follow me on Twitter.
So if you ask the question on Twitter and just go to this link right here if you ask the question and
tag me in it so you might say like I'm going to tweet and you might say hey at Todd.
So I'm tagged in it and that way it comes to my attention.
What is this.
And then you add a link to code or your question or whatever.
So I might not be able to answer the answer the question but a lot of people who follow me and like
right now have a ninety five hundred followers lot of people who follow me or go programmers or into
programming so you will often have other people answer the question other people chime in.
So those are the two best ways to ask questions is just first on the form going bridge and then also
just right there on Twitter.
And and please know that if I'm not able to respond it's not personal.
I totally wish I could respond to every one of the thousands and thousands of questions that I get and
I totally wish and want to be able to sit down and have a meal with you.
So maybe at some point in the future if I ever end up in your city we could do that or a bunch of us
could go out and get some dinner.
I've done that before I was up in Portland and a bunch of former students and I from these online courses
got together and is awesome.
So definitely reach out and say hi to me on Twitter.
I love hearing from people all hard.
I'll give you a quick reply.
I love connecting.
You know when people reach out to me often I'll follow them and be like oh yeah this is somebody that
if I'm ever in their town and then I'll tweet like Hey I'm coming to New York.
Anybody want to get together and grab a bite to eat more go out.
It's fun.
So connect with me on Twitter.
But when you have questions try that going bridge forum if that doesn't work tweet to me and tag me
in it and off and other people who follow me will answer it.
And if I can't I will try to answer them too.
Wish that wasn't the reality I wish I could be there for everybody.
But that's also not the way the world works.
It's not that's not reality.
So yes that's how you ask questions and hopefully at some point in the future we can grab a bite to
eat somewhere with some other students in whatever city you live in so definitely connect with me on
Twitter.
All right.
Next video we're going to talk about principles.