OK.
So I want to just speak to principles here for a moment and what principles represent me as I'm going
to teach you.
Let me see.
I'm going to teach you the principle.
Looking for the phrasing I used and it's right here there is the principle and I'm going to just uppercase
that because it didn't just pop out to me.
I'm gonna do.
There's the principle and there's the practice right.
And so we're gonna teach you the principle.
And Dan you'll be here when I finish recording the centrist stuff we're gonna teach you the principle
and we're gonna show you the current practice.
And so just an illustration of that.
Right.
Like Twitter recently changed and the.
And this is just to illustrate the principle is that you can tweet and the current practice is that
you come down here and you click tweet right.
But you know the practice by the time you watch this video might be that the tweet buttons up here or
the tweet buttons over there.
So we've taught you the principle here is the principle that you know that being able to tweet is possible
and then we'll show you the current practice like this is how you do it right now.
But things might change from the time you watch this video to from the time we record this video to
the time you watch this video the practice the implementation might change.
And so if it has changed you know the principal go and see if you could try to figure out what is the
current practice.
And so you could google it you could YouTube it.
Right.
Like how do you do it.
Now you could try to just figure it out on your own but if you can't figure out the current practice
you know on going bridge form or as tweeting and tagging me with a question if it's not easy to figure
out definitely give me a heads up that like hey this video is looking a little bit it isn't clear to
students anymore it's not applicable to students anymore.
You might consider go update it tell me to go update it go update it dog.
Just tell me to go update so.
So that's the principal the practice will teach to the principal.
We'll show you the current practice by the time you watch this video which will be later than the time
at which it is recorded.
The practice might be different.
Try to figure out the new practice if you can because you know the principal.
This is something that's possible.
Try to figure out how you do it now.
And if you can't figure it out by googling it you doing it or you know asking questions let me know
that there's a video that needs to be updated.
So that's what principals is all about right.
We'll teach you the principals and then the practice might shift a little bit but see if you can figure
it out.
If you can't let us know and we'll update the video.