All right.
So just a real quick note on collaboration here.
And so we create these courses and in this course it's going to be we are creating this course about
Daniel myself but we create these courses and then we move on.
Right.
Like I'm off doing something else learning something new.
Creating a new course.
And so the courses are really a collaborative process.
And I just wanted to invite that collaboration from you and let you know that we not only welcome it
but that we want it.
And so that collaborative collaborative process includes you letting us know if there's a video that
needs to be updated.
Just give us a heads up or also if there's something in the code that you think should be changed you
could submit a pull request to us and we'll take a look at that and hopefully get to that.
And if you wanted to be like even an administrator on one of the get hub accounts where you could accept
and reject pull requests you know our repos are backed up obviously.
So you know you could reach out to us and say Hey I'd love to be able to help facilitate this.
And you watch that that repo for the watch the repo for this course as Paul requests come in.
I could look at them and contribute to the community and also you know continue learning and see what
other people are thinking.
And so we welcome that collaborative process and that collaborative process can include let us know
when video needs to be updated and then also
offer code suggestions pull requests through get hub and moderate manage admin whatever they call it
right get have to accept reject pull requests.
So if you wanted to fill that role just reach out to me let me know and we get Addy in there to pull
into the code base.
All right.
So that's a collaborative process.
We not only welcome it but we want want that so that this course stays robust and good for everybody.
So please let us know if you want to help out any ways or just help out in those ways.
If you're interested in doing that.