So we're going to include exercises in this course hands on exercises really make a big difference in
learning material.
I've seen that over twenty three years being a college professor a university professor and so it's
really easy and tempting just to watch these videos and keep gone.
It's late at night and it's just kind of fun right.
But it's also really important to apply what you're learning.
That's going to deepen your learning it's going to quicken your learning it's going to allow you to
learn more efficiently and effectively so you'll learn quicker more efficiently and more effectively.
You're going to retain it for longer you're going to know it better so more efficiently more effectively
you will learn as Yoda said.
If you do the exercises right.
So the exercises are included for your benefit.
Feel free to do them.
This is obviously your course this is obviously your life.
You are in charge of your life.
You get to choose what you do.
You can go through this entire thing sequentially or you could pick and choose and jump over whatever
you want.
You do not need to do the exercises we are not assigning grade maybe this course is being used at a
college or university or some other class where that teacher will assign a grade.
But in this class as you and I write here you don't need to turn your homework into us.
Right.
The homework is there for your benefit.
So we'll have homework or we'll have we'll have exercises hands on exercises there for your benefit.
And we'll also include the solutions to those and we do that.
So it's a more robust course because we want to help you learn.
So if they're beneficial do you do them.
And if you don't feel like you need them feel free to step over them.
Either way works.
But that's what the exercises are all about.
Exercises are not required.
OK.
So that's that's exercises.