All right.
So we are at the last video in this kind of getting started section and just learning about the course
and the last thing I want to share is just about personal anecdotes.
And we already spoke about how students statistically research backed will do much better in classes
where they like the teacher versus classes where they don't like the teacher like Noda who needed to
research that.
But it's actually been researched and and so as part of that I will include personal anecdotes at times.
I've already done that some of this course.
And as an illustration of the collaborative process I'm always welcoming feedback to the classes and
I'm just going to add that in here providing providing feedback providing proof putting feedback on
how to improve the course.
One piece of feedback that a student gave to me one time was like hey todd love your courses but I'm
in a rush dude like I don't have time to hear about your friend Joe and what happened to him when he
was driving to work.
Like can you like just like teach me the coding stuff.
And I realized OK when I include personal anecdotes which which have a pedagogical value right they
have a reason for being in there because it allows us to connect as humans and allows you to get to
know me hopefully you like me if you don't that's OK I'm not for everybody but you know if you develop
that connection with the teacher if you get not only skills knowledge but also wisdom motivation inspiration
like all the data says that's going to be better for you in your life.
And so I'm here looking out for you.
I want this to be the best course possible this is what the research says will make it the best class.
So but personal anecdotes when I include them I will include them at the end of the video.
So if you are in a rush right.
If you're in a rush.
Generally speaking as much as possible try to include them at the end video and if you're in a rush
you could just like watch like I'm here I got learn to code.
OK I get to work.
You just watch the coding stuff and then occasionally at the end of video be like oh I got to tell you
about this.
I'll tell you that in the video.
And then at the end of the video all I'll tell you some personal anecdotes I will save my personal anecdotes
to the end of the video.
If and when we have any of those to share.
So that's that's that's anecdotes.
The reason we include them is research back plus I just like chat and at times and sharing what's going
on in my life.
And so that's that's what the anecdotes are all about.
And I will save them for the end of the video as much as possible.
So if you're in a rush you could just get through the cone stuff in the beginning.
All right ladies and gentlemen we have reached the end of this foundation of the class is 4 7 ten eleven
videos I hope it was worth your time.
Hope you're getting value out of this and I look forward to jumping into the course which we're going
to do starting in the next section.
It's gonna be awesome.
Daniel's going to be here with me and we're gonna have some fun coding and learning some skills so I'm
glad you're here.
If you watch all that interest stuff.
Hope you enjoyed it.
And yeah let's get started.
Let's get started could see in the next video.