So in this section of the course, what I want to do is take all the work we put into the last section
and add some functionality to the core celebrity's code that makes uploading a file to any file system,
including the local system on a server absolutely trivial to make it a one line command with an error
check, of course.
So something like this, and I'm just sticking this into a random handler just so you can see what the
code might look like.
Perhaps something like this error is a sign of the value of.
And this is going to show errors in my I.D. and just ignore that.
Here's the sort of thing I want something like a dart app.
Dart upload file.
So right from the celebrity's application, a command named upload file.
And that would take something like the request, the name of the field that we're uploading, say,
uploaded file and then what file system do you want it to go to?
So something like and we could get it out of the map and maybe even make it easier something like H
Dart app Dart.
You know you.
Like that leads to an air check.
So basically one line of code.
And of course, we're getting all of these errors because I'm referring to things that don't exist right
now, but hopefully you get the idea.
One line of code that allows me to pass just basically at the request, the name of the field in the
request that we're passing it, that has the file attached.
And then we have a file system you want it to go to.
And that's what I want to work on in this section.
So let's get started in the next election.