So in order to make things simpler, before we start writing the actual generic uploading code.
Let's go to the file celebrities don't go and just simplify the tape a little bit, so the file celebrities
don't go in the celebrities project.
And right here at the top of the file, we have this type of celebrities.
And right now, all of her file systems are stored in a map with an index of string and the contents
of interface, which could probably be file systems dot EFS.
But that's fine for now.
So let's instead add three or four new types, or 14 fields.
That's three, which will be a type as three file system Dot S3, and we'll add SFP of type SFTP file
system setup and obviously WebDAV
of Typekit WebDAV file system WebDAV.
And finally, meanwhile, I've type, you know, file systems document.
I o OK, so that way we won't have to pull our value out of the map and cast it to the correct type,
which doesn't bother me.
I don't mind doing that at all, but lots of people want to keep things as simple as possible.
Now we'll be down to the Create File Systems function, which I believe is near the bottom of the file
right here.
And in addition to populating the map file systems with S3, now we can say C Dot S3 is equal to a three.
And again, that's three that's better.
And down here, see, meanwhile, IO is equal to the Nile.
And here she is.
SFTP is equal to SFTP.
And finally, see that WebDAV is equal to WebDAV.
OK, that'll just make it easier for us to access the correct file system when we call our uploader.
OK, let's move on in the next lecture.