So now that we've added these four fields to our celebrity type and populated them in the Create File
Systems function.
Let's get started with the uploading code itself.
So I will go to the root level of the silver project and create a new file, which I will call upload
dgo.
OK, so my I.D. added my package declaration, which is perfect and what I'm going to do here is define
a function with a receiver of C type type pointer to celebrities.
And I'll just call it upload file, which I better spell right now in terms of parameters.
We're going to get the uploaded file from the request, so we'll need the request, which I'll call
our pointer to repeat that request and we'll pass that rate from the handler.
We're also going to need a destination string, which I didn't think about when I was kind of mocking
up with this function.
Signature might look like, where do you want to put it on the remote file system or the local file
system?
So destination, which would be a string?
We also need the name of the field to look for in the request.
So that rule, which is called field, both of those are string.
And finally, we want a file system now, you might think that you would want to pass, say, a pointer
to a file system dot face like that.
And you know, that doesn't generate any errors, but it won't work.
Remember, this is an interface and an interface doesn't care if it receives a pointer or if it receives
a concrete type.
So don't put the asterisk in front of that.
And that's a pretty common mistake.
And this function will potentially return an error.
OK.
So that's going to be my first function, and I'll return Neal here just so I don't have any compiler
errors.
And I'm also going to want to extract the file and save it in the temp directory.
Now, if you recall, we already have a function that does exactly that makeover in the Maya package,
let's find the handlers and find the get upload file system or get file to upload right there.
So all I'm going to do.
Is copping this entire function from my handlers.
Go back to upload, go paste it in here and give this the receiver of C pointer to slap us with that.
OK, so that's something that we'll just take the request, which will we'll call this function, get
file to upload from this function, upload file.
This one's not exported, so it's internal to the celebrity's package.
This is the one that people will call.
OK, so very first thing we'll do back up here and upload file is get the file name the full path to
the file name.
We want to move to some kind of file system.
So finally, and we'll check for an error, and those come from calling C Dot get file to upload, and
that requires the request and it requires the field name, which we called field.
OK.
And for some reason, they made this a response, right when it's supposed to be a request, that's
better.
And we'll check for an air if air is not equal to nil.
And I'll just use my error logging built right into celebrities, see the error log dot print line the
error and I'll return the error.
OK, but if I get past that now, I have the full path name of the file system.
Now when we call this function, we might be uploading to mean.
We might be uploading to an S3 bucket or we might be uploading to the local file system on the server.
So what I'm going to assume right now is that when I populate this last parameter in the call to this
function, I'm actually going to pass a pointer to the file system if I'm using a remote file system,
or I'll pass nil if I'm uploading to the local file system on the server.
And the reason I'm using pointers is if my last parameter is in fact a pointer, then I can pass nil.
If it's not a pointer, then I can't pass nil.
And we'll just be simpler if we check to see if S is equal to nil, which is exactly what we're going
to do right now.
So we'll say if FS is not equal to nil, then I'll do something.
Otherwise, I'll do something else.
So what am I going to do if FS is not equal to nil?
Well, that means I'm uploading to a remote file system, and that becomes as simple as this will check
for an error and will use EFS, which because it's not nil.
I know it's a pointer to a remote file system and I just call the method and I'm putting file name,
which I got right there on line 12 and I'm putting it in destination like that and we just check for
an error.
So I'll just copy this error checking code right here and paste it in here.
Now what if F's is nil?
That means I still want to upload the file.
I just want to put it somewhere on the server, and that's just OS Dot rename built right into the standard
library.
So error is equal to OS rename.
And I'm going to rename file name by that again name.
To a new destination, so format Typekit Sprint.
I'm going to put it in a particular location and when I'm going to put it in, of course, is destination
and path to base again, base it.
So that gives me my look, so rename actually just takes it from the temp folder, which is where we're
storing uploaded files and puts it wherever it needs to be on the local file system.
And again, we just check for an error so I can paste in my error checking code.
And that should be it, literally.
So if we come down here, let's make sure we have this one correct.
Right now, this is taking a field name that's taking a field name.
We're putting it in the temp directory.
Everything seems fine.
So that is pretty straightforward, but we're not done yet.
I actually want to put more logic in here.
For example.
I don't want a hard code, things like maximum size of uploaded files.
And I also should do a little bit of security checking.
Maybe it would be nice to limit upload spy file type.
We could go by extension, but I've seen far too many situations where someone uploads a file named
picture jpg, and it's actually some kind of script with the wrong extension.
So we're going to want to check for mime type, and we're also going to want to check for the maximum
file size.
We're allowing to be uploaded to our server and we'll get started on that sort of thing in the next
lecture.