So let's get started by limiting our uploads to a certain set of mime types, and we're going to do
that here and upload Echo now.
Eventually, we're going to add this to the dot on file and add it to our celebrity's configuration,
preferring now let's just get it working.
So.
At the bottom of this file in get files to upload, this is where we want to check the mind Typekit,
so we don't even want to save it to the server in the temp folder if it's a mine type that is not permitted.
Now there is some limited functionality in the base or the standard library that allows us to detect
type.
We used that a while ago with the HTTP Dart Detect Content type, but you never know what someone's
going to be uploading.
So what I'm going to do is open my terminal and clear the screen and make sure I'm in this Alatas folder.
I am now I'm going to go get this package, which is a pretty commonly used and well-written package.
It's at GitHub dot com slash Gabriel Dash, the seal vassily, which I'm almost certainly pronouncing
wrong, and I apologize if you happen to be watching this lecture Gabriel slash mime type.
So I'll go get that.
Now it's available to me, and this is a really good library for detecting my paper.
We're going to use that right here.
So what I'm going to do is at this point.
Right after I defer file clothes, OK, I'm going to create a variable called mine type with a capital
T. So it doesn't clash with the package name I'm about to use and I'll check for an error when I call
mine type dot and it should find it for me and I want to use detect reader.
Right here.
OK.
And my argument for that is just pile, which we created right at right up there in line thirty nine.
Now if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll return nothing in the air, an empty string in the air.
OK, so that gives me the mime type now after I've read the mime type and this is a really common mistake
that a lot of people run into when they just read part of the documentation.
What Detect Reader actually does is look at the first 512 bytes of the file or so just to figure out
what the mime targets.
Now, because I've moved forward in that reader, I actually have to go back to position zero.
So we have to go go back to start of file because right now that file is pointing to partway into the
file, and that's no good.
If you're trying to upload something, you will upload a file.
But if it's a picture, you won't be able to see it.
If it's a word document, you won't be able to open it, that sort of thing.
We want that to go away.
So we'll ignore the first return value, but we will check for an error when we call from the variable
file seek and we want to go to zero zero right at the beginning of the file.
And again, there's going to be an error check here, so I'll copy this and paste it in.
So at this point, I now have the mine type of file.
OK.
And what I'm going to do now is just hardcoded some mime types that I'm going to allow to be uploaded
and I'll just disallow everything else.
OK?
So I'll create a variable called valid mime types that I'll make that a slice of strings.
And I'll just put in image types, so image gif.
And by the way, on the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a link to the most commonly
used mime types, which I'm sure you could find on your own.
But I'm just going to allow images and PDFs.
So that's my first one, and my second one is image slash JPEG for JPEG images.
And then all the pings.
Image slash slash PNG and finally, PDFs application slash PDF.
So here's my slice of valid mime types, and I want to make sure that if the mime type of the file the
user is attempting to upload is not in this slice and not allow it.
OK, now unfortunately, GO doesn't have a simple method of checking to see if something is in a slice,
but it's pretty easy to write our own functions down at the bottom of this file or write a function
called in slice.
And it's going to take a slice, which is a slice of strings and a value which is also a string.
And it returns Boolean.
And all we have to do is say for ignore the index, look at the current item range through slice our
slice of strings and we'll say if item is equal to vowel, then return true.
It's in the slice.
Things are good.
Otherwise once we finish ranging through this return, false.
And up here, after I've declared that variable and I've received my mime type, all I have to do is
say if not in slice and my slice is valid.
Mime types, which is a temporary variable, will be replacing that with a configuration later on,
reading it from the dot on file.
And now I give it the current mime type, which is in mime type with a capital T. The variable we declared
dot string.
Now, if we get inside this if statement, that means someone tried to upload, say, a Microsoft Excel
file, something we're not allowing to be uploaded, so all we're going to do instead here is, say,
return the empty string and a new error errors doc new.
And I'll just put invalid file type upload.
That's enough for our purposes.
OK.
You can put whatever you want for an error message there.
So this, at least in theory, because we haven't tested it yet, should only allow this particular
function to accept gifts, JPEGs pings and PDFs.
And if anything else is uploaded, it just goes back and throws an error to the user.
OK, so let's move on.