So let's make configuring which mime types are allowed for file uploads a lot easier for end users,
because right now, if we deploy our application the way that it is, no one will be able to upload
anything except for images and PDFs, and that's no good.
So we'll start by opening the door on file in my app and I'll go near the bottom of this file and I'll
put it in here.
Permitted upload types.
Just a comment.
So the key will be called allowed file types and they'll be equal to a string.
And I do have to put this in quotation marks, so this probably won't work.
And I'll just put image, gif and then a car with no spaces.
Image slash JPEG and then another comma image slash PNG and then another comma and then application
slash PDF.
OK.
And what we'll do is read that and put it into a slice and add it to our configuration at system startup
time.
And we may, as will also put in the max upload size and just make that equal to one two four eight
five seven.
Six zero zero zero.
10 mins.
OK, so this is in bytes.
So now those are in the own file and of course, we have to do something with them.
So let's go back to the file.
Celebrities don't go.
Now, what I want to add is something to this type config.
So what I want to put in here is maybe something that's called upload config, so will define another
type.
I can put that in the file type Stargirl, but I'll put it here just for simplicity.
I'll call this upload config and will be a struct
with just a couple of members say aloud mime types, and that will be a slice of strings and Mac's upload
size.
They'll just make that an N64.
OK.
And now I'll add that to the field, which I call uploads of type upload config.
OK, now let's scroll down to where we populate this config type.
Right here, let's just add a comment in here that says file uploads, so I'll just declare a variable
called exploded, which I better spell, right, because I'm going to split a string, I'm going to
explode a string, and I'll do that by calling from the strings package.
Dot split right from the standard library.
And I want to split OS God, get on and I'm looking for a loud file types.
And I want to split that on a comma, OK, and then I'll create a variable mime types.
My which will be a slice of strings and I'll just range through exploded for underscore m for mime type.
They're populated by calling range exploding.
And would you say mine types is equal to append mine types?
OK, so that gives me the mime types that I'm going to be using momentarily.
Now let's declare another variable.
Max upload size of type in 64.
And we'll try this, we'll see if this in the next line, if Max and potentially an error come from
stricken 8y.
We're going to convert a string to an integer.
And we want to look at polls, don't get on max upload sites right there.
And if the error is not equal to nil, then we'll say max upload size is equal to and she's always before
10 megs else.
Max upload size is equal to what cast it to an int.
Sixty four.
Thanks.
Then down here, where we populate the config, we'll just add the field uploads and that will be equal
to an upload config.
That's the type we'll populate its two fields max upload size is max upload size and allowed mine types
is mine types.
And that should take care of all of the errors, so let's format this.
The last change is to go back to upload, go and find that variable valid mine types and get rid of
it not using anymore and instead read this from the config.
So it becomes See Got review, which is our receiver dot config uploads allowed nine times and then
down here.
Or up here.
This gets changed to see ducks and fig uploads dot.
Max upload size there.
Now we allow the users to specify how big the uploads can be and what mime types they want to accept.
So the next step is to create a handler and a page in my app and try this out and see what we got wrong
and we'll get started on that in the next election.