So I think we have our uploader pretty much where we want it.
There might be a few changes required, but we should be relatively close.
So let's give it a try.
If you open the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file you can download called Celebrities
Dash Upload, Dot Jet Dot Zip, download that file, unzip it and put it inside The View's directory
of your My App project.
It's a very simple file, so it's very similar to the one that we were using for the Choose Your File
system and upload.
But this one doesn't actually specify.
It doesn't have a dropdown list that lets you choose your file system.
So this will be the actions slash, upload and we'll have a handler that displays this page.
And then the handler that uses our new upload feature will be the post version of this this URL.
So get we'll just display the form and post will actually process the upload data, so get that in the
correct folder.
And then we'll go to our handlers file, which is right here and a lot of handlers and we'll put this
say near the top.
So to start with, I'll put it right after the home handler, a funk with the receiver of pointer to
handlers, and I'll call this one celebrity toss upload.
That's as good a name as any.
And it requires a response writer
and a pointer to a request.
OK.
And this is dead simple.
We're just going to have an error variable and we'll call each dot render and we'll give it W and R.
And the file we want to render is called Celebrities Dash Upload, and we're not handing it any data
at all.
So it's dead simple and we just had an error check if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll print it out after error logs.
Print line here.
OK.
So that's the one that will display the page, and that's not interesting at all.
But a more interesting one is this one func h pointer to handlers, and we'll call this post celebrities
upload
and again w HDP, the response writer and our pointer to HDP Dot request.
So what we want to do here is very, very simple.
We want to call error.
We're going to check for an error when we call H Dot App Dot Upload File.
And that requires the request.
It requires the destination string, which can be just an empty string like that and it requires the
name of the field.
Now if you go look at that celerity upload jet, the name of that field is actually form file, so I'll
copy that.
Paste it in here.
And it requires a pointer to a file system.
Now I just could just do this if I wanted to put Neal in there.
And that would be fine, and that would upload it to the local server, to our actually remote server
in production.
But you get the idea so would upload it to the temple.
But I want to upload this one to say my a reference to a short app S3 like that.
And that should put it on my Amazon file system.
OK, now that will do the upload, but of course, we're going to check for the error if error is not
equal to nil, and in this case, I'm going to include an else as well.
OK.
So if the error is not equal to nil, then I'll say print out the error, file each dot dot error,
log dot print line the error and then I'll say H Dot app dot session dot put.
I'm going to put an error message in the session and that requires urgent context and it requires some
name.
This will be error, so we'll show up at the top of the page appropriately and the error aired out here.
OK, belts, everything went right.
So all I'm going to do here is put a success message in each app.
The session Typekit put up context and the name of this will be flash, so it shows up at the top of
the screen.
And that's because there's logic in that template.
Celebrities upload jet that displays the message, but I'm sure you figure that out by now, and I'll
just say, upload, OK.
And of course, at the very end, I want to redirect them somewhere.
So I'll take them back to the same page they were on.
Repeat on redirect.
And that requires an hour and some path name.
I'm going to use slash upload, which is dead simple with some status issue report status, see?
OK, there we are.
So now we have her two handlers, so let's go to our roots and hook those up.
So I'll put it right here after the home Page Eight Get in my path will be slash upload and my handler
is a dog handlers.
The celebrities upload and I'll duplicate this changes to post.
And this would be post celebrities upload now if everything went according to plan, we should be able
to stop our application, start our application, go to localhost 4000 local host code and 4000 slash
upload and see the form and upload something.
And because I specified here in my handler that I want to upload to the S3 file system right there,
then it should show up on my Amazon S3 bucket, which of course, is on OneNote.
But same difference.
So we'll give that a try in the next lecture.