So let's give things a try.
I'll open my terminal.
I'll make sure I'm inside my my app directory.
I am, and I'll type make start.
So everything starts up, and let's go to our web browser and over here.
Remember, we're going to be uploading to my Amazon s three system, which is actually on A. In my case,
and I'm looking at my object storage and celebrities the name of the bucket that I have connected to
my app and there's nothing in there right now, which is perfect.
So if I go to the homepage of my site and go to filesystems list files and choose S3 bucket, I should
get nothing.
Perfect.
Now the moment of truth, let's go to local host.
4000 slash upload.
OK, so far so good.
Let's try uploading a picture.
So I'll choose this one called lorem dash blue dot pink, and I'll try uploading it.
And it says it uploaded.
So let's go back to our tab here for listing the file systems listed.
And there it is.
Perfect.
Now let's go back here.
And this time, I'll close this little message and I'll browse, and I'll try to upload a Microsoft
Word document, and I have one stuck right here.
We're Dot Dot X.
And that's not in my allowed mime types.
Let's try uploading that.
And it says invalid file type upload.
Now I have that is the wrong color, which is my own fault, and that's easy enough to fix it.
I'll leave that as an exercise for you.
But this is not a production web page.
This is just to try things out, and I'm pretty happy because it's now limiting the upload by my type.
Now I don't happen to have a file more than 10 megs and I to try to upload, but I know that's going
to work and I'll leave that as an exercise for you.
So the last thing I want to take care of and this is just a bit of housekeeping.
Back to our I.T. and hide this and look inside the My App folder inside of the temp directory.
Every time I upload something, the temporary file stays there, and that's a bit of a pain.
So let's try this instead.
Let's open up the Upload File Upload doc, go from celebrities and right here upload file.
After my statement and before my return, I'm going to put it differ in there, so I'll defer a function
that returns nothing.
But it does require the parentheses at the end here.
I'm going to defer a simple call with an explicit ignore of the error code.
So if there's an error, I don't care about it and I'm going to call off start remove.
Now, what I want to remove is really just the name.
I got back from that call to see Dot get file to upload.
So filing that should be the full path to the file that I want to delete.
And because I'm deferring it down here explicitly, I know this is not going to run until everything
up here is done, and I think that is a little bit cleaner and safer.
So this will empty out our temp directory.
There'll be nothing in there when everything works on delete those.
So the next time I run this, after I upload a file and get a success message, that temp directory
should still be empty.
OK, that is enough for this time around.
Let's move on to the next section.