So let's get started implementing our Mineo file system, and we'll start with that one.
OK.
So right now, I'm looking at the file system start go file inside the Celebrity Sprocket project,
inside the file systems folder.
And as you can see, we want to implement this interface and that interface requires that we have these
four functions.
So let's get started.
And the first thing I'll do is I'll right click on the file systems folder and create a new directory.
I'm going to create this package, which I'll call Mineo File System.
Make sure I spelled that right.
I did create the folder inside of there, and what I'll do is create each of my file systems within
the file systems package.
OK.
And instead of that, I create a new folder inside Mineo File System and you file not any folder which
I'll call mine.
Ioco and Golan helpfully does the import for me.
Now we're going to be working with Mineo, and that means we need to import a couple of packages.
So I'll open my terminal and the first one I want is this one.
Go get GitHub dot com slash Mineo slash Mineo Dash Go slash movie seven and a version eight is out.
Please use version version seven for this course and then upgrade after the fact.
The reason being, as I'm sure you're aware, when you have a major release, it almost always entails
breaking changes.
And if you try to use version eight, when I'm using version seven, bad things will happen.
So let's just avoid that and stick with version seven for right now.
So I'll go get that.
I probably already have it.
I do, and then I'll get another one.
Same thing, but slash pcgg slash credentials, which we need for authentication and that might be imported
when you import version seven.
But I like to be sure.
So that goes and gets it for me.
And we're good.
So I'll hide my terminal now.
Very first thing I'm going to do is create a type which will use when we access this system type and
I'll call it Mineo with a capital M. So it's exported, it's just a struct, and it has a few fields.
The first one is the end point.
What are you going to connect to?
And that'll just be a string.
The second one will be the first part of authentication, which I'll call cheat.
OK.
And that's a string.
And it also requires a secret.
The other part of our authentication, and that also will be a string.
Next, use SSL now in production.
Presumably.
Hopefully, you'll be connecting to an encrypted end endpoint, something using SSL, but in development,
of course, we're probably not going to bother doing that because it's not necessary.
So I'll just make that a boolean.
And region, which isn't actually required for Mineo, I mean, it's required as a parameter, but they
don't I don't think they actually use it.
It's just to maintain compatibility with Amazon S3 buckets.
So that will be a string.
And what bucket do you want to connect to?
And again, that's a string as well.
So there now we have a type of format that and next we need to implement all of the necessary functions
that are specified back in filesystem scope.
And those are put get listed to.
OK, now before I do that, I'm going to create another function just to make my life easier.
It's a function and it has to have the receiver of a pointer to mean I.
So we have access to the necessary fields from that struct of that type.
I'm going to call this one get credentials, and I think I spell that right.
I did.
It takes no parameters and it returns a pointer to a Mineo Dot client.
OK, now every time we connect to that endpoint, we're going to have to authenticate, and I don't
want to bother rewriting that authentication logic over and over and over.
So I'll just put it in a function, and it's pretty easy to authenticate against me.
And I know we're going to get to returns to return values from a function, and the first one is our
client.
That's what we use to connect.
The second one is just checking for an error.
So we'll call Mineo Dot new, and that requires a few parameters actually to the first one is our endpoint,
and we have that from our receiver MDR endpoint.
The second one is a pointer to Mineo Dot options, and we'll just build that manually right in line.
Meanwhile, the options and we'll populate the necessary fields, and we definitely need the first one
krenz.
OK, and our credentials come this way.
Credentials.
L.
S Dot new static, v4, not v2, but v4 like that, and it requires a key, a secret and then an empty
string.
And we get our key from MKI, our receiver, our secret from EMD Secret, our receiver.
And the third one is a token.
Functionally, that means we're only authenticated use a key and a secret.
So that's sufficient for our purposes.
So we have to use that.
And the second thing we want is is this secure connection or not secure?
And again, from our receiver, don't use SSL.
So that gives me a client and potentially an error.
Now, if there's an error, I'm just going to lock it.
You do whatever you want.
If error is not equal to nil and I'll just log beer logged on print line the error, OK?
And finally, we return the client.
OK, so now I have my get credentials.
So let's take care of, first of all, putting a file on the remote file system.
So that's the first of the four functions we have to implement func with the receiver of M Pointer to
denials.
So we have access to the fields in the struct.
We'll call this one put.
And if you recall, if you recall back over here in file systems, put it has two parameters file name
and folder.
Both are strings, and it potentially returns an error.
That's easy enough.
So we want our file name and our folder, both of type string, and we're going to potentially return
an error.
Scroll up and give us some room here.
So when you're working with Mineo, you almost always work with context as well, because you might
need to cancel the operation if it doesn't work out.
And we do that the way we normally do and go.
That's what almost everyone calls context and cancel.
And those come from context, not with cancel.
And our parent context is just the background context, which is always available to us.
Context.
Background OK.
And then we defer cancel.
OK, so now we have our context.
Now we want to get the name of the object.
We're going to put up there now.
File name.
That first parameter that we have in our put function will usually be the full path name to the file
we want to put up.
But what we want, we want the name of the file we're putting out.
So we'll call that object name and we'll get the actual name from the full path using the path package
and go past on base, which is a really, really useful function and handed the parameter filing.
So if that path name happened to be slash user slash local slash, my file text Typekit base strips
off the first part and just gives me whatever the end of that half name is.
In other words, the file name itself?
Well, that's what I need now.
I need a client in order to make my connection to the endpoint, so client is assigned the value of
that function.
We just wrote import get credentials.
OK, so now I have the file name.
Now I have a client.
Now I can try to put it up there.
So to do that, I will say I'll create a variable, which I'm just going to call upload info because
that's the information getting back from the column about to make and potentially an error.
And they come from calling the client variable that I just created on Line 36 Dot.
The method I want is if put object right there, and that requires the context CTCs, which we declared
on line thirty two.
It also requires the bucket I want to put it into and that comes from the receiver AMD bucket and it
requires.
Where do you want to put this?
So I'm going to put this into a folder slash object name, so I'll just use Format Dot as print f,
and the format string is percent s slash percent s and the substitutions are folder.
The second parameter we get in this function and object name, and the next thing it requires is the
actual name of the file file name, which is the full path named to the file.
I'm putting up there and this is a long one, but it also requires an options which I'll just pass as
an empty option.
Denial Dot put object options and just leave it empty.
OK, so that's a long line.
But but those are the required parameters, so we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And since I'm just getting started a monologue, a few things I'll say logged crit line failed with
f put object just so I know what's going on, and then I'll print out the error logged out print long
error because things almost never work right the first time.
And finally logged on print line.
What did I get for uploading, though?
The return value upload info and I'll print out upload info.
OK, and then I'll return the error, but I'm going to go any further.
Otherwise, the return null.
OK, so that's the very first function of the four that we need in order to implement that interface.
Now this lecture is getting fairly long, so I'll pause here or stop here and pick it up with list in
the next lecture.