So let's implement the list function.
And if you look in the file system, stock go file list requires a prefix to string and returns a slice
of listings and potentially an error.
So let's implement that and it's pretty simple.
So in maniacal, I'll add the function func with a receiver m pointer to the mean IO and this one's
called list, and it takes one argument prefix, which is a string, and it returns a slice of file
systems dot listing.
And it should find it for me, filesystems the listing.
Why aren't you finding that?
Systems, why?
Because you're misspelling file systems, file systems, listing and potentially in error.
OK, so let's create a variable to store results in VAR listing, which is going to be a slice of file
system store listing.
And let's get our context X and cancel come from context dot with cancel, and we'll just take context,
background as usual and defer cancel.
Now, let's get our client, and I can just copy this line right here and paste it in here.
So now we have our client, now we want to call the function list of objects on the variable client.
And we're going to store the result in a variable or call object C-H.
We'll see why in a minute.
Client Dot and we want list objects and that requires the context c, t x and it requires our bucket,
which I get from my receiver bucket.
And then it requires some options.
I mean, I o dot list object options versus to find them in line like we did last time.
But this one doesn't require a pointer, so a prefix is the first required field and that's just our
parameter.
We received prefix and it also requires recursive.
And I'm going to say true.
Give me everything you find in that bucket.
OK, which is good enough for our purposes.
So list objects, as you can see right here, returns into a channel object info.
That's why I put suture because it's a channel.
OK.
Now we're going to get one or none or more than one objects back, so we better range through our Channel
four object, which is just a variable I'm declaring right now is a sign the value of raging through
our object channel.
And we'll check for an error if object
dot e r, which is built right into the type we're getting back.
If it's not equal to nil, then I'll print out the error.
Format dot print line object dot error and I'll return listing, which is currently empty if this error
occurs the first time through Amber Watcher in the error object error.
OK, but if there is no error, then we can keep going.
Now, in some cases, you might have something that starts with a dot, and I don't want to return any
variable names or any names that begin with a dot because these are typically hidden files.
So I'll say, if not using the strings package strings dot has prefix right there, and the name of
the file will be stored in the field called key object key.
I'm looking for a dot, so if it doesn't start with a dot, then I need to return everything that's
in file systems dot listing and that includes the E tag.
The date last modified the name of the file, which is called key and also size.
But I want size to be, you know, pretty consistent.
So I'll use megabytes as my file size format, so I'll declare a variable called B, and I'll a sign
that the value of converting it to a float sixty four, because that's the type I'm storing in my listings
type.
Object size.
OK.
And then I'll convert that to kilobits kilobytes.
Assign the value of bytes divided by a thousand twenty four is what we get back or bytes.
And then I'll declare a variable called megabytes MBIE, which is equal to kilobytes divided by a thousand
twenty four.
Simple math.
OK, and now I'll create an item new variable and it will be of type file systems, dot listing and
I'll just populate its fields.
So we want E tag and that comes from object dot e tag.
We also want the date last modified, which I called last modified mass just object last modified.
We want the name of the file, which is called key object key to an object key.
And finally, we want the size, which is now in a variable called megabytes me.
So I have my item.
Let's just append that to our slice of results listing, which is that variable.
I declared right at the start of this function on line 52 is equal to append listing an item.
And once I get outside of this for loop, I simply return listing.
And no.
So that should do it for listing a remote file system.
In this case, a Mineo file system, which is functionally equivalent to an Amazon S3 bucket, but it
has its own client.
Now, in theory, you could use Amazon's SDK, its package to connect to Mineo, and it would work fine.
But I'd like to use the right client for the right tool.
So we're working with Mineo.
We'll use the mini tool later on.
When we go to an S3 bucket or some version thereof, we'll use Amazon's package for connecting.
OK.
So in the next lecture, we'll move on to implementing the next required function.