So far, we have the ability to put something to a remote file system, a mini file system and the ability
to list all of the contents of a given bucket on that.
And we still need two more functions delete and get.
So let's take care of delete this time around.
So I'm still in the file mine ioco inside the mobile file system folder inside the file system folder
inside this Holyroodhouse folder and let's take care of delete and it's a pretty short function.
Again, a func with the receiver of M Pointer to Mineo.
And this one's called delete.
And as you recall, that takes one parameter items to delete, which is a slice of string and it returns
of Boolean true or false.
So once again, we need the context.
So CTCs and cancel come from context with cancel and we use context background as it's one parameter
and we defer cancel.
Now we need to get our client.
So client is assigned the value of don't get credentials.
And now we need to specify some options and I won't do them inline this time.
I'll do it this way.
Ops is a sign the value of Mineo Dot remove object options, and the only thing I want to put in there
is one parameter and it's one that if you're going to be working with Mineo or with S3 buckets, you
should read up on this.
It's called Governance Bypass, Governance Bypass, and I'm going to set that to true.
And there are situations, many situations actually where you want that.
You want to read about this a little bit and find out exactly what it does and make sure that you want
to set that to true.
But in our case, for our purposes today, this is perfect.
Now we'll just range through items to delete for I don't care about index, but I do care about the
current item is assigned the value of range items to delete, and all we do is check for an error and
call from our client.
Remove object, remove object right there.
And I don't know why I have parentheses around that, I must have been working in JavaScript recently.
So we'll get rid of those.
That's better.
Now Remove Object takes a few parameters.
Context is the first one.
The second one is what bucket are you dealing with?
Which is amp up bucket rate from the receiver.
What do you want to delete?
And that's item which we're getting through the range statement.
And finally, what are the options which we just specified right up above there?
OK.
So we try that and we try to check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And I'll print it out.
Format dot print line the error and I'll return false because it failed.
OK, otherwise outside of this for loop, we just return true.
And that's all there is to it for deleting something from him in your file system.
OK.
So in the next lecture, we'll take care of the last function, which is get one.
You won't use very much, but just to be complete, we might as well implement it.
It's not a lot of work.