So we have one more function to implement in order to satisfy the interface necessary for our file systems,
and that is get and as I've said before, this is one you may not use very much.
But remember, you're not writing this for yourself, necessarily.
You're writing it for other people to use as well.
And there are situations where you may want, may need to get a file from the remote file system and
pull it down to the server.
Rarely will you do that for an end user, because most file systems have some means of getting a public
file built right into them.
But in any case, let's implement this functionality because it's not very difficult.
So func receiver and pointer to Dominico and this one's just called get, and it has destination as
its first parameter, which is just a string.
Where do you want to put it and what items do you want to get?
And of course, that is a very adequate parameter.
One or more strings, and it potentially returns in error.
OK.
So let's get the context, which I'll copy from right up here to say some typing and I'll need a client
too.
So I grabbed grab that at the same time and paste those in here.
So now I have my contacts to my client, and now we want to go through all of the items because we might
have more than one thing we're getting.
And go get them.
So that's a for loop for don't care about the index, do care about the current item is equal to range
items.
And that, of course, is a very, very idec parameter that we have at the end of our function signature.
So we'll check for an error and we'll call from our client.
And there are many ways of getting an object, but I'm going to use f get object, which is the simplest
and that requires the context.
It requires the bucket name and bucket from the receiver.
It requires the actual item to get which is, you know, the value of item on our current iteration
through the loop.
And then where do you want to put it?
Well, we want to put it in format as per def.
I'll use that and build my string this way.
In my format, string is percent percent as my substitutions or destination, which is a path name and
then the name of the file.
And of course, that's the actual base name of the file.
So once again, we'll use that ever so useful function path dot base and we want the base of item.
OK.
And the last one is Mineo get object options, which we can just leave empty, but we need to declare
it.
So Mineo Dot get object options and we'll just leave the curly braces empty.
OK, so that takes care of that part.
Now let's get on the next line and hit return and check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll print it out format or print line error, and I'll return the error otherwise if everything
goes according to plan.
Outside of this for loop.
We could just return nil.
And that should take care of it, so now we have our get, we have our delete.
We have our list and we have her put.
And then we have her a little helper function for getting credentials.
So at this point, we satisfy the interface efforts, which means we can try this out.
Now we've got a couple of steps to take care of before we can actually do that, but we'll get started
in the next lecture.