So it's almost time to try out our mini or fail system, but we have a few things to take care of before
we can actually do that.
And one of the things that will make our lives simpler is to actually implement stub functions for our
other three file systems, and we're going to do that right now.
So inside the celebrity's folder, inside the file systems folder, we have this mineral file system.
Let's create three more folders.
The first one?
I'll create a folder named S3 file system and then I'll create another folder right beside that.
So at the File Systems folder level, a new directory called Web Dev File System, and the last one,
of course, is SDP.
So create a new directory at the same level as the rest of them.
And we call this one SFP file system.
OK, now let's start with S3.
So inside of the S3 file system, I'll create a new go file and I'll just call it S3 ago and go land,
added the package declaration for me.
But make sure you have it or create a type here, which I'll call S3 and it's just as dropped and it
will have certain fields pretty much the same as the other one key, which is a string secret, which
is a string region, which is a string end point, which is a string and finally bucket, which is a
string.
OK, I will format this now.
I need to have certain functions in here to satisfy the interface so func and I'll use the receiver
of Pointer to S3.
This three, we need a put function and put text file name, which is a string
and folder, which is a string swiveling each string.
Once we get rid of this one, that's redundant.
That's better, and it potentially returns an error.
And just as a stub, I'll say return nil.
OK.
And we also need a list.
So func s pointer to S3 list and for parameters that requires just a prefix, which is a string, and
it returns a slice of file systems, dot listing and potentially an error and all dos declare a variable,
which I'll call listing and then make it a slice of file systems dot list.
I'll just return listing and nil.
And there's a stub function that'll do the trick.
Next, I need delete func as pointer to S3, and I'll make that delete.
And that requires nothing more than items to delete, which is a slice of strings, and it returns of
Boolean.
And to make this work, I'll just say return true.
And I better put an e after delete.
That looks better than the last one is get func as pointed at S3, and we'll call this one get and get
requires destination, which is a string and items which is a one or more strings.
Technically, zero would be a valid number two, but we're we're going to pass it zero and it returns
an error.
So we do return now.
OK.
So we've created stub functions here just to save some time.
I'm going to copy everything except for the package statement copy that and I will go to SFP File System
and I'll create a new go file in there called SFTP Doggo.
I'll return a couple of times, then paste in what I just used and I'll change the keys here and I also
change our type.
I'll name it SRF type, and we don't need the same keys for us.
FTB we just need host is a string user, which is a string pass, which is a string and port, which
is a string and now a copy.
Step and change all of these receivers.
All right now we have stub functions for that type.
So now I'll copy all of this except for the package declaration, and I'll do the same thing for WebDAV.
I'll create a new go file in the WebDAV file system folder called WebDAV.
Don't go there, return a couple of times and paste.
And for this one, we just need host user and pass.
We don't need part because that's actually part of the whole string so we can delete that.
Rename this one to say WebDAV
in all caps like that and fix our receivers.
Paste, paste, paste and paste there.
Now I have stub functions for that one.
So we have Mineo, we have S-3, we have SFTP and we have WebDAV perfect.
So now that we've created those stub functions, we can actually move on and begin connecting our new
file system packages to celebrities itself, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.