So we want to try out our new mineral file system, and there's a few things we have to do before we
can actually get started.
And the first thing is to put some additional information into our dot on file.
And of course, that's in my app.
So let me open my app and find the dot on what we want to put in here.
And I'm going to put it right at the very bottom is this and I've got this copy and paste it to my clipboard
and I'll put a version of this up on the court.
Of course, resources for this lecture.
So I'm putting in entries, as you can see here for Amazon S3, buckets for Mineo, for SFTP and for
WebDAV.
And I'm leaving everything except for Mineo empty.
And the values I have in here are exactly the same as what you would be using, except I'm going to
change your mind eight thousand because I support, I'm listening to.
And you may be listening to nine thousand, but as I said earlier, I'm using forty nine thousand,
so I'm using eight thousand here instead.
So we have our root password and user.
We have don't use SSL and we have a region and the name of the bucket we're going to connect to.
And the one we created was called Test Bucket.
So we have that in our dorms, and now I need to go over to the celebrities package.
So I'm going to minimize my app and open up celebrities and go to the file celebrities.
Don't go.
And the very first thing I'm going to do and this is a decision I'm making, you may want to do it differently,
but I suggest you follow along as I'm going to add a field to the celebrity's tight right here at the
very end and I'm going to coal mine file systems like that.
And it will be of type.
Map with the key of string and the the content of a given entry will be of type interface.
OK, that's sufficient for our purposes right now so we can put anything we want in there.
So now I've added that type and of course, I need to populate that type with some useful information.
So what I'll do is scroll down to this function new and go to the very bottom, very near the bottom
in any case.
Down here, after I create the renderer, I'll put a call in here to a function that doesn't exist yet,
and we'll create that function in a minute.
So I'll say, see dot file systems that feel we just added that's going to be equal to.
The return value of C Dot create file systems, which takes no parameters.
Now that doesn't exist yet.
So let's go at it and I'll just go near the bottom of this file and put a new function, which I'll
call func with a receiver of c a pointer to scylaticus create file systems, and it takes no parameters
and it returns a map of string interface.
So I'll declare a variable file systems and that will be assigned the value of make a map of string
interface.
And now I want to go through all of the various values that we just added to our on file and decide
whether or not I should add an entry for that particular kind of file system.
And of course, the only one we care about right now is minimal.
So I'll just do a check if OS don't get on.
So we've already read our own file by this point, so I can check to see if there are values in the
environment.
And I'm looking for one of the things that I know is in my dot on file related to mine.
I own mine.
I o secret right?
If that's not equal to an empty string, which is what what it'll be if we haven't got any values in
there, then I'll put some things that I need in here.
And for simplicity, I'm going to say use SSL is a sign the value of false.
I don't check to see if it's set to true in the environment.
If strings start to lower just to make sure it's all in lowercase O's, don't get on.
And I'm looking for Mineo use SSL if that's exactly equal to true string.
True because we got string values when we pass our.
Our report on file.
Then I'll set.
Use us as hell equals a truth.
So it defaults to false.
But if true is the value that I find in the dot on.
Then it becomes true.
Now, after that if statement, let's create a variable called Mineo and that will be assigned the type
of Mineo file system.
Dot.
I mean, I know and we populate its fields, and those are our end point, which would be equal to us.
Don't get on.
And I'm looking for an end point right there.
So endpoint, the key will be equal to most dog get on.
And I'm looking for know, key.
The secret and that, of course, that's equal to us get on.
Meanwhile, secret right there.
Use SSL and that's equal to use SSL.
The variable we just dealt with in the previous lines, the region ost, I'd get on, you know, region.
And finally, the bucket and that's equal to oast, don't get off your bucket.
So now I've got that variable.
I'll just add it to my filesystems variable that I declared up on the line 384 file filesystems and
we're looking for Mineo.
I just picked that key because it seems to make the most sense.
That's a the value of I and down here, just before the end of this function, we return filesystems.
OK, so that will populate the new field.
Little back up here to the end of that function where we're doing it.
That will populate the field file systems in the type celebrities with the return value of this function.
And that gives me a really easy way of having as many file systems as I want.
All right now, I just have one, but we'll be adding three more as time goes on and I can just grab
them out of the map, cast them to the correct type and use them at will.
OK, so let's move on.