So we've set up our file systems in Celerity House, at least for a minute.
And we have the appropriate values in our on file and let's make sure things will actually compile.
So I'm back in my I.D. and I'll open the terminal and I'll make sure I'm using my app directory.
I am.
And let's just try running this.
So make it start.
And it should tell me that I need to go get some things.
And it does.
So right here.
It gives me two things I need to go get go, get celebrities, file system slash.
Meanwhile, file system.
And that's all I need.
So I'll copy this.
And paste it, and it should go get it from our local directory up one level, the folder name celebrities
and it finds the appropriate thing and adds it.
So now I should be able to run this make start just to make sure it works.
And there it goes, it's running, so I'll stop it, make stop.
Let's try that.
So just to make sure things actually work, let's open up the routes file in my app.
So we'll go to routes.
And here I'll just add a test route.
So I'll add a route that says, don't get and we'll say Test, meanwhile, is the route and then I'll
do an inline function.
W. A. Ebola response rider and a pointer to H-E-B request, which I'll call out as they usually do.
And in here, let's just get the current value of our file systems right from our app, which is stored
as part of our application.
So if it's just a variable name I'm declaring comes from a Dot app.
Dart file systems.
And we're going to get Mineo, which is what I named it.
So we now have that value and will actually cast that to a Mineo file system, Mineo file systems.
I mean, I o.
So that gives me a variable F, which is my file systems, and I should be able to call an actual method
on that.
So I'll say files in error come from afterthought list and we'll give it a prefix of nothing.
OK.
And we'll check for error if error is not equal to nil.
We'll just log it logged the print line the error and return it.
Otherwise we'll rip through it.
So for I don't care about the index, but I do care about the current value, which I'll call file.
Is assigned the value of ranging through files.
And now I'll say log print line, file dot key to give the file name.
OK, now in order for that to work, of course, it would be useful to have something in a criminal
file system.
So I'll switch to my finder and I'll open up the DB data.
Mineo files right there and test bucket that folder, and I'll put this picture in there.
You can put any file you want in there.
It doesn't matter what it is.
As long as we can actually look at it, it's not.
If I come back here and start my application again, make a start.
Make sure it all compiles and runs.
And it does.
OK, so now I have a log file running.
So let's go to our web browser and go to local host whatever port you're listening to, test Dash,
you know, so I'll open up Firefox and we'll go to localhost four thousand slashed Test Dash.
You know, I should get nothing on the screen and I don't.
But if I go back and look at my log file.
There it is, it found we'll dash tailed Dash toddler dog JPAC, so we know we can connect and we know
we can list things perfect.
So now in the next lecture, we'll try building some functionality to upload files and to display them
in a web browser just to make sure all of the functions work properly.