So now that we know we can connect to our immediate file system and at least get a listing of any files
that's in our test bucket, let's try building some web pages that allow us to test all of the functionality
associated with this particular file system.
Now, if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file called VUes Dot Zip.
And if you download that file and unzip it inside, you'll find some jet files and a folder.
And I'd like you to replace the current contents of the Views folder in my app with the contents of
that zip file.
And what you wind up with, of course, is the standard layouts, and that layout file is based on a
jet.
And the only big change in this one is that I've added a nav bar with some drop down menu items.
OK.
And we'll be using these as the course goes on.
Some of them right away.
You'll also find an updated home jet file and the one we're going to work on right now or in this lecture
or the next one is this one will allow us to list our current file systems.
OK.
So do that now before we can actually use those views.
Of course, we need to write some code to populate the appropriate pages and add the roots to our root
file, and we'll get started with listing the contents of our mineral file system now to make that happen.
Let's go to our handlers folder, OK, and open up the file handlers go.
And right here after the home handler, I'm going to add a new function, which will be a handler so
func with a receiver of a pointer to handlers.
And I'll call this one list f's for list file systems, and it will take a response, right?
Or of course, a response writer and a pointer to a request, as all handlers do.
Now the very first thing I'm going to do is declare a variable fs of type file systems fs so ver the
fairness of type file systems.
F's.
And I'm also going to create a variable that will hold the contents of whatever files are on that remote
file system, and I'll call that list and it will be a slice of file systems listing.
So there's two variables we're going to have to use now, the actual web page that allows us to display
the contents of a file system.
We'll have a dropdown menu at the top, and we can look at that right now to go back to our Views folder
and open up a list for us.
You can see right here.
This is standard template logic.
I'm going to have an option that says Choose and you'll have to choose something and you can choose
S3 or Mineo or SFP or WebDAV.
This is the only one we care about right now, but we may as well take into account the fact that there
are going to be multiple file systems later on.
So back in listed jet, I shouldn't have gone away.
The name of this dropdown, this parameter will be named EF-S Dash Type.
OK, so that can handlers.
What I'll do is get that, so I'll declare a variable FS type like that and just make it an empty string.
And then I'll see if we have that query parameter passed to us because the form that submits that is
is a is a get request, not a post request.
And that's as simple as if from our our variable or request URL dot query.
And we want to get we're going to get first dash type the name of that field in the form.
If that's not equal to nothing and it won't be if it's supplied and it will be if it's not supplied,
then we'll set X Type EFS type is equal to our short URL dot query.
Don't get.
And we want this dash type.
So now I know what kind of file system on would be dealing with me to scroll up a bit here.
The next thing I'm going to do is when you're looking at a remote file system, particularly in S.F.
SFD, B file system or something like that, or WebDAV, you might be looking at different directories
in that file system.
So I'm going to declare a directory called her path or a variable called cur path, and I'll make that
default to slash.
In other words, you're at the root level of whatever file system you're looking at.
And now we'll check for a second query parameter that's passed as part of that get request.
And that is called purpose.
So if our dot query their URL, dot query dot get and we're going to be looking for her path and I'll
show you that in a moment on the actual web page.
If that's not equal to nothing, then we'll say her path is now equal to our own URL query.
Don't get her pass.
And just to make things are safe, we're going to escape that, so we're going to Earl Okwiri escape,
and when we receive that perimeter, we'll on escape just to make sure it's Earl safe.
So purpose, and I'm going to ignore the error in this case, just to save a little bit of time from
the Earl package as part of the standard library.
We want query on escape right there and we're going to escape her path, and that will make sure that
what we need has been properly on escaped.
So spaces aren't percent, 20 and all that sort of thing.
OK, so now I have that variable, which we're not going to use this time around, but we might or we
will definitely be using it later on.
So now I'll simply say, if f's type is not equal to nothing, then you've submitted the form and we
want to switch based upon the value of that variable offense type.
So we'll say switch and we'll switch on FS type, OK?
And the only one we care about right now is case scenario, which will be in all caps because that's
how it's passed by the form.
Then we'll declare a variable f just like we did in our inline function, and we'll go to H Dot App
Dot File Systems and we want to get, you know, and then we want to cast that to an Mineo file system.
Meanwhile, right there and then we'll take our variable EF-S that was declared right up on line 28
and that will be equal to and we can't just say F because there are different types, ones, a pointer
1s.
Not so we use Ampersand.
OK.
And I'm also going to say F-Type type is now equal to men.
Oh, OK.
And that's the only thing I care about at this point in terms of the Switch statement.
Of course, we're going to be doing more than that a little bit later on.
But right now, let's come down here after a case and let's say l an error.
L is just a variable, I'm declaring, and we're going to check for an error is equal to from our file
system.
We'll call list with a prefix that will be her path.
And of course, that's an empty string right now.
So we'll get the contents of the top level of that directory and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil,
then we'll love your H2 app error log dot print line here and I'll return.
I don't want to go any further, but if we get past that now, we'll take that variable with declared
right up on Line 29 list.
That's equal to L.
Now, outside of the if statement, now we want to render our template.
So we're going to be passing data to this template and it's a jet template.
So I'll declare variable hours vars and make that equal to an empty jetport bar map.
And I will set list versus dot set and I'll call it list for the template and hand it list the contents
of that directory, the listing of that remote file system directory.
I'll also set.
F's underscore type, and we'll see that in a minute when we go back to the template, and that will
be to first type.
And I'll set her path.
First off set, her path will be equal to her path.
No wonder the template, so error is a sign the value of each dot render.
And we're going to render with W an hour.
We're going to pass it the name of the template, which is the list of f's, because our file, our
actual file is called List Fast Jet.
Well, hand it the verse, which is populated and kneel for the final parameter, which I almost never
use.
You might, but I don't.
And I would check for the error if error is not equal to nil.
Then each dot app error dot print line here.
OK, so that is the beginning of her handler.
Now, obviously, when we implement additional file systems, we'll be adding more cases here.
But basically, the logic will be almost identical for every one of the file systems because they all
implement the same interface and therefore have the same methods.
All right, we have this template or we have this handwritten list.
So quick look at that template one more time.
So we start at the top and as you can see, nothing more than the standard browser title.
I did put a little standard style in there just to make things a little more obvious, particularly
for the alerts that will be showing up later on and down.
Here we have our page content and the variable I'm checking right here at this underscore type.
Remember, we're handing that over here.
F's underscore type.
It just ensures that the correct option is selected when you list a file system.
So when I submit this form and actually does, a browser round trip comes back with the listing past
as data.
The file listing and then make sure that the appropriate option in our dropdown is selected here.
OK.
And we have a hidden field cur path, which we're not using in this lecture or the next one will, but
we'll be using it a bit later on.
And finally, if we have values in that variable list, we just display a table that lists the contents
of that file system.
OK.
That's all there is to it.
So in the next lecture, we'll hook up a root and give things a try.