So now that we have our handler in progress and presumably at least partially functional, let's create
a route that points to it and try things out, and I'll use this test route in my rootstock go file
inside my app project.
I'll just modify that to point to our handler and strip so aident get and we'll go to and do use this
for the URL, because that's what is in the templates.
We used that you installed a couple of lectures ago and we'll point it to air handlers list f.
S.
And now I should be able to open my terminal and type make start.
And it's going, so let's go over to our Web browser and hit that URL, so I'll go to localhost 4000.
And from my dropdown menu, I should be able to choose list files.
And of course, that's the only one of the dropdowns here that works at the moment.
And it should, in theory, only work for me.
I o and if I click list, there's my whale tail.
Taller?
Perfect.
Now we do have some other things here.
For example, this delete does in fact pop a dialogue, but we can't delete anything yet.
We'll be adding that before too long.
But at the moment, I'm pretty sure that this works.
So let's try one more thing.
I'll switch back to my finder and I'll open up the Mineo Test bucket and I'll put a second file in there.
These views don't zip should do the trick.
And I think come back here now and click list, it shows up.
Perfect.
OK.
Let's move on to uploading to the file system.