So we have this bit listing the remote minnow Mineo file system working really well, and now we want
to work on this.
The ability to upload files to the remote file system.
And of course, that'll just give me a page not found error because we haven't written any of that code
yet.
So let's get started.
So back to our idea and I will start my application like stock and hide the terminal and let's get started.
So what I'll do, first of all, is create a handler.
So let me go over to handlers dot and go.
Which is right here, and let's right the handler to display the upload page, and as you recall, we
already have the upload georgette file here in The View's folder, and that's what we want to point
to.
So we'll create a function with a receiver of a pointer to handlers and we'll call it say, upload to
F.
S for file systems and give it the standard two parameters for every handler, a response writer and
a pointer to in CTP to a request.
And this is simple.
First of all, we are going to be getting a file system type query parameter.
So let's trap for that first type is assigned error, the URL query not get.
And if you look at the form on that upload jete file, the parameter is called type.
OK, and we'll create a variable because we need to pass some data to our our VAR map.
So we'll create a vase variable and that's of the type.
Make a jetport VAR map just like before, and we'll add the file type to that first set.
And we'll call it if underscore type and the variable is EFS type.
So now we've set our data and now we just render that page.
Error is assigned the value of each dot render and we're going to render W an hour and we're going to
give the template upload because it's called upload.
Chet will hand it the variables we just created.
And as usual, I don't use that final parameter and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll render the error h to app error log print line and we'll just
print the error out.
And that's enough.
So we have this handler.
Let's go to our roots, file and add in that.
And we'll say, put it right here and yet.
And we're going to look for the path.
Let me go to my.
Layouts and find out what it's actually called.
So under layouts based on and yet what did I use for a URL there?
Upload a file is files, uploads or a copy that and switch back to roots.
And paste that in there and then pointed at that handler, a dog handlers dot upload to EFS.
Now if I start, my application may start.
I should be able to render that page.
So it started.
Let's go back to our Web browser and just refresh this.
And there it is.
So as you can see, we have a dropdown menu and this is the only one we're going to use right now.
Mineo will browse for a file and we'll upload it.
So the next step is to create the handler to handle that form post, and we'll take care of that in
the next election.