So we have this form displaying properly to upload files to our remote file system, and now clearly
we need to make it functional.
So let's go back to our code and we'll create a new handler and I'll put it right here in the handler
dog go file right after the one we just did upload to FS.
And I'll call this one func h pointer to handlers.
I'll call it simply post upload to EFS and again, give the standard two parameters and are a pointer
to a checkpoint request.
OK, now the first thing we want to do is to get the file, to upload and to actually get the name of
the file.
So what I'm going to do is just move that logic into its own handler because I won't use this in a lot
of places.
So I'll call this get file to upload, and it's going to take a request, which is a pointer to an issue
DHCP request, and it will return the name of the file and potentially an error.
OK.
I'm just putting that in its own function because I like to have functions do one thing and one thing
well.
So in this case, what I want to do, first of all, is to pass the multipart form because this will
come as a post request, but a multipart post requests which you can attach files to, so that returns
an error.
What I'm going to have to call what I'm calling is earned pass multipart form right there, and that
takes one argument, and the argument is simply the maximum memory.
How big can this file be?
And I'll make it relatively big 10 and 20.
That'll give us, I think, 10 10 megs of disk space we can use now.
I'm ignoring the error there, and you probably shouldn't in production, but for our purposes, this
is sufficient.
Now I'm going to get three values when I look at our dot form file.
I'll get file header and an error.
And those come from a method built right into the request, which is called a form file.
And I'm looking for form file.
I'm looking for that for a reason.
If I open up, upload again and go down to the part where I'm actually putting in the the file input
type input type equals file.
The name is form file.
OK, let's go back to our handlers.
So I get those three return values and I'll check for error if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll simply return the nothing, an empty string and the air, OK, something went wrong.
But if we get past that?
Now I want to defer filed, OK, close.
Otherwise, I'll have a resource leak.
OK, so after this function exits, file gets closed.
Now I want to actually create a file from that posted upload.
So I'm going to get a return value DST for destination and potentially an error.
And those come from Overstock.
Don't create right here and I'm going to create or I'll use print f to build my strength.
I'll upload it to the temp directory, which I know exists, and my placeholder is a percent S. And
that gets replaced with header file name.
OK, so that will create an empty file in destination and it can check for an error.
The error is not equal to nil return and empty string and the error otherwise I've created by empty
file.
And again, I need to put a defer destocked close close that file when this function exits.
Otherwise we have resourcefully, then I would just copy it.
So we'll get ignore the first return value check for an error and that comes from Io Dot Copy.
Into destination, the contents of the variable file, and that will populate my new destination with
the posted file, from the upload, from the request and again checked for an error if errors not equal
to nil, then return an empty string and the error OK.
And finally, I'll return.
Format as pro-death.
Dot slash Tempe.
And then a placeholder percent S..
And again, I put in header dot file name.
And I return no error.
So now I have a function I can call that does nothing more than take a request.
Get the posted file name, which in this case is called form file to make this reusable, I probably
should do this field name
and make this.
Feel them and give that, of course, the type of strength
there now, it's reasonable.
So let's go back up to our actual handler and call that function.
So I'm going to get filing, which is the full path to the file that's upload and check for an error.
And I'll just call get file to upload and hand it.
My request and file name.
I think that's what I called it, let's make sure.
Upload just form file.
Better do it right.
Good thing.
I noticed that here.
For a while, and we checked for an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll say issue to error
and I'll give it W and the error error error.
And HDB status, internal server error right there.
I don't want to go any further, so I'll just display that error and I'll return, but if I get past
that, I now have the name of the file, so I have the file where it's stored.
It'll be in the temp directory with whatever name was assigned to it when it was uploaded, and I need
to get that somewhere.
I'm going to get it to a Mineo file system or an S3 file system or an SD FTP file system.
Well, in our case, we only care about one right now, but we're going to be doing more later, so
we will take care of that.
And if you go back to upload Jet, we have a dropdown menu, a pick list here that is called upload
dash type, and these are the possible values for it.
So we'll get that back over here.
New variable upload type is assign the value of our form.
Don't get upload dash time and I will switch on that switch on upload type.
And the only one we have right now is case, you know?
So that's the only one I care about right now.
So we'll do the similar sort of thing we did last time around.
We'll get a file system, EFS, and that comes from each Dot app dot file systems and looking for the
key, meanwhile, and casting that too in your file system does not mean I.
Ah.
So now I have a file system.
An error is now assigned the value of or equal to that variable fs, and because it satisfies the interface
for file systems put and the file name, that's the first argument is just file it.
I'm going to put it nowhere, just at the root level of that file system, and we check for an error
if error is not equal to nil.
Then again, we'll grab this code right here, copy and paste it in there, and that's sufficient for
our purposes.
We'll know that something went wrong at the very end.
After a switch statement, let's put something in the session app that Session Dot put, and we want
to put it using the context context.
And it's a flashing message which is built right into celebrities, if you recall, and we'll just put
it in a message file uploaded
and then we'll do a redirect redirect.
And that requires the response writer, the request where we want to go and we're going to go to files,
slash files, slash upload, and I want that menu to to default to the same thing that was selected
when we posted it.
So what type equals?
And just add upload type and give it the status of issue Typekit status.
See other right there.
And that should be sufficient.
So now if I copy this, Chandler, go back to my roots and here we're going to have an eight hour post
slash files slash upload eight handlers dot post, post upload to F's.
And now I should be able to restart my application.
Make stop case, it's running.
It wasn't make start.
It's running.
Let's go to our Web browser and see if this all works and remember, you got to have your Docker compose
running right now, so those Docker images for Mineo and so forth have to be running.
But back to our web browser, reload this page to make sure it works.
It does.
I'm going to upload to Mineo and I'll choose a file from my file system doesn't matter what it is,
so I'll go to the desktop and I'll choose say, Well, this that's too big, so I'll go to my pictures.
I must have something in pictures here where a picture of a whale, let's upload it.
File uploaded now, let's go make sure it's actually there, so I just uploaded that picture of a whale.
I'll go back to list files.
Choose Mineo and last.
And there it is Whale Dash Bing that worked perfectly.
So the last step for many Mineo and will be using that code that we write next for all of our file systems.
This is delete functionality and we'll take care of that in the next election.