So the last thing we have to actually implement for our Web pages to be functional is that delete button
when you're looking at the listed file system from Mineo.
There's a delete button next to it and I should actually have a handler and a route that makes that
functional, and that's pretty simple.
So back in our file handlers dot and go in my app.
Let's go to the very bottom of this file and add a new handler, and we'll set the root up after the
fact.
So func and this will be each pointer to handlers as usual, and we'll just call this one.
Delete from FS for file systems with a response writer
and a pointer to a request.
And what I'll do is create a variable force, which is a type filesystems force that interface we defined
and then we'll go to.
If you look at the actual list Fastjet over here and you go to the very bottom, we have some JavaScript
that actually deletes the item.
And what that does is fire up a little dialog box using that wonderful JavaScript library small.
And it says, Do you want to delete this file?
Yes or no?
And if you click yes, then it calls the URL slash delete dash from dash fs and then it passes a query
parameter.
And that's the file system type and the name of the file to delete.
OK, so we're getting our file system type.
So back then our handlers, we better make sure we actually get that.
So that's type, which is a very well, I'm just declaring that's a sign of value from RW R Okwiri get
and I'm looking for the name EF-S lowercase underscore type.
OK, so now I know what filesystem type.
To delete that, we need to know what file to delete item is assigned the value of a URL on query.
Not yet.
And I'm looking for file and I would just switch on if it's tight.
Same as always.
Switch on FS type.
And the only case we care about right now is, meanwhile, case, you know, and we get our file system,
so f is assigned the value of each AP file systems at the key, meanwhile, has to file systems.
And now that variable f's, which were declared on one line 132 that is equal to can't just be equal
to f because one's a point or one's not.
So we pass a reference to F instead.
Now we have our file system.
And of course, we'll add cases for all the other ones in a bit when we get to those file systems.
Now we will get the value deleted returned from.
And that's an assignment returned from the variable f's dot delete and that wants a slice of strings,
so we'll create a slice of string.
And inside of that, we'll just put item.
We're only deleting one thing and that will do the trick.
So delete it as a boolean if deleted, then.
H-2A app session put, and we use our context as always, and we're going to flash and we'll put format
Sprint F percent s was deleted and substitute item four percent, yes, OK.
And I will do a redirect HDP to redirect w her list fs same as before.
Question mark f s dash type equals plus f s type with the status http dot status c others.
And that should do it now.
Clearly, there's no error checking going in here because this isn't a production quality web page I'm
building.
This is just to demonstrate that a remote file systems work, and this is absolutely sufficient for
our purposes.
So let's switch over to rootstock, go and add a root into delete files.
And I'll just put it right here and you don't get and I want to get slash delete.
From that face, and that calls aid handlers from the office, and now when I restart my application,
make restart, this should all work.
So back we go over to our web browser, refresh this page to make sure it's current.
It is, and let's delete Whale Dash Big Dot Ping, so delete.
Am I sure I want to delete this file?
Yes, delete.
And we have an error.
So let's go back and see what we got wrong.
That happens sometimes.
And the air is.
Right up here.
Conversion interface is no, not minimal filesystems, I.
So I got something wrong, my handler must go to delete from file system, and if you misspell the key,
you're going to have a problem.
I'm sure you saw that.
So let's make restart.
And back to my Web browser, and I'll go back one page.
To hear refresh this and now let's try deleting the whale big that looks better.
It's gone perfect.
So that takes care of testing out and making the core functionality active for minute, and we'll move
on to the next file system in the next section.