Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about Maps concept.
Maps and go blank.
And that is a data structure that provides you with an on older collection of key value pairs, mats
are also sometimes called associated arrays in the hash tables in Java or dictionaries in Python.
Maps are used to look up the value byte is associated key U.S. values into the map based on a key.
This rings of a map is its ability to retrieve data quickly based on the key.
It key warps like an index pointing to the value you associate with that key.
And that is implemented using a hash title, which is providing fast and loose run on the data element,
and you can easily retrieve a value by providing the key.
Maps are on ordered collections, and there is no way to predict the order in which the key value pairs
will be returned.
Every iteration over a map could return in a different order.
You can see maps in the following table.
She has to be distinct in the map value chain IQ industry case, you can access the key value pair of
a map using key key in a map acts like an index in an array.
Maps specification.
Go land mass is a collection of old dictators of key value.
It's widely used because it provides new crops and values that can retreat, update or delete with the
help of peace.
It is a reference to a hash table due to its reference time.
It is inexpensive to pass, for example, for a 64 bit machine.
It takes eight points and 42 Big Machine.
It takes four bites in maths.
The values are not unique like keys and can be of any type like in float 64 room S2 point to a reference
type, map type and etc..
In maps, you can only add value when the map is initialized.
If you try to add value in the uncivilised map, then the compiler will through any rule.
These are the Maps specification.
In the maps, a key must be unique and always in the type which is compatible using equal to operate
or or the Typekit support, not equal to operator.
So most of the built in time can be used as a key like an envelope, 64 room sitting comparable area
in structure pointer and said throw the data types luck slice and non-credible arrays and instruments
or custom data times which are not comparable.
Don't use as a map key.
The type of keys and type of values must be of the same time, different types of keys and values in
the same maps are not alone.
But the type of key and the type values can differ.
And the map is also known as a hash map hash stated unaltered map dictionary or associated array.
OK.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we've been finished and we will continue the content
in the next session.
Goodbye.