Hello and welcome to the Go Line programming language course in the previous session.
We talked about Maps, a specification, and in this session we want to talk about the authors map concept.
Creating and initializing maps, you go language maps can create and initialize using two different
ways.
First, they simply.
In dismissal, you can simply create a mess using the given syntax.
You can see the syntax for creating an anti-matter, and you can see the creative map with key value
pair, by simple way.
In maps, there's zero value of the map is need and in need, map doesn't contain any key.
If you try to add a key value pair in the mean map, then the companion will through wrong time and
all.
Now, go to this school to illustrate how to create an initialized mass by a simple way.
OK.
First, create a project folder like maps and create a file like name the school, create package
and create main function.
First, define an antique map without initializing.
Now do the following code that and the map.
Equals map.
And telling it straight and without initializing now displayed a created map if the and to now and set
the barrier to entry A. Map now defined in Map Valley a bit and initialize it.
Go to the next line and create value for the example on my map equals map.
Keys in and values string.
Now initialize it for the example key is volume and values can then put a comma and right, are that
a key value pairs long?
Colin Quinn said comma to Colin
Jeanne said comma three column rather said comma four column gene and five column for the example to
add more and said the calm before might be called and display the created very even more map.
FP my know my ma.
We create two variable first empty map without initializing and second map by initializing.
And the key for it is int and the value of it is a string.
Save the project, go to the terminal first clear screen, go to the folder projects, see the maps
and execute the project by the command, meaning that Google.
Now we can see the output for the anti-malaria vary a.
We have, Neal, because we don't initialize my variable able and for my map very a bit.
We have von keen to gene to rob her and fully game gene because we can duplicate the value and five
is at work.
Now we could define Ant-Man and creating an initializing and another map by simply.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.