Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
creating an initializing maps by sympathy.
And in this session, we want to talk about the authors map concept.
Creatine and initializing mass using make function.
You can also create a map using make function.
This function is an inbuilt function, and in dismissal, you just need to pass the time of the man
and it will return and initialized map.
You can see the syntax.
Now, go to Waskow to illustrate how to create an initialise map using make function.
For the example, creating your map using may function to restore students at schools.
That my math.
Equals make function math.
He is estranged and value is flawed.
Sixty four, as we already know, that made function always returns in map, which is initialized so
we can add value in it.
Go to the next line my map
for the exam pad.
She is keen and value is eighty point fifty five.
Go to the next line and add another value.
My map, for the example she is gene and value is ninety point thirty three.
Go to the next line and the other element my map for the example key is Robert's and value is 75 dot
60.
OK, reformat the code now.
Display the map elements FP, my my column and my map value, and save the project and execute the code.
Now we can see the output for S Score is eight point fifty five and GM is cool is ninety point three
and four.
Rather, its core is seventy five point sixty.
We could define the map for restoring the students is caused by the make function.
The student's name is stored in the map as index and there is cool as value in the map.
In order not prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in the
next session.
Goodbye.