Head on over to the golden programming language course in the previous session.
We talked about truncate map.
And in this session, we want to talk about the other maps concept.
Marriage maps, the keys and values of second map getting added in first maps now go to Waskow to illustrate
how to merge maps together.
First, create all my babies and initialise, then follow the example first, Colin equals man eat and
string and initialize it and column.
In
20, one g and 30, Colin Alex
and define another map, the second column, because no sit in, sits history as value times and visualize
it 40 columns, rather 20 column jean,
50 column Julia
and 60 column.
For the example, the
now use of fold in second map Marie and put the value of second body that in first the by the following
code full on Homer J.
Colin Equals range is secondary to the
first value of SITS index high and equals to G.
Now, peacefully, the elements of First Man Labor Pool I J Colin equals wrench in the first radiator
display all elements that is index rather.
Per cent, the.
Right is less T for space between index and value and value.
This thing is back in session and sit there validated I and G.
T Gold said the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output and we could add second variable elements in the first variable elements.
We have reached the end of decision.
I hope you have taken full advantage of this decision until next session.
Goodbye.