All right.
So welcome back.
And I'm excited to learn more about jihad P.C. with you and Daniel has done the lead legwork on figuring
G.P.S. out and putting together some examples.
So he's going to lead the charge here in sharing information about jihad P.C. and shown us how to get
things set up in just an hour brief conversations before we started this video.
Sounds like some good work.
He did some good work and the examples that are on GOP Web site one you've already seen how they're
not applicable to go modules.
And so it's nice yesterday Daniel to see you know how to get G.P.S. installed so that we can use it
using go modules and I made notes for you in the course outline how to do that.
And so as Daniel goes through and shares with us some examples we're going to see some examples with
using G.P.S. and you know understand them.
My job's going to be to ask questions and to clarify and to take notes and sort of make sure that the
process is all really well documented and solidified step one step two step three for you for me for
everybody when we need to look back and see area what do we do to get that running that's going to be
my job.
So Daniel thanks for your legwork on this and looking forward to seeing more about GOPAC What do you
got for us.
All right.
So so yeah I created in 0 1 prototype folder inside our GOPAC folder.
And so this will be where we'll do our first steps.
So inside this 0 1 prototype folder I'm creating an echo folder because I figure that first thing we're
going to do is create an echo server.
It will just repeat wherever you ask it or wherever you tell it right back to you.
Yeah.
So an echo service kind of like hello world with servers.
Right.
And we get one server to talk to one computer to talk to another computer so maybe a client to talk
to a server.
And is this what we're gonna do.
Yes.
So.
So I'm going to create an echo server first.
So I create the 0 1 protocol is where our projects in and inside there have got a sub folder called
Echo an inside echo.
I'm going to create a file and I'm just going to call this file Echo Dot proto So the DOT Pro is the
file format for protocol buffer the protocol buffer domain specific language.
And so in this file we'll describe a protocol about her messages and the G RBC service that will be
using those messages with so very first thing in a dot profile will be what version of proto a Protocol
Buffers you're going to be using.
So that so you'd find that with the sin the sin tax man syntax equals double quote proto three is the
latest one.
Now if you skip this one a semicolon if you skip this Protocol Buffers will Potosi will default proto
two proto three is the current recommended protocol buffer version to use and so it's taking this the
top of your dot profile will tell Potosi that you're using proto three C in three.
So after that you can define either your service or your messages.
So I'm going to find the service first.
So the service was gonna call it echo server.
It's just defined just like this say serve it I yes you say service you give it a name and then curly
braces.
So inside here you can define methods that can be used.
So you'd find a method by saying our P.C. and then you define the name of this method.
So I'm going to call it echo in parentheses you put in any parameters.
So this particular echo thing takes in an echo request which I have not defined yet.
And then it returns in parentheses and echo loops echo response and then empty curly braces.
And so this defines an echo server.
We'll have a command echo.
We'll have a method echo that takes that echo request and returns an echo response.
What's the RBC remove C.J..
That's just like a little signature keyword.
Yeah.
That you kind of like.
All right.
Yeah.
So a funk might have a function.
Yes.
Exactly.
So once you got this you've got to define what Echo requests an echo response are.
So those are both protocol buffer messages.
So to find them with message echo request curly brace and then you can fill in this body with what is
an echo request.
So an echo request I will say is a string with a message in it and then you put equals one.
If you have multiple things in here like you want to say a message and signed or sent by you put two
there.
So these numbers just have to be unique and you should not reuse a number even if you delete.
If I delete send by if I add nothing new later I should make sure not to put it to again.
Almost makes me think of a key field in a database.
They're using these internally somehow to identify.
Yes.
So that's echo request is just a message an echo response.
I think we'll probably be just about the same thing except it will be string response.
One called right.
And so this will be our complete Echo Dot Proto.
This defines an echo server an echo server has an echo command that takes an echo request and returns
echo response.
And these are what Echo requests and echo response are awesome.
So just in the desire to keep videos short this is kind of a good thing just getting the first chunk
of code written.
Do you have anything or you want one to add to this more or is this a good stopping to focus is a good
topic.
Okay great.
So in the next video what are we going to take a gander at actually turning this into code.
That sounds good.
See you the next video.