OK so in this video we're going to take a look at compiling the service.
And before Daniel jumps in and shows that I just wanted to share a little bit of information from my
reading which admittedly has been limited.
But here if you go to GOPAC dot I Io docs and guides what is GOPAC.
This is a nice little document to read through.
Just gives you introduction GOPAC but you can kind of see here you have clients communicating with the
server like that picture right there.
OK.
Clients communicate with a server.
Right.
But it has a little bit more information in there and you could see here defining a service very similar
to what we just set up and then down at the bottom.
The information about proto 2 versus proto 3 you know the universal principle of life.
Try to use the most recent version you all right.
So just you know whenever you watch this video maybe you came across this.
You're an archaeologist investigating the civilization of humans that lived for a while and you're like
Hey let's get this thing running.
Whatever is the most recent version in the land in which you come from where you are used the most recent
version and then I just want to point out one thing about DSL versus ITIL.
And so Daniel just casually said oh it's a DSL and if you haven't been exposed to DSL what a DSL is
before you might think maybe that's like some sort of Internet service.
But in DSL domain specific language is that what it stands for.
Yes.
And so it's language to help you write code automatically.
And so in go there's go.
Which Daniels had a ton of experience with and has a lot of value.
So you might want to check out go.
If you're into go and go OK is a DSL if you'd learn a different language which is the downside.
But then once you learn that language it automatically will generate code for you.
And that could be a benefit and then a DSL.
He used the word DSL but in the documentation for proto they talk about it in our interface definition
language.
And so if you do a little research between an ideal and ideal interface definition language and in DSL
it's kind of like tomato versus tomato.
They're pretty similar.
So that's what a DSL or ideal is.
And and you know that's also yeah just a little bit of information about that.
So I'm going to leave this as its own video I'm just going to make this Todd's commentary actually I
really like keeping video short and in the next video we're going to take a look at compiling the service
see the next video.