Well another one of the benefits of keeping the video short is that you know it's like OK got that one
good in the can stop there before you mess it up.
And so now we're going to take a look at compiling the service.
And Daniel you got some more stuff to share with us.
Let's see it.
Yeah.
So I will just keep in this oh one product for here because this is very I'm not actually writing any
code in this one.
So here we are just going to convert this stop profile into a dot go package that you can import that
actually can do stuff.
So my fair kind of code.
Yes.
So the command to do it is proto C which we just installed previously along with its extension and there's
a number of command line arguments that you have to add into this.
So I need to make sure I am in my 0 1 product folder and so I am one level above that.
I've got the echo folder in there.
Inside echo folders the Echo Dot protocol.
So.
So I'm basically in the base of this particular project and so I may use Potosi.
There's a dash I can dash capital I argument and you get this.
This is this should be the folder where your dot profiles in.
So my dot profiles in The Echo folder so debt dash capital echo then you give the full path to the DOT
profile.
So that's echo echoed out Proto.
And if you're on Unix posits Linux type machines it's going to look slightly different.
Yeah.
It'll just be forwards to the backslash.
Yeah same thing.
And then finally because we want to use make a go of this we want this to be a go package.
We use Dash Dash go underscore out equals.
And now there's kind of two kind of sections and so I will I'll do the first one first.
Just call it echo again which is just the the name of that folder again and if we look here we can now
see the sights echoed out Proto.
We now have an echo dot PDB 4 protocol buffer dot go to click in there.
This has are two messages echo request and echo response
so.
But this is not this is not have echo server listed in it.
It's just the protocol buffer part of it.
Echo request echo response.
So if you do the same command except go back to the Goda out or go underscore out equals echo instead
of putting echo you put plug ins equals G or C colon.
Echo so in between the go out in the echo you put in a plug in equal to your P.C. run that when you
go back here to the Echo PBT go it's
it's not running it
delete that it's plug ins plural plug ins that's funny.
Now you can see it's importing G.P.S. and if we scroll down past the echo request echo response we now
have some stuff about Echo server client and echo server server so the first one where you just did
the echo that didn't create the protocol buffer is that right.
So so that just created the protocol buffer messages.
Did not give extra code about service.
OK.
And then when you included the second commands it create the service.
So that was just to illustrate what the different different different flags are doing in the command
here.
That's what you want to illustrate.
Yes.
OK.
Say one thing to check when you're doing this make sure your package is matching your folder name just
to just for convenience sake.
Good.
Anything else to compiling the service.
No.
So now you've got to go file you can import it and be used.
All right see the next video where it's going to be a surprise for me even it's going to happen.