So two things for me that kind of came up as questions as protocol.
Buffer I think.
JASON Yes.
Does that get good association.
Yes.
And the other one is.
You know I think it'd be good just to have a little bit of a discussion of package name versus folder
name cause folder name could be totally different than package name.
And you could even have one folder with many different packages in it.
Correct.
Well I know all go files within a single folder must have the same po.
Oh go will actually give you an error or if you've got a different package name amongst go files in
a folder so you can have some folders underneath that with different package.
OK.
Okay.
That's right.
That's it.
And.
And just as you would go to there.
Okay.
So you just.
That is actually the folder name.
And it's just a best practice to have your folder name match your package name.
Yes.
Because when you import import by default you normally you can either define the package name manually
how what you're going to call it or it's based on the tax shame and what you're importing.
And so if that just matches the last one of the folder name that's easy for people to remember when
they're importing say all that again that went past me.
So it's like when I'm importing this stuff this proto thing.
Yeah.
If it grabs it from the older which is the same deal.
So it's actually whatever the package they list is.
So if that matches the folder path that's easy to remember yeah yeah but where does it get.
That has an alias there.
So in this case it's got legal aliens in them.
Right.
And if you don't have the alias it call you call it from the package name not the folder name but then
it's easy to associate if you have your folder or package.
So it's best practice.
Yes.
Temp folder named to package.
OK.
That's a that's a nice clarification.
I hope that that helps.
Those are my two reflections on Daniel's previous video compiling the service and the next video.
We've got some special planned for you.
I'm not sure what it is but I'm looking forward to seeing it.
See the next video.