All right.
So just to anchor you anchor you in the course outline what we've seen so far as defining the service.
And then I had a little commentary on DSL versus ideals of domain specific language versus interface
design language or definition language.
And we also talked about versions using the most current version.
And then we looked at compiling the service and then after that we talked about Protocol Buffers.
And then when I hear protocol buffer I think Jason and we also discussed folders and packages and go.
And so now we're going to see setting up a G.P.S. server and that's going to require writing some go
code so that we can use what we've generated so far and this will be a multi-step process.
And so we're not going to deal with the client yet.
We're just going to setup the server.
And Daniel is going to give us a walkthrough on that code.
And then in the video after this if needed all out and we'll add in another video we're all just kind
of like go through the code to help us all understand the code if that needs to happen.
And so that's the game plan that's where we've been where we are and where we're going.
And and the one thing that we were discussing off line which I added into our notes here for us to discuss
on videos that you get a piece of it was making sure to commit your ideal DSL whatever you want to call
it proto G.P.S. calls it ideal so maybe we should stick with ideal interface definition language.
And I just need to make sure I'm using the right right interface definition language.
There it is.
And and so you know we were talking about the importance of committing to get GitHub wherever you can
meet your code you're your ideal DSL stuff.
So you had a couple of thoughts on that and some experience with that.
Yeah just.
So yeah you need the dot the dot profile because that's your actual that's your important bit but you
also want to commit the DOT go filed that got generated from it.
So even though you can regenerate this whenever you want just by rerunning that Potosi command off of
the the DOT profile you still want to commit this dot go file so that you can import it or use it as
a module in other packages.
So make sure you commit both both the the file you write and the generated code based on that.
Yeah a little gotcha there as you might think well this could be generally the time I commit it.
And so don't do that just commit it all.
All right.
So let's see how to setup a G.P.S. sir.
So I've copied everything from the 0 1 0 2 0 2 server here just to to keep things clean and step wise
so I going to create a new file in here.
I'm just going to call it a mean go.
This is in the folder 0 2 server directly at same level as the echo folder so this will be my package
main with my func main.
And here's where we will create the server.
So first thing I'm going to want to do is if you go to the generated code and you scroll down enough
you will find the echo server server.
Yes it's got a little bit of stutter there.
So the first part their echo server is just what I define as my service and then it's the server part
of that.
So this is got an interface.
So you need to implement this interface as this is what you will call will be called whenever a request
is made to this.
So.
So to fulfill the interface you're going to need some type.
So I'm just gonna type echo server is an empty struct.
I don't have any fields that I need to have in that struct I could put an inch there just or just as
easily but empty struct is good because it takes no memory
so I'm going to and then I need to create in the echo server function I'm just gonna go over here to
this interface I'm just gonna copy this part here directly and then go back and add in the Echo Dot
and Echo Dot there in there.
So now I've got the function I'm going to save and I'm gonna need to go back and add the imports.
I'm going to need to import context and I'm going to need to import the.
This echo PDB.
So that's located at our namespace that are go modified so hub dot com slash goes to do that then slash
Golding project and then sub folders I mean 0 0 5 dash G R P C slash 0 2 0 2 server slash echo
looks good.
So that's R so that's that imports.
This generated echo from code.
And when I see that we're now creating a method with the receiver pointer to echo server attached to
the type echo server struct then we have to in this method return that pointer to an echo response and
an error yet.
So we've got to get something to go in there that returns a pointer to an a response.
Yeah.
There see a pointer to an egg to an echo echo response.
And so this will just be your normal response and error.
So because our response if you look in your profile or echo responses has a restrained response.
So if we go into our generated code we can actually find an echo response is a struct with all these
fields these three ones that start x x x are internal to proto buffer so we don't need to worry about
them.
So we just have this response.
So we can just create that as response.
So this will be what our responses.
And so we want our response to be maybe echo colon and then whatever they sent us in the echo request.
So our echo request we need to make sure we actually have variables for each of these so I could request
we got request dot and there's a bunch of stuff in here.
Message though is what we defined an echo request has a message.
And again if you go to the generated code we can find echo request and it's got message and some proto
Buffington.
Nice.
So.
So now whenever someone calls echo we will send back a response.
Echo colon space whatever they syntax let's call it my echo.
I know it's just like text right.
There you go.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Great.
So.
So now we've defined our End Point.
Now we need to actually create the server part.
And so this is not actually as easy as the HP package we're just listening server.
It's got a few extra steps.
So first off you GOPAC server does not listen by default on a network port.
So we have to create a network listener ourselves.
And so that's in just the the net package not net HP just net so net
listen takes in to our net debt listen takes them to arguments it takes in what kind of network you're
listening on and then the address.
So that what you're listening on we want to listen for key messages and the address is just basically
the port.
So colon 88 works here.
So to listen on Port 88 this gives our listener and their potentially so once we got that check our
error is not equal nil.
It's an IC error so we've got our listener now.
Now we've set up the GOP C server so I'm just gonna go to this generated code because it's got the import
for G.P.S. and just import that real fast so GOPAC
you can create a G.P.S. server like this and this takes in a number of options that are all optional.
So I'm going to skip all of those that you that would be where you'd set up like authentication if you
wanted like TRW or something that would be a potential argument but an on off antiquated servers.
Good enough for here.
So we'll just leave it at that.
Now we need to create our echo server so this server is a pointer to echo server.
And now we need to register our echo server with the GOP server or so.
So that line twenty seven there you're just instantiating I want to see instantiate you are you are
initializing a variable of type echo server and it has no fields.
So.
So to register echo server with the service one of our generated functions.
If we go all the way down to the Echo server server interface right underneath it there is a register
echo server server function that takes in a GOP server and an active server server interface so we can
just use that directly Echo Dot register echo server clear pass in our G.P.S. server and our.
And our implementation of the Echo server server interface now GOP C knows about our service and now
we need to actually listen.
So we tell our G.P.S. server to serve on our listener and this could potentially return in error so
we'll check our error
so one thing you might do to just make things nicer to you might put in a print line now serving at
Port 88 just to just to let you so you can know when you are when it's finished starting at
right.
So this server is now running available I can go run main dot go
which will build and run it
however long it takes.
There it goes the breathless moment you hear it's now 0 or 80 80 awesome.
So done.
Let's say we don't have a client yet.
We can't actually check if it's working as we intend yet.
That'll be the next video.
But this is how you how you create a server or implement your service that you've defined and how to
register it up with a GOP server nicely done.
See you next video.