So just a couple of reflections that came up for me while you're writing your code.
The first one is Daniel's.
Ed does something special with not equals.
And so if you look at like line twenty two if error is not equal to nil you could see an equal sign
with a slash through it.
And so that is like whenever he has not equal just replaces the exclamation in the equal sign with a
different visual notation.
But he knows and I know that when I see that on his screen that means not equal.
But if you're watching this you like how do I get that symbol in my code.
It's good for you to know that that symbol is actually the not equal.
And so that which is the exclamation.
And then the equal silence you could see Daniel demonstrating there on his editor.
So it's the first thing I want to point out.
I don't think you have any of those other ones that we've come across right.
Yeah.
My my font also has like greater been equal and less.
You know which is a great around for you.
Yeah.
All right.
So just to know if you're seeing that and you can go google that if you want to try to figure out how
to set that up and sublime or something else.
And then the next thing which was an interesting point for me was the comment that you made that an
empty strike takes no memory.
Tell us a little bit about that.
That's just the design of go.
But you have any other thoughts or insight into just a struct is just a struct it takes up as much memory
as all its fields.
So an empty struct has no fields and no fields means no memory.
So this is so just overall it doesn't really matter in the long run but just if you do have if you need
a type just to the point to interface and you don't really have any anything else that you need that
type forward you're just doing it to input the interface empty struct is in theory at least more efficient
than any other underlying type.
So if I created a type echo server with the underlying type and so type echo server int right.
And then later down below online twenty eight I create a server as equal to an echo server.
And yeah.
And so there that's actually going to take memory right.
Yeah it's going to close now.
I mean it takes that service storing the value 0.
But if it's just echo server struct it that's not taking any memory or less memory because when I initialize.
So if I did line twenty eight there about the curly braces or just say serve as colon equal to pointer
to an echo server that doesn't work.
But I could do var serve pointer echo server and that would declare Savi we type that in.
Can you type that in var serve and pointer to an echo server.
All right.
And and then that is very similar.
And that declares it that the variable s Savi is of type pointer to an echo server.
But I haven't allocated any memory yet is that so it is declared the memory for S or V which is a pointer.
Yeah so.
So technically matter of memory for one pointer but that point to no.
Okay so this is same thing except the pointer is not normal but it's pointing to no memory anyway because
the underlying type takes no memory or what it's pointing to takes.
So if you go ahead I think this would work as it is because we're not actually using e here.
So the fact that he is no it would actually run still but it's not really a big deal or anything.
Yeah.
No I'm just exploring this concept of memory allocation and when does memory get allocated.
Not initializing.
And then you know having the curly braces at the end there actually initialize Is that right.
So you have memory allocated at that point.
So this also allocates the memory but it sets to zero value which for a pointer is null.
Okay.
Or or nil.
All right not totally clear on that you have anything more you want to say about it.
That's feels like a little bit of a bigger topic.
Yeah.
Maybe not drop into it right now and then the last thing that kind of stood out to me was everything
was making sense up to line 26.
So a line 21 you do TCB not listen and then line twenty six you create a new GOP server and then line
twenty eight.
It's like well you have this method that needs to be implemented.
How did you know to connect that method.
You know the echo method with the server that you have to tell the server about that.
That was looking in the generated code you knew you had to connect to those.
Yes.
They either generate code has that register which kind of almost matches having to setup a mucks for
HDP.
You've got to tell them you had to use handle func to tell your server where your end points are and
then in the gypsy docs tutorials for a go.
There is an example for starting a server which includes that kind of thing to all right good.
So that's the the work procedure you going twenty eight create a variable value of type pointer to an
echo server you register that so that your server your GMP server now is aware of that value with that
echo method and it can use it.
And and then you serve and it's ready to serve on that listener.
Cool.
Great.
Those are my reflections and we got more for you coming in the next videos.