So next step is to create a client for this.
And so I'm just gonna create a go client or quick and easy bit and perhaps later perhaps later we'll
show how to get it set up so it works with a web browser.
So in this case though I've created 8 and 0 3 client which is a copy of the 0 1 Proto.
So it just has the echo folder with the profile and the PDB the generated code and so I'm going to create
a I may not go 0 3 holds what 0 2 held right.
0 1 0 0 2 has the server so I don't use the serve and the clients haven't got it yet.
So copying off just the prototype.
The protocol buffer no prototype.
So this is package mean it's got func mean so.
So that's all pretty normal.
So what you need to do.
I gotta get outta there.
So first thing you're gonna need to do is you're gonna need to make a connection to the server so you.
So you're gonna need a connection.
And so you do this with G R P C dot dial and you're gonna import G.P.S. real fast
so GOP speed dial to create a connection.
So Gypsy dial takes in where you're connecting to.
So in this case I'm connecting to my own local host server at Port 880 and it takes an additional arguments.
So one of those additional arguments that we're going to need is g or P.C. dot with insecure this this
tells GOPAC that your connections not secured through teal s or any other security protocol expected.
Don't worry about it.
And now as you discovered that how a trade it out without it.
And GOPAC actually just printed out a message saying exactly that there's no security.
If you intend this add this to your dial function nice.
So the usual if error not equal nil.
I'm just panicking on errors here because I don't have any other response.
Normally you'd log with them and do something but for demonstration purposes panicking works.
So whenever you got a connection you're gonna need it for closing that connection.
So deferred closing the connection.
So when Maine ends we'll close the connection to the server.
Then you need to.
We're going to need to import our echo generated echo code.
I'm just gonna go back to the server copy that import line and change it from 0 to server to 0 3.
Client
now ex to echo and their echo has one of the generated echo functions is new Echo server client.
This takes in a G.P.S. connection.
It returns an echo server client.
So we've got that connection.
This gives us our echo client and so our echo client has our echo function.
Just as we defined in the protocol
so with the Echo function it takes in a context an echo request and optionally some gypsy call options
which most the time you shouldn't need.
And it will return an echo response and an error.
So we need to pass in a context.
So we're going to if we need a context we're gonna need to create have one.
So since we don't have one already we can create one with context dot background
Mitre import conflict context
to get the context and we need to make Senator echo requests so echo echo request echo request has a
message.
So let's just say hello world.
This will send back a response and an error.
Check our error
and now we've got a response.
So our response has bunch of private stuff from four protocol buffer.
But most importantly it's got response which is as we defined in our profile an echo response as response
so let's just print that print line got from server response that response and import jumped because
we're using it.
So now I have the server running at port 80 80 so if I go here I got 0 3 client and I go run mean go.
This should make that connection and called the excise to go from server might echo well done.
Como see in the next video.