Anything to say in another video.
So one thing I have it's just like a reflection on response versus response and so when we do our ideal
interface definition language our response is lowercase.
But that's a different language.
And when it gets compiled in go code it becomes capital.
So it could be exported right.
And so if we look here at the actual structure that gets generated a response response capital R it's
got the tag here pro above.
And it's got a name response lowercase.
And then the next thing is just a little bit of a discussion of what are we actually doing here.
And so a remote procedure called idea behind a remote procedure calls that your client.
There's a server there's some procedure function method up here on the server.
And right now in our ideal are in our definition language we said that up on our our client we're going
to have a remote procedure called Echo that this client can call this procedure function method whatever
echo up on the server and it's going to run.
This is just another way for me of thinking about a client makes a request the server does something
and sends it back.
Right.
Like it's just like different terminology for talking about you know if we talked about this to the
HP we'd be say endpoints and back Jason.
Right.
But here we're saying you know a function you know the RCC is usually disguised as if it looks like
an ordinary function.
So if you did not know this that this was an error procedure call you wouldn't think it was.
You just see oh it's just an echo function takes in a context and this struct it returns some other
struct.
So the fact that it's actually going across a network in between the middle.
This is hidden from the from the code from the coder here.
OK.
For the client.
Yeah but you guys set the server up to deal with that obviously.
Yes.
All right.
Yeah.
So when we call E dot at good barracks we have a client and calls echo and new Echo is available because
of our ideal because we define that our generated code.
And when it calls echo it's actually you know call that on the client on the server and then it sends
back the response.
Yeah.
Huh.
Cool.
All right.
Any other reflections you want to add to that.
So this is the most basic of GOPAC.
He has many many additional features to kind of add on top.
So for setting up secure security e you don't have to go with this insecure connection.
Streaming requests and responses when you don't have all the data available but you get some of it immediately
you can rise to meet a stream that response and then come up with more responses later.
There's a lot more to GOPAC but the absolute basics is just request response and that is how you get
it set up and then this would be something that we could use to fulfill any type of a service.
Right.
Maybe you know in the past we maybe would have thought of that as client server endpoint in a restful
endpoint or whatever API sin back.
Jason you know and have the client deal with that and display the results.
And here it would just be instead of that sort of a framework GOPAC you know makes its calls the function
the client calls the function that function runs on the client remote procedure it runs on the server
remote procedure and then data comes back which the client uses.
What's the advantage of GOPAC it's more is it faster and more secure.
It's it's smaller and faster and then it's got the additional features kind of on top of what rest traditionally
has.
Good.
All right thanks.
It's good stuff.
I like that discussion.