Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about F.A. package concept.
A family package in Golang.
Taken kind of defining a package is essentially a container of source code for some specific purpose
packages are very essential.
As in all programs ranging from the most basic programs to a high level complex codes, these are used.
A package ensures that no code is repeated and that the main code is and consist as possible in a very
structured manner.
Google provides various inbuilt packages to users so they can ease, including with pretty defined basic
functionality packages.
One of such packages is the FMV package.
If emptiest stands for the format package, this package allows to format basic strings, values or
anything and preen them or collect user input from the console or write into a fine.
Using a writer or even print, customized, fancier or messages.
This package is all about formatting, input and output.
Let's look at the functions it provides to its users, along with a brief description of each function
print function.
The print function and go language formats using the default format for its offerings and rise based
on the output print function simply prints whatever input it receives as it is on the output console
screen, beginning from the current cursor position without appending any space or nil lines unless
explicitly coded.
Here is spaces are added between options, then any a string is not used as a parameter.
Moreover, this function is defined under the empty package here.
You'll need to import this empty package in order to use these functions.
Now you can see the syntax.
A 3.0 interface containing some strings and declare constant variables.
Return value, it returns the number of by 310 and in your right error in concert.
Now let's go to this school with program to illustrate the uses of brain function.
First, go to expeller and create a project folder like if!
A..
Create a file like name that go.
And define package me and define main function, okay?
First, declaring some esoteric variables, for the example that is still one comma is still two comma
is CRT and initialized, then A and B.
And for SDR three, we said see that you go to the next line and column print function to display defined
string variables.
A. got dot print function and set this variable as arguments for this function is t r one, s t r two
and SDR G.
OK.
And declaring some no variable sport b pick that number one, number two and number three initialize
them five, 10 and 50 for Gnome three, go to the next line and it will create function to display defined
number variables if anti-God can't print function and set these variable as arguments or print function.
No one known to and said No.
Three.
OK.
The format the code save the project and execute the program.
First, go to project folders, CD20 and run the program.
Now we can see the output in the first go, the variables used are extremes.
Hans Espaces are not added in between two extremes, but in the second coat the variables used are no.
Hans Espaces are added in between two numbers in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.