Hello and welcome to the golden and programming language course in the previous session, we talked
about escena function and in decision, we want to talk about the other half empty package concept.
Yes, again, Ellen, function.
This scandal and function in language, it scans the input tax, which is given in this standard input
leads from there and distorts the success of the space separated values into successive arguments.
These functions stop scanning at the new line and after the final item, there must be a new line or
end of fine.
Moreover, this function is defined under the half empty package.
Here, you'll need to import the empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see the syntax a tree dot interface receives, each given text and returns value.
It returns the number of items successfully scanned.
Now let's go to this school with program to illustrate the uses of this scantlin function.
Now, declaring some variables like that name and type of it is strange, and their age and time for
it is eight.
Now calling it function for scanning and reading, Dame could take given in this standard inputs for
this work before passed the variable as argument, the use ampersand symbol for the example for that
value from input a standard to name variable.
So we write F.A. Dot Scanlen.
And person name.
And do these for other variable Ethereum 2.0 skin and Anderson H now printing the given text FMV dot
print f Kurson s conversion character for name variable because it is a string and first in the converging
character for age variable because it is an integer and set variable name and age, reformat the code,
save the project and execute the program now into a desired value for this value that, for the name
the Inter chain, go to the next line by Inter and for the A's we import 13 Inter.
Now we can see the output chain name and thirty four h.
We were able to get the value builds value from using scantlin function from this standard input, then
print them in the above example with defined tool variables and assign values to each of them in the
new line.
For the example, one set value for name write value and presenter.
Four Go to the next line and set value for age variable so we could set values for these variables by
this candle and then function in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.