Hello and welcome to the goal and programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
Eskin function.
And in this session, we want to talk about the other half empty package concept.
S skin function.
The scan function in Golden Goose scans, this specified ticks and is sold to successive estates separated
takes into successive arguements as a skin walks similar to his skin, except the difference that it's
can collect input as the argument is strong and not the input from the consulate screen in the default
formatting.
Moreover, this function is defined under the empty package here.
You'll need to import their empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see the syntax parameters.
This function accepts two parameters which are illustrated below.
First, SDR type is string.
This parameter contains the specified text, which is going to be scanned and a three dot interface.
This parameter receives each text and returns.
It returns the number of items successfully scanned.
Now, let's go to this school program to illustrate the uses of Siskind function.
First, declaring some value varies by the different times.
For the example, their name is strange that age ain't that Mark felt very too.
And that is, I accept Paul
now calling the scan function, which returns the number of elements successfully scanned error or if
it is persists.
So we define two variables and return time for this system function and assign it to these variables
like number, comma, E. R. Collins equals and invoke essence and function from empty package if empty
40. As the scan set value for value, for example, Robert four nine two five four eight seven to nine
point eighty four Mark and true for his accent and set variable for this value, ampersand name and
ampersand age and ampersand mar and ampersand is exit.
Below statements get executed if there is any or even e are not equals to mean
punish.
And sits there at all and now printing the number of elements and each elements of empty dot print earth,
no.
All elements percent de Dash percent, this person, the person G and percent T and set variables.
Number four, despite a number of elements and set variables, name
age, mark and is exit the format.
The code saved the project and executed the program.
Now we can see the output number of elements is four and values are Robert four main twenty five for
a seventy nine point eighty four mark and through four is accepted.
Now we were able to get the variable this value from using a Siskind function and preens din in order
not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.