Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session we talked about
is can Alan Fonctionne?
And in this session, we want to talk about other empty package concept.
If she can function.
The EFSF can function and go languorous, its cards, the specified takes leads from Io dot reader and
then it the successive Espace separated value into successive arguments here.
New lines get counted as a space, unlike other Eskin functions.
This conflict improved firm user or the program console in default formatting, efficient reads content
or takes from the input file and returns the known of items pass.
It reads Character wise, progress direction depends on the point or location you provide.
Moreover, this function is defined under the empty package.
Here, you'll need to import the empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see the syntax.
Parameters, this function accepts two parameters which are illustrated below.
First, our type is i o dot reader.
This parameter contains this can specify text and the either a tree that either face this parameter
receives each type of the specified texts and returns value.
It returns the number of items successfully scanned.
Now go to the school program to illustrate the uses of efficient function.
First, declaring some type of variables that may destroy their age, eat that mark.
Float turn two and that is accept bowl
now, calling the new reader function to specify some type of text variable.
A scan contains the scan takes, so write a scan column equals some strings package in new reader function
and set value like Roberts and three, five, four, eight and nine to five point fifty four mark and
total for the IS accept that even now, calling the office can function to receive this scanned text.
First, define two variables like number and you are calling equals from the F.A. package.
Be invoked if the scan method and sets for first argument is scan and then set the value of a large
Andersen name.
Ampersand, H, Ampersand, mark and Ampersand is exit.
If the above function returns an error, then Bill, our statement will be executed if we are not equals
to mean.
So, right, if A. don't have plaintiff from the this package select is T D, B, R R and sits message
if skin color person v. bank and and sit very well at all.
Now printing each type of a scan takes number of items successfully.
A scanned FP number of elements set no variable.
And the other variable name, age and mark and is exit reform the call, save the project and executed
the program.
Now we can see the output number of elements four and values Robert, four main and three five for age
and ninety five point fifteen for Mark and threw for easy exit.
Now we were able to get the variable its value from using fse and function and print.
Then in order not to prolong the time of decision, they will finish it and we will continue the content
in the next session.
Goodbye.