OK.
Hello and welcome to the goal and programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
if a skin function.
And in this session, we want to talk about the other half empty package concept.
If it's going to function.
The first kind of function in go language is carries the specified text read from Io dot reader and
then source the successive space separated values into successive humans as determined by the format.
Here are new lines in the input most match new lines in the format.
If of works similar to it, the skin.
The only difference is that if this kind of reads from reader in the specified format, rather than
following the default format, you.
The match case is sensitive, who walks the spaces and new lines and hands, the argument is true and
takes the string must match entirely.
Moreover, this function is defined under the empty package.
Here you need to import this empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see the syntax parameters.
This function accepts three parameters which are illustrated below.
Our time is I owed the reader this parameter contains this can specify takes format assigning this parameter
contains different formats for receiving the elements.
A TV that interface this parameter is the specified variable for each element and returns value.
It returns the number of items successfully pass.
Now, let's go to a school with program to illustrate the uses of FSG and the function.
First declaring some type of variables.
I mean, it's strange that h in that mark float 32 and that these exit four is
now calling the new leader function to specify some type of text variable to skin contains the scan
tastes, so skin radiated collagen equals from this drinks package.
Select new reader function
and set value like Robert, 35, for age ninety point fifty four more and through for the ease exit.
Now calling the foreskin function to receive this scan takes.
So first, define two variable like number and your calling equals from the Affinity Package.
Select FC function
here.
Set I ordered reader in this case is Eskin variable Lescure and set Estyn formatting for defined variables
per cent.
Yes for name person B four eight person, F for Mark and person, P for ease, exit and set variables
and person name and Anderson age and Anderson March and Ampersand is exit.
If the above functional returns and there are 10 below statement will be executed.
E e are not equal to mean if n t don't def fiend
from OS Estero or s package that this t raw and set value for skin color person v backslash end and
set a rule value
now printing each type of a scanned text number of items successfully.
A scan FP number of elements.
Sits no and sit the other variables.
Name, age, Mark and his exit now reformat the cool, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output number of elements is full and value for name is Robert and 35 for age and
ninety point fifty for Mark and two value for his assets.
Now we you're able to get the variable value from using FSC on a function and Princeton in order not
to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.