Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about print function, and in this session we want to talk about
the others empty package concept.
Print if function.
The print function in go language formats, according to a format, is spicy air and rise to standard
output print a format, staying put the string as the user's choice and then prints the formatted string
onto the output console, beginning from the current cursor position without appending any space or
new lines, unless explicitly coded.
This function is defined under the empty package here.
You need to import this empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see the same tests.
Parameters, dysfunction, access to parameters which are illustrated below format extreme.
This contains some strings along with some depth and a three dot interface.
This contains a specified constant variables and the return value it returns the number of by 310 and
any right or encountered.
Now, let's go to the school curriculum to illustrate the uses of print a function
first, deep learning some history variables that.
For example, the name and value and equals by the values go and true and language.
Now calling print and function go to the next line if!
A. Don't print if.
OK.
For former, this drink as argument dry earth, and it's because it's case is conversion connector for
string value, this is a person.
Yes.
The art back is less and and said name and venue.
Now let's define some other variables like that.
Number one, No.
Two and number three, integer variable equals five, 10 and 15 now would print a function again.
FMC Dot Plaintiff.
Because we define integer variables, we said Person de la Chase as an emerging characters, plus per
cent the equals per cent the bank and and set these variables here.
No.
One, No.
Two and No.
Three, reform the court, save the project and executed the original.
Now we can see the output go is a programming language and five plus 10 equals 15.
So we could use print at function for formatting variables and display.
Then in order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content
in the next session.
Goodbye.