Hello and welcome to the Ghoulam Programming Languages course in the previous session.
We talked about printing and function and in decision, we want to talk about the others this empty
package concept.
Aspirin function.
Are sprint function and go language formats using the default format for its operations and in return,
the resulting string is spinning functions the same them as Sprint does?
The only difference is that Sprint returns the input string instead of printing on the output console.
Here the spaces are added between operations, then any stream is not used as a constant by either.
Moreover, this function is defined under this empty package here.
You need to import this empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see this syntax here.
A three dot interface contains some strings, including a specified constant variables and return value.
It returns the resulting string.
Now, let's go to this school program to illustrate the uses of aspirin function.
First declaring some assumed variables.
That name value equals and initialized in go and programming.
Language.
And now calling his brain function first define a variable like result, calling equals from this empty
package, be called a spinning function and set variable like name and a string value is a set another
variable large value and set a new line that is large and now calling.
Write a string function from I or package to write or retain contents of this string function.
As a string result, thunderclouds go to the next line.
I start writing string and set CD out from, or is packaged as a writer or start out and set a string
line result.
The city out, also known as a standard output, is the default file descriptor or very process can
write output, reformat the code, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output go is a programming language.
First, we created a string value then and then using the sprint function, then we assigned the return
value inside the resort variable.
And finally, we print the value of the recent variable inside this standard output in order not to
prolong the time of decision will finish sheet and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.