Hello and welcome to the Golang Programming Languages course independent news station.
We talked about print function and indecision.
We want to talk about the others if empty package concept.
This print alone function.
It's print and function in go language formats, using the different formats for its offerings and returns,
the resulting string, this being in function the same way as print and does.
The only difference is that it's print and returns.
The input is streamed instead of printing on the output console.
Here, its cases are always added between operations and a new line is appended at the end.
Moreover, this function is defined under the F.A. package.
Here, you'll need to import this empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see the syntax.
A 3.0 interface is containing some strings, along with the specified constant variables and return
value.
It returns the resulting string.
Now let's go to this school program to illustrate the uses of its print and function.
First, declaring some missing variables that name and venue equals go and.
Programming.
Language.
Now, Corning Estrin and function from the empty package first defining variable like these are calling
equals.
If Empty Dot is print and function and set variables to its name, comma set a value for a string like
is a and common and another value.
Then George Bagyo, now calling write a string function to write the contents of the string result to
always start a study out now right i o dot write the string and set arguements first from the package
is thought out and then search results.
OK, now let's define some other variables.
So go to the next line and define that number one, number two and number three and number four and
initialized for the example, at five, 10, 15 and 50.
Now calling sprint and function and display class and multiplication of these variable is again.
So define a variable like result.
One call equals from this empty package is sprint and function and set variables number one, comma
class, number two, comma equals and set number three and go to the next line.
Define another variable like resolved to call an equals F.A. Dot.
Select Sprint and function.
And Set variable number one camera multiplication and no.
Two Comma equals and select norm.
For many of us, now, cutting right is adding function to write the contents of strings results and
then result to two always thought study out so right.
I o the arthritis three.
And sits, oh, is that a study out as writer and said variable result Juan and go to the next line
and i o dot select writers string function and sit o is thought out as writer argument and said result
to variable the format.
They could save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output go is a programming language.
Five plus 10 equals 15 and five.
Multiplication 10 equals 15.
First, we create this string variable and using the print alone function.
Then we assign the return value inside the result variable and finally be preaching the value of the
results variable inside the standard output in the second code.
Now new line or space is used nested this function up a new line in the space between the operators
in order not to prolong the time of decision to be finished, and we will continue the content in the
next session.
Goodbye.