Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
screen and function.
And in this session, we want to talk about the author's empty package concept.
If print function.
The f print function and go language formats using the different formats, both its offerings and rise
to eyeball writers.
Unlike other print function, the print does not read or print anything on the console.
If print formats, the input is strong as per the default formatting and rise the formatted input entering
into the input file.
Here, the spaces are added between operations, then any string is not used as a parameter.
Moreover, this function is defined and or death empty package here.
You'll need to import the empty package in order to use this function.
Now you can see this syntax.
Parameters this function, access to parameters which are illustrated below first W Time I cowriter,
this is this specify the standard input or output and a tree interface.
This is containing some strings or constant variables used in the code and return value.
It returns the number of by written and any write error encountered.
Now let's go to this school with Cary Grant to illustrate the uses of f print function
first declaring song value.
This for the example that no one and No.
Two and No.
Three and initialize then by value five, 10 and 15 now calling if print function is free to too many
of us, for the example, first number as the number of by 310 and error as any error encountered.
So number and e are
equals from the empty package select f print function.
First, always thought this out
as a standard output and select value, there's no one and No.
Two and No.
Three and defiant and back end now printing the number of by 310.
So if empty dot print function, no comma bytes written.
That's like a slash and.
And printing, if any, are encountered, if A. Don and said the value of reformat the code, save the
project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output five, 10, 15 and eight by 310.
And no error in the amount of code variables used are numbers.
Hands spaces are added in between two numbers.
First, we create a variable and using the f print function.
Then we assign a retain value inside to variables like number and URL.
And finally, we print the number of buys written as number, and if there is an error, we will display
it as error value.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.