So now we know how to send an event from our application to our pusher server and then have that sent
off to all the connected clients, and in order to do something useful, we need to do a little bit
of work just to set things up.
So I'm looking at the application right now and I'm looking at the overview page.
And apparently we're going to be monitoring hosts.
And over here I have a list of hosts and those hosts will have services and each service can have one
of four possible statuses.
If everything is OK, it's healthy.
If there's a warning of some sort, we would we would populate this list.
If there is a problem, like a host is down or whatever, this would be in the problem section.
And pending is a service that we've said start monitoring this, but it actually hasn't checked it yet.
So it's a pending service.
So clearly, we're going to need something in our database to hold hosts and services.
And I think the easiest way to do that is to set up a model, a table in our database that holds all
of our hosts to set up another table, that holds all of the possible services that we want to monitor
and then have a third table that lists all of the hosts for a all of the services for a given host.
So let's set that up.
It won't be too hard.
So I'm going to go over to my idee and I'm going to open my terminal window and I'm going to generate
some migration's to generate these tables because I don't want to build them by hand.
So I'll say SOTA generate and I'll generate a Buis format.
And if you're not familiar with that, you'll see it in just a moment.
It's just a really simple syntax for describing tables.
And I'm going to generate, first of all, create post table and that's just the name of my migration.
And when I run that, it creates two new migrations and you'll find those in your application folder
under Migration's.
So here there are two new migrations, one for the down and one for the up and the down.
Migration will actually create the up migration will actually create the table and the down migration
just reverses it.
So let's do the up migration first, so I'm going to create and this is the syntax called Fiz Create
a table named hosts.
And inside of the curly brackets, I just define each of the columns to column on in the column ID and
that will be a primary key, it's a type integer and then some options for it.
And the option for this one is this is my primary key.
So primary true.
And then closure parenthesis, then I'll have another call, Titcomb, what else do I want for my host?
Well, how about hostname?
Something that we can actually refer to so we know what it's called and it will be of type string and
we'll just specify size of, say, 255, and that's going to be in quotes size of 255 characters.
That should be sufficient.
And close my parenthesis, then another column, and I'll just duplicate this to make it a little faster,
I'll call this the correct domain name for the host.
So what's it actually called?
So I call this canonical name, canonical name.
So that would be the name that it exists on the Internet.
So.
Could be my post.com, whatever it is, and I've got to get rid of that extra quotation mark.
It will also be a string and it'll be a size of 255, then I want the euro.
So the euro will be a string 255 should be sufficient for that.
That's how you get to the host.
So HTP or HDB s, whatever it may be.
Let me ask Staats IP address.
I don't know if I needed it or not, so I'll just call it IP and that will be a string and it might
have an IP version six.
So I'll give it an IP version six.
Where's the house located.
What data centres it in.
So location, maybe the operating system.
And then I'm going to have an active yes or no and that will be an integer and I'll just give it a default
of one.
So when we enter something by default, it is equal.
Now fears will also create or sota running fiz migrations will actually actually create two more columns
for us.
And those two columns are created at which is a timestamp and updated at which is a timestamp.
And one thing I'm going to show you here, the very first migration in the list, and this is because
we're using Postgres postgrads will not by default do those update the the columns for us.
So I created a trigger right here that says create a trigger set timestamp.
And all that will do is make sure that updated at is updated to the current timestamp any time a record
is created or updated.
So I'm going to put that trigger in here as well.
And I'm just going to say sequel and then I'll use my back text so I can have this on multiple lines.
And this will execute Rosabelle for us and I'll say create trigger set underscore timestamp.
Before update on hosts, which is the name of our table.
For each row.
Execute.
Procedure.
Trigger set time stamp, and that will just make sure that I don't have to manually update the time
stamp every time I make a change to the particular record in this table.
All right.
Now, if I've typed everything correctly, I should be able to run this migration.
So let's try this sota migrate and there it is.
Now, if I go look at the database, which I have opened right here before I refresh it, I just have
preferences.
Remember, tokens, schema migration, just these tables.
And once I refresh it now I have a host table and the structure of that host table corresponds exactly
to what I specified in that.
So that's pretty straightforward.
All right.
So we created our host table.
Now let's create our services table so we'll generate a new migration sota, generate Fiz, create services
table.
We'll do the down migrations in just a moment.
So just to make things a little faster, I'll copy this and I will go to my service table up and paste
it in there.
And I want fewer things in here, but I definitely want an ID and I don't want to hostname, I want
a service name and I do want the active and will say requires client.
Now what also we need in here, we need the actives.
Let's get rid of this all the way up to here.
I'm also going to put an icon that's associated with a particular service just to make it more visually
appealing.
So I'll just create another column here.
Teda column.
And I'll call it icon, and it's a type of string and it is a size out of 255, again, that's long
enough.
So I'd service name active icon ID, service name active icon, that should be enough, and here we'll
just say not on hosts.
This time we're going to create the trigger on services and name the table services.
OK, so let's run that.
So to my great good, make sure it actually created the table for us back to vigilante reload and there's
my services table and the structure is correct.
Good.
OK, so the last table I want to create is hosted services, so let's create that again.
I'll just copy this to make it faster.
So to generate views with two Zs, create host services table.
And I should create my two empty files, which are right here, I'll go to the up and I'll paste it
in, this one will be a little bit different because it's going to have foreign keys.
But we're going to call this host, underscore services.
It will have an I.D. of type integers.
That'll be our primary key.
And then it's going to have to call column
and I'll call this post ID and it's of type integer.
And it has no extra parameters, and then there will be a service ID and these are the keys that link
our hosts and our services together.
So if a host has five services, there will be five entries in the host services table.
So we've got Idy hosted service ID.
I mean, will keep the active because I need that.
I want to be able to turn the monitoring on and off for individual host services.
And what else do we need?
We want to figure out how often should we run our our particular service scans.
So let's say call them.
And I'll call this schedule No.
And it will be an integer.
And it has some options and the options are default of three.
So I want to monitor something, a particular service say we're looking to see that a Web server is
up on a particular host and I want to monitor for a number of three.
And then I need to also specify what are the units?
So the units will be schedule unit.
And this time, instead of an integer, I'll make a string and I'll give it a default of four minutes,
so I want to monitor it for three minutes, that would be the default that we enter in here and that
should be enough for what we're doing here right now.
So let's just take this.
Well, let's just put one more thing in here.
Call column and I'll call this last check.
The last time that a CAT scan was run against this particular server.
And this is a type timestamp and the default, I'll make it equal to nothing, zero zero zero one zero
one zero one and at one second after midnight.
Now, there's a reason I'm doing this.
And it's because one of the one of the idiosyncrasies of go when you're connecting to a database, though,
doesn't like null values in a database.
And there are ways of doing this with the gold standard library.
But typically, just because I'm a little lazy, I'll simply insert a default date.
That is the year one.
The month one, the first day of the first month at one second after midnight.
And when I'm checking to see a date, when I get the date from the database, I just check to see is
the date after year one.
If it is then to validate.
If it's not, then just ignore it.
And that's just a quick way to make sure that I can pull information out of the database without without
having to check for null values.
OK, so we have hosted services.
Let's copy this and paste this down here.
So that will create the table.
But I'm not quite done.
I also want to set up a couple of foreign keys and fortunately Fiz.
And so to have a really easy way of doing this, add foreign key and I'll warn you ahead of time.
I almost always mistype this the first time around, but I'm going to try really carefully to get this
right on the table.
Hosted services
for the column host ID.
That references hosts the hosts table, and I'm looking for the column, and it has to be in the format
of an array because, you know, foreign keys can point to more than one column on a remote table.
But I'm just looking for the column ID.
For that, I want to execute these things on delete if somebody deletes the foreign key or the one that
this is pointing to, just Cascais, delete this row as well.
And on update, if somebody changes the foreign key that I'm pointing to, Kaskade just change my foreign
key as well.
So change the entry in this database.
And I think now I almost always forget that closing parentheses.
So I'm going to copy this.
Now we've got a foreign key for house services to host Edet.
We also need one for service item on the table services.
And I'll just use exactly the same logic here.
So do I have this typed right now?
I don't have to close that and I have to close that.
And that's what I told you.
I almost always get these wrong the first time around, but I believe I have it set up right.
So let's try writing this migration and see what happens.
So to my great and if I get this right, there's a very good chance I'm going to go out and buy a lottery
ticket because I never get foreign keys right the first time around.
And this time I did.
So I guess now I have to buy a lottery ticket.
All right.
Last thing I want to do is write the down migration's and they're really easy.
So for the host table down migration is just this drop table posts and I'll copy that and go to the
down migration for services, drop table services and for the host services table, drop table host
services and make sure everything is spelled right.
Hosted services, services and hosts.
OK, so I'm going to commit these to get.
And paste them, not paste them, post them, push them up to my remote server, and this is Database
Migration's and push.
And push.
And there it goes.
Look at my database, make sure they're all there, reload host services, hosts and services.
Perfect.
So in the next lesson will set up the database models for these.
So our go code has a means of getting information from the database and storing it somewhere.