OK, so now we want to have some services showing up, and first of all, I want to fix this because
it bothers me.
I want that to be a nice little badge.
So let's go back to the idea and let's look at the hosts play host hosts Jet right here.
And I want this to be a badge.
And the way I had it before was like this badge badge success.
And I didn't work and it didn't work because this is the way it used to be in bootstrap for but in bootstrap
five.
Now it is big for some reason.
I'm not entirely sure why, but I'm sure they have a good reason.
So let's make this a badge and big danger.
And when I say that and come back here to my web browser, that should look like a nice little badge.
It does.
And I want the same thing over here.
I want a green badge that says one healthy service and a red badge that says one problem service or
something like that.
I want those to be here.
And of course, to make that happen, we need to actually add some services under this tent.
So right now, that just has some tech.
So let's go fix that up and get it set up so we can populated with useful information.
So I'll go back to my host page and find the service content right here and I'll delete that text and
put in a div class equals row and then a div class equals call and then I'll put a heading in each three
services.
Underneath that I'll put a table table class equals table table striped and a T head and a tr and T
which I'll just call service and we'll just have one, one column in this and then we'll have a Tibaldi
and a TR.
I'll just make that empty for right now.
TD td.
OK, so let's see what that looks like.
Reload this page, click on services.
OK, maybe push that down a little bit so class equals maybe three.
Let's save that and that should push it down a little bit and it does.
OK, so this will list our services and we'll have one or two services now if we look at our database.
Right here, under services, under content, we don't have any anything we're monitoring right now
at all.
So what I want a monitor to start with is just a website to make sure a Web server is actually running
a service in here.
And I'll call it HTTP, which will be a sugarbeet.
We'll make it active.
I'm going to leave the icon empty and I'll have to create it at some date, say twenty twenty one 02.
Twenty to twenty twenty one zero two twenty two and save that.
So now I have one entry in my services table which says icon cannot be not so icon will be.
Oh call it.
If a server doesn't matter what it is we'll fix that later.
We're going to use a font awesome icon at some point possibly.
So I have that in there now.
I have one entry in my services table and if I reload, that's a good idea too.
Clearly I had one in here at some point, but that doesn't matter.
I just want to have a service in here.
OK, so I'll reload this and what I'm going to do is just list all of the services that we have here
with a radio button beside it that's either on or off.
And I'll use that same kind of switch like I have up here.
OK, so let's go in here.
And I'm just going to hard code this right now just to get it working.
We'll call this service and then I'll duplicate that row or that TD and call it status.
And here I'll have HTP.
And underneath that I'll pull a switch.
Now, the syntax for the switch, I have that up here somewhere.
Right here.
Copy this and paste it down here and just pull the logic out of it, so we'll take this statement out.
Here and with the Idy will be HTP service and the name will be HTP.
OK, so let's just save that, reload this and see what it looks like.
OK, not quite right.
What did I get wrong?
Oh, yeah, I've got to put this around it, div class equals form, check, form, switch.
So that should be here, pasted in here, give it a closing, give format everything and reload the
page.
OK, so managed services.
So we're just going to have one right now on or off.
And this isn't reading anything from the database.
It's not saving it at all because we've not written those things yet.
So let's go look at our database structure as it exists and go under models don't go right now.
We have a host and a host has only the things that correspond to the kinds of things that are actually
in the database.
But we actually want more information associated with a given host.
So I'm going to say services and that's going to be a slice of of services.
Since I'm in the model package, I don't have to pretend that with models.
So those services, should it be a slice of services?
It should be a slice of hosted services.
Like that, and I'll call this host services just to be absolutely consistent so I don't get confused
about what's what.
So how service consists of a slice of hosted services so one host can have one or more services or no
services if we want to do it that way.
And down here under host services, I'm going to add another thing here as well.
I'm going to actually put the service information so the service is a service.
One service will be associated with one service, which is called services, for reasons I'm not entirely
sure about.
But there you go.
So that gives us our necessary database structure.
Engo And now of course, that means when we get a host by ID, we need to also get its host services
and that host service.
Every service we get for a host, every host service we get for a host should also have a service associated
with it.
So right now we're monitoring just whether or not a Web server is we're going to do one service and
maybe we'll add another one down the road, maybe we won't.
But right now we're going to work with one just to get it going.
So this gives us our necessary markup.
We have a place to display the HDP and whether it's on or off.
So now we need to have the means of adding a service to a host by checking it and making it active or
checking it and making it inactive.
So when we add a host, it adds a host with no services.
So the very first time we display this page, if we add a new house, if we for first time we display
this tab, this will be unchecked and there will be no entry in the database associated with the host
service HTTP.
But when we turn it on and click save and we'll need a save button here at some point or else do it
using Ajax, then it will put the necessary entry into the database.
If it already exists, it'll, it'll turn it inactive if we turn it off.
But if it doesn't exist it'll enter it and make it active.
OK, so we'll take care of that in the next lecture or two.