OK, so right now we have just the markup for this and as I said last time, right now, if I look at
my database and I go over here to my database client, I have one host in the database with an idea
of one, but I have no home services.
And while I could write the necessary code to add a record if it doesn't exist for HTP in house services,
I think it's cleaner and simpler to actually add the services and mark them as inactive at the point
of entry.
So what I'm going to do is go back to my database and go back to my house table and just delete this
post entirely and save changes.
So now there's no host.
So if I go to hosts, there's nothing in there.
So let's go back to our code and modify that insert method, which is insert host in host, underscore
PostgreSQL ago.
And before I return the ID, I'm going to add host services and set to inactive.
So we need a statement which will be assigned the value of and I'll just do this with back takes on
multiple lines, insert into host services and what I want to insert in there.
Let's go look at the structure of that host services structure.
I want to insert hosted service died inactive, so host ID, service ID and active.
I also want to insert schedule number and schedule unit schedule no better spell right schedule unit
comma and then last check.
I'll leave out a let that stay as null created an updated ut.
I will definitely do and status.
I will definitely definitely definitely do so.
Status created at updated at values.
And the first thing is my host ID and I'll be getting that from this new ID variable we have right here.
The next one is my service ID, which is just one, that is the one that I have in my database.
Now, just as an aside, when I actually inserted my services and if I look at the content the first
time around, it had to because I must have been playing with this table.
At some point.
You need to make sure that the one service you have in your services table has an idea of one.
So if necessary, go and change that just to be safe.
Krab.
So service I.T. active is going to be set to zero because I want it to be inactive by default schedule.
No, I believe that's an end.
But let's make sure structure schedule number is an integer and schedule unit as character.
Very so a number.
I'll make it three minutes schedule unit.
That's minutes for M and four minutes then status which will be pending because that's a character very
column created and updated.
I'll just do dollars on two in dollar sign three and I'll use the built in time package to get the current
timestamp.
So let's make sure we have this right.
Insert into host services, host ID, service ID, active schedule, no schedule unit status created
at updated UT.
So that is one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
I look at that right.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
OK, so that's our statement.
Let's execute that statement.
We get a result that I don't care about.
An error that I do is assign the value of my DB context, pass it the context.
My first value will be the idea of my host, which is stored in the variable new ID.
My second value is time now and my third value is time now.
OK, let's check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, will return a new ID and the error.
OK, so that new ID.
Context new.
What's to say you cannot use military type as type string?
Oh, yeah, I'm going to put my Creary in there, CMT, that's better.
OK, so that should take care of it.
So I need to start my application, start my application and go at a new host.
So I'll say new host.
And again, I'll use the same thing I did last time.
Localhost localhost you url is HDB localhost 880 IP addresses one two seven zero zero one.
Don't care about IP version six.
It's in New Brunswick and the operating system is Mac os x and I will make it active and hopefully if
I save this, ok, changes are saved and if I look at the host services table, I should now have one
service in their content refresh and I do.
And the service idea is one perfect.
OK, so now we have that information in there by default, which is much cleaner.
Now if we had a second service, we would have to of course, come in here and add the second service.
If I had multiple services, what I would actually do is query the services table and then loop through
the results of that and add one inactive service for each of the services available into my host services
table.
But we just have one and this will suffice for our purposes at the moment.
So what's the next step?
The next step is to go back here and modify this so that when I toggle this, it somehow updates the
database.
And I think the cleanest way to do that is with Ajax.
So you don't have a save button, nothing like that.
You just toggle the switch.
It makes the change behind the scenes and then pops a little alert here that says, hey, the service
has been added and made active or whatever it is, we'll give some kind of success message for turning
it on and turning it off.
And we'll take care of that in the next lecture.