So we're at the point now where we want to do something with this toggle, I'm looking at a host, an
actual host with information in it.
So my one localhost mine happens to have the ID of six because I've been playing with the database and
yours might be one or two, but it doesn't matter as long as you're looking at a host.
And when I click this, I actually want something to happen.
I want to if somebody turns it on, I want to fire off a request in the background using Ajax and update
the service for this host for the one service I have http.
I want to make that active in the database, which means it's an active service that we're going to
want to monitor.
And if somebody turns it off, we want to do the reverse.
We no longer want to monitor this service on this host.
So to make that happen, first of all, let's work on the JavaScript.
So I'm going to go back to my idea and I'm going to find a hosted jet and I'm going to find this part
where the toggle is rendered.
And I'll just put this on another line so we have a little more room.
And what I'm going to do here is add some data attributes.
And the first one I'm going to add is data dash service.
And I'll make that equal to and if you recall, the one service we have in our services table in the
database is Idy one.
So I'll make that I.T. one.
And then I also want one other piece of information, data host ID, and that's going to be equal to
and I'll just grab that from the data pass to our template host ID.
And I've got to get the quote out of there and put it here.
OK, so now we have a data service and a data hosta ID and that's really information I want to use for
two purposes.
The first one is actually I'd better put a third one here is I need to selector, so I'll call this
data type and that's going to be toggle service.
So I'm going to use this data type as a selector.
So I'm going to use JavaScript to say finally all the elements on the current page that have the data
type of toggle service and that will get me a collection of all of the toggles and we just have one.
But we might have more in the future.
Data service will give me enough information that I can pull using JavaScript to find out what service
it is.
This happens to be ID one http and the last bit tells me what host this service is associated with and
that's the actual ID of our host in the database.
So I have this information added to my input.
Now we need to go down to my JavaScript section just after this opening script tag and I want to fire
something when the page is entirely loaded.
So we'll add an event listener document at event listener.
And the condition I want is dom content loaded spelled exactly like that.
And it's going to be a function.
And when it's loaded, the very first thing I want to do is get all of my toddles, all of my service
toggles, so I'll create a variable.
Let Turrell's equal document.
Weary selecter all and make sure you have the all of the end or this won't work and I'm going to look
for anything in quotes and then in square brackets, anything that has the data attribute data service.
OK, so don't need the quotes there.
So that gets me a reference to all of the services.
OK, so now that I've done this, let's see if we can actually find any services.
So what I'm going to do now that I have this collection, which might be zero elements, it might be
55 elements.
It's something let's loop through it for let I equal zero.
So we'll start counting at zero because this will be an array I is less than the length of toggles.
So I'm toggles that length and add one each time through.
So as long as, as long as there's at least one element on the page that has the data attribute data
service, then I should have found something.
So we'll just say console log found one.
OK, so let's save this and go back to our Web browser and open the JavaScript console and reload the
page.
And it found one perfect.
OK, so we know we found at least one.
Now, what else?
What else can we get from that?
Well, now that we found it, we can actually give some and see what information we can pull from it.
So we'll say console, dot, log service, and that will be toggles by the current index that we're
iterating through.
Get attribute and we'll get data service, which we better spell right.
Or it won't give us anything.
OK, so it found the service.
Let's see if it can find the service ID service one.
Perfect.
Let's get the home study so I'll duplicate that line, post data, post ID and let's reload the page
and it found everything we need to know.
Perfect.
So now that we've done that, this is a good start.
But when I actually go to the services tab and click on this button, nothing happens.
So what we're going to do is not log all this information, a comment, this edit or delete it in a
moment.
What we want to do instead is to add an event listener to the current button.
As every time we go through this and we find a toggle, we want to add an event listener that says when
these changes do something, so we'll just say toggles our current iteration, which is index.
I will add an event listener and we want the change listener.
So when this when this toggle changes state from on to off or off to on, we want to fire a function.
And all we'll do right now is to determine whether or not it's actually been clicked.
So we'll just say console.
Log toggle was changed, OK, and I'll just comment this stuff because we know that's working.
I shall just delete it.
So we'll save this, go back here, clear the JavaScript console, reload the page, make sure we're
looking at the services tab and toggle what's changed.
And every time I do it, it increments the counter here.
So I know what's working.
So now let's see if we can figure out whether it was clicked or not, whether it was clicked on or off.
So in this case, I'll say if and I can use the the keyword this because I'm referring to a specific
element.
If this DOT checked will just say console dot, log toggle is checked, otherwise it's not checked ELT's
console log toggle is unchecked.
OK, save that.
Reload the page, clear the JavaScript console, go to the services tab and toggle toggle is checked.
So when it was off and I turn it on at that point the target list checked.
If I turn it off toggle is unchecked.
So this is exactly what we need.
So what we want to do next is not just to console log this.
We actually want to fire off a JavaScript request in the background and AJAX requests.
So let's go back to our ID and let's think about how we're going to manage this.
So I know that I can finding all the toggles with the data service.
If it doesn't have a data service, it will be ignored.
And I know that I'm looping through them all and adding the event listener.
So what I want to do is actually fire off a JavaScript request in the background and Ajax request,
and we do that using fetch.
So I'll write some code here right now.
Fetch and it has to have a path name.
So let's look at our roots file and see what a good path name would be.
We're working right here, so maybe we should have something like Agosta Ajax so we know it's a background
request.
OK, so I'll make it long enough that I know it won't conflict with any other route.
So I'll put some admin slash host slash Ajax toggle service and that's probably long enough.
It's got one, two, three, four elements.
Is that going to match anything in my file.
Now we're good.
OK, so I can use that as a euro, so that's my my first part of my parameter and I want to give some
specifics to this request.
I want to make this a post request method, which will be post like that.
And I need to pass it a body.
I need to pass it some information.
So this I'll call form data, which doesn't exist yet, but I'll create it in a moment.
So up here, let's create a new form, a new form document.
So we'll say let the form data equal new.
Form data with caps, so that creates an empty form data object for us.
And what I want to put in there is all the information I want to post to this.
You are out.
So I'm going to need the whole study for sure so I can say form data, dot append and I'll append something
called Hoshide and that will be equal to this dot get attribute.
This got get attribute and it was data post ID, that's our host I.D. I also want to get the service
ID, so I call that service I.D. and that's called data.
What was it called?
Come up here, make sure I get it right.
Data service.
Data service, and the last thing I need to append is actually my CSF token or else this won't work
and that's a mistake I make all the time.
So let's add it right now while I'm thinking of it form data append and we'll call that to see SRF token,
which is what it has to be called, won't work and will put in simply the CSR RF token that we pass
right from.
And it's going to be in quotes, right from our data past all templates, CSS, RF token.
And this should be a lower o they're.
OK, so now we have all of this information that we need, we're going to post it, the host I.D.,
the server said to you, the CSF token, is there anything else that I need?
Well, yes.
Whether or not we're turning it on or off.
So we'll say let it turn on equal.
True, so I'm just defining it to be true, and we can say, if not this checked, then.
Turn on equals false, then I don't even need this statement, so this should actually be exactly what
I need.
I just need to append here, turn I'll call it turn service on.
And we'll make that a boolean.
We'll just say turn on, OK?
And, of course, it needs to be a string, so I can't do that.
Turn on as equal to one turn on is equal to zero.
There you can't pass anything but a string in a post like this unless you're passing binary data.
But we're not doing that.
So we're making our request here, but we haven't done anything with it yet.
So typically what you're going to do next is DOT then and we'll get our response, which we're going
to turn into, Jason.
And then we do something with it, then data, we can call that whatever we want and that's just a function.
So we'll just say console log called Ajax, which means we need to send back in Ajax's response from
this Eurail.
OK, so does this all look right?
It does for now.
So let's copy this URL, just this part, because the admin has added in our reads file, go to our
reads file and we'll create a new handler, Muxtape Post.
That's our URL and we're going to call handlers dot repo and we'll call a handler that doesn't exist
yet called Targo Service.
For host.
So let's go create this handler just so that there's no error in our code, so I'll just jump over here,
go to the very bottom and say funk and it will have a receiver of.
Repoll start DB repo and what did I call that handler toggle service for host?
So we'll go back to our handlers, give it a name, make it a handler by giving it a response writer,
HTP response writer and or is a pointer to a request.
A sheepdog request.
OK, so if we go back to our roots file, that error should be gone.
It is so in the next lecture we'll actually write some code in that handler that just sends back Jason.
It won't actually do the toggling on and off right away.
We just want to make sure everything's wired up and that our JavaScript is talking to our handler and
vice versa.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture.