OK, so we have this button hooked up and this button functionalist custom JavaScript behind it, and
the first thing I want to point out is that I had a typo in the last lecture right here on line two
thirty five.
And my code when I'm getting my last response or the last then from my fetch, I have a column that
should be a semicolon.
So let's fix that.
Now back to our handlers.
Right now, we're going to be posting to this URL, which is a post request, these bits of information
which are turned service on service Side Hoshide and then Kharif Tolkan, which I'm going to put at
the end because it's not something we're actually working with.
OK, so we're posting this now.
Let's go back to our handlers, which are right here.
And I have this empty handler.
So first thing I want to do is just make sure everything works.
So I'll do what I always do whenever I have a posted form.
Error is assigned the value of our passport and we check for an error if error is not equal to nil because
I got an extra quote there, parentheses, they're logged off print line error.
And again, you should have more, more robust error checking here.
But I'm just going to ignore that and log the air for right now, OK, because I just want to get this
wired up.
So let's get our values.
And we're posting three things homestudy, service, study and turn service on.
OK, so let's get those values posted and potentially an error, which again, I'm ignoring.
Is Sterkel a I.
And we want our dot form dot get posted and I'll duplicate that twice, the next one was.
Service ID and turn service on, so service ID, and then I called this one turn service on, which
I'm going to change in a minute because I don't like that this was called service ID.
When you think about it, this last one turned service on that's really active in our database.
So when our host services table, we have a a value active or and it's set to one or zero.
So I'm going to rename that to Active and I'll rename this to Active and then back in our host jet,
I'll rename that to Active as well.
And I may as well call this active and this active and this act that way.
I'm just not going to get confused.
What I'm looking at this in six months and saying, what the heck is turn service on?
I'll know it's active.
OK, so we have those values past or grabbed from our request here and we'll just log them logged up
print line data and I'll just list them post Idy service ID and active and then I need to send a JSON
response.
So what I'm going to do here is just define a type and I'll call it service Jason and it will be a struct.
And right now it's going to have one value, OK, and it is a bool and in JSON I will call it OK.
OK.
So here just to get this working to make sure it's all wired up correctly, I'll create a new variable
var service Jason.
I'll call it response.
Varvara resp is of type service Jason and Remsberg ok equals true.
And I'll just write this JSON out to the client, to the connecting service.
So out and ignore the error or assign the value of JSON dot mercial indent and my variable is called
RESPA and I'll just give it a few spaces to format it properly.
Set my header header set and I want it to be content type of application.
Jason.
And right, and I'm going to write the OK, and that should be all that we do, except I have a typo
here.
OK, so in theory, when I stop my application and start my application.
It's running and I go back to my Web browser and open my console window and reload this, my air is
gone away because I fixed that already and we go to our managed services and I'll toggle this and see
what I got wrong called Ajax.
It worked.
Let's see if we actually get the values back from Ajax.
So back in my host Jack console log, OK is and I'm going to get it from my data.
OK, let's try that better spell console.
Right though.
There, let's reload this, clear the JavaScript console, go to our managed services page and OK is
true.
So everything is wired up correctly.
So the next step is to actually write the necessary database procedures to update our service for a
host to turn it on or off.
And at that point, we're almost ready to get to the WebSocket stuff.
A few more things to do, but nothing too terribly onerous.
So in the next lecture, we'll write the necessary database functions to update a hosted service from
active to inactive or vice versa.
And we'll go on from there.