OK, so now we need to write some database functions that will update the status of a hosted service
for a given service for a given host.
So let's go back to our ID and let's look at this handler, which is right over here, under handlers,
under handlers.
The very last one in my code, I put it at the bottom of the page.
But the the function is called toggle service for host.
And at this point, we have three pieces of information.
We have the host I.D., the service ID and the active what we want to set active to for the given entry
in the database.
And if we look at the database over here, this is the host services table.
We have all these fields, so we're going to be looking it up by host IDs and service ID because we
don't actually have the ID of this record at this point in our request lifecycle.
What we can look it up by host I.D. and service I.D. because there will only be one entry with a given
service ID for a given host ID in this table.
So that's how we're going to look it up.
And what we want to change is this value active.
So let's go back to our host, PostgreSQL.
And at the very bottom, I'll define a new function func and it will be of like I used M for the receiver.
Yeah, M is a postgrads DB repo and I'll call this toggle service and I'll just call it update host
service status.
And I'm going to take and host it and I'm going to take a service indeed and I'm going to take active,
all of which will be events and I'll return potentially an error or nil if there's no error.
And as I always do, I'll get the context bit and I'll paste it in here and then I'll write my statement.
So I'm going to update host services set active equal to dollar sign one where host ID equals dollar
sign to and service ID equals dollar sign three.
And that's all I have to do for the query.
I need to execute the query.
So let's go execute the query and we're going to use error is assigned the value of IMDB that exact
context and I think that returns to things.
But we'll find out in a minute.
Sirtex EMT and my first ID is active or my first placeholder is active.
My second one is host ID and my third one is service ID.
And that does return to things, doesn't it?
It returns a result in an areas I don't care about the results all ignore that.
So we do that, we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, return error, otherwise return nil.
OK, let's format this, give it a comment.
Update the active status of a host service there.
So this is our signature, which I need to copy and I need to go to my repository and paste that in
right here.
OK, now back in my handler, now that I have that available to me, I need to actually update the information.
So before I give my response and after I log this information, we'll just say error is assigned the
value of not not assigned as they already have an error equals repo.
DB update um, hosts service status and it requires my host I.D. It requires my service ID and it requires
an active
OK.
So if air is not equal to nil, then what I'm going to do at this point is set my response, which I'm
going to take right here.
I'm going to get it out of here and put it right up here, I'm going to say my resp dot, OK, he calls
false because something failed.
OK, and I'm also going to log the air logged our print line air.
OK, so here I try to update the information.
If it works, I set OK to follow to true.
OK, leave.
OK, that's a true.
If it doesn't work I set it to false, I just send back that one response and that really should do
it for that part.
Now back on the host jet page, OK, at some point I'm going to have to determine whether or not to
have this checked when it shows up.
OK, so that means I'm going to need to have that information available to me from my home services
when I render this.
And I might have that already.
I don't know.
I'll figure that out in the next lecture.
Right now, let's just test this and see if it works.
So we'll stop our application, start our application.
I'll go look at this House page, so I'll go right to the beginning, I'll go to hosts localhost services.
So at this point, when I look in the database, if I look at the content of hosted services and refresh
it, I have one hosted service that is currently set to zero.
It is not active.
OK, so it's not active.
Now, I'm going to do this.
And hopefully this changed it.
Let's go look at our log file, no errors, let's go refresh this database table refresh and now it's
active.
So it works.
So really not helpful to just say, OK, here, maybe I should do something like this.
This is back on House Jet, and it's on the last then of my fetch, I don't want to have nothing happen.
I want to give some feedback to the user so I can say if data OK, if it worked, do something else,
do something else.
So if it worked, maybe I could just go successful.
The changes saved and if it failed, error alert.
Oops.
Something went wrong.
OK, so let's go back here and reload this page and go to my managed services and active changes saved.
Perfect.
And that should go away after a few seconds and it does change.
You saved much better.
OK, so the next step is to in the next lecture to actually do a few things if we can do them all in
one lecture.
If not, we'll split it into a couple.
But I want this to be checked or unchecked when the page is first rendered based upon the actual contents
of the information in the database.
And on the overview page, maybe I should list my host here as well, along with some information,
along with what services are being saved for this being monitored for this house.
So we'll give that there.
And then after that, we're going to be able to start scheduling our monitoring services and actually
populating this bit of the page, the four possible statuses with meaningful information and then finally
will be able to use WebSocket to update things in real time.
So let's get started on that in the next lecture.