So next, I want to make sure that this button is checked, if it's actually active in the database
and unchecked, if it's not checked in the database, and if you look at the host jet file right now,
we're hard coating this.
We're manually typing this table row right down to this table row and populating all of this by hand.
And yet, if you recall, if you look at our models and you look at the host model, we have hosted
services as a member in this model and hosted services actually has right here a service in its as a
member in it.
So we should be able to modify our get hosted by ID database method to actually populate this struct.
How services the site with a slice of strokes of type host service.
So let's do that.
And then if we do that rather than hard coding this, we can just loop through all of the host services
that are associated with the host.
We're already passing to this template.
So let's do that.
Let's go to our host postgrads and get hosted by ID is right here.
And the first thing we do is we just write a query.
We get the host, we populate all of this information, we check for an error and we return it.
Now, at this point, before we actually return it, let's get all services for host.
OK, so let's write a query query.
We already have a query, but we're just going to reuse that variable is equal to and we want to select
something.
So let's go look at the database and see what we're selecting that's over here.
And this is hosted services.
So we want to select Idy hosted service ID and host ID service ID.
Active schedule, no schedule unit, active schedule, no schedule unit.
Last check created an updated out in status last check.
Status created at an updated ad from Host Services where posted ID equals dollar sign one and we already
know our host I.D. We have it right here.
So now we can actually just get that from the database so we get a result.
I don't care about we get an error.
I do care about equals imdb dot query context, pass at the context, pass our query and passed it.
Host sorry h dot id.
Check for an error if error.
Try that again, if error is not equal to nil, we'll just return and return each error and along the
error logged up print line error.
And of course, we don't need to redefine this variable error because we already have an error.
So that takes care of that then.
Deferred action.
What does this return?
It returns rose in an hour, I do care about that, so that's Rose, Rose and error.
And now I do need to make this in a sign, defer, rose close, define a slice variable to hold all
this information.
So that would be.
VA services host services, which is a type of slice models, post service.
OK, we're going to modify this query in a minute because we also want to get some service information.
But let's just get this part done first, OK?
For Rose Dot next and will define a one variable called HHS.
So VA, HHS is of type models hosting service.
OK, and then we scan into erro.
Error is a sign the value of rose dots.
Can we scan that into the variable we just defined?
So into HHS, we want to put it and I'll duplicate that a few times and screw up.
So we're getting the idee, the whole study.
OK.
Then we're getting the service.
Then we're getting the active, and that's the part we need for the House page for sure.
Schedule no
schedule unit,
last check.
Status
created up and updated it, and it would be great if we could actually go back to our models, if we
could populate this part of the record to the surface.
And we can do that.
We just have to come back up here and we'll change this to a ID and put that in front of every variable
we're selecting initially.
And this will be an alias.
And I'll move this down to its own line, so, uh, I data from there anyway from house services, which
I will call HS and move this down here, I just format this whole thing in a slightly more attractive
fashion.
Got my commas.
I do.
OK, now we'll just left join.
Left Join Services airs on.
Estcourt ID equals HFS service.
Now we've joined that table, so there's nothing to stop us from populating this as well.
Let's see what's in the services table.
So we have already service name active.
Where am I?
I can't create it updated at.
OK, so created an updated.
OK, so now that I've got this in my query, I should be able to come down here and just say duplicator
change this to service.
ID and I'll duplicate that a few times, so we got the service name next.
Service, debt service name.
Get rid of the ID.
And after service name comes active and after active comes icon, and then created an updated.
OK, so we scan for that if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil, we'll say log the error
and return H and error.
Otherwise we'll append that to our slice, which we called home services.
So host services equals append host services.
And HFS is the very religious created.
And after this entire thing finishes, I just say HO services equals HO services.
So if we wrote this all correctly, we should, when we get the ID, have all of the services and all
of the all of the services and all of the services associated with a given host service.
So let's make sure this compiles.
It does.
And let's go back to our hosts file and I'm going to leave this here is a reference, but I'm going
to say instead range and I called my host host, not host services.
I'll just range through all the services, not only be one right now, but that's all we need.
And every time we're arranging through this, we want to go H.R. No tr td and then the service name,
which would be DOT.
Postal Service DOT, service name, I think that's what it is, let's make sure so hosted service right
here.
And that has a service and that has a service name.
Yes.
So that gives us our service name.
And then I'll just copy this entire part here, this TD.
Kopi.
And paste it in and modify it as necessary so this can now be commented out, I'll just put comments
around it.
Because I might need it back.
Who knows?
OK, so we have div class equals form check form switch.
That's correct.
Input, classic form check input value equals one, which can be anything.
We just need to make sure that it's actually checked when it's posted.
Type is a checkbox, ID is HTP service.
What I really need that not using it.
So I'm going to get rid of that data type is Torgau Service Data Service.
This would be the host service service.
So that's Dort post service.
Dot.
I'm going through her services, so it's just service side.
OK, data host ID is the host ID and I'm getting that from host services, I can just put host ID here
and that's called host ID, I think.
Let's make sure in models, host service host I.D. Service ID is Capital I, Capital D, Capital Cappotelli
Capital D name equals HTP.
And of course what do we have in our services.
Let's look at our services table.
So services content, it should be a service name, so that would be.
Service service name.
And this is not house service, it's service service.
So service service name, I think that's all right.
Let's see if we get that right.
I may have my syntax wrong here.
I often do when I'm working with a new templating service, but we'll find out.
OK, so let's just go reload this page and see what I got wrong.
Managed services.
There it is.
OK, so now we should be able to at this point put an if statement if and we're looking at the host
service and we want to know whether or not it's active, active equals one and closer if statement.
And we checked there.
All right, let's go back and reload this again and look at services and it's inactive.
And what's in the database for host services services reload at zero.
So let's check it.
Saved it.
Let's go to the overview.
Let's go back to Host's click on localhost and hopefully it'll be checked when I click on managed services
and it is perfect.
Now, the nice thing about this and I can go delete the comment section now.
The nice thing about this is I don't have to do any more work if I add a new service to the database,
not to this page anyway, because it will list all of the services that we're going to have in the database.
So that's this part done.
And next, now that I have this done next, I want to get this overview page listed properly run.
Just list my host and all of its services in this table.
And that's going to require a couple of changes, just like we did right here in our host postgrads
QOL.
When we did our getting of an individual host and got all of its health services, will we find our
all hosts, which is all hosts right here?
I probably want to get the same information there, or at least the services associated with a host
so I can display them on that overview page.
OK, that's enough for this time around in the next lecture.
We'll work on that.