So now we want to list all of the hosts and their associated services on this overview page, which
is what the pages you see as soon as you log in.
And we also want to list the count of problems that are in any of these states.
So I don't know if we'll get them both done this lecture, but we'll get started and we'll start with
this house part, which should be pretty simple, because if we go back and look at our code and we
open the.
Internal folder repository DB, repo host, postgrads, we already have somewhere for all hosts and
all hosts and it's right here.
So we need to modify this and we need to modify it so that we can list the services.
So back on this page, I want to list all of the surface services that counts for them that exist on
this, for this for a given host.
So that's not difficult.
So if we actually find get hosted by ID, if you recall, we recently modified this query so that it
looks more like this.
So we're saying get all the services for.
So first of all, we get all the hosts and then when we have a given host, we go and get all of its
services.
So we should be able to.
And I'm just going to copy this query, copy this bit, find all hosts again right here.
So we get the hosts then as we're looping through this, at this point, once we've populated the first
part of the host record with this information and before we append the information, we actually want
to do another query for this host.
So I'll just paste what we have in there and modify this and I'll just call this service query just
so we're not overwriting anything.
And I'll have to use the assigned variable, of course, or the assign operator.
So we now have this query and we want to look at this, make sure we've got it right.
We want to get yes, we want to get all the service information, all the hosts service information
and all the service information from this is the where correct.
Where host ID equals dollar sign one.
Well it's H ID is what we're assigning it right here.
And if we get past this error check then this will execute.
So it is append hosts right here where host data equals one.
So we need to execute that query.
So again, we're going to be getting rows and I'll call it host rows and service rows.
Potentially an error are assigned the value of IMDB, that exact context, no query context, query
context and will pass that context and we'll pass it or query, which we just called service query.
And then we passed our operator, our one parameter of passing in here, and that would be ID.
Then we checked for an error, if error is not equal to nil, then we'll just do the same thing we've
been doing right along Lagat print line error and return and I'll return nil plus the error.
But if we get past that and we want to scan the service rows, actually we have to we can't defer close
here, but we'll get to that in a minute.
OK, we don't we don't want to use a deferred CLO close inside of a while loop.
So what we'll do instead is simply scan our four service rows.
Next.
And we'll create a variable var.
H.S. is of type models Gotho service.
And of course, we need a slice to store these things, we may as well put that right here before the
for loop via postal services is a slice of models hosted service.
OK, so we now have our variable we can append things to, and now we just skip service, rose dot scan.
And we're going to scan into what what will scan right into our eyes and we'll just go to ID.
On homestudy.
And I'll put that in a second line so it's more readable.
Got service, service.
Not active.
Eckstut, schedule No.
Start schedule unit.
Then at last check, Høst status Eckstut created an updated at and now we're into the services, so
escort service.
Not ID, and of course, these all have to have ampersands in front of them, so let me copy that and
paste and paste and.
Paste, paste, paste, paste, paste, paste, paste, paste, duplicate that after service ID comes
service name and duplicate that and then active and duplicate that icon.
And created a.
And updated at.
OK, so now we're scanning all of that into our variable, we check for an error.
And I think that this actually scan throws an error.
Yes, it does so error equals.
If there is not equal to no log print line here, return nil and error otherwise appended.
So host service, which is our slice of models.
So services equals.
Append.
Hosted services, HHS, and then now at this point, just before we append our host to our outreach
to our hosts, we just assign each dot hosted services equals hosted services.
And that should work, so we should have that information available to us.
So let's just make sure everything compiles.
And it does.
OK, so now let's go find our handler that renders this page.
So I'll go to my roots file and I'll find the overview right here, admin dashboard.
So what I want to do is right now I have I've made a VA map already and just passed it some dummy data.
And that's fine.
We can use that.
So let's just get our hosts.
So I call the variable all hosts and check for an error is assigned the value of M or DB Repo DB Dot
all hosts and check for error.
If error is not equal to nil then I'll just say logged print line error and I'll just return.
And again, if you're writing this for production code, you want to do something nicer.
You want to maybe generate a sessional variable that has the error information, take them back to some
other page and display the error.
But we're not going to bother doing that in this course because this is not a course in Web development.
So I've got that variable, all hosts.
Let's just put it in our our version first set and I'll call it hosts and I'll put in all hosts.
So now it's available to this template.
And I got to get rid of the assign operator here because I declared an error up here.
So now it's available to us on dashboards yet.
So let's open dashboard chat.
And find the part where we're listing hosts, which is right here, and we'll just say, what's my hope?
What's my variable called will say range.
I think I called it hosts.
I'll verify that in a minute.
Range hosts, which doesn't need to be in quotes.
And end and I'll make sure I call it hosts, I'm pretty sure I did.
Yes, hosts, so arranging through that every time we arrange through it, we want to tiara and inside
of that we want a TV and inside of that we want the host name, which would be Daudt Hostname, I think.
Yeah.
Host name.
We'll just go with that for right now and we'll create a bunch of empties just to make sure this works
that I need.
One, two, three, four.
OK, so let's go back and see if we got it right.
So I should be able just to reload this page.
And we have identified a host not available in current map, no healthy, no pending, no apparent scope.
So why can't it find hosts, range hosts?
Maybe I just need to stop and start my application.
I don't think that's it.
I must have a typo somewhere, but let's make sure.
Reload.
There it is.
I must not have started and stopped there, stopped and started the application, so it's available
to us now.
I want this to be a link that will link us to this page.
So if we get our hosts, let's see what the link would be.
The link is admin, host and host it.
So let's go back to our template and change this to a link.
A tariff equals slash admin slash host slash Heidi, which is the host ID.
And close that.
And that should work, so let's make sure it works.
Reload this, sorry, reload this, go back to our overview and this now should link, and it does.
OK, so let's go back to our overview.
Next, we want the services so the services we want to list right here.
And those are all stored in those services.
So I should be able to range host DOT services, which would just be services in this context.
And I'll just do it like this right now and just to make sure it works and inside of this, I'll just
put in dot service dot service name, because the dot refers to the current piece of data, which is
comes from hosts.
Hosts has a member called Let's make sure it's right here.
Models.
Host has something called host services.
That's what I want.
Thoughts go back to our dashboard jet range hosted services.
Their range of services and then get the service from this current piece of data and display the service
name, so that should work, let's make sure it does services HTTP.
And if there are two services that simply display beside each other, maybe I want to make that a little
more attractive so I can wrap this in a span class equals badge.
Big and then what do we have here?
Let's just choose.
Oh, it doesn't really matter.
Info.
And wrap it like this spane, let's see what that looks like.
There, OK, so that will list all of our services, so there's only one service being monitored right
now or that will be monitored when we get things done, but I think we're much closer than we were a
moment ago.
So let's just put these last three in here and this one is for OS.
So that's just OS.
And the next one is the location, location, location, and the last one is status, and I'm not sure
what that is actually called.
So host status is active or inactive, right.
OK, so back to my dashboard.
We need to put an if statement in here if.
Not active equals one on display, one thing else display something else and end, and these are just
badges.
So if it's active, we'll go spane class equals badge.
Big success, active, and I'll just copy this.
Pasted in here.
Make it a big danger and change that to inactive.
OK, and let's reload this, that all looks good.
OK, so the only thing we forgot to do and I'm glad I thought of it now because otherwise it might cause
me grief down the road is inside our query where we're getting all services for host.
And again, this is in the method all hosts.
I make the query, I get the service rows.
At no point do I close those rows and I don't want to put a defer in here because you really don't want
to put a different side of a while loop unless you're absolutely sure what you're doing.
So instead, I will do it right here.
I will just say service rows close.
There, OK, so that should take care of it for us, so that gets this part working properly.
Well, we're going to list all of our hosts and all of their associated services, which right now is
a maximum of one because we only have one service in the database, but we might have another one in
there later.
The next step will be to populate these.
How many of these are active?
And when we get it finished, because we actually have no, no, Krall's taking place right now to make
sure that our hosts are up or down.
We should have one pending service listed here.
And the rest of these should be empty because we have this one service which has a status of pending
when it's inserted.
So we need to get a database query that will get us those four pieces of information, the count of
healthy services, of warning services, of problem services and of pending services.
And we'll take care of that in the next lecture.