So we have our host displaying properly in the overview page, and the next thing I want to do is populate
the number zero in all four of these boxes with the actual accurate number.
How many healthy services are we monitoring?
How many pending services are we monitoring?
So on and so forth.
And that's pretty simple.
We just need to get a query written that will return the count of all of those services and pass that
data to our handler and then render this page with the appropriate information.
And if you recall, if we go back to our code here and I go two routes and I look at the admin dashboard,
I'm hard coding zero in right now.
So we just we need to get a database query that executes right before this populates the four zeros
with actual meaningful information and pass that off to our template and everything else should just
work.
So let's go figure out how we're going to do this.
I could if I wanted to let me go to my postgrads client and I'm looking at the host services table.
All we really want here for pending, for example, is account of all of the entries in this table that
have the status of pending and that have active set to one.
So let's just write some sequel.
I'll do it right here.
So I'll say select count IDE from host services where active equals one and status equals pending.
I run that I should get a one and I do.
But if I change that to say healthy, I should get zero and I do.
OK, so I'm going to put this back depending and I'm going to delete this now.
I could if I wanted to write one database query that does this and change the value of the pending part
using a parameter and just make for database queries.
Or I can make one database query, which I think is way more efficient.
So I'm going to do that instead.
So I'll put before that statement I just wrote Select and then I'll surround this statement in parentheses
and put as pending here.
Let's just run that and make sure that it works and it does.
Now I'll delete that semicolon, copy this entire line and has a comma at the end of it now.
And that's important.
Paste it three more times.
Delete the last comma and change pending for the second one to say healthy and then put healthy in here.
And then warning and warning.
And energy and then problem, so those will be our four statuses problem.
Now when I run this, I get all the information in one query and that seems way more efficient to me.
So let me copy this whole query and go back to my code and go to host postgrads and I'll just put a
new function in here.
It doesn't matter where it goes.
Func M and it's got a receiver of postgrads DB and I'll say get all service status counts, which is
as good a name as any, and it doesn't take any parameters and it returns and eat and eat and eat and
eat and potentially an error.
OK, and then I'll put my query in here and I'll just paste in the sequel I wrote a moment ago, OK,
and I'll just have this over so it looks a little more attractive.
Put this back tick up here now I my context so I'll just copy it from the function right next to it
and I would just execute the query, but I got to declare four variables to store things in.
So I'll say var pending warning know pending healthy to them in the same order.
Healthy warning and problem.
Those are all going to be ense and now I'll just execute my query.
So Roe is a sign, the value of IMDB, the query, query, row context and pass it in my context hasset
my query.
I have no parameters so I should be able to now just say error is sign the value of Rodust scanned and
scanned into those four variables and the first thing I'm getting is pending.
So I'll scan that into my pending variable and I'll just duplicate that three more times.
That's one too many.
And the second one is healthy.
The third one is warning, the fourth one is problem.
Check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, I'll return zero zero zero zero.
So I'm going to ignore those.
They'll be paying attention to the error instead and the error otherwise.
Return pending healthy.
Warning problem and no, OK, so that should do it.
So let me copy this signature, open my repository and paste that new method right in here and now it's
available to me so I can go back to my roots, find the admin dashboard.
And now rather than passing these, I will say instead, let's see what order do we do them in pending,
then healthy, then warning, then problem and error are assigned the value of repo DB and I think I
called that get all service status counts there.
If error is not equal to nil and I'll just do what I've been doing right along.
Logged uprate line error and return so they'll see a blank screen, but we can check the log file to
see what's going on.
And in production I would do something a little more user friendly, but I'm not in production now.
I substitute the number healthy with healthy, the no problem with problem, the number pending with
pending and then no warning with warning.
And if I stop my application and clear this and run my application.
And go back to my dashboard and say, I'll just go to the House page, then I'll go back to overview.
I have one pending service.
Perfect.
And if I go back to my database, I need to go to my database.
I can just go to my hosts and look at my services and turn this one off, which should take place in
the background that I get an error message.
I'm terminated, quoted string Learjet.
I'm going to fix that.
Where is the layout Parshall's Jast Jet and under UN terminated quoted string.
So let's find that I must have hit return at some point and I better fix that right now.
So that's interviews.
Parshall's Jast jet, and it says to look at line for, line for.
And I get that somehow I mess this up, so let's fix that.
Let's see what's going on here.
Oh, I know what it is, I must have formatted this text at some point, and that messed it all up.
So this can go back up here.
This can come back up here.
That's one of the problems of not having a correct plug in for jet for my I.D. And it's making me rethink
using this in the future.
But let's just make sure that's not going to generate any more errors and reload this.
Check the console, no errors.
Now, if I go to manage services and make that inactive, that's better.
OK, that's where I wanted to get.
So I.
You don't have that error, I'm sure.
But I do.
And just so you know, if I am looking at this just jet page and I reformat it by hitting the key combination
that reformats my text sometimes, but not always, which is the most irritating kind of error ever.
It will actually break the formatting for this this sort of thing.
And that's what happened here.
But spaces between the hyphens and put things in other lines.
Anyway, I cleaned it up.
So now that's working.
Now, if I go back to my overview, this should say zero, and it does because that service is not active
on localhost.
But when I go back to localhost, go to services, turn it back on and go back to my overview.
Now, it shows the number one in pending over here, and that's exactly what I wanted to do.
So this page, it looks like it's done.
It's working exactly the way I want it to.
So the next step and we'll do this for one and I'll leave the other three is an exercise for you because
it's exactly the same sort of thing.
We need this page to list all of the problems, all of the pending services, and we want to see the
hostname, the service name, the status and the message.
And there will be no message because it's pending.
Nothing's happened yet.
The status will just be pending.
The service will be the name of the service in our case, HTTP and the name of the host is the name
of the host.
And this is just a quick way to list all of the services that are in a given status.
And we want to be able to click on the service or the host and go right to the appropriate page.
OK, so we'll take care of that in the next lecture and then I'll leave the last three that are not
the pending status as an exercise for you, which should be really straightforward.