OK, so we have our list of hosts showing up on the overview page, we have all of the service count
showing up.
So this page is done.
And what we want to do now is this page.
We want to have one page for each of these.
And as I said last time, I will do this one and then I'll leave the next three as an exercise for you,
because it's exactly the same logic.
You're just changing one thing.
Instead of looking for host services with the status of pending, you're looking for a status of problem
or warning or healthy.
So let's do this one.
So this is the page and this page has the URL slash admin slash all pending.
So let's go back to our code, open air routes file and try that again.
Routes file and find the one that has the correct you URL, which is all pending right here.
All pending.
So that lists all pending services.
And it looks like all that this does right now is render that page with no information.
So what I need to do is to get all post services with Hosta info
for status.
And so I need to write a query that will do that.
And we know how to do that.
So we'll go back to our I'm going to do it here, first of all, in my Postgres client.
And I will look at the host services table.
And I want to get all of this information.
And is there anything else that I need?
Let's look at that page again.
We have hosted service status and message.
I don't know what message is right now, so I'll just leave that one alone.
But I know I can do this.
This is pretty straightforward.
So we can look at the structure for this.
We're going to get the ID, the whole study and the service IDs.
So my query is select ID, host ID, service ID.
Try that again, and it is here, active schedule, no schedule unit.
Active schedule, no schedule unit, comma, and then last check created an updated Eisenstat status
soldi status, first status, sorry, last check status created at updated apart from host services
where status equals and I want pending.
So that will get all the information.
Now, it's not doing it in any particular sorted order.
So maybe I should make this a little bit better.
Maybe I should say.
Host Services has left join hosts h bon høst hosted ID equals H ID.
Now I joined the host table, which means I need to prepend hs dot to all these.
Let me copy that.
Paste, paste, paste.
And the wrong spot.
And then from the host, I want to get the host name, OK, so that should work.
We run this.
There it is.
And the hosting should be the last thing.
And it is OK.
Is there anything else that I need to have here?
Well, I have the idea that I also want to get the service name.
So let's join services services as on and it's escort service ID equals estcourt ID and now we'll put
escort service name.
No point in telling you that you have a problem or something is pending if you don't know what the actual
services.
So let's run that.
That was good.
OK, so I'm going to copy this query and I'll go back to my Idy and I will open my in my internal folder
in repository under debri, I'll open host Postgres and at the very bottom I'll read any function.
Func M a pointer to Postgres DB Repo.
Now what am I doing here.
I want to get services by status, so get services by status.
And I'm going to actually pass in one parameter which I'll call status and it will be a string and I'm
going to return a slice of something.
Models dot host seems like the most appropriate one and potentially an error.
OK,
now that's caused me grief.
Get rid of that.
So let's paste in our query.
Query is assign the value of and I'll paste that in there and then tab it over so it's a little more
attractive and move that back, tick up and I'll copy my context lines from another method, paste them
in and now I just need to do my query but I need to make one modification here.
I don't want to hard code pending because I want to use this same method for problems and for warnings
and for healthy.
So I'll just make that a placeholder.
And now we can do our query executed on the database so we get rows and potentially an error or assign
the value of IMDB dot query, context, pasada, context, passata, query and pass it our status,
which we get as a parameter up here in the method signature.
Then we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil return and we have nothing to return yet.
So we have to find a variable to hold the results.
VAR services, which is a slice of models post.
And we want to return services and our air otherwise and errors, just E.R., we defer our rose close.
OK, now we scan through our rows and start spending things to this slice.
So four rows dot next will create a variable to hold our current iteration.
And that would be var H is of type models dot host and now we just scan into this row.
So scan, try that again.
Rows dot scan and we want to scan into
H.
So ampersand H and the first thing we're getting is our host ID and that is our.
This is a type models host.
Yes.
So it's not.
The second thing is.
Hmm, that's the whole service, let's try that again, HD host service Dog Idee.
Let better look at the model for hosts models.
I don't want to get this all wrong.
So a host right here has a host service which has a hosted service and that, yeah, I don't want to
scare this into a house service.
I want to sell into a house.
I want to scan this into a host.
So it's hosted service.
I just go back here, find this and change this into host services, host service.
And here this will be a model of hosting service that makes more sense.
And then we just scan in the ID.
OK, so we'll have to add some attributes to our hosts service model in a moment, but that's OK.
So Ampersand ID gives us a host service ID and then ampersand host ID and I'll just duplicate this a
few times.
Next we're getting our service ID, then we're getting our host services active or not.
That's always going to be one because we're only looking for active ones.
I think we're have to check that in a moment.
Then our schedule number, which we don't really need, but it's not going to hurt to get it in there,
that our schedule unit.
OK, and then our last check.
And then our status.
Which will always be pending when we pass it pending, then created and then updated at now hostname
and service name, they actually aren't part of our models.
So if we go back to our models, which are over here and we look at a host service, we have no where
to put a service name or a hostname.
But we can we put the service name under service service's name, OK, so we know where to put a host
name.
So I'll just put it added here.
It's a string, OK?
And I might want to put a comment there saying it's not part of the database, but for our purposes
right now, I can just store the information there.
So let's go back here.
And that is ampersand H Hostname.
And the last thing I'm getting is a service name, which I can put in an H service.
Service name, because that's part of the model structure, so that is our skin and we check for an
error.
If error is not equal to nil, just return nil and error if error is not equal to nil.
I've got to, of course, create errors, assign the value of there.
That's better.
So we check for error.
If everything worked as we expected, then we say our variable name, which is services, is assigned
the order of equals append services.
And I called this one.
OK, so how service what is this services.
That's right.
This has to be a service.
That's better.
OK, so now we have this information and we can just return it.
So we'll say return services and nil.
Now let's look at this query and make sure we've got it right from where status equals dollars, sign
one.
There's one more thing I want to add there and start active
equals one.
So I don't want to return inactive services as part of this query.
So that should do the trick.
So let's copy this signature.
Go to our repository, paste it in there, so it's available to our handlers, close that and go back
to our handlers and I share, but go back to my roots so I can find the appropriate handler.
That was all pending right here.
This one.
Yes.
So we want to now get that information so we can just say services and potentially an error are assigned
the value of repo DB, get services by status and the status I want is pending.
OK, check for an hour.
If Bear is not equal to nil and I'll do what I've been doing right along, log it and return.
And I'm not going to bother telling you you shouldn't do that in production because you know that by
now.
No, I need to create a vase.
How did I do that?
Let's find that again.
So that would be under handlers and there it is right there.
Vase make jet via a map.
So back to this one and paste this into here and we can say vase dot set and we'll call this services
and we'll pass in our services and then we pass that data to this map refers to this template.
And this is now an equals because I've declared an air up here.
So that's that.
So let's stop our application, make sure everything compiles more than one character in Rune Litoral
and that's on services status page go thirty seven, which is right.
These are double quotes.
Try that again.
Run.
Perfect.
OK, now we know we stored this in our very map and called it services, so let's find the all service
are depending page and it is pending jet lag views.
I think this is it.
Pending services.
Yes, it is.
So I have no services there right now, which is what I probably see on this page.
So let's delete that and let's range through our services that we just passed to this page and end and
in the middle we have a table row for every entry and a closing table row for every entry.
Get rid of this and this because you don't want to row within a row.
Try that again there.
So let's tab these in so it's a little more attractive and let's filter values TD and that's just going
to be hostname.
Pretty sure that's what I called it to make sure in their models hostname.
And underneath that, I'm going to have the service, which is Dott Service DOT service name.
And underneath that I'm going to have the status which is dot status I think.
Let's make sure.
Yeah, that's the status.
And after that is a message and we don't know anything about that yet.
So we're just going to leave that empty.
So if I've spelled everything right and stop the application and start it and go back here, I should
be able to reload this page.
And I do.
I have a great OK, so pending should be a little more attractive.
Let's make that kind of a gray.
So let's wrap that in a badge.
Spanned class equals badge, and it's big, big dash.
I'm not sure which one it is.
Let's just try.
Let's try secondary dark and see what that looks like
doesn't really matter.
I just want it to look a little more attractive.
Reload pending.
OK, that works.
OK, so there is our status picture.
Now, what I want, of course, is I want this to be a link to go over to my hosts page and right over
to my hosts.
Click on localhost if you want it to bring up this tab and that tab.
If you roll over the link here, you can see that in the bottom left hand corner of my browser, it
has hosted six and then hash pending dash content.
So maybe we can link directly to that.
Now, let's go back over here and make this an actual link.
So I will say, hey, HPF equals admin's host host Idy, which I can get from the data I'm passing here,
host ID and then a hash pending dash content.
Let's see if that works.
I'll copy this or cut it, paste it here and just reformat this by tabbing in a little bit.
Let's see how that works.
So let's go back to our overview and look at our pending services.
And this is now a link to slash admin, slash host, slash six hash pending dash content.
All right, that's exactly what I wanted to do to take it right to this page.
OK, so that is how we're going to populate the information for all of those tabs are all of these tables.
So I've done this one.
You should be able to do these three with no difficulty whatsoever.
So if you do have difficulty, just look at the source for the next for this lecture, because I finished
it without recording it.
And it's right up there on the source for this lecture if you run into any difficulties at all.