So while I was recording this course go one point one six came out and go one point one six is a pretty
good upgrade with a lot of new features.
And there's an article here on Long Rocket.
This is a blog post called What's New and Go One Point one six.
And I've posted a link to this in the course resources for this lecture.
And there are very few changes required.
And to be fair, if you don't do any of these changes, there's only two small ones we need to make.
Everything will still work.
But I think it's always a good idea to stay current with the language and to keep my code base up to
date with whatever changes have occurred in the language.
So the part that interests us and we you scroll down this article all the way down to IOU til right
here, the IOU IOU still package is now deprecated and all they've done is they've left the existing
methods that are in the ideal package as part of the language.
But they've actually moved, the methods are copied, the methods to other places where they make more
sense.
So the part that interests us are these methods right here and we're only using one of them.
So if you go to our code and just to be clear, if you make these changes without installing go one
point one six, your code is not going to work.
So the first step is to go update from go one point one five or whatever.
You have to go one point one six, then you make these changes.
So if you look at our code right over here, the only places where where we make a call to IOU till
there's only one place and it's in Pusher Go, which is found in internal handlers, pusher go.
And it's this in my code, it's line 17 and all we need to do is to change IO util to IO and our updates
are imports should update and they did.
So that changes is necessary to make this current with go one point one six.
The other place is in my go modify.
I just changed the third line from go one point one five to go one point one six.
And assuming that you've installed go one point once a one point one six.
Life is good and those are the only changes required for our code base.