So we have a couple of tables now, we have our host table, our services table and our host services
table, and we need to set up some models that allow us to map the information that we'll have in the
database with our go code.
And that's pretty straightforward.
So let's go back to our idee and let's open up this package that's in the root level of our application,
inside the internal folder, inside the model's folder.
And I'm going to open model Stocco.
And here you see, we already have a couple of models.
We have one for users and one for preferences.
And we're not using the preferences yet, but we'll get to that eventually.
So we need to set up some new ones.
So we'll set up one for host type post, which is just a struct.
And everything inside that struct will correspond to what we have in our house table.
So let's have a look at that and let's look at the structure for it.
So it has an I.D. and a host name.
So let's add those ID.
We'll just that'll just be an aunt and our host name, which will be a string.
And then we had our canonical name, which will also be a string.
And what else do we have you URL, IP and IP version six, your URL String IP, which is the IP address,
which we might not use, but we might say we may also put it in their IP version six.
That will also be a string.
And what else do we have.
Location, operating system and active location, which is just a string OS for operating system, which
will be a string and active created an updated and active that will be an int created that which is
of time, time and updated at which is also of time.
Time.
OK, so let's give it a comment.
Host is the model for hosts.
OK, now we need one for services type services, also a struct, and it will have an ID for sure,
which is an ENT and it will also have created out and update it out.
So I'll copy those and paste them down in here.
Now let's see what else we have in their services.
So that has an idea.
Service name at an active service name, which will be a string active, which will be an ENT.
And an icon, which is just a.
OK, let's give that a comment.
Services.
Is the model for services and are third one is how services type hosted services.
I'll just call it host service struct.
That will have an ID for sure.
And we'll have a creative created and updated out for sure, so let's put those in there and let's see
what else is in their host services right there.
So hosted in-service day ID
in.
And those are our foreign keys that allow us to determine which services exist for a given hope host,
active schedule, no active input schedule, no.
What is that?
It's an int.
Schedule unit, which is a string, so that would be like three minutes for for number and unit and
last check,
which will be a time time.
OK, so there's our host services.
And let's give that a comment is the model for hosting services.
OK, so now we have models set up for all of these things.
Now let's think about if we've missed anything.
We have all the information for our host and we absolutely need to know its ID so we can find it in
the database, its host hostname, which is just a string, something we can refer to.
So it makes sense to us.
We know which server we're looking at, canonical name.
We absolutely need that.
That's its domain name.
It's your URL.
How do we get to that?
If it's a website that it's HTP or HDB followed by whatever the URL is to get to it, IP and IP version
six.
We may not use those, but we might if we don't have a hostname, a real canonical name, for example,
we won't be checking by IP or IP version six location OS active.
I think we have everything you need for our hosts there.
What about our services now?
Services is the table that's just going to list the services we want to check.
So a given service in this table is not tied to a service, a particular host.
We do that in the host service table, but we have an ID so we can find in the database a name that's
descriptive so we know what we're monitoring, whether it's active or not.
Sure, an icon.
We're just going to use that for display, which we'll get to when we start building the necessary pages.
That seems to be everything we need here.
What about host services?
So I need some means of determining whether or not a service is up or down or in a morning state or
not yet checked, whatever it might be.
So what we have here is an ID, a host ID and a service ID and these to allow us to link services to
hosts using foreign keys.
Active makes sense how often we check it.
When we last checked it, I think we need one more thing and that would be the status, whether it's
up or down and that can be an A..
It could be a string.
It could be anything we want.
I think I'm just going to make it a string and that string will be OK or healthy for the service is
fine warning if it's in a warning state problem if it's in a problem state or pending if it's pending,
we could use anything we wanted.
We could actually have another table called status and use foreign keys to link them together.
But for the purposes of what we're trying to do in this course, I think just using a string is sufficient
for our purposes for the moment.
Now, we've added this to our model, but it doesn't exist in our actual database table.
So we need to run another migration.
So I'm make sure I'm in the root level of my directory.
I am.
And now I want to add a column to this particular table so I'll generate a migration.
So to generate fiz add status to host services table and that will allow me to have my two new migrations.
So let's open them up.
We'll go to our migration's.
And find the two that we've just added and I'll look at the up table first and the syntax to add it
is really straightforward.
Add column to the post services table and we'll call it status.
And it's a type of string and it's default.
We'll be just make it empty for now.
That way we'll never have a null value in there at all.
All right.
Actually, that's make it pending.
When we first add something to the table, its status should be pending because we want to run any checks
yet.
So there's our up migration and let's put our down migration in there as well.
And that's as simple as drop column from the host services table hosted services.
And the column I want to drop is status, and that should be it.
So let's try writing this migration so to migrate.
There it is, let's make sure it's in there, so I'll go back and reload this table and now I have status.
All right, so I'll add these to get.
And commit everything.
Create models and call them to host services and commit and push.
And push.
So the next step is to go create some database routines that allow us to add, edit and delete entries
to our hosts house services and services table, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture or
two.