So hopefully you didn't have any trouble finishing up these three screens, and it's pretty straightforward,
and if you looked at the source that I posted at the end of the last lecture, you'll notice that I
did make one minor change and it's literally one little bit in the school query.
So this is the get services by status method found inside the host underscore PostgreSQL go file.
And all I did was add this little bit at the end.
So when we have more than one service, of course you want them to be ordered in some meaningful way.
So I said order by hostname and service name.
And that way when we have more than one host or more than one service, things won't be arranged just
randomly.
They'll have some sensible order.
So that's the one change we made there.
So now if we go back and look at this, this page looks good.
We have one service with one host and it displays everything just the way that it should.
But if we go back here, I don't like this.
There's nothing here.
And this table has no information whatsoever.
And it's just cosmetically it's not that attractive.
So let's go fix that up and then we'll move on to the next step in this project.
And this is really easy.
So let me go to my code and let me look at my views folder, which is right here, and we'll start with
healthy.
So at this point, I'm ranging through the services and displaying them right here in the template.
And if there's nothing in there, of course, none of this code gets executed.
Therefore, we just have an empty body so we can improve this just by saying and the simple if statement
if Lenn of services is greater than zero.
And put an ELT's here.
And put an end here and let's just tab things around so it's a little more readable.
So if we have at least one thing in our services variable, then this code gets executed.
Otherwise we'll just put it in one table row with one table column that has a call span of one, two,
three, four, four, no services.
And that's all we need to do.
So let me that was the healthy one.
Now let's get to the next one, which would be spending.
If Lynn of Services is greater than zero.
ELT's.
And I'll just have this over go back to my healthy copy, this one section here and pasted in.
And have it in, so that's pending now problems, same idea.
If Lenn of services is greater than zero.
ELT's.
Pasting my code.
And.
And I think there's one more warning.
If one of services is greater than zero.
Beltz, Paiste and.
And this over.
And tab this over and make sure everything is done properly.
So let's just go have a look at this overview.
There should be one row in this table that says no services and that looks much better, not just a
cosmetic thing.
I just like it much better.
And let's make sure the pending actually displays properly and it does.
OK, so that's simple.
Now, the next thing I want to do, and this is where things start to get a little more complicated,
but not too much when I look at my host.
This is correct.
And these are empty.
There's nothing in them.
And we want to actually display all of the healthy services here, all of the warning services here,
all of the problems and all of the pending.
And I also want to allow the user when they're looking, say, for example, at the pending services
or the problems or any of these for a list, the service, and I'll have a button beside it that allows
me to check.
Now, that will actually fire off a request in the background, do a check of that service.
If it's not changed status, give them some message to that.
That indicates that.
But if it has changed status, what's going to happen down the road is will remove the entry from the
current tab, display an alert or a message to the user saying that the status has changed from something
to something else and then add a row in the appropriate tab.
So for impending and we say check now and it moves from, say, pending to problems, it deletes the
entry from the table here, adds it to the table here and displays an alert up here.
So let's get started doing that.
The first thing we're going to have to do, of course, is figure out how we populate each of these
tabs with the information.
So let's go back to our roots file roots and find the part where we're showing a host, which is right
here, handler's repost.
So what we're doing here is we're grabbing the ID from the URL.
We're creating an empty models host.
We're getting the host from the database if it's greater than zero.
And we're going to assume that's the case here right now and that calls get hosted by ID.
So when we go to get hosted by ID under the Postgrads File, which is in the repository in DB Repo and
it's called Host Underscore Postgrads.
Let's find get hosted by ID right there.
So what are we getting here.
We're getting the basic host information.
We're scanning that into our variable, then we're getting all the services for the host and this includes
all of the services that have any status.
So we're having them all there and it also includes inactive services.
Perfect.
This will give us everything we need.
So we already have enough information that we can go to our hosts file host jet right here, host Cingular
Jet.
And let's do the let's do the pending one first because we have some content in there.
So let's create a t a div of class equals row and then a div of class equals call and let's create a
table so we'll create a table.
Table class equals.
Table, table striped.
And give it a head and think about what information we want in there.
Well, we definitely want the TIAR.
We want it.
We want the service, the service name.
We want the last check.
And we'll have a message which will be empty for right now as we have nothing display in that, but
we'll get to that later on.
So this gives us our table heading and then we want our table body.
And we want to display information again only if there is a status that is of the status pending so
we can do it like this range.
Host Dot, and I think it's called host services, but let me make sure in your models.
So host has hosted services, yes, plural, so let's go back to our House page.
Hosted services and.
Let's just display the services here.
So the first one would be a tiara, because we're going to loop through this one item at a time and
then a TV, and then we want the service name, which I believe.
Let's just go back to our models and make sure wherever they're here, we are host services, a hosted
service holds a service that has a service name.
So back to host.
So that would be Dort service, not service name.
Clothes are curly brackets.
Let's just make sure that works.
I'll just put in two empty rows so it satisfies that requirement and go back and go back to her overview,
look at our hosts and look at pending.
And that should list one service and it does HDP last check and message.
OK, so we know what that has that information.
I probably should give it to that pending content, but let's go down here and change that pending content.
Just delete it.
And just before the just after the column is opened, we'll put a little heading in there each three
and we'll say pending services.
And we already have last checked.
So let's just stick that in there as it looks right now.
Last check.
Reload.
Pending.
OK, that needs to be pushed down to maybe a little bit smaller, so last check, OK?
That's my default value and I'm not really happy with the displaying that way, but I'll take care of
that.
I have some functions available to us that will format this more appropriately, but it looks like it's
actually getting the information the way that we want.
And the problem with that, of course, is that this is going to list all of the services, whether
they're pending or not.
And we don't want to do that.
We actually only want to list the pending services.
So first of all, let's push this down.
I'll make this an effort to make it smaller.
Class equals empty, say, three, reload this pending.
Class equals PT three padding top three doesn't seem to be working.
That works better.
OK, so we only want to display things here that are actually pending so we can just do it like this
if.
DOT's status equals spending.
And then do an end here, not the most efficient way in the world, but it'll work, this should actually
display the information again and it should include the pending one and it does.
OK, so let's get to getting us started.
Let's just quickly duplicate that.
All of this information starting with here.
Copy that.
And go back up to problem content and just paste it in here and only after changes this problem and
this to problem.
OK, let's just make sure that's working.
Reload this and that should show nothing.
OK, so that worked.
We'll just have this in.
And to have that in good, so there's only one of thing I want to want to put here, and that is status,
so I want to have that check now Button.
So where am I going to put that?
Let's go back to our pending service issue and I should put a check now button right there.
So let's do that.
So after the service name.
I want to put a little a HSF equals go nowhere, so JavaScript void zero, which will make the Celenk
but won't go anywhere.
And we want to say unclick or just say class.
We'll give it a class now.
We'll make it or not.
Click on click equals check now and then the ID of the host service, which would be Dort ID because
we're looping through host services here.
We know, we know, we have the ID and we'll just say check now and we'll format this in a little,
a little more nicely in a moment.
OK, I think I have that.
All right.
And down here we need to put a check now function so I'll just make an empty function function check
now and the ID and it does nothing.
I'll just say console log clicked.
Check now.
OK, let's go reformat this a reload this, open our JavaScript console, go to pending and we should
have a check now button and we do.
And when I click on it, uncaught reference.
I got a typo in there somewhere.
Let's go fix that.
Oh, yes, probably want to close that there.
That looks a little better, let's close this and apparently I don't have IP running, so I'll start
that up to avoid those errors.
Now go back and reload this page to make sure everything's current, go to pending and click on Check
now.
That looks better, and if I clear this check now, check now, OK, so that all seems to be working.
Let's make this a little more attractive and I can probably just make that a button or a small let's
go like this.
Let's go.
Spane class equals badge.
Vague outline, secondary, I think that will do it and put this one down here and let's see how that
looks.
Reloads tending, OK?
Apparently, that's not a background, so we'll have to change it to something else.
Let's change it to, well, info, see what that looks like, reload pending, that's not going to work.
B.G. Dash.
Say, secondary, PJI secondary.
Let's try that.
Still pretty dark.
OK.
What it doesn't need to be an if at all.
Let's just take this on Klickitat there.
Put it up here, get rid of the AI altogether.
And Unclipped needs a print this earth quote after it.
OK, Alex, right, let's try that.
That looks better.
OK, so that will give me my check now button, and I probably want to add some success.
So when you roll over this, that it turns into a pointer.
But for now, this is sufficient for our purposes.
So that works there.
Let's just copy this little bit.
And add it to this one, so after the service name.
And it goes right here to have that, and so it looks a little better.
And that and so it looks a little bit better analysis, copy this entire range bid and add it to the
next one, which is warning content.
Actually, I want to copy the whole thing.
Div class equals row all the way down to here, so we're going to go to warning.
Which is right here.
Paste that in and make that morning services that make this morning.
OK, and healthy and paste that in there and change this to healthy.
And change this to healthy.
Let's make sure this all works appropriately and pending good problems, no problem.
Warning.
And healthy.
OK, so that's sufficient for our purposes right now.
This gets us started.
So now we know we can display all of the appropriate information.
So if I go back to my overview and look at pending services and click on localhost, it should take
me to the pending tab and have everything displaying as it should.
All right.
That's enough for this time in the next election.
We'll move on to the next step.