So let's just clean things up and make them a little more attractive, and the first thing I want to
do is take care of this, I don't want this date, which is my default date, because I don't like dealing
with moles in the database.
I don't want that to show up unless there's actually been a check performed.
And once a check is performed, which we're going to get to very shortly, this will have a valid date
and time stamp.
Otherwise, I don't want to display anything.
So let's go back over to our code and I'll show you.
I have some helper functions in here, so I'm going to look, first of all, let's just go to the reads
file.
So in Route's, we'll find a place where we're displaying a page.
Here's a place where I'm displaying all healthy services and that calls this helper's render page and
render page right here is just a function.
But it does have this one little thing down here at the end that says ad template functions.
Well, let's look at that.
So ad template functions.
It's just at the top of the same file, which is template or in a file called template.
Dasch functions.
Dargo and I have three functions available to me human date, date from layout and date after year one.
Well, this means this is available to me in my in my all of my templates.
All of these three functions are.
So let's go back to the hosted chat and come down here where I'm displaying last check.
And let's just change this a little bit and see if I can get the syntax right in the first try.
If and the function is called date after year one.
And it takes one argument, which is time, not time.
So back to host yet.
If a date after year one and my time dot time is last check if it's after year one, then it's actually
been populated with meaningful information in the database.
So I want to do something if that takes place else.
I want to display something else.
And so I if I just do this, if I cut that out of there and if the date is after your one, then it
should render it.
So if I go back to my.
And what tab is this?
This is in the healthy tab.
That's not helpful at all.
Let's go down to spending.
And say the same thing.
So do this, Hoopes.
If data after your data, after year one, date after
year one, I think that's what I called it, date after year one, yet if data after year one and pass
it last check.
Then display the information.
And I'm going to do that.
I don't even need an alt statement, so now when I go load the host page right here and reload this
page and look at pending, that should be empty.
And it is OK.
But I don't actually want to display the date in that much information so I can actually take advantage
of this template function which says date after date from layout, and that takes a time and the layout
string and we just use the standard go layout string.
So back to host Jack and I can just say date from land because I want to call it a date from Las.
Data from layout, and it takes a time and then it takes the layout string, so we'll use the standard
twenty six zero one zero two and then 15 zero four.
And that will give me the correct date and time formatted in a way that makes sense to me in Canada.
If you like a different format, whatever format you want in your layout string, just using the standard
go date layout format and things will be good.
Now I could actually just either put an Alice in there as well just to make it a little more readable
if you wanted to, and say pending there.
So now if I come back here and reload this and I have a unclosed less parentheses and it's OK post three
19.
So I got a unclosed less right here.
Yes, let's try that again.
Now it should stay pending and it does.
OK, so this is the kind of information that will be changing using Web sockets in a little while.
But what I want to do next is to look at this bit right here.
I have, if you recall, in the database, if I go back to my database and look at the services, I
have this little icon and I'm not using that at all right now.
So let's see what we can put in there.
So I'm going to go to the font awesome site.
And this is where I'm I'm grabbing my free icons from.
And I have a paid version, but we're just going to use the free ones.
So let's go to icons and I'll just look for a server icon and there's one.
So these ones you have to pay for.
This one is free.
I'm going to use the free one.
How do I use this?
Start using this icon and the syntax is FASB dash f a dash server.
OK, so let's go back to our database and change this to f ASFA dash server and save that.
And go back here just to make things a little more visually appealing and where do I list the services?
So service is.
Right here.
So before that, before I displayed the service, I can actually mine the host jet file and I'm looking
at pending services.
Right here, just before the service name, let's put in a Spath class, equals service dog icon.
That might be it.
Let's find out.
That looks better, and then I have a little icon next to it, and that's purely for cosmetic purposes.
So every time I add a new service, I will add at least one more.
Before this, of course, is over, I'm going to give it a nice icon and you can use whatever icon set
you want.
But I think this is not a bad one.
So what I want to do next is to actually perform a check.
I want when I click on this and I'm going to add some success to give it a little pointer icon just
because I can.
I actually do want it to fire a request off and I want to get the response back and I'll use Ajax to
fire the request off and to handle the response.
So at least for right now, we'll change that as time goes on.
But I would just want to get this working.
So this means we need to write some code that will actually perform a check and we'll start that process
in the next lecture.