So now I want to make this check now button, which actually isn't a button, but acts like one, I
want it to actually go and check the status of the service that I'm currently looking at.
So this is pending.
All right.
When I click this little button, I want to fire a request of using Ajax in the background that will
go to the server and tell it.
I want to test this service and I need to send it some information, say the host service ID.
And just to save some time, I'll probably send the current status as well.
It'll just save us a database to look up on the back end.
Then the back end will actually go and try to connect to that service and get some kind of response.
Either it's it's good.
It's bad, it's morning, whatever it may be, and send that information back to me.
And that's all I want to do.
And it's going to take a couple of steps, but let's get started doing it.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go to my roots file, which is right here, and I'm going to put
a path in here or put a route in here that allows me to perform that check so I can just do it like
this and I'll make it a get request.
We could make it a Gedera post, but it doesn't matter.
I'm going to make an to get for right now.
And what I want to check for is say it'll be slash admin because we're in here and I'll call it perform
check and then I'll pass in the ID of this this whole service.
And after that I'll pass in the old status.
Of this service, and that will go to handlers and we'll go to a handler that doesn't exist yet, Repo
and I'll call it test to check.
And that should be enough.
OK, now we need to create this handler, so I'm going to go back to my internal folder.
I'm going to find handlers and I'll create a new file.
And I would call that file.
Um, perform checks don't go that's as good as name is any, and I will add that to my repository.
So let's go create a handler, Funke Repo is Star Dot or Star DB Repo, and I call this test check and
because it's a handler, requires a response writer.
And it requires have pointed to a request.
OK, so now that handler exists, so if I go back to my roots, that error should go away and it does.
Maybe I'll call old status with a capital S. So it actually won't give me a warning from the formatting.
All right.
So let's see what we're going to do in here.
All right away.
I want to grab my parameter values, so I'll say the host service ID and potentially an error because
I'm going to convert this from a string to an end and I'm ignoring the error.
And you're not going to in production, of course, is equal to stir conv.
I and I want to get the euro parameter, and since I'm using the key router, I can just say Chheda
Euro Perram and hand it the response right after the request.
And I'm looking for it.
OK, that gets me my host service ID and old status is just equal to CZI Euro Perram and I'm looking
for I have to hand it the pointer to the request and I'm looking for old status and I capitalize that
s so all of that so I can actually compile this log print line, try that again, print line on a log
post service ID and old status.
OK, so now what am I going to do in this request?
Well, the first thing I have to do is to use that ID to get the host service.
Then is there anything else that I need to do?
Do I need the host information?
I'm not sure.
Let's just think about how this is going to work.
So I'll just say get hosed.
I may need that information.
So what I want to do next is I want to test the service and I don't want to do that in this handler
because I'm going to be testing services for multiple places.
So I'll read another function to actually test that service.
And then I want to create Jason a response and send the Jason to client to the request, whatever made
that request.
So this stuff I'm not going to worry about right now.
I just want to manually send the information back and and make sure that everything is hooked up correctly.
And I do this all the time.
I'll create the necessary fetch on the template.
I'll send the request off to this handler.
And I have this handler send something back just to make sure that everything works.
So let's just manually do this.
Let's say let's create a variable which I'll call resp, and that will be assigned the value of JSON
resp, which I haven't created yet.
Have I know I better create that type.
Let's create a type that will actually allow us to send information back to the client.
So I call this type Jason Response, Jason Rasp, and it will be a struct and it's going to have some
information.
So OK, which will be a bool.
And in Jason, I want that to be cold, OK?
Lower case, definitely don't want to send that information back to let them know whether or not the
request actually succeeded.
I'm probably going to have some kind of message.
I'll make that a string.
And then Jason, I'll call that message.
I'm probably going to have a service, I'd like to know what kind of service we're dealing with when
we send it back, because I might need that on the client end and that will be an INT.
And in Jason, I'll call that service underscore ID.
Probably going to want the whole service tidy.
Which will be Adient and Jason, I'll call that post service ID.
Probably going to have the host study, which will be an end, and in Jason, I'll call that host study.
And old status, let's say, will hand back the old status, what was the status before we performed
the check?
That is just a string and I'll call that in Jason.
Old status and the new service, a new status, its new status.
And again, that's just a string.
And I'll call that in, Jason.
New status.
And last check.
So we're going to be performing this and I want to send back the timestamp for the last check.
And it'll be of type type times time and in Jason, I will call that.
Last underscore check, OK, let's format this and see if we have everything we need.
Now, this may be more information than I actually need, but I may need all of it and there's no problem
sending it.
It's just a very small JSON file.
So we're sending back whether or not the request took place.
That's good.
Whether we succeeded.
So, OK, that will be false.
If something went wrong, the message will be whatever message we're sending back.
And there might be an error message, it might be a success message, whatever it may be, the service
ID that tells me what kind of service I'm checking.
We just have one HDP with an idea of one the host service ID.
I know that at the point of request and I need that to look up the host service, the host ID will be
sending will be sending that back.
Whether we need it or not.
We're going to send it back.
And old status and new status, very straightforward if it was pending and a change to healthy I send
back pending for the old status and healthy for the new status.
Last check is the date and time, the time stamp of when we perform this check.
So now I have some information.
I can send it back, send back.
So back down here in my test check where I'm just wiring things up and making sure that they work.
This will be type of of type JSON resp and we'll just send OK.
We'll set that to true and for message will set that to test message, and this should be enough for
me to actually make the request and send that information back.
So let's turn this into Jason out.
Underscore is a sign the value of Jason Marshall in debt and we're going to Marshall RESP and we'll
just use nothing for the second parameter and a few spaces for the third parameter.
So now we have our out variable.
Let's set our header correctly.
Header set and we're sending back content type of application, Jason, and we just write that to our
response writers, so w dot right out.
OK, so this should give us enough information to make sure that this is actually working.
So let's go back to our host jet page and find the part where we're performing a check.
And I'm going to add a parameter here.
I'm going to call it old status, OK?
Which means when I call this right up here, underspending, so we're underpinning services, we want
to actually say check now, not just the ID, we also want pass pending.
OK, so that, I believe, is formatted correctly, but you can't use double quotes and inside of double
quotes will change that to single quotes.
And that should be right.
OK, so down here, I actually want to do more than just click it.
I actually want to do a fetch so we can just say fetch.
With our you are you are all and I can't remember that what that was, but I'll look it up in a minute
and I need to pass two other pieces of information.
So the pieces of information I want to send are going to be right from our you are out.
So let's go to our roots and see what that you were.
I was perform check old status or ID and old status.
So let's go back here, find our host yet just paste that in there and get rid of this.
This is not going to be an I.D. like that will just manually put it in.
It's our ID from the parameters pass to this function, plus a slash.
Plus.
Old status, so that is what we're going to be calling.
That's the URL, and then we want a dot then response which will change to Jason.
Response.
Jason.
And then we want to do something with that response then.
I'll just call this a data which is going to go to a function.
And we need to close this off, all right, and all we'll do here is say console.
Log.
OK, followed by day two, OK, I have a typo here, response, response that works better.
And then I'll say message, DataDot message.
And that will let me know whether this is actually working or not.
So let's stop our application.
Oops, I just stopped it, but ah, start that back up.
Stop our application.
Run our application.
Go back to our Web browser, open a JavaScript terminal, clear the console, reload the page.
Apparently, I have to log in now admin at example, dot com password.
Log in.
That's better clear the console, go to our local host, look at the pending services and see what we
got wrong, even though I haven't changed the case for this, this is still clickable.
So hopefully this will fire off an AJAX request in the background.
Wait a second.
Let me remember.
I think I missed one thing here before I do this.
Yes.
It's not perform check.
It's admin, perform check.
OK, let's reload this page, clear the console, go to our pending tab and try to check now.
And it gave me OK, true messages, text message.
OK, I know everything is hooked up properly and that's good.
So the next step is to go back to her handlers which are under perform checks.
No, I actually want to do this stuff, get the host service, figure out whether or not I need the
house and send the information back to the client.
That's not just hardcoded.
That actually comes from our test function.
So this means we need to create a function to actually test the service and pass it, the necessary
information to see whether or not the service is alive and send the response back appropriately.
OK, so we'll start that in the next lecture.