So we're at the point now where we have this nice check now button and when we click on it, we actually
do get some valid JSON back from the server.
So we know that everything is wired up correctly.
And what we want to have happen next is when I actually click on this check now button, in our case,
what should happen is it should try to check for the status of a nonexistent server because we don't
have anything listening on the port AT&amp;T for localhost.
So it should send back a message saying there is a problem.
So we're moving from pending status to a problem status and we'll get a message up here.
This road should disappear from this table and it should get added to this table for problem services.
So that'll be quite a few steps before we can make that happen.
But let's get started.
But before I forget, let's change it so that when I roll my my mouse over this check now button, it
actually changes to a pointer because that's a little more attractive and a little more useful in terms
of visual feedback.
And it's really easy.
So let's go to our hosts file.
And at the very top, I'm just going to create a new class called Pointer, a new CSS class, and all
it's going to give us is the cursor.
Is pointer, and then when I go down to my pending tab, which is way down here, there's pending where
I have spane class badge, badge, BGU Secondary or B.G. Secondary.
We'll just add a pointer to this when we go back to here and reload this page and go to the pending
tab.
Now, when I roll over this, it should change to a pointer and it does.
OK, so let's get started on the actual code to make this happen.
And if you recall, I wrote some comments, so underperformed checks don't go.
I have a bunch of comments here.
Get the whole service.
I know I have to do that.
I may have to get the host.
I'm not sure yet.
Then I want to test the service that I want to create an actual Jason file with the appropriate data
in it and send the response back.
So this will be the Jason that we're going to create.
So I'll just move it up here underneath the appropriate comment.
And let's look at the first step, get the host service.
Well, I'm pretty sure if I look at my repository repository, Dongo, I actually don't have a method
that gets a host service yet.
So we need to go right that.
So I will open up a repository DB repo host, underscore PostgreSQL Dot to go or create a new function
func and it'll have the receiver of type pointer to postgrads DB repo and I will call it get host service
by idea and it will take one parameter ID, which is an ID and it will return a model, a model staut
host service and potentially an error.
OK, so as I usually do, I'm going to come up here and copy my contacts code so I don't make a typographical
error and I'll paste it in here and we want to write a query.
So query is assign the value of and let's go look at our database and make sure we get all the appropriate
columns.
So connect to localhost, go to my localhost, find vigilante, and we're looking at host services right
here and we'll look at the structure of that.
So I want to get the idy, the host idy in the service idee, OK?
Select.
And I'm going to use an alias, thought I'd start poster ID, service ID and I'm using an alias because
I'm going to join the services table in a moment.
Active schedule, no schedule unit and just not active.
Hey, just up schedule no.
And on the next line extorts schedule unit and then last check and status created out and updated at
last check.
I've got to put the house in there.
His status has created at HHS, updated at.
And I'm not going to put a couple of blank lines in there from hosting services.
Yes, and then I'm on a left join services s on escort service ID equals Estcourt ID.
And then I'll need to wear clause where ID equals dollar, sign one, and up here I want to join the
services table, so I'm going to definitely get the ID, Estcourt ID and let's go see what else is in
the services table.
Service name, active icon, escort service name escort, active as icon and create an updated ESTA
created at and updated app.
So let's just make sure this query works.
I'm going to copy this.
See what I have in the host services table.
And the content is I have one with an idea of one, so let's just make sure this query works the way
we want it to and change this to a one and execute.
Perfect.
OK, so that query is correct.
Now we need to create a variable sort of type models, dot host service in order to hold this information.
Then we query our database row, assign the value of IMDB, dot, query, row, context, query, row
context and in our context hender a query and handed ID and then we scan.
This error is assign the value of Rodon scan and we just scan into our newly created variable and present
ID and I'll duplicate that a bunch of times.
So HSR ID, host ID, service ID.
And next comes active.
Active.
And then schedule no, and I'm not using all this stuff, but I might use this query somewhere else,
so I may as well get all the information right now.
Schedule unit.
Last check and a few more duplications.
Status.
Created at.
Updated that and a few more duplications.
I've worked into the service now, so service dot ID and I'll delete these and duplicate this just to
avoid some more typographical errors.
So after service Erevia service name.
Then we get active.
Then we get Ikon and created and updated at.
Now we'll check for an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll just return and the error and
along the error to.
Logged print line error, and if everything worked, we get past this and we just return our panel.
OK, so let's copy this.
Signature go to our repository.
And pasted in here.
Perfect.
Now we go back to our perform checks and now we can actually get the hose service, so I'll create a
new variable X and error, and that is a sign the value of repo DB get host serviced by ID.
And what I want here is host service ID, which I grab from the parameter right up here.
So let's make sure this works by checking for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, all I do is logged up print line error and return.
And again, you're going to use more robust error checking in actual code and then just to make sure
this works, let's just say log print line service name is and we should be able to get that from service
dot service name.
And if that works, I know my database query is working and giving information back to my handler.
So I will stop my application, start my application.
He returned a few times, go back to my Web browser, reload this, go to the pending tab and click
on check now.
So this came back all right.
And in my log file, service name is HTP.
That is exactly what I'm looking for.
OK, so that step is done in the next step.
We we may not have to get the host.
I'm going to leave that comment there for now and in the next lecture will write some code that actually
tests the service.