So we're at the point now where we actually want to test the service and I have this one comment here
that says Get hosed, questionmark.
And the more I think about it, the more I know I'm going to need the host.
So let's get the host.
And we already have a database method for that.
And I'll just call the variable H for host.
And we're checking for an error.
And our method in the database is repo DB get hosted by ID and we have the host ID right in our host
service so I can just go start host ID and again we'll check for an error and I'll just copy and paste
this and I'm going to stop at some point telling you that you'll do more robust error checking because
I know you know that by now.
So now I want to test the service and I know I'm going to be testing the service for more than one place.
So I'm not going to write the code in here.
Instead, I'll come down here and write a new function func and I'll give it the the repo and I'll call
it a test service for post.
And that will take two parameters.
It'll take the host, which will be of models host and it will take the host service, which will be
of type models.
DOT hosts service.
And I think I'll have that return more than one thing, but I'm not sure what is going to return yet
right now, so I'll just leave that empty for the moment and I'll copy this name up from here and I'll
just call that function.
Now, it's going to return something in a moment, but I'm not sure what it's returning yet.
So instead, I'll just put in the H for the host NHS, for the host service.
And of course, because this is in the repository, it has to go repo test host for a test service for
host.
And I've started that with a lowercase letter because I'm never going to call this function outside
of this package and giving it a first character.
Being lowercase means it's not visible outside of this package.
So let's go down here and see how we're going to do this.
Now, this function is going to test any kind of service, and right now we just have one.
But chances are we're going to have more than one as time goes on, we're definitely going to have at
least two in this course.
So at the top of this package, I'm going to define a few constants just to make things more readable.
OK, so we will define a constant, more than one constant, actually.
And I'm going to, first of all, put in the kinds of things I want to test.
So I will call HTP will have the value of one.
And that's our one service that we're testing right now.
So we'll leave it like that for right now.
And as we add more services to test, we'll come in here and put more service or more Constance's to
reflect those services.
So, for example, we might test for an SSL certificate
and that will be equal to two or make it three.
We might also test for HDP s, which will be equal to two.
So right now we're only going to use this one.
But I'll define these two just to show you how you can have more services defined in your constants.
So back down in this this function right here, when I actually test a service, let's think about the
kinds of things we want to return.
We want to return.
Whether the service has changed, say, from spending to problem, which will be the case when we actually
run this code for the first time or the service has not changed.
We want to send back to things.
We want to send back the new status, and we want to send back also some kind of message.
So let's define two variables var MSG and new status, both of which will be strings.
And maybe that's what we're going to return.
So we'll return a string and a string.
OK, so back up here, I can actually say we're going to return a new status and we're going to get
back from this function.
Also some kind of message and those will come from here.
OK, so we're not using those right now.
So just to make this compile, I'll say logged up print line, new status and message.
OK, so now we're back down in our test service for host.
And as I said, I'm not sure what kind of service this is going to be testing AM right now because there's
just one.
But as time goes on, we'll have more than one service to check.
So maybe I'll just try to switch statement switch and we're going to switch on escort service ID.
What kind of service are we getting?
And what we want to do here, of course, is check for the first one.
Our first case will be HTTP, which is the constant we've defined just a moment ago.
And when I'm checking that, I want to get two variables, a message and I want to get the new status.
From somewhere now, I could write all of the code necessary to check the TV service right in here,
but I'm not going to I like to keep things small and simple.
So instead of will a new function and I'll call it test HTP for host and one on a pass in there is the
domain name, and I need to get that.
And that's why I'm passing the models host in this variable.
If you look in the database, what we're checking here is our new URL, which is stored in the host
table under you, Earl.
So back here I can say test this URL.
OK, and once we've done that test, we'll just break.
We don't need a semicolon.
So this, of course, means that I need to return something.
I'll return the the message in the new status, and I'm returning those.
In what order?
New status and message.
OK, so message and news status don't need the sign, that's better now we need to create this function
and that's pretty simple.
We'll just create a funk call that it takes one message or one one parameter, the URL, which is a
string, and it returns a string and a string.
Now, testing HTP Engo is absolutely simple.
It is dead simple.
It is in other languages too.
But I really like the way that happens here.
But there are a couple of things I want to check.
So I'm getting this URL.
First thing I want to check is that to make sure that it doesn't have a trailing slash because that
will cause problems when we we actually run the test.
So I will make sure that the string doesn't have the suffix of a slash and that's really easy.
If strings has suffix and the string I want to check is Yoro and I'm looking for a trailing slash if
it has that just stripped that off.
So you arrow equals strings, dot, trim suffix.
And I'm looking for the string which is Yoro and I'm on a trip off trim off the slash.
The second thing I want to make sure is when people enter the URL, they might have entered it as http
s colon slash slash.
But I don't want to test that.
I'm not testing https.
That will be a second test.
Instead, I'm checking for port 80 or so.
Let's make sure that we don't have an HTP at the beginning and again, we can just use a strings package.
Eurail equals string's replace.
Are you, Earl, we're looking for HTP Collins and we want to replace it with HTP Colon's and we want
to do that everywhere now.
It'll only occur once, but minus one will take care of it for us and we do require that parameter.
So now we have our correct URL.
It's been sanitized so we can actually run our test.
And it's dead simple to do that.
We get a response.
We also potentially get an error and we get that from the package and we're just going to do a get request
to where you are.
So we check for an error.
If the error is not equal to nil, then what do we want to do?
Well, we want to return the actual information that we have.
So those are return.
And I'm going to use format as Pranav.
And I want to return a string followed by a hyphen followed by another string, and the first part of
the string is nothing more than our URL, and the second part is our connecting.
And then we also want to return the actual message, and if we look down here, we're returning up here,
we're looking for where is the test, a message and a new status.
What's our new status?
And our status is going to be a status problem.
So we just put problem.
All right, now we've opened that response, so we've got that response from HDB get and one of the
things you're going to want to do and you're not going to want to forget this is to close that when
you're done with it.
And we use that do that using the defer key word.
So after this function finishes executing respawn body, don't close.
Otherwise you're going to have a memory leak.
And those sometimes can be pretty hard to find.
So assuming that we don't have an error here that we've actually connected, we want to check the status
code.
And if it's not 200, which is status, OK, then we're returning a problem.
So we just say if resp dot.
Status code, which is available to us right from that request, if that's not equal to and I could
put two hundred like that, but I actually prefer to use the status, OK, because it's more readable
and that's just a constant defined in the package.
It's equal to two hundred.
So that makes it more readable.
If this is not the case, if we don't get a status two hundred we can return and I'll just copy this
and paste it in here and we'll say the same thing, our euro.
But instead of er connecting I'll actually put in what we got here, which is respawn status and that's
a strength.
And again we're returning a problem and if everything else is OK, then we can just paste in our return
again, get rid of the error connecting and put in respawn status.
Which is a string, and this time our status is healthy and that should work, we should be able to
do this now.
We want to test this to make sure it's actually going to work.
So let's make sure we've got everything right.
We're getting our new status and our message from test service for host, and then we're lugging that
just so we can compile.
So when I run this test right now, if I start my application and start it, what should happen when
we click?
This is it should call this test check, check function.
It should print this out into the log our host service ID and our old status.
What we're checking, we should get our host service that we print at our service name.
We get our host and then we call this test service.
And what we should get back is our new status, which will not be that it's healthy or pending.
It should come back with a new status and a message that tells us there's a problem with this, with
this particular server we're checking, and that's because it doesn't exist.
So let's run our code.
He return a few times, come back to our Web browser, reload this, go to the pending page, clear
the JavaScript console to make sure that there's no errors and we have no messages yet.
So that's good.
Now, let's run our test.
And it's giving back to Jason because we didn't change the Jason we're sending back, we'll do that
in a moment.
But the actual message is problem localhost.
That's our euro area connecting.
That's exactly what I wanted to have happen.
Perfect.
So when you think about it, all we need to do here is to change the Jason that we're sending back.
So we need to actually modify this instead of being hard coded to actually return useful information
that we can deal with in our JavaScript on our client site.
And we'll get started on that in the next lecture.