So we still have a few more things to do before this check now Button does exactly what we want.
So right now I click on it and I get my hardcoded Jason response.
And the very first thing we want to do is to actually send back meaningful information rather than hard
coded dummy information.
So let's get started with that.
So I'll go back to my Idy and I'm in the performed checks go file and I'm at the test check method in
that file.
So let's scroll down here.
Here we have this create Jason and all we need to do is to modify this Jason.
So it actually gets the information we're sending back.
So if we look at the things we expect to find here, we want OK, message service ID host, we want
all this stuff.
What I'm going to do is just delete this entirely and just help my ID, help me out.
RESP is assigned the value of Jason RESP and I want to fill all the fields and I'll delete the ones
that I don't need if necessary.
OK, so, OK, all right, now that is been hard coded to true and what we're doing in here, of course,
is this OK, I should actually respond with whether or not the the check actually passed, not that
it gave back the appropriate response, but that nothing went wrong while we're doing this.
So what I really should do to make that work properly is to actually set a variable up here that says,
OK, give it a default of true and then set it defaults.
If I have an error here and set it defaults.
If I have an error here, test the service and if it fails, there again said it defaults.
And then down here, if false is set to true send back faults and the error message so we can do that.
So let's come up here and say, OK, is a sign the value of true.
And down here we can say instead of log print line error return, we can just say OK, equals false.
And the same thing here, OK, equals false.
And then down here we can just check, we can create a variable called the rest, which is of type JSON
resp.
Change this to an equals instead of an a sign and say if, OK, we'll do this or else we just redefine
response to say resp dot equals false.
And rasped message equals I'll just put something went wrong.
And down here, we're returning that variable as Jason, so that would work fine, so all we need to
worry about here is what's the message?
Well, the message we're getting right here from testing the service.
So that's message the service ID.
We know what that is, escort service ID, the host service ID, we know what that is.
HHS ID, the host ID is host I.D. The old status was passed right to this function I believe.
Yeah.
So we've got old status so we can set that to old status, the new status.
And again, we get that from right here, new status.
And the last check is just the current time, time, we can just say that's time now.
OK, so that should send back the correct Jason, let's find out.
So we'll stop our application.
Start our application.
It return a few times, just so if we have a log file that's in error, we'll see it here, go back
to Firefox, reload this page, clear the console, go to our spending tab and see what we get back.
Check now.
And what we get is, OK, true error connecting, so it gave us the correct information.
Let's look at the network and see what it actually gave us back here.
Well, we'll just click it again there, so there and look at the response.
What what did it give us for response, it gave us everything we wanted, it gave us the air connecting
the service.
I'd absolutely correct.
OK, so that we know actually works.
So back in here, is there anything else we need to do?
Well, in fact, there is we've performed this check and everything seems to be working properly.
And I can get rid of these things right now.
So they don't need these log files anymore, these log print lines anymore.
So let's clean that up.
At this point, before I send the Jason response, there's some other information I want to keep track
of, quite possibly at the bare minimum, I want to update the last check field in the host status tables.
So we go back to our database and we look at how services we have this last check field.
And that's even if I refresh this, that's never been updated.
That's my default value that I stick in the database when I created this record the very first time
around.
But of course, I just did a check.
It was a manual check.
So this should be updated.
Absolutely.
And if the status has changed from pending to problem, which it just did, this should be updated as
well.
So I definitely need to do more things at a bare minimum.
Before I send this Jason response, I want to update the Postal Service in the database with status
if changed and last check.
So I definitely want to do that now.
This is a manual test, so I'm actually not going to send an email notification or a text notification.
So I don't need to worry about that.
But I do want one other thing to take place.
And of course, that is when this status changes, as it just did, this row should be taken off the
pending table and it should be added to this table.
Now, I could do that if I wanted to write in the host OzJet, no problem at all.
I definitely could do that, but I'm not going to instead, I'm going to do that using WebSocket.
And the reason is because this is, of course, about WebSocket and also because I don't want to write
JavaScript for every page, any time a check takes place.
I just want to have that handled automatically behind the scenes.
So what I need to do here at some point and not right now, but we'll get to it eventually is broadcast
service status changed event?
OK, and the last thing I want to do is when this changes.
I need to get a message up here and that's really easy.
So let's go back to our host file.
And down here, when we get a response, let's not just console log it, OK?
I said we'll say first of all, we'll check to make sure that things are OK if DataDot OK, so if we
got an OK and the check actually performed, we can do something of the result or else we want to have
an error.
And what I'm going to do here is just say error alert, something went wrong, OK?
And of course you can put whatever message you want in here.
You can pass that as part of the JSON.
But for our purposes, we'll just say something went wrong.
But if something went right, if the status changed or if the check went and we got a result back,
we need to give some kind of meaningful notification to the end user.
And I have built into this starter code a little JavaScript module, which I've called attention, and
I'm going to use that.
And it's just a really nice way of doing things.
So let's just see how it works.
So I'm just going to say, if data OK, and I'm going to broadcast or not broadcast, I'm going to put
up a little message that gives some message back to the user.
I'm going to do that by calling attention, which is built into my code.
The code that you have right now.
And I'm going to call the toast method, OK?
And that requires a few parameters.
So it needs a message, which I'll just put as message is assigned to data or gets the value of data
message because I think I called it message.
No, I called m e s s.
I think we'll find out in a minute.
We'll give it an icon, which I'll just say is info.
And it needs a timer.
How long do I want this to stay, this little toast to stay up there and I'll leave it up for sixty
thousand milliseconds so a little while and show close button.
And these are just parameters that determine how long this thing will show up.
OK, so let me save this.
Save this.
Go back to my page here.
Reload it, go back to my console.
So I'll bring up my JavaScript console, clear this, go to my pending page here and say, check now.
And it's just going to give me a dummy value for the moment.
And there it is, error connecting.
So that's exactly what I wanted to see show up.
And it's got a nice little close button here.
OK, so let's see what we want to do rather than just putting up this, didn't this this default message,
we can actually make a determination.
We can say little things like what was the old status and what's the new status?
So I can say if DataDot old status is not equal to exactly equal to DataDot new status, then do something.
Otherwise, if the status is changed, we're going to do something else.
OK, so let me copy this or cut it out of here and I'll paste it in twice, once here and once here
if the status has changed.
And I think I called that old status a new status.
Let's just make sure.
Old status and new status, yes, I did.
If the status has changed, then I want to give an info and I want to give the message and show the
close button else.
If it stayed the same, I can just say message rather than data message.
I can say a service is still in and put a space there plus and the status will be the old status or
the news status because they've not changed at all.
So I'll just say data, new status
state.
OK, and I can leave it as maybe a shorter timer because it's not really a problem.
I can leave it up for five seconds.
OK, so let's reload this and go to pending and it actually should display the same thing it did last
time.
But I should get no errors in the JavaScript console.
Check now.
Perfect.
OK, so that's actually working the way that I want.
Now the last thing we want to do here and we won't do it, this lecture will do it.
The next one is where's my comments, perform checks.
Right here, I want to update the host service in the database with a status, if it's changed, we
want to update that and we definitely want to update the last check.
So there's no question we want to make an update in the database.
So if we look at a repository, do we have a method that allows me to update a host service?
I have one for updating post service status.
Is that enough?
Let's go look at it.
Update host service status, so this will update host services, no, that's just going to do the active.
So what I want to do is create a new method that will allow me to just generically update anything in
a host service.
And we want to call that and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.