So we need to write a more general function to update any of the fields in our host services table,
so I'm in my host underscore PostgreSQL go file.
And as I said last time, we already have one that updates a host service, but it just updates the
active status.
But I can use that as a starting point by copying and pasting it and just changing the name to update
post service and fix the comment, updates the post service updates, a host service and the host service.
Now it's a EHO service in the database.
And we're not going to take three cents, we will take a IHSS, which is a type model host service,
and will return an error, if any.
So all that's going to change here.
Let's just delete this part time.
And I'll just update this query, so we want to update his services and I'll have it in and we want
to set not just active, we'll fix those in a moment.
Where?
Host where ID equals and get I don't know what the dollar sign is going to be, so I'll just leave it
empty for a moment.
OK, so we want to set.
And get rid of this, I up with the set up there.
And we're going to fix what fields or update what fields, I'm going to put them all in there because
I may use this same method at some point later or in the future.
So let's go to post Toco.
We have Idy Hoshide inservice.
We don't care about IDs or host IDs, service ideate active.
So host I.D. equals dollar sign one service ID equals dollar sign to active equals dollar sign three.
I'll go to the next line.
After activity of schedule number and schedule unit schedule number equals dollar sign for schedule
unit equals dollar sign five.
Then last check and status.
Last check equals dollar sign, six status equals dollar sign seven and updated X equals dollar sign
eight.
Which makes this night so let's just fix our query or exit context statement to say we want to get this
from HFS dot and the first one is posted.
Now, duplicate this a few times, service ID active.
Schedule No.
Schedule unit and duplicate that again and again and again.
Last check.
Status.
And update it up and the last thing is ID and make sure that everything's going correct here, perfect.
OK, now we could, of course, just get rid of this method altogether and use this one instead, and
it would work just fine.
But this isn't hurting anything, so I'll leave that there.
So I'll copy the signature of this method or this function and put it in my repository, paste it in
here and I'll go back to my perform checks.
And this is the point right here where I want to update the whole service in the database with status
if changed and last check.
And as you know, we already have the hoster service.
We grabbed it right here and we already have the new status and we know the time that it's going to
change.
It's just time now.
So I can simply say dot status equals new status.
Just set that value.
HSA updated at equals time now because this is when we're doing it and call this new function error
as a sign the value of repo DB update host service right here and hand it my HS because I just overwritten
the values I pulled from the database with this information and just check for an error.
So I'll copy this and paste it right here and that should do it.
So let's stop our database or application.
I guess mine's not running.
I'll clear it.
I'll run my application.
And this should work and what should happen when I go back to my Web browser and reload this page and
I guess I have to log in again, so I'll organize it mean at example, dot com with the password of
password and save that or login.
So now when I go to my hosts and I go to my problems or pending when I check now, it should update
everything in the database.
Now I'll get a message up here.
Nothing else will change on the screen.
But when I go back to overview, I should see a problem service here and no pending service here.
Let's see if we got it right.
So pending.
And it says air connecting and nothing else changed on this page, and that's OK, because I'm going
to change the contents of this page using Web sockets in a little while.
But I should be able to go to overview and see that now I have a problem service and now I have no pending
services.
And when I go to localhost and I look at spending, it should be gone.
And it is.
And if I look at problems, it's here now.
And this is exactly what I want.
Now, I have some things to clean up on this screen and these other two tabs as well.
I need to format the date properly.
And actually my last check.
Let's go look at the database.
Last check.
Oh, because I did an update.
That was silly.
Let me go back here.
I make these mistakes all the time and so will you.
So I need to go back to my form check.
And here it's not just updated at its last check.
That's equal to time now as well.
You notice that, didn't you?
And you're laughing at me right now, aren't you?
That's OK.
I've been left up for.
So let's stop this, start this.
And I should be able to get that field update just by doing the check on the same screens.
Let me reload the page, go to problems, check now and again.
It didn't change on this page because I'm going to do that using Web sockets.
But if I reload this page, last check should now have the correct value in it, and it does.
So we need to format the this page a little bit better and we can do that really quickly right now.
And I'll do one tab and you can do the rest at your leisure because it's fairly straightforward.
Let's go to Chad and I'll hide my menu, split my screen just so I can see things a little better.
I'll find the pending part, which is right here.
And this is the kind of change I want to make in problems.
So let's go to problems.
This is just so I can see things a little more easily.
I do this all the time and you probably do, too.
So this is going to have the badge secondary.
It's also going to have the pointer class and let's copy these and replace that in that is last check
so I can delete this and paste it in there.
OK, and I think that's it for that.
Now I have the service icon, so let's get the service icon, copy that, and that goes before the service
name.
And I want to come back here and reload this page and look at problems there.
That all looks a little bit better.
Still don't have a message here right now.
And I may drop this column altogether because it's not terribly useful information at the moment.
But when I first started doing it, I thought maybe I'll have a message.
I'm not sure that it's going to make it to the very last version of this code, but I'll leave it there
for the moment.
So you'll probably want to do the same thing, just kind of take the same content and also put it in
the warning services and put it in the healthy services modified as necessary.
And I'll leave that as an exercise for you.
I'll do it myself after a record this lecture, and it'll be available to you on the source code for
this lecture.
But it's pretty straightforward and I don't think you need to watch me making those changes.
OK, so we'll pick it up in the next lecture.