So we have some database tables for our hosts, for our services and for our host services, and now
we need to create some forms that will allow us to enter some information into the database.
So I'm looking at the application which is running right now.
And if I go to the hosts button and then click on, there's nothing listed here.
Of course, this is where our hosts will be listed.
Once we have some in the database, I don't want to click on the new host button and that takes me to
an empty page.
And the empty page has a breadcrumb at the top and then a place for content underneath.
And here's where I want to put my form.
And the form I want to put there is actually going to be a TABD page.
I'll use bootstraps tabs to create a page that has a host tab that will just give the basic information
about the host, the managed services that will allow us to list the services and add or delete any
services we want to monitor then one tab for each of the possible statuses.
So a healthy tab, warning problems and pending.
And each of those tabs will list services that we're monitoring that are in one of those states.
So all the healthy will show up and are healthy and so on.
So let's get started doing that.
So I'm going to go over to my ID and this is the host page hosted Jet and it's found inside The View's
folder.
So inside of that, in this content area, I'm going to I'm going to create a new div and it'll be a
div of class row.
And inside of that I'll create a div of class call.
And this is where our content is going to go.
Now I know I want to TABD page and if you go back to the application, I already have a tab page.
I have one here for settings that has general notification, so on and so forth.
So what I'm going to do is open up the settings page and just copy this part that creates the tabs for
me just to save some typing.
So I'll go back to host Jet and I'll just paste that right in here and then I'll modify this as necessary.
So it's not for settings, it's for host.
And the first part is not general, it is the host.
So I'll call this the host tab.
The second one is for managed services, so I'll call it the service tab and it will go to the service
content and this will go to the host content.
And this is referring to Divs that don't exist yet.
But we'll get to those in a moment.
Then I'm going to have my healthy tab.
So for healthy services and I'll call this healthy.
And I'll get rid of the icon, because I don't need that.
And to have an icon up here now, it looks OK, so healthy can be that one, and that will go to healthy
content and then we'll have warning.
And again, I don't need an icon for that, so I'll delete that little tag there, and this is for warning.
Warning.
That looks right, so after warning, we'll have problem services, so a copy and paste and this will
be for problem tab.
Problems.
Problem content.
And the last one is for pending, and that will be the pending tab for pending.
Pending.
I think that's it.
So none of those divs exist yet, which is not a problem, let's just go see what the page looks like.
So go back to Host's new host.
And there now we have some tips and we can put some content in each of those.
So underneath that, if you look back at the settings page, we're going to have a div class equals
tab content, which I'll copy and put that underneath the URL and it has to have a closing tag.
So we'll put a closing tag in now and reformat that and then back to settings to see how this works.
So inside of that we have a debate div class equals content.
So put that in there.
It's a tab pain and we'll close that and that has to have the correct you URL or ID and right now it
doesn't.
It's labeled by the very first tab, which is called Host Tab.
And it's I.D. is host content, so now a copy that.
It host content.
Host Hebb host content that is good, why do I have a oh, so I copied the wrong thing here.
Let me go back to settings.
Post content.
All right.
Host Tab's host KAB contest there, just give it a different idea and see if that works host Tab's.
That looks good.
OK, so I have this and let's just make sure it works by putting the word host content in here.
Then we'll copy this and paste it one, two, three, four, five times.
But first of all, post it once and get rid of active.
And the second one, does it have a show on it, I can't remember.
No, it doesn't.
OK, so we'll get rid of the show here, so the second one is for services content and it's labeled
by services tab.
Now, I can paste this as many more times as I need to, and it looks like I need one, two, three,
four more taps.
OK, so this will be services content paste two, three, four.
And the last one was pending.
Pending.
Pending tab.
Is there an extra tab in there?
Problem TEB.
Problem, problem.
And then it was warning.
Warning.
Warning tab and get rid of all these extra tabs.
And this one is healthy.
And this should be healthy and we will spell warning, right, since I'm here anyway.
All right, let's save this and make sure that we get everything right.
So I should see content under all of these casso managed services.
Didn't work healthy does morning does problem does pending does.
So the one that's not working is managed services.
Let's see what we got wrong with that one.
Managed services.
I got an extra tab in there.
OK.
Tap safe.
So now these tabs should all work.
They're not pretty yet, but we'll make them pretty in a moment.
Those reload, this still not working services TAB services content.
Services content.
There you go to get your I.D. matched up for the tabs, just don't work, and just so you know, the
way the tabs are built here is using the bootstrap alpha version, which happened to be the version
of bootstrap that was built into this template.
You may have the final version of bootstrap depending on a bootstrap five, depending on when you're
taking this course.
But just look at the documentation or use the alpha version that worked fine for the purposes of this
course.
This is, of course, about WebSocket, and we're just going through the steps necessary to get to the
point where we can work with WebSocket.
OK, so now we need to put a form in here and put the form, first of all, in this part.
So let's put it in a div class equals row and a div class equals call.
So we'll have rows and columns within this tab and inside of this will put our form and I'll put the
form tag in in a little bit.
Right now I just want to get the elements in there, so I'm going to have this in two calls.
So instead of a div class call, I'll say div class call MDX and call excess 12.
So if you're hitting it on a phone, everything will appear in one column.
But if you're on something bigger than a phone, then you'll get the two columns just to make the make
better use of screen real estate.
So let's put it in our first form control.
So let's first of all, look at our database to see what our very first piece of information is.
So I'm looking at the vigilante database at the host table ID.
I don't need to worry about that, but I definitely want to hostname, so I need to put it in a text
input.
So I'll put in a div class equals EMB three just to give it some padding on the bottom.
Then I'll put it a label and it will be four.
And the very first column was called Hostname.
So I'll call the same thing here.
Hostname and I will put in a class of form control which are supposed to.
And the label will be hosting them and then we'll put our input in input, Heidi, equals hostname name
equals host name value equals I'll leave that empty will populate that with information from the database
and a bit.
But we need to get it first and then we'll have its type is text.
And its class is equal to form control, form text.
No firm control.
Yeah, form control and this one's wrong is supposed to be formed, labeled.
OK, let's see how that looks back to our our Web browser and go to the host and reload.
And there probably need a little bit of space at the top here.
So let's put some space at the top as well.
Merge and top three.
Let's see how that looks.
Reload, that looks better.
OK, so I have one place to enter information right here for the hostname.
What's next back and look at our database after the hostname.
We have the canonical name.
OK, so let's just go back and make things really easy.
We'll copy this.
Paste it in here.
We don't need to merge in top on this one.
And this is canonical name.
Canonical name.
Which I will copy and paste and paste and changes to canonical name.
OK, that should look OK and it does.
And the third element is after canonical name is Earl.
So let's copy this.
Paced, and this is just called you URL, so copy paste, paste and get rid of this and put your URL
and the next one is the IP address and then IP version six.
So paste, paste, and this is for IP, IP address, version for.
IP, IP.
IP and did I have an underscore in the name, I can't remember no IP Version six copy paste, paste,
IP
address, version six.
And again, we may not use that, but we may and we may as well put it in there.
So then location OS and active and I'll put those in another column just to make this a little more
attractive.
So we have a call here and I'll close this, call them off and then I'll create another call.
Div class equals call MMD six, call excess 12.
Just so things are in two columns and location is the next one.
So let's put paste that in here and I'll just put a blank space in there to make it a little more readable
location.
Location, copy paste.
Paced and this does want the padding at the top, so, um, empty three, I think is what I used.
Let's see how that looks.
Now, that's looking good so far.
OK, operating system, I think is next operating system and then active.
So let's put it in an operating system.
And I'll just copy this one.
Right here.
And this is operating system, which I called os, os, os operating system.
And that should look good, looks OK, and the last bit we want is an active right here and I'm not
going to use a dropdown box, I'll use a toggle kind of like this monitoring one right here, OK, just
because it's more attractive.
So that comes right after operating system.
I want a div class equals form check.
Form switch, and this is just a nice thing built into bootstrap five, that gives us an attractive
toggle which looks better than a radio button or a checkbox or something like that.
So we put an input in their class equals form check input.
Type is a checkbox.
And the I.D. will be active.
And the name will be active, which are better spelled right?
And then we put our label after it, label class equals form, check that out, get rid of that check
label.
Four equals active.
And active.
OK, so I might have to put an emergent top in there.
Let's just go see what it looks like first.
It looks OK.
I think I can live with that.
OK, so there's a place to enter some information about our actual hosts.
So let's put a form tag around this whole thing and I will put a form tag around the whole tab list
just in case I have form elements on other pages.
I don't think I will, but if I ever want to in the future, it'll just save me.
Reformatting this entire page subform method equals post.
Our action will be exactly the same as the world to this page.
So that will be slash.
Let's go look at the URL slash admin slash host slash the idea of the host so I don't have the idea
of the host right now, so I'll just put zero in there admin.
Post and I'll put zero in there.
And I do want validation on this form and I'll use bootstraps validation, and that requires that I
put no validation here and to give it a class of needs validation.
And we'll give it an ID ID equals host form, so that's my opening tag there.
I don't want to close it straight away.
I'll close it right after the last panel, which would be right here and format everything.
And if I go back here and reload, the only thing missing right now is a save button.
Well, I already have one on the settings page, so let's just copy that one.
Down the bottom somewhere here, there's a safe.
I'll just search for safe.
There it is.
OK, so I will copy this.
And I'll put the counsel in there as well and go back to my host page and after the forum closes, where
do I want this save button?
I think I just want it on the first tab.
So that would be right here.
And I have a row.
So close that row, open a new row after that div class equals row, div class equals call and paste
that in there and maybe I'll put a
horizontal rule before it.
OK, so is there anything in that I need to do in there?
No, not right now.
Of course this is calling JavaScript.
That doesn't exist yet, but let's just see what it looks like.
Save, save and close saving.
Continue and cancel.
Perfect and cancel.
Shouldn't take us back to admin overview.
You should take us back to host.
So let's reload this.
And there is no House page, so what what did I call that admin host, all admin host, all save.
Let's go to a new host and now cancel.
Should take me back to the previous page.
And it does.
All right.
So there we have our forum built.
Now we need to actually write some handlers that will either pull a host out of the database and display
it on this page with all of these things pre populated or to create an empty hosts object and pass it
to this page so we know we're creating a new host and leave these empty.
And then the next step will be to create the database handlers and database functions and the handlers.
So when I click this button saving continue or save and close, it will actually validate the information,
populate the database and take us to some other page and we'll take care of that in the next lecture
or two.