So we have a form and we have a save button, but at the moment that save button doesn't work because
it's calling JavaScript that doesn't exist.
So you find the save button, which is right.
Where is it?
Here it is, we need two functions, save and close and VAO and both of those validate the form and
one will save the the form and take us back to the same page.
That's the saving continue.
And the other one is save and close, which will save the form and then take us somewhere else, presumably
back to the host's list list of hosts or something like that.
So let's create those Java scripts.
And just to save some time here on the Settings page, I already have two functions that seem to do
pretty much what I want.
So I'll copy those and I'll go back to the KOSTJA and I'll go down to the JavaScript section here,
the Block Jazz, and I'll put it in a script tag and I'll paste those two functions in.
And they're both colling settings form.
But that's not what we called our form.
We called our form.
I think it was host for the host form.
So let's just change that to host form.
And down here, host form.
And I'm not going to worry about this, check all tabs.
I'll leave that on there for right now, it's not going to hurt anything.
OK, so let's go back and reload this page and think about what we need to have as required items.
I definitely want to have a hostname as a required field, and I definitely want the canonical name
and I definitely want the URL.
Everything else should be optional.
Active by default will have some value.
So I don't need to worry about that.
So let's go back to our form and find those first three elements hostname and on the input I'll add
required and on the canonical name I will also add required and on the URL I will add required.
So hopefully when I come back here and reload this page and try to save and continue, for example.
Nothing happens.
Let's look at our JavaScript console and see what we have wrong console, document, get out of it by
ID is not.
And where is that?
That's on this line.
All right, so let's find out what we have wrong here, so we say.
Document.
Oh, yeah, we have to have an action, OK, so when we call Val, that will set a hidden field name
action to a value of zero.
And when we call save and close, it will look for a hidden field called action and send it to one.
So let's just add the hidden field and we can put that right up at the top here after our form tag.
And we need another hidden field here, too.
Now that I think about it, input type, people's hidden.
We need our action, which I'll put a value of one and the idea is action.
And then we need a series of CSR token as well, CSR, SRF token and the value will be equal to and
this comes from the information we're passing to every template CSR F token.
And it doesn't need an I.D., so let's try that again, go back to our console and it looks like buy.
What are all these errors?
Oh, I have that IP running.
Let's go start that.
Here to open our tab, open a new terminal window.
IP, and that should start it for us and I want to come back to my browser and clear the console, that
error should go away.
OK, let's reload the page to make sure I have everything current and try save and close.
And that says we have three required fields.
Perfect.
So that validation works the way that we want.
Now just everything works the way we expect it to.
Let's go back to our roots file and create a root and a handler to actually handle the post of this.
So this is our route.
So let's copy that, open our roots file and find the part where we are logged in and find the part
where we go to host right there.
So let's duplicate that line and changes to a post and that's fine.
So we'll just change this to post host, which is something that doesn't exist yet.
But we can actually try this.
We can come over here, copy this.
Paste it down there, name it to post host and change the comment to post host post host.
Handles posting of post for their so post hosts and all we want to do here right now, I'm just going
to comment this out.
Try that again, comment this out and I'll just write that we have actually posted will say w dot write
an array of bytes.
Posted to form.
OK, so let's stop our application, start our application and make sure this actually works.
So we'll go back to our form, reload this to make sure it's current, put some values in here, doesn't
matter what they are and say, save and close.
And it posted the form.
Perfect.
So now we have a means of actually handling information that's posted.
The other thing that we want to take into account here is that when I render this form, if it's a new
form, it should just be empty.
But I still should have some information posted to this page, because if it's not a new host for pulling
something from the database, I need to have the necessary information to populate this form with the
information that's in the database and also to populate the content of all of these tabs.
So let's take care of that and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.