So we have this form right now, and it seems to work pretty well if we go look at the actual house
form, there it is.
And it the form displays properly are validation, appears to work properly.
So what we want to do now is to think about how we're going to handle hosts and this form when we're
creating a new host the very first time we display this form.
So this part right here before any validation has taken place.
Let me go back to the hosts and say new host.
We don't actually want these tabs to show up at all because there are no services for a host, because
there's no entry in the database right now.
We just want that first tab to show up.
So what we need to do is to make a decision when we're displaying this form, if it's a new host, don't
display these these tabs.
If it is an existing host, then do display these tabs and also populate this form with data.
So let's go back to our code and let's find our roots and let's find the route that displays a host.
And it's this one mux.
Get host some ID and it will be zero if it's a new host or it'll be the ID for that entry in the host
table if it's if it's an existing host and that's this handler.
So let's look at that right here.
All we're doing right now is rendering a page.
And what we want to do instead is to get the ID from the euro.
And that's pretty straightforward.
We can just say ID or potentially an error is equal to stir conv from the strings package.
Sture conv thought a twohy, and that will the stricken package will actually take our parameter and
which we get as a string and pass it to an aunt and we can get that from CZI dot get are you Earl Perram?
And that takes the request and it takes the key.
And the key is ID like this.
I think it's just ID.
Yeah that's it.
I'm going to ignore the error in this case.
Of course in production code you would want to handle any, any exceptions.
But in this case we're more concerned with WebSocket than we are with writing web applications.
So let's just see if we get that.
I will say log print line ID is and its ID.
Now, let's make sure that that's actually the ID from the roots.
Yeah, it's just ID, so I'll stop the application.
Start the application.
Hit return a few times, just so there's some blank lines there.
I'll go back to my Web browser and I will go to hosts and new host and in my log file, it says the
ID is zero.
But if I change that to, say, 10 and it return the ideas temp.
So we're getting the ID perfect.
So let's go back to her handler.
And let's make a decision here, I'll get rid of this log file, because I know that's working properly
will say if it is greater than zero, then I want to get the host from the database otherwise.
Put an else in there else, and what I want to do here is create an empty post.
Now I can do that really easily.
I can create the value right here.
I can save her host, which I'll call H and it's of type models host.
And down here, I need to get it from the database, if the ID is greater than zero, so I'll just use
the variable H in here and I'm not going to do that right now because the database function doesn't
exist at the moment.
Otherwise, I don't even need this because at this point I already have my H variable.
So now I need to pass some values to the to the template and I can do that by saying Vires is equal
to make jet var map.
And all I need to do is to add this to my my this, this variable to my verse.
So Verstraete set and the name will be host and the value is H and then I pass this variable Verve's
to my template right here.
So if we do this properly and we can, we can actually check this by saying, well I'll just put a value
in here.
So I will say H dot.
Hostname equals some host.
OK, so now I've created the variable, my ID will be zero when I display the page.
So this whatever is in here wouldn't get executed.
There's nothing in there now, so it doesn't matter anyway.
I'm setting the hostname to some host and I'm passing that to the template now in the template host
jet.
I actually want to display the hostname, so I'll get out of the part of the former.
I display the host name.
And what I want to do, first of all, is get that value from the template.
So all I have to do are for my template data.
So all I have to do is find the value and say that is equal to a hostname.
And that should work once I stop the application, start the application.
Go back to my application to my Web browser, choose hosts, choose new host, and I have what do I
have here?
Default variables, tax danger.
OK, there's something missing there.
Let's find that.
Handlers host jet, and the value I'm getting here is dot hostname.
Right, it's called host.
Let's go back here and reload this, and there it is, some host and I could do the same thing for everything
else.
Now, obviously, I don't want to have some name in there, so let me go back to my handler and get
rid of this line.
So the next thing to do is to make sure that the tabs only show up if for ID of greater than zero,
so we can do that really easily.
We can come in here and put in a statement.
We can say if post ID is greater than zero.
And down here, put an end and we'll just have this in so it's more readable and we'll copy this line
and we'll do the same thing with all of the other tips.
So that would be after this form.
Right here.
We're not going to have services or any of the other tabs if it's a new host, so I should be able to
have this image so it's more readable, save this and reload this page by going to host just to make
sure we're getting everything current, a new host, and now we just have the one tab.
And that's exactly what I want at this point.
So now that we have this form displaying properly for new hosts where there are no services yet, the
next step is to write the necessary database handler to insert a host into the database.
Take us back to this page and show those taps.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture.