So now we want to insert a host into the database and I'm looking at the host jet file and there's a
few changes I need to make to this.
First of all.
Right.
Here in the form method equals post action equals admin host zero.
I don't want that to be zero.
That's going to be the host side from the host variable that we're passing right here in the handler.
So host right here.
We get a we create an empty models host.
Then later on we're going to grab it from the database.
If it's it is greater than zero.
Otherwise we're passing an empty host.
So the ID will be whatever the ID of the model is, because we're storing it with a variable name host
here inversed set and in the host object, we can get access to that host variable just like this.
So that will give us the correct ID.
And the other thing we want to do is to populate all of the content of that form with whatever's in
that host variable.
Now we've done it here in host hostname.
We also want to get it in the canonical name.
So I'll post that in here and change that to canonical name and the euro will Paysite in here and that's
just set to you earlier.
And if I look at my models, I think I put it in all uppercase.
Yes, I did.
OK, and the same thing in the IP address, which is just called IP IP IP Version six.
Not sure what I call that.
Let's go find out.
IPV six, all caps, IPV six.
And the location is just called location, so we'll just put host dot location.
The operating system is OS, host OS and the switch.
This doesn't have a value right now and it probably should.
So we need to put an if statement in here are actually no we don't.
We can just say value equals host dot active and that of course has to be in quotation marks.
So we'll put a quotation marks around that and get rid of the extra quote and save that.
And this should all work.
Is my application running?
Yes.
I'm going to stop it and start it, just to be sure.
And I'll go back to my Web browser and I'll go right to the hosts page, click on New Host and this
should have the ID of zero in the action.
So let's look for action.
And it does.
It has zero there and everything else is exactly as it should be.
So now I want to fill this form out.
I want to grab the data and I want inserted into the database.
So we need to create a database function.
So let's go back to our code and let's go to the internal folder and then the repository folder and
look in the DB repo folder.
And inside of that, I'm going to create a new file.
And you go file, which I will call host Underscore Postgres Cual.
Don't go.
All right, so that creates a new one.
Yes, I want to add that to my repository.
So let's create a function and this is a database function.
And because it's a database using a repository, I actually pass it.
It has a receiver of I'll call it M Postgrads Postgres DB Repo, and this will be called insert host.
And it will take one parameter which I'll call H.
It's a type models host and it will return an event which will be the ID of the newly created record
and potentially an error.
OK, now, because this is a Web application, I tend to do this.
I use the contacts package and I'm going to create a variable called seatbacks and a variable called
Cancel and they will come from the contacts package.
And I want with time out because this is a web application and periodically things will go wrong.
Either the user will lose their connection to the Internet or they'll click cancel partway through a
transaction, whatever it is.
But I want it to time out after a while and we use the context with time out.
That method has two parameters.
The first one is just the background context, which is always available.
So context up background.
And the second one is how long do I want this to last?
Well, if it takes more than three seconds, then I want it to time out.
OK, so I've created that and now I need to defer the cancel.
In other words, when this function exits or three seconds past, get rid of the cancel.
So we'll defer the cancel.
And that's of course a function.
So we'll do it like that.
Now we wrote a query.
Query is just a variable I'm creating and that's a sign the value of insert into hosts and what we want
to insert.
Well, let's go look at our database again, which I think I still have running right here.
Yes.
I don't want to insert the ID that will be handled automatically.
I want hostname a canonical name, so hostname canonical name, canonical name and then it is you URL,
IP and IP version six you url ip IP Version six, which I didn't have an underscoring did I know location
was an active location OS active and finally created an updated app created at an updated app.
And then on the next line I will put values and because this is Postgres we have to have the dollar
sign placeholder.
So dollar sign.
One dollar sign, two dollar sign three.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
So I have a total of ten dollar sign for dollar sign.
Five dollar sign.
Six dollar sign.
Seven dollar sign.
Eight dollar sign.
Nine dollar sign ten.
And I want to return.
So returning the ID.
OK, so there's my query.
Now we need to create a new variable to store the ID that will become a successful insert.
I'll call that new ID and it'll be of type Int and now we just call our database.
Error is a sign the value of M which is my receiver and that has a member called DB and I want the method
built into DB called query row context and I pass it my contacts, which I created right up here in
the first line of this function and my query which I better spell.
Right, and then I'll put these on separate lines.
They're more readable, all the values, and these need to correspond to the same order that they're
called in the insert statement.
So the first one is H hostname and the second one is a canonical name and then short URL and then H
IP and then H IP version six H dot.
Location H os.
Not active, and then the last two older shoes, time now and then I'll duplicate that line, the current
time will be inserted into both created and updated.
So we do this and now we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then what do I want to do?
I want to log the error.
So logged our print line error and I want to return the new ID, which will have no value.
So it'll be zero.
And the error which is erm.
And I missed something here.
Oh, yes, I got to scan the I.D., I got a scan into my.
That and that will take care of it, because postgrads actually doesn't work the way that, say, if
you're familiar with Maria Debe or Maisky.
Well, it's a little different the way that you get the created ID.
But in postgrads, we need to Queretaro context and scan its return value into some variable, which
is what we're doing here.
And if I don't do that, it's not going to throw an error.
So now if we get past this, then all is well and we just return the new ID and nil for the error.
And let's give this a comment.
Inserts a host into the database now, because I'm using the repository pattern, which is a really
common one, and if you're not familiar with it, you should become familiar with it.
I actually have to add this method signature, this entire thing, the method name its parameters and
what it returns into this file repository.
Dacko So I'll create a new comment here posts and just paste that in.
Now if I stop the application and start it, I didn't need to do that yet, but I'm going to be doing
it in a minute so I may as well do it right now and go back to our handlers.
At this point, we want to insert a host into the database.
OK, so that means we need to read all the values from our post, put them into a model of type models,
dot host and then call our insert host function so we can create a new variable.
VAR hope for each is a type model host and we just start inserting values into it so we can say each
dot first name.
Actually let's do it this way first.
Let's make sure that we get the IDs up here in the previous function, which is host, we grab the ID
from the, from the URL and we're going to do the same thing right here.
OK, so now I have the ID and I'm going to do the same kind of logic I do up here.
If ID is greater than zero, get the host from the database.
So what I'll do is read the host from the database, then overwrite the values from the post into this
and then call an update method that doesn't exist yet.
So we can't do that.
Otherwise we'll just populate this model host, which has to come before the IF statement because I'm
going to be using it in here.
We just populate its values.
So we'll do this the long way first and we'll clean up the code a little bit later on.
Right now, I just want to insert something into the database.
So what do what am I getting here?
I'm getting the hostname.
So h dot hostname is equal to we need to get it from a request.
So we be are dot.
Form dot get hostname, and this name here needs to match exactly what's on the host jet form and what
I'm calling it here in the host form is hostname perfect.
So back to our handlers.
So we get the hostname, then we get the canonical you URL.
So I'll just duplicate that line and changes to canonical name.
And this is called Canonical Name.
And then what's the next thing we get.
Let's just go look at our form here.
We get the URL that's called URL and in the models it's called URL uppercase.
Then we get the IP, which is called IP.
Then we get the IP version six, which is called IP Version six.
We make sure that's what it's called on the form here, IPV six and I'm using IPV six.
Good.
And the next thing is the location, the operating system and active.
So the location.
That's easy.
That's just a string location is called location.
OS is called OS and the last one is actually an ant, so I need to convert what I'm getting from my
form post, which always comes in the form string into an end, and I can do that pretty easily.
We'll just say active is a and potentially an error, which I'm going to ignore.
And again, in production you wouldn't know it.
But I'm not focusing on Web application development here.
I'm focusing on Web sockets and we need to jump to some hoops to get their Østergaard on a tour.
And what we're going to get is art form douget.
And the name of this is active.
So now I have a variable active and I can say H dot active is equal to active.
So here I actually want to get the artist for this in the database and I want to take them back to the
same page in some cases.
So I need to get the ID after the insert.
So back up here I'm going to create a new variable var new ID are very hostile, call host ID and it's
a type eight.
And now that I have all this information and I'm not doing any sanitizing of the data at all and you
should in a production web application, you should make sure that this is actually not empty, that
this is not empty.
We've got JavaScript validation which will take care of that in most cases.
But computer scientists are not optimist's.
We assume that things are going to go wrong.
We assume that an unlikely scenario is always going to take place.
But again, I'm not going to bother doing that in this course.
If you want to get a more detail on form, validation and so forth, I have a course in Web development.
You can go and you can go look for that one or find it online or do whatever you want.
But anyway, we're going to skip it right now.
So I'll just get my values and I'll say new ID, which will be the returned value from my insert insert
statement, potentially an error or assign the value of.
And because I've added that method in the data, that database method we just wrote into the repo,
it's available to me repo db dot insert host and I pass it the model host which I called H.
If there's an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll just say logged print line error and
then I have a helper's method helper's dot server error which takes the response writer the request
and an error message.
And I'll return because I don't want to go any further after this point.
But if I, if I pass this then I can just say host ID is equal to new ideas and at that point we should
have it inserted.
Now what I'm going to do right now is get rid of this writing thing.
I'll just do a redirect back to the same host page that we were looking at.
So I'll say flat or set up, I'll put a message in the variable, which is repo dot app, dot session
dot put.
And it requires a context which I get from my ah my response right at my request ARGT context, I'll
name it Flash so it'll display a success message to the user and I'll just say changes saved.
And at this point I'll just do a redirect.
Now we're going to change this in a little while based upon the button that the people choose.
If they choose, save and continue or save and close, we'll do different things.
But right now I just want to get this working.
HTP don't redirect and it requires a response writer, a pointer to a request, the URL, which will
be admin host.
I mean, check that you URL it again, admin host and the host ID.
So I'm going to wrap this in a format as print F in a moment.
Format s, print F and will replace that percent d with the idea of our host, which is host ID, and
then the last parameter requires is a status C other, and that'll be good enough for our purposes.
So what did I get wrong here?
Oh yes.
To close this and I should do it.
So in theory we should be able to insert a host into the database at this point.
Let's see what we got wrong, if anything.
So I'll stop my application and start my application.
Unexpected parentheses.
And this is in go line 177.
I get too many parentheses there.
Let's try that again.
Run.
There it is, it's running, so let's start right from the beginning.
We'll go to our hosts page will say New Host and I'll call this localhost canonical name is localhost.
The URL will be SCDP Colden localhost AT&amp;T.
And I'm going to leave these other things that are not required empty, but I will make it active just
to make sure this is actually working.
So let's see if this works.
Save saving close page not found admin host zero, what do I get wrong?
So let's go back here and see what the URL is.
It's admin host zero.
Let's see what the log file has to say.
Oh, there's an error and the error is Syntex.
Oh, I got an error in my sequence.
So let's go find our our host talk show host, Underscore Postgres.
There it is right there.
So I have a typo somewhere.
Insert in the house.
OK, got to close this parentheses.
So let's stop that.
Try this again.
And see what else we got wrong, because I think there's another mistake, but we'll make sure.
So localhost, localhost, HTP Cologne's localhost 88 and I'll make it active and see what else gets
wrong.
So let me put some blank lines in here.
Save close.
And it took me back to host one.
Perfect.
Now let's look in our database and let's look at our host table and look at the content and reload this.
And I have some values.
So I have the hostname.
I had the canonical name.
I have the euro.
I left those empty.
So they should be empty.
Active is zero.
And that I actually do that.
Right?
I'm not sure.
OK, well, I'm not sure if I checked active or not, but so far it seems like it might be working.
So the next step is to actually grab the host from the database and display it in the list.
That requires a couple of steps to start with.
I need to be able to list all of the hosts that are in the database on this table.
So I need a database method that says get all hosts and gives me enough information to display it on
this page that I need to modify this page to actually use the information we're passing to this jet
template.
Then clicking on the host should take me to in this case it would be one, because that's the idea of
our inserted host.
OK, so we're getting closer.
We'll take care of the update section and the displaying of information in the next lecture or two.