OK, so so far we have this we can go to house and this is the create a new host, but I already have
one in the database.
You can see that right here.
I have one with an idea of one.
And this information in the database.
And what I want to do is when I'm on this screen looking at slash admin, slash host, slash one, I
definitely want to display the information that's in the database in this form.
So in order to do that, I need to have a database method that goes and gets a host.
So let's write one of those.
So I'll go back to my idee and I'm in host Underscore Postgrads Culgoa and I'll just create a new method.
Func M it has the receiver of type postcrisis DB repoll and I'll call this ghettoised and it will take
one parameter ID which is an aunt and I will return to things, or at least potentially two things.
Models dot host and potentially an error.
OK, so I'm going to copy the context bit as I often do, to save some typing and avoid typographical
errors and I would need to write our query.
So that's the simple, simple statement.
Query is assigned the value of and I use Bachtiar so I can put it on multiple lines.
I need to select the ID.
Let's see what the field names are.
So structured hostname canonical name url hostname canonical name you url ip ip version six ip ip version
six location os active location os active created out and updated at.
From hosts, where ideas equals and because we're using postcards, we've got to use a placeholder.
So there's my query.
So let's execute the statement.
Row is a sign the value of IMDB, dot, query, context, Queretaro context.
And that takes the context.
It takes a query and it takes our ID.
So that gives me a row.
Now I need to put a variable in place, which I'll call H to hold the results.
And it's a type models host.
And we'll be modifying this query later on to get more information, but this will get us started and
now we scan the row robot scan into our variable, we just create it.
So we're going to scan into it and then hostname and I'll just duplicate that a few times.
Then each dot canonical name you url, h2, IP, IP Version six and duplicate that a few more times.
OS active created and update out.
OK, now we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, I'll just return H and the error.
Otherwise, things are good, return each and.
Now, as I said, we're going to have to get more information from this query later on, but this will
get us started.
I'm going to call this get hosted by ID just because that's a better name.
Now, I've created this, so I have to add it to my repository.
So I copy the entire signature, go to my repository, go file and paste that in there.
And while we're at it, we may as well do the update code as well.
So let's go back to our ID and back to our host Underscore Postgrads and let's create another one which
I will call update hosts.
So func M receiver is Postgrads DB Repo and I'll call this update host and it will take one parameter
H, which is of type models to our host and it returns potentially an error.
And again, I'll copy the context line's paste those in here so there's no typographical errors and
now I need to write my statement.
Statement is assigned the value of.
Update hosts set and I don't need to worry about the ID, but I do need to worry about the hostname.
He put the dollar sign one and then canonical name equaled a dollar sign to better still name, right,
the.
Hostname canonical name, and then we have the URL Euro equal to dollar sign three IP equal to dollar
sign for IP Version six, equal to dollar sign five.
OS equal to Dollar Signs six, and I'll go to another line.
Active equal to Dollar Signs seven and updated at Equal Dollar Sign eight, where ID equals dollars
are not.
So that's my statement.
Now let's do the database call.
So I don't care about the result, I do care about the error is a sign, the value of IMDB, the exact
context right there, has the context.
Past my statement and then just on separate lines to make it more readable, we want to put in our hostname,
not canonical name.
You.
IP h dot ip version six H os.
How active is this all, just use time now to get the current time to get the updated set to the current
date and time, and the last thing is my I.D. and that is EDEK.
So that does the query.
Now we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll log beer logged uprate line error and return error, otherwise
return nil, OK.
So now we have an update and we can use that to update the information.
So let's add that to a repository.
Let's make sure everything compiles.
It does perfect, so let's go find her handler sonder handlers, we want handlers.
And what we have here.
Well, let's go to the Reedsville that will give me the right spot, so we want to host post and host
get most of the hosts get first.
So here, back in this one, this will should display the information on the form for us.
So this is called.
But we want to display an individual host.
And what we want to do here is we've already created a variable.
Models are each of type models host.
If the idea is greater than zero, then we want to get the host from the database database so we can
just say H.
I'll call it host.
Potentially an error or assign the value of repo DB don't get hosted by ID and pass in the ID that we
grab from the parameter right from the.
You are right up here.
If error is not equal to nil and I'll just say logged print line error exit not an exit return and I'll
just give my blank screen, we'll fix this up later on.
Otherwise if there is no error then my variable H is equal to host.
OK, so now we're passing that information.
What is this host.
Can I use host type of models.
User get user gravities get get hosted by ID.
That's better.
OK, so now we have the variable H and we're putting that in our verbs, which means I should be able
to go to the host page host jet and make sure that I'm displaying some information.
We'll just so we have the hostname, we have the canonical name.
This should work.
So let's see what happens.
So let's run it and go back to my Web browser and I'm looking at ID one.
So let's load that page and see if we have any information and we have an error.
Expected 11 destination arguments, not 10.
So that is in get hosted by ID.
So let's go back and see what we missed.
Host Postcrisis so get hosted by ID is right here so I have ID hostname canonical name you url ip IP
Version six OS Active created an updated out where hosts ID equals dollar sign one.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Oh yeah.
He Levan.
So I missed one idy hostname canonical name, Euro IP, IP version, six location area, each dot location.
Let's make sure we didn't make the same mistake down here.
Hostname cannot claim you were an IP OS active.
I left it out of there as well.
Yeah, I did.
Active.
Then location date, which makes this nine, which makes that 10, and then after active each location.
OK, try this again.
And reload this page and now I have some information perfect, so the one thing I'm curious about and
I think I know what it is, but we'll get to that when we get to the update section is when I save this.
I'm not sure that's being handled the active.
And we'll figure that out in the next the next election when we do the update.
So now we've got a means of at least displaying something.
We still have to do this part where we go and get all hosts, enlist them in this table, but we'll
take care of that in the next lecture or two.
Right now, let's go.
And in the next lecture, we'll worry about saving the updates for a particular host.