So right now, we can display a host on this page, so I'm looking at the one host in the database,
which is Itaewon, so I'm an admin host one, and it is showing the information is in the database.
And this is all accurate because this host is currently not active and I'm not sure that works.
Right.
So let's write the necessary code in our handler to update the hosts in the database and make sure this
active is doing what it's supposed to do.
So I'm back in my handlers, I'm in Handler Go and I'm in the Method Post host.
And right now we have some logic that says if the idea is greater than zero when somebody posts this,
get the host from the database, otherwise update all the values and inserted into the database.
So this is accurate and it works well.
We can simplify things.
We can take the information actually right now.
Let's get the host.
So we'll say host and potentially an error are assigned the value of repo DB, get hosted by ID and
we pass in the host ID, which is ID.
We get that from the URL up here and that gets me the host.
If there's an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'm just going to log the error print line
error and I'll return.
I'll just display a blank screen.
And of course you don't want to do that in production, but for our purposes right now, this is sufficient.
Otherwise our value of of H which we declared up here on line 157, that's a sign the value of host.
So we now have the host from the database.
Do we really need this statement?
I don't think we do.
So let's get rid of that.
And come down here and get rid of that, I do, in fact, let me just reformat this.
No matter what happens, I want the value, the values that the user entered to be assigned to host
here.
I'm overriding the existing values.
And if the ID is not zero, I'm just entering the values into an empty house model.
So that works great.
Here's the part where we want our if statement.
If Ivy is greater than zero, then we'll update the host, otherwise we'll insert the host.
So this is the part we want to change right here.
All I want to do is call my update.
Error is assign the value of repo DB update host, which is right there, and I pass in my house model.
And again, if there's an error, I'll just log it and return.
So in theory, that should work, so let's try this and I'm going to always return back to where we're
going before I have an error in here somewhere.
Let me find this.
Right there.
Should be like that, and this new idea should be inside that statement right here.
Because I'm redirecting to host I.D., which is actually now that's going to be hosting the equals I.D..
And make sure I've got this returning properly.
Host was new I.D., which just changed that the host ID eight ID and make this redirect to a fourth
ID, OK, that should work properly now.
All I was doing was making sure that when I did the redirect I'm going back to A'Court ID after I do
by insert here, I just assign the value H or the Model H, which is our host.
I give it the returned ID for the insert statement.
So in theory this should work.
So let's start our application hostilely declared but not used.
Let's get rid of that.
All right, now it should work.
So I run I go back to my Web browser, I reload to make sure I'm looking at the right page, and let's
just give it an IP address of one two seven zero zero.
That one, the localhost IP address, save and close, which gives me an error.
And the error is syntax error at or near active.
OK, let's find our error in the update.
So that's in host up postgrads get hosted ID update.
So the act, the error is here.
I'm missing a comma.
I do that all the time.
So let's start our up.
Stop our application.
Start our application.
And reload this page by clicking the oil and pressing air, giving it an IP address and one two seven
zero zero one and save and it brings me back and I saved it.
Now, let's try this active button.
Safe.
And it's not displaying it properly, let's look in the database and see what's happened there.
So I'll go to the content and refresh this and active is still zero.
So there's a problem there somewhere.
OK.
Yeah, it's still zero, so let's figure out what we're doing wrong on that one.
It's got to be in the host's Jett page and it has to be in the part where I have the active right here.
So I have an input classes, form check input.
That's correct.
Value is hosted active.
OK, type is a check, but it is active.
Name is active.
Well, first of all, let's put it in this statement in there to check it if necessary.
If.
Are active, equals one, if it is active, then checked and.
OK, let's see if that actually renders properly reloaded good.
Now let's go into the database and manually change it to be active, so I'll change that to one and
save the changes.
Good.
And I want to load this page that should be checked.
It is OK.
So it is checking it when it's active, but what it's not doing is passing the necessary information.
So can I actually make this inactive and save?
OK, and now make it active and safe.
Now it's still not passing that information.
So this is a check and does it have a name I.D.?
Active name is active.
OK, and the value is most active.
Let's just change that to one.
So it doesn't really matter what it is, the way the checkboxes work, if it's checked, it sends the
value as part of the form post.
If it's not checked, it doesn't even include it.
So let's just save that and go back here and we're going to restart the application.
Now, we don't let's reload the page, make it active and save it.
Save and close.
OK, now let's make it inactive.
Save, save and close.
Perfect.
What's in the database?
Reload.
It's inactive.
Now let's make it active.
Save and reload, and now it's active, so that's all it was, we just need to make sure that we handle
checkboxes the way that checkboxes are actually handled, send disvalue when it's checked, otherwise
it doesn't even get included in the post.
So that should work just fine.
OK, so the next step now that we've got this part going and we still have to deal with these, Tab's
up here, but we'll get to those in a while.
The next step is when I click on the hosts page.
I actually want my one hosta that's in the database to be loaded here on this screen.
So in the next lecture will take care of that.
We'll have to read a database handler and pass the information to this template.
And that's pretty straightforward.