So let's get started with the steps necessary to display on this page over here, posts on the overview
page, which is a slash admin slash host slash.
All we want to list are one host here and any other hosts, we might add.
So in our roots, you can see that host all takes us to all hosts.
That handler.
Let's go there.
So here what we want to do is to get all hosts from database and then we want to send data to template,
which is pretty straightforward.
So let's go to our host, underscore postgrads and at the very bottom, call that a new method func
has the receiver of Postgrads DB Repo and we'll call this all hosts.
And it takes no parameters and it returns a slice of models, host and potentially an error.
So I'll get the context.
I'll copy it the way I always do, because I always make a mistake when I type that up by hand and then
read her statement.
Query, query is and we'll just make this a simple query right now.
Again, we're going to have to come back and modify this later on, but it's not necessary to do that
at the moment.
So all I need to do is select it and let's look at the actual contents of the host table to make sure
we don't miss anything.
The structure is as follows.
We want the hostname, the canonical name in the URL, hostname canonic call name.
You ip IP Version six, you URL, IP, IP, Version six, we're not using all this, but I may as well
grab it now because I might use it later on location OS and active location OS Colma Active.
I think it's just created an updated at Yepp created at an updated act from Host's order by and I'll
say hostname.
So there's our query now let's execute it, rose error or assign the value of IMDB dot query context.
Right there and handed the context and handed our query.
And of course, we want to check for an error, if error is not equal to nil, return the error.
Otherwise, defer rose clothes so we don't wind up with a memory leak and now we'll say declaring a
variable and the variable will be via our hosts, which is of type, slice of models, thought host
and now for rows.
Next we go through our entire ROSET.
We create a new variable.
VAR H is a type model host and that's what we'll store.
This in error is assign the value of rows scam and will scan into this h.
We just created the ID and I'll duplicate this a few times.
The hostname.
The canonical name.
The euro, the IP, the IP version six.
The location, the operating system OS.
Whether or not it's active.
And they created app and the updated perfect, so if there's an error, error is not equal to nil,
we'll just log the error, logged our print line error and return.
Nhill and the Air.
Otherwise, we want to append this to our slice and a slice is called hosts equals host append and we're
spending the two hosts, we're spending each perfect.
So now we have our hosts.
And then after we're doing all of our scans, we'll do one last error check.
If error equals Rosewarne error and error is not equal to nil, then log the error logged up print line
error and return nil and the error otherwise return hosts and nil.
OK.
So up here, this can't be air has to be returned to an air, and I think that's it for errors.
It is.
All right, so let's copy.
Are all hosts signature?
Go to our repository.
And paste it in here and now it's available to us in our handler, so back to our handler.
We want to get all the hose from the database.
Well, that's easy.
Now hosts an error or assigned the value of repo DB all hosts, not all users, all hosts.
If error is not equal to nil logged up print line error and just return again, you're not going to
do that in production.
But I just want to get this up and functional so we can get to the WebSocket stuff.
Now we want to send this host data to our handlers and that's pretty straightforward.
We've already done that.
We just create a variable which I'll call VARs and that's a sign the value of make a jet map and then
Vasin set and I'll call this hosts and hand it hosts.
And then down here, this error, because we have one above, is now just an equal stunt, a sign,
and we pass it first.
OK, so let's just make sure this all works.
We're not going to render anything, but make sure it all compiles.
And it does and I should be able to see this House page by going to hosts, and I do so now, I should
be able to open the jet file, which is called host OzJet.
And in here, I should be able to range through that data, which is as simple as range hosts.
And and in here, I want to have a table row and I want to have a table data for one entry and this
is the host, so it will be hostname and I'll just leave the rest of them empty for right now just to
make sure it actually works.
TD And there are one, two, three, four more.
So one, two, three.
Save this.
I should be able to reload this and see my one host and I do.
And of course that should be a hyperlink.
A traffic equals admin slash, admin slash host slash Heidi.
And close this and close my A and save that and reloaded, and now I should be able to click on that.
Perfect.
OK, now back on this table, we also want to list services.
And what I'd like to see here is how many are OK, how many are in mourning, how many are pending,
how many are in problem state lists, the operating system, the location on the status.
What?
We can't do this part yet because we have no services for our host, but we can definitely do the last
three.
So let's do those.
So the last three, the first one is The O.C., which is just doorposts.
The second one is the location, which is location, which I don't think are even populated for our
existing house, but it will show up as nothing and the status if status equals one.
Else
and end, and I think the syntax for this is spam class equals, what is it called batch?
Badge.
And if the status is one, its active badge success.
Active, otherwise, it's inactive, so I'll just copy this, paste it in here, tab it over so it's
properly formatted and make it badge danger inactive.
Already there fact, OK, you don't need two versions of that.
Save it, reload it.
And I have something here, can't you?
Status as field name and struct type model host.
Right.
It's not called status.
It's called active.
OK, try that again and nothing showing up.
Range hosts.
Spanned class equals badge, badge danger.
Well, just put it in here and see what it looks like active.
So it does have one, if not active, equals one span.
Well, I've got the syntax wrong for that, so let's go figure.
I'll just do it like this.
Spang class equals tax excessed.
And spin class equals text danger.
That's not a great text success and get rid of this and that should at least put it up there and I'll
figure out the bad syntax in a bit.
And it's not critical there.
So it shows it up is active.
Now, if I open this up and give it more information like its location, say, Toronto and its Kubuntu,
it's actually a Mac Mac OS X and it's not in Toronto.
It's in New Brunswick.
That's where I am right now.
And save this and go back to hosts.
It now displays the rest of the information.
OK, so now we have a means of getting to our hosts very, very easily.
So the next thing we need to worry about is this services bit.
And this is critical because these are the things we want to monitor and that's what we're going to
be using web sockets for.
So there's some work required to make that happen.
None of it's terribly difficult and we'll get started on it in the next lecture.