In this section of the course, we're going to focus upon adding some concurrency to our code base.
And what we're going to do first is send email concurrently.
In other words, we're going to send it in the background.
Now, there's a good reason for that.
Sending email can slow things down if you're connecting to a mail service and it's having a bad day.
So you're connected to Mail Gun and for some reason they're really slow to send emails.
You don't want whatever you're doing in your code to just stop until that email gets sent.
Instead, you want to send it off in the background.
And we're going to do that using two channels, actually three channels, but only two that are involved
with actually sending email will send information off to a channel and that will have something listening
to that channel.
And when it receives it, it'll send it off in the background.
It'll fire off a new go routine that sends our email off concurrently and the other channel will listen
for errors.
And if something goes wrong, then we send something in that error channel, and a third one is just
used to shut things down.
And that will be our third task for this section, and that is adding some cleanup logic to our application.
If our application is sending emails and doing all sorts of things in the background and someone decides,
Hey, I need to stop the application to install the new version or whatever it may be.
You don't want it to just stop because some things that were queued to happen in the background or that
were actually happening in the background, they'll just die and you'll never find out about it.
And that's a bit of a problem.
So let's add some logic that allows us to wait until everything that's running in the background is
finished, and then we stop our application and perform some other cleanup tasks while we're at it.
So let's get started.