So what we want to do in this section of the course is to implement the ability to send email asynchronously
or in the background through a go routine.
And obviously that means we need to be able to send email.
So let's set up a really simple file that actually allows us to send email.
Okay.
So in the CND slash Web folder, let's create a new file, which I'll call mail or don't go
and let's go make this in package main.
Just to get rid of the error, let's go and get a few things that we're going to have to have in order
to send email.
Now, we could do everything just using the standard library, but there's a couple of packages I want
to install that will just make sending email a little less painful.
So for the root level of my project, I will go and get first of all, your hub dot com slash v a in
in g 8 to 2 slash go dash pre mailer.
Agree Mailer.
And all this does is inline cascading style sheets just to make email more more compatible with the
various email clients out there when you're sending HTML formatted email.
Okay.
So that's just a convenience package and now we'll go and get an actual mail package.
GitHub dot com slash x hit slash go dash simple dash mail slash v2 and please use v2.
Okay.
Even if V3 is out, so that goes and gets the necessary packages.
Now let's set up our necessary code to send email and we'll get it working so we can just send email,
you know, synchronously during regular program execution and then after the fact we'll make it run
in the background.
Okay.
So first thing I'll do is set up a type for mail, okay?
And this will be describing the actual mail server.
So it's a struct and we're going to use domain is the first first field in this and it's just a string.
And of course locally that'll be local host But in production you're going to tie your email to a specific
domain and then what mail host are we using?
And that's a string again and what port is the mail server listening on?
And that's just an end.
And does it require a username to log into the mail server to send the email string and a password string?
And is the email server encrypted encryption?
And it almost certainly is in production, but in development it won't be.
Who is the default from address string.
When you send email it has to come from someone.
And what's the default from?
Name again?
A string.
And then we're going to have a wait group.
We're not going to use that right away, but we will be using it before too long.
So we'll just call it wait.
And it's a pointer to sync Don't Wait group.
And that did the import for me.
And now we're going to have two channels and we're not going to be using these right away, but we'll
be using them before too long.
Okay.
So we'll call the first one a Mailer channel.
That's where we're going to send any email we want sent in the background.
And that's a channel that takes the type of message.
Okay.
And message doesn't exist yet, but it will momentarily.
And Chan, if there's any error sending email, we'll send it to this channel.
Chan of type error.
And finally, when you're done and want to stop, things will just have a done chan, which is a chain
of type.
Okay.
So we'll save this and now we'll go set up the message type.
So that type describes the actual mail server and here's one that describes an actual message and it's
a struct and it has from as the first field that's just a string.
In case you want to override the default from name and address from name will be a string to to whom
is it going?
That's a string.
And this will hold the email address we're sending to what's the subject of the email message again?
A string.
Are there any attachments?
And we'll make that a slice of string.
And that will be the full path name to any file we want to attach to the email message.
And we can have more than one because it's a slice.
Data, which will actually be the body of the message.
And it's a type I'm going to put any in there.
Okay.
And if you're not using go 1.18 or later, you'll have to put interface with curly brackets.
Data map.
Just a way, a convenient way of getting data to the actual template will be rendering as a type of
map string.
And again, any.
And lastly, what template do you want to use to render this?
And that's a string.
Okay.
So we'll save this to format it.
Now, there's are two types.
Now, let's put a comment here.
Okay.
What we're going to have at some point is a function to listen for messages on the Maler channel.
We're going to have to have one of those later on.
But we'll just put a comment there for right now.
Then we'll have a function with a receiver of M a pointer to the mail type, not map mail type.
We just set up.
And that's just going to be one called send mail.
And that will allow us to send an email message.
And that will take as one one of its parameters.
MSG of type message, that second type we just defined.
And then we'll also take the error channel, which is a channel error.
Okay.
Now, what do we want to do in this actual function?
Well, to start with, we'll check to see if they specified a custom template.
So we'll say if msgid a template.
If that's equal to an empty string, then we'll use the default template.
And if you look over here in the templates folder, we have two that begin with the word mail.
One is mailed HTML to go each HTML and one is mailed up plain go to good HTML.
Now, obviously, when we send email, we don't want to send a plain text email as the only means of
communicating with our customers.
So we'll actually send it in two formats.
One plain text, which is visible to any email client anywhere on the planet, and one that is actually
going to be used by the vast majority of them.
A nicely formatted HTML message.
So if they don't specify if we're sending email to this function and it doesn't specify anything in
the message template, then we'll just use the default one.
And all we have to do is say message dot template is equal to mail because that will capture both mail,
HTML, Deutsch HTML and the plain text message.
Okay.
That's the first thing we'll check.
The second thing, did we specify a custom from address in this message?
If
MSG from is equal to an empty string, then we'll use the default.
One message to off from is equal to right from the receiver.
M dot from address.
And the same thing with the name.
If messaged from name is equal to an empty string, then message
from name is equal to.
Import from me.
Right there.
Okay.
So that takes care of the defaults.
Now, what we're going to do is send information to these two templates.
And if you look at the plaintext one, for example.
It's really simple.
What we're doing is having one define with the name body and we're putting the value message in there.
In other words, data that's passed to this template and we do the same thing in go each time out.
The only thing that's dynamic in this particular template is on line 19, which is dot message.
So let's close both of these.
That means we need to pass data to this template.
So let's define a variable data, and that's going to be a sign the value of a map of string.
That's the key.
We look things up with an any and then we'll populate one value in that map with the name message,
which is what the template is going to be looking for.
And the value of that is going to be MSG, dot, data, whatever we got as a call to this function.
Okay.
And then we set a MSG data map right there to be equal to data.
That map we just created.
Now, the next thing we want to do is to actually build two versions of the message.
So we want to build each HTML mail, and then we want to build plane mail.
Plain text mail.
Okay.
Now, I can do that right in this function, but what I'm going to do is actually break that out into
its own function, each one of these.
Okay.
So I'll call a function that doesn't exist yet, which I often do.
So I'll declare a variable formatted message while checking for an error.
When I call from M the receiver there is going to be in a moment a function called build each HTML message
and it just takes a MSG as a parameter.
Okay.
And then I'll copy this whole thing and paste it here and change the name to plain message.
And I'll change this to build plain message.
Plain text message.
Okay.
And of course, I should check for errors.
So I'll say if error is not equal to nil.
What I'm going to do at this point is actually send this to the channel that I received as a second
parameter to the code of this function.
I'll send error channel whatever the error was.
Okay.
And I'll copy this and paste it here.
And down below this, I'll just create stub functions that I'll fill it in moment.
So I'll set func with receiver of m pointer to to mail and I call the first one build to mail message
and it will take one parameter MSG of type message and it returns a string in an error.
Okay.
And then I'll have this for the moment.
Return an empty string and nil, and we'll fix this up in a minute.
This is just a stub.
So then I'll copy this whole thing and paste it beneath it and call this one build plain text message.
Okay.
So we'll fill we'll fill these things out in a minute, but let's go back up to our send mail function.
And after I make the call to those two functions, I just created stubs.
For now I need to create an SMTP client something in my code that will connect to the mail server.
So I'll call that server.
And that's a sign the value of from the mail package we just installed a little while ago.
And I may have to go do this import import in a moment, but we'll find out.
I want a new SMTP client.
No, they found it for me.
Now let's go up to the top and make sure that imported the correct package.
And it needs to be av2, I think.
Okay.
I must have imported it before it was actually versioned at version two.
So I have this server variable now and I would just set some values on it.
So what is the server host?
Server to host.
Try that again.
Host.
Is equal to import host.
And server port is equal to import port and server.
Port username is equal to import username and server password is equal to my password.
And again, I'm just putting in all the information that's necessary to connect to an actual server.
Now the next one is server dot encryption, server dot encryption.
And if you actually go look at the package, the mail or package we installed, you'll discover that
it has it supports various kinds of encryption.
But I don't know right now what server this actual code is going to be connecting to, what mail server.
So what I'm going to do is scroll down below all of this.
I'll just leave that as it is for right now.
Will finish line 74 in a moment.
I want to write another function that will allow me to get the encryption method for a particular server
because there are certain constants we have to use with this mail or package and it's really easy func
receiver of imported a mail mail and we'll call this get encryption.
Okay.
And it's going to take one parameter E for encryption, which is a string, and it's going to return
from the mail package, the encryption type, which comes as a constant.
And all we have to do is type of switch, statement, switch on E and the first case will be the string
kills.
If that's what it specified, then we'll return from the mail package encryption start.
Tell us right there.
Okay.
But if the case happens to be SSL, then we'll return from the mail package, encryption, SSL, TLS.
And again, that's the right one.
Yes, it is.
Okay.
And if the case is none, which is what we'll be using in development, then we'll return mail dot encryption
right there and we'll put it in a default case just to capture the most, most common ones.
If nothing is specified, then we'll return mail dot encryption start TLS.
That's far and away the most common one.
So now I have to get encryption.
And what I can do is back up here on line 74 and my code that will be equal to m dot and get encryption
and will hand it m dot encryption as the parameter.
Okay.
And that sets up the encryption and just a few more servers to keep alive.
Do I want to keep my connection to the mail server a lot?
Well, we're not going to be sending mail every second, so I'll say false.
Okay.
And server disconnect timer.
We'll just set that.
There's something logical.
This should be running in the background, so we'll give it 10 seconds.
Ten times time dot second.
And we'll do the same thing for server.
Send time out right here.
Okay.
So that describes everything I need to connect to that server.
Now let's create the client, SMTP client, which is a variable I'm declaring right now and potentially
an error come from calling server that variable which is created to connect.
And if we get an error, if error is not equal to nil, once again, we'll just send that to the error
chat.
I missed an equal sign there.
We'll send that error to the error chat.
Okay.
So error can get whatever the error is.
So let's go beyond this now.
And let's create an email message using the information that we received in that variable MSG.
Well, call this email and it comes from the mail package, not new MSG.
Okay.
And we'll set the from information.
So email dot set from and that will be set to msg dot from and then a dot and then it will say add two.
So we're going to add it to address to this.
And of course, that's MSG data.
And then we'll set the subject, set subject.
And that will be a major subject.
So that gives me an empty e-mail message with the correct to and from information in the subject set.
But we still have to put it in the body.
So email, dot, set body.
And by default, the body of our message will be the plain text.
So we'll use mailed out text plain to describe the kind of content we're adding, and that's just a
constant return of that package.
And then we put in plain message and then to get the HTML format in their email dot and alternative.
And that's the type mail from the mail package.
Text, HTML, and we put our formatted message in.
Okay.
So now we have an SMP client, we have an e-mail message all set up.
We've connected to our mail server.
The next step before we actually send this is to check if there's any attachments.
And we do that by saying if the length of MSG dot attachments is greater than zero, then we need to
add the attachments.
So we just range through that slice for we don't care about the index, we do care about the current
thing, which I'll call X comes from range through MSG, dot attachments.
And each time we arrange through that, through this we just add an attachment.
And that's as easy as saying email and attachment and attachment right there.
And we're adding X, which is the variable I declared right there in line 92.
So now we have our attachments, we have everything all set.
Let's try sending the email.
And we do that by saying error is equal to.
Email that sent and we had it sent to the client as a parameter.
That's how we're sending it.
And once again, we do an error check.
So I'll copy this and paste this right below that.
Okay.
So the last thing to do is to actually build the HTML message and build a plain text message.
But this lecture's getting fairly long, so we'll pick that up in the next lecture.