So let's finish up our Malago file.
And what we need to do is to finish off these two stub functions and to write one more that will inline
CC using that package, the pre mailer package.
We imported a couple of lectures ago and this is pretty simple.
So here in the build HTML message function, let's do that 1/1.
Okay.
So the first thing I'm going to do is declare a variable template to render and that's going to be assigned.
The value of what we're going to be doing is passing things like just mail to this, this function,
and then we'll build the name of the file using format of print F right there.
And my format string will be dot slash, cmd slash, web slash, templates slash and then percent s
dot, html, dot and go.
Each HTML is we're doing the HTML version of it here.
Okay.
So that gives me the name of the full path to the file I want to use to render this email.
Then I'll declare a variable T for template while checking for an error when I call template dot new
and the first thing I to do is give it a name.
It can be anything.
So I'll call this email, dash html and then I'll pass files right there and use the variable template
to render.
Okay.
So that passes the file and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return an empty string.
And the error.
Okay.
But if we get past that now, let's declare a variable var tpo and it's a type bytes buffer.
And we're going to render into that rule, execute into that.
So we'll do that by saying if error is equal to t dot execute template.
And we're going to execute it into that bite stop buffer TPO.
We're looking for a section in the template named body and we're passing it our data message data map
right there.
And if the error is not equal to nil and once again, we'll return an empty string in the error.
Okay.
But if we get past that now, we have a formatted message or something we can use as a formatted message.
We still have a bit of work to do on it, but we'll say formatted message.
It's a sign the value of two year old string, which you get a string at of that vital stop buffer.
Okay.
Now, at this point, before I send that back, I want to inline any excess.
So what I'm going to do is come down here after build a plain text message.
I'll create another simple function with the receiver.
A pointer to mail.
And here's what we'll use that perimeter package.
Okay.
I'll call this one inline CSV, because that's what we're doing.
We're making the CSC more acceptable to various email clients.
It takes one parameter, which is I'll call S, it's a type string, and it returns a string and potentially
an error.
Okay, let's give ourselves some room here.
And this is very, very simple.
So the first thing we need to do is to set up some options for the pre mailer package.
So I'll call that options.
And it's a sign the value of the type pre mailer options.
I'll just fill in the fields.
So we'll say remove classes.
And there are many options you can use here.
But this will do the trick.
I'll say don't bother.
We're moving the classes, some email, clients use them 62 attributes and I'll say that one false as
well.
Okay.
And I'll say keep being important.
If someone puts an exclamation mark in front of a CSV rule and wants to make it important.
I'll say you keep that one too.
True.
So now I have some options.
Now all I do is say premise for pre mailer while checking for an error comes from pre mailer.
Right there.
Dot knew pre mailer from string because that's what we're getting is a string and we'll give it the
string and we'll give it a reference to our options and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return an empty string and the error can't go any further.
Otherwise we'll declare a variable called HTML while checking for an error.
When we say preempt, transform.
And once again, we have our check.
So I'll copy this and paste it here.
And if we get past that, then everything went according to plan.
So we'll return to normal and go.
Now I have this function available to me.
So up here.
Back in build H2O message.
We'll try to inline the CCed, so we'll say formatted message.
An error or equal to from the receiver.
M will inline the CCS and we just hand it formatted message and we'll do our error check.
So I'll copy and paste this
and paste it here.
Oh, and if we get past that, we're not going to return an empty string.
We're going to return the formatted message.
Okay.
So with all of that, now we can copy this.
Paste it down here in the build plain text message and just modify it.
So we're going to modify first of all, we're not going to be using HTML to go HTML.
We're going to be using plain dark HTML as the template.
Okay.
And we'll change the name here to email plain, which doesn't really matter, but it makes it more readable.
This all stays exactly the same, but we don't actually inline the CSRs.
And just to make it readable, we'll make this one plain message and we'll return plain message.
Okay.
So with those changes, we should be able to actually use this code to send email.
Now, we have some warnings here, but I think this is from go, please.
I'll look at that up here.
I did, in fact, miss something.
It's a good thing I spotted that.
We want to put an MSG out template, and down here we want to put MSG to a template that wouldn't have
worked otherwise.
And we still have some errors here or warnings here.
And it says it is unused, but in fact.
We are using it up here.
That's just a language server and Visual Studio code.
Not quite keeping up with me.
So I believe that this should work for us.
We'll find out before too long.
But in any case, let's move on.