All right, let's give this a try.
We have our mail all set up, and we think it works, but we need to verify that.
And what we're going to do is send email synchronously.
In other words, not in the background at once.
We're sure that's where we'll send email using go routines.
Okay.
So to make this did simple.
Let's go over to our roots file right here and let's create a test root and I'll put it right at the
end here.
Okay.
So I'll say, Mark, start, get and I'll just call this test dash email and we'll inline a function.
And of course, this has to be a handler, so we'll give it a response writer and a request.
And what we'll do is create a variable of the type mail.
So we'll call this well, M is assigned the type of mail and we'll fill in its various fields.
So we'll just hard code these just to get this testing out of the way domain we'll make that local host.
And our host is also local host because we're sending through mail hog which will have running in our
Docker images.
Port Mail Hogs port is 1025.
Encryption will make that none because we're in development.
From name will make that equal to say info at my company dot com.
Actually, that would be from address credit again
and from name.
We'll just make that info.
And the Sync Group and the Ericsson and so forth where we are using --.
So let's make an --.
So since group we can leave empty dung.
Shan We can leave empty because we're not using those yet, but we'll actually make our error Chan equal
to make Chan there.
Okay, so now we have this variable and what I should be able to do to do now is to create a message.
So we'll take a message will be the variable name and it's a type message.
Okay?
And we'll fill in its various fields.
So we'll just put in the bare minimum to make this work.
Two is me at Care.com.
You got to send a message to someone.
Subject is, say, test email.
And then of course we need some data and we'll just make that hello world.
Okay.
Make that a colon like it's supposed to be and get rid of this.
That's better.
Now, let's try sending email m dot and we'll just call, send mail and give it MSG.
And give it an air chain.
So we'll make a chain of air.
Okay.
Now, when we hit this handler, assuming we have our Dr. Images running in the background, when I
go to slash test, dash email, I should get a blank screen.
But I should also get an email sent if everything went according to plan.
Let's find out.
So I'll open my terminal and I'll clear this and make start.
And it was already listening on that.
So make restart.
Okay, so it's running.
So let's go to our web browser.
And first of all, I'll just reload this page to make sure it works.
It does.
And now I'll click test.
Dash mail was a test stash mail.
I'm going to verify that.
Test.
Dash.
Email.
Test.
Dash email.
So we've got a blank screen.
Now, if I go to local host port 1825.
There is my test email, so there is one formatted as HTML and there's one formatted as text.
So now we know email actually works.
So the next step is to actually send email using go routines in the background, and we'll get started
on that in the next lecture.