So let's get started sending email in the background using our routines.
We know our mail works.
So now I'm going to go back to Mailer.
Don, go right here.
And actually let's go over to the Roots file first and get rid of that test root because it's just cluttering
up my roots and I don't need it anymore.
So I'll delete that and save this, which would clean up the imports.
And it did.
Okay, so let's go back to Mailer Duco and down here we have a comment that says let's read a function
to listen for messages on the mailer chain.
And that's what we're going to do right now.
So what I'll do is declare function and this is going to have the receiver of app pointer to config.
Okay?
And we'll just call it listen for mail and it's not going to take any parameters.
This is going to run in the background.
Okay.
So we'll put a for loop in here that runs forever.
And now we'll use these select statements which we haven't seen for a while, but here we're going to
listen to different channels and do different things.
So the first case will be we get a message MSG and that comes from so we use the assignment operator
it comes from and we'll use a channel.
Now what kind of channel are we going to use?
Well, we need a channel to listen to and of course we have the MAILER channel up here, but we don't
have access to that because we're not using the receiver of type mail.
So let's go over to configure go and we'll give this a new field which we'll call Mailer and it's a
type mail.
Okay.
And we'll save that.
We'll, of course, want to populate that at some point.
But now I can go back to Mailer Dot go.
And this will come from Laporte Mailer Dot Miller Channel.
So when we get something there, what are we going to do?
Well, all we're going to do is send email and we're going to send it in the background.
So go app, dot mailer, dot send mail and we'll hand it the message and the channel will give it is
app dot mailer dot version.
Okay, so that's our first case.
Our second case is we tried to send email and something went wrong.
So case and in this case we're going to populate a variable error when it receives something on the
channel app dot mailer error chain.
And that has to have a capital mailer error.
That's our second case.
And what do we do with this point?
Well, here's where you'd actually handle the error.
And of course, depending on what your application is, you might do different things.
You might send the text to someone, you might notify someone on Slack, whatever the case may be.
But all I'm going to do is say app error along the print line and we'll just print out the error.
But again, that's the logic that would be specific to a given project.
And the last case, there's one more channel we're listening to.
This is where we get anything from app, dot, mailer, dot done channel.
In other words, we want to stop processing email in the background, so we'll just return in that quits
this go routine.
So we have this function and of course we need to do something with it.
So let's go back to Mango.
We're right at the top here.
We're going to call a function.
It doesn't exist yet.
And here's where we have this comment set up mail.
And this is in the main func.
And the first thing I'll do is I will set up our email.
So as I often do call a function that doesn't exist yet.
So what I want to populate is in my app variable mailer that's going to come from calling app dot create.
Now.
Okay, now that function doesn't exist.
So let's go.
Set it up.
Way down here at the bottom of the file, I'll create a new function func with the receiver of app pointer
to config and this is going to be called create mail and it takes no arguments, but it returns the
type mail.
Okay.
So first thing I'll do is create channels.
The three channels we're going to use in email.
So Ericsson.
And that will be a sign the value of make a chain that accepts errors then will have Maler channel.
And that's a sign the value of making a channel that accepts messages.
Okay, now do I want to have it just as an undercover channel?
If I do that, it means I can only send or queue up one message at a time.
Let's make this a buffer channel.
I'll allow 100 messages to be in that particular channel in a given time before blocks.
Okay.
And then we have Mailer done channel, and that's just make a channel of rules.
Now, just like I did in that temporary function we made up, operate a variable.
Say, M is a sign the value of the type mail and I'll fill out its various fields.
I wish I hadn't deleted that route over in roots now, or I could have copied and pasted.
But in any case domain we'll just hard code these and these would come of course, from the environment
or command line flags or something like that.
But we'll just hard to add them here.
Host is local host.
Port is 1025.
Encryption is none.
From name is say info from address is info at my company dot com.
And here we're going to have a wait group and we can get that from app dot.
Wait.
Okay.
So we have one point group being handed around in the appropriate places.
Eric Chan is Eric Chen just created
Maler.
Chan is Maler Chan that I just created and done.
Chan is done chan right.
Mailer dum chan that I created right there.
Okay, so that creates the variable at the end.
Now I'll just return it.
Okay.
So let's go back up to our main function right here.
I created that mailer and I populated it in the appropriate field in my application config.
Now I just start listening for mail, go after this information, and that should be all I have to do
to send email in the background.
Except, of course.
It will be kind of irritating if I actually ran this program right now and thought everything was going
to work the way that it should.
We have one more change to make over in Mailer w.
And it's this one.
And I want you to think about what's going to happen when I call send mail.
There's one more thing I have to do here, or you're going to run into problems pretty quickly once
you start sending email from your application.
Okay.
So think about that for a moment.
What am I forgetting at this point?
Hopefully you thought of this.
I need to call.
Defer.
M dot.
Wait, dot don't like that.
Otherwise, I'm never going to decrement my weight group and we'll never be able to exit the application
without finding into its processor ID and killing it the hard way.
Okay, so you have to do that.
So at this point, the next thing that will make our lives a little bit easier is to write a helper
function, just a convenience wrapper that I can that will make sending email as simple as possible.
And we'll get started on that in the next lecture, and then we'll try things that.