So we think we have our code set up so that we can send email in the background.
And of course the function that's called ultimately once we send something to a channel, this function
which is running in the background is a go routine listing for mail.
Once it gets something on the app dock mailer, mailer, channel, channel, it fires off send mail
this function down here as its own go routine.
And of course, that means any time I send something to this channel, I probably need to increment
this weight group, which is on the MAILER channel, and we get it from the application config.
We need to increment that by one.
We need to add one to the weight group.
Otherwise, you know, bad things will happen.
And of course, that's something that I personally will forget to do.
So to make life a little bit easier, let's write a little helper routine.
So over here in the CMT Web folder, let's create a new file in there.
I'll just call it Helper Echo and we'll just write a simple wrapper.
So this is in package main.
It will declare one function func with receiver of app pointer to config and we'll just call this,
send the email and it will take one parameter MSG of type message.
Okay?
And it doesn't return anything.
And inside of here, here's where I'll increment my weight group so I know.
Don't forget to do it at dot wait dot add and we'll add one to it.
Okay?
And then we'll just take that message and send it to the appropriate channel.
So app dot mailer, dot mailer channel it, get sent MSG.
And now I have a really easy way of sending email and I don't have to remember to increment the weight
group by one.
Okay, so a dead simple function and we'll use it in the next lecture.