So this time around I want to add some code that will send some email using our new concurrency code.
And I think the simplest place to do that is here in handlers dot go in this function post, log in
page.
If you scroll down here a bit where we have this comment check password, the first thing we do is we
try to get a value invalid password by calling password matches a method that's available on the user
type.
Now the first error check is just to see if something goes wrong.
We don't actually know if we have a valid password or not when this fails, so I'll ignore that one.
But in the second case, if we get valid password back at this point, I know whether or not the user
has typed the correct password.
So what I'll do is if that check fails, if valid password is false, I'll send an email notification.
Now, of course, in production you want to keep track of the number of log ins and only send it after
the third check or something like that.
But I just want to test out my email.
So how do we use our new helper function?
Apks send email?
Well, the first thing we need is a message.
So let's create a message of type message.
Okay, and I'll leave the from name and from from fields empty.
So I'll use the defaults, but I'll send this to the user.
And of course in this case just email.
We have that variable, we get it way back up earlier in this function and we'll give it a subject.
We'll just call this field, log in attempt and we'll give it some data and the data will just be invalid,
log in attempt.
And of course you might put a more specific or more sophisticated message there, but I just want to
try this out.
So now that I have a message variable, all I have to do now is call that helper function app, dot,
send email and hand it to chemistry and that goes off in the background if everything goes according
to plan.
So are we ready to try this out?
Have we done absolutely everything necessary to write good concurrent code?
Think that through, don't run this right now.
Just think that through.
Is there anything else we need to do?
Well, in point of fact, and I'm sure you've thought of this already, back over in main doggo, if
we look here in the main function, we have this listen for shutdown.
And if we go to that function that actually calls another function after we get the appropriate signal,
either a SEGUINTE or a C term and we're ready to shut down the application.
We first call app dot shutdown and this is where we perform any cleanup tasks.
So we have a little bit of cleanup to do at this point.
Our wait group is waiting and that's good, but we actually have some more cleanup to do.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture and then we'll try this code out and see if it actually
functions.