So I'm back in the Mingo file and I'm looking at the function shut down near the bottom of the file.
Of course, this is the one that is called by listen for shutdown.
Okay.
And here's what we need to do.
A little bit of cleanup.
So what kinds of things do we need to do to start with?
And this is you know, you really just being a purist and make sure that things work the way that they
should.
We have that channel dungeon on the mailer, which is in our app config.
So I'm going to send that a true just to tell that go to quit.
So app dot mailer got done can that get sent through.
Okay.
So that's the first thing I'm going to do is quit that routine.
Now, think this through is not the right place to put this.
Ask yourself that question.
Should I quit that go routine that's listening for mail by sending true to the dungeon?
Should I do it here or should I do it later on?
Well, if you think it through, I'm blocking until the weight group is empty.
I probably should take this.
Not here.
It doesn't belong there.
That should happen after I'm finished sending any email.
Okay.
So we send that true.
And then we just close our channels and I'll put that after the comment that says I'm closing the channels
right here.
Now, how do you close channels?
Well, we close apt mailer dot mailer channel.
We close at dot mailer dot error channel and we close app, dot mailer, dot dungeon.
And those are now all closed.
Okay, so now I think we're ready to give this a try.
So what I'm going to do is open my terminal and I'll type make restart in case it's running.
And it wasn't, but it's starting up now and I have my Docker images running in the background, so
I'll go to my web browser and I'll reload this page to make sure it's working.
It is.
And I'll try logging in and I'll try logging in with the wrong information.
You'll notice I have mail hog running in a separate tab over here, and it's currently empty.
There's nothing in the inbox.
So let's log in with the valid email address admin app example dot com.
That'll put in the wrong password.
I'll just type the word wrong and I have invalid credentials.
Now if I go over to Mail Hog, I have my email failed login attempt and there it is, all nicely formatted
as HTML.
Well, it's not that formatted, but it could be how I wanted it to be.
And I also have it as plain text.
So that works exactly as it should.
Okay, let's move on to the next section and before we can do some of the other tasks that we have commented
there in the handlers dog go file, we actually need to implement the logic that allows the user to
register and to subscribe to one of the three services we're offering.
Okay, so we'll get that out of the way in the next lecture and then we'll move on to more concurrent
logic.