So let's begin the process of writing some tests for our code.
And right now, I'm in the Celebrity House package and I'm looking at render don't go the render package.
And here's where I want to start writing tests.
So the very first thing I want to do is inside the render package, I'm going to create a new folder
called test data.
OK.
And inside of that, I'm going to create another folder called views because I don't want to have to
have an application like my app right beside my myself, US project in order to write tests.
So instead, we're going to populate this test data folder with information that simulates exactly what
we needed duplicates the environment of a running application.
OK, so obviously views is where we're going to put our views.
So in there, I'm going to create a new file called Home Page Up Tempo, and it really doesn't matter
what's inside of it.
Hello, world will do the trick.
OK, so now I have a test data folder.
Inside of that, I have to have a vues folder and inside of that I have homed up page duct tape.
The next thing I want to do is write inside the render folder.
Beside the test data folder, I'm going to create another file called set up underscore test, not go.
And that is a special file that we can use to run some function before we run our tests.
But like all good files, it requires a package declaration.
So package render in this case.
And the first thing I'll do is declare a variable VAR views and this will be our jetset.
And we're not going to use it in this lecture, but we'll get to it very soon.
So views is equal to Jet Dot new set, just like we did in Silver Tasker, and we need to populate some
information inside of that.
And the first one is our OS file system loader.
So Jetport New OS File System Loader and we'll pass it to path dot slash test data slash use.
OK.
And just like I did in Celerity Start Go, I'll set jetport in development mode just to make things
a little simpler.
That's my first variable.
The second thing I need is actually need a variable of the type render.
Well, that's easy.
VAR and I'm going to call this test render.
And that's equal to render.
That's the type.
And we'll just populates fields renderer like that, an empty string and root path.
I'll make that equal to an empty string.
And finally, get views.
And of course, that will be equal to the views variable we just created.
And the last thing I'll do in this file for now will be coming back to it later is I'll create a function
called test me.
And this takes one parameter, and this is something that will I'll talk about in a minute, let's get
it set up first is parameters called M of type point or two testing dot m and this is a special function.
Any time I run tests in this directory, if Go sees a file named set up underscore test, don't go with
a function called test main that takes the parameter pointer to testing M.
It'll run that function and then that function will run any tests it finds in that directory.
So this is going to be a really simple one right now.
We're just going to put an OS Typekit exit.
But before you exit.
Run and run and that will run our tests.
OK, so we've got that all set up now.
Now let's finally write some tests.
So again, at the root level of the render folder or create a new file and I will call it render oriented
year, underscored Tesco.
And that's the convention.
First of all, the file doesn't end with underscore test.
Don't go to any test that happened to be in there will be ignored.
And of course, the convention when you're creating these files is to take the name of the file you're
going to test and put underscore test before the don't go.
So this will have a package declaration of render, of course.
And let's write our first test, so I'll test the page function.
This one right over here.
So this is the function I want to test to begin with.
OK, so let's go back to render underscore test.
Don't go and I'll call my function test, render
underscore page.
And it takes one parameter t a pointer to testing dot t.
OK, so what are we going to do here?
Well, to start with, I'm going to need to have a couple of well, some information in order to call
render rendered Go's function page.
So we're going to need a response writer and we're going to need a request or the request is easy.
I can just go R and potentially an error, and our is going to be our pointer to an HDTV http request.
We'll just call HTP Dot New Request and we'll give it the get.
That's the method we're going to call and we need, of course, some URL, but it really doesn't matter
what it is.
So I can literally put some URL like that.
And no, I'm not passing anything to the third parameter because I don't need it.
I just want to request I'm actually going to do anything with the request or not very much anyway.
I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll just generate an error in the testing package to error and I'll just pass it over.
Now I need a response rate, but I don't want a real response writer.
Instead, I'm going to take advantage of TV Test Dot new recorder, but I'll call the variable W because
that's what I've been calling it.
Every time we use a handler that's assigned the value of HTP test dot, you recorder.
So now I have my error and I have my W.
What else do I need?
Well, in order to create or call the page function, I actually need to populate a couple of the members
in the render type, which, if you recall back in set up test, I called a test renderer so I can just
say test renderer, dot renderer and first of all, go file's equals go.
And I also need the root path test renderer dorey path that's going to be equal to not what it was in
my app, but instead we want to go to dot slash test data.
And that's my root path.
No, I can simply call.
Page, so I'll look for an error.
Error is equal to test renderer dot page and hand it.
The things that need to have W are the name of a template.
And if you recall, we already created a really simple file called hold up page dot template and then
for data for it.
Now I'll just say no and no,
and we have an error because I left the parentheses off there.
That's better.
Now we checked for an error if error is not equal to nil, and then.
We'll say to error error rendering, page number.
So let's try this out.
Let's go to our command prompt or terminal change into the render directory.
Clear the screen and tap Go Test Dot.
And that test passed.
Perfect.
All right.
Now let's try rendering a jet page so.
Test renderer Typekit renderer now it's equal to jet, and it's as simple as saying air equals test
renderer.
Typekit page and again, W are code nil and nil, and I can just copy my error check now if I run this
right now.
It should fail because there is no file called homecourt chat.
Let's make sure it fails.
So back to my terminal.
Clear the screen go test dot.
And I should fail.
And it did so now if we put in here in a test out of use, if we create a new file in there called Holmgren
and say hello yet again, it doesn't matter what it is.
Now, when I come down here to my terminal, clear the screen and run go test dot.
It actually succeeds.
OK, that's enough to get started.
We'll pick this up in the next lecture and write some more tests.