So let's keep running tests, but let's make our life a little bit easier.
It can be really difficult to make sure you have good test coverage.
I mean, you can, as I do here in the command prompt, right now I'm in the rental directory.
I can type go test, cover, dash, cover dot and that will tell me the percentage of that particular
file that's covered.
Right now, it's sixty five point five percent of statements.
But which sixty five point five percent of statements and I can figure it out, of course, but let's
make her life easier.
I'm going to go over to the root level of my celebrity house project and create a new file with a capital
m make file all one word and you'll find a copy of this in the course resources for this lecture.
But I have a copy copied in to my clipboard, so let me paste it really simple, and I'm going to delete
this one.
Leave it there, still going to hurt anything.
Eventually, we're going to be building a command line interface, a little command line project.
We're not doing that yet.
So that can just be ignored right now.
We just run that command.
These are the ones we care about test cover and coverage.
OK, so now that I've created that make file and you can download a copy from the course resources for
this lecture, if I go back to my command prompt and go up one level.
So I'm at the root level of the celebrity project.
Now I can type my test and it will run all of the tests for the entire project.
And of course, there's only one to worry about.
But I can also type make cover and that will open up my browser and show me the coverage for all of
the files that I have to test for.
Right now there's only one, and it shows me a hard look.
Here you have this is all the green stuff is being tested.
The red is not.
And you can see that's much clearer for the sorts of things that are being tested.
Perfect.
So let's close that.
That will make our life a little bit easier.
And let's go back to our code and continue reading some tests.
OK, so right now, if I go back to my render test, render underscore test, not go, I'm only testing
the page function.
So let's write some more here.
And you notice that it actually executed and tested some of both of the rest of them.
But let's be explicit in our tests.
So, for example, right now, we're testing situation where we do have a file called homecourt page
template.
So let's read another test copy this or just extend this test.
Really paste that here, and I'll make it go for a non-existent file.
No file.
And in this case, if the error is equal to nil, if it doesn't throw back in error, then this test
should fail.
So we'll see error rendering non existent.
Template and then me do the same thing down here, we can copy this whole thing and paste it down here.
And again, we don't need to make any changes.
We can just put the word jet template here so we know what the error is.
And now if I type make a cover just so I can see what's covered now.
Up Pops, my Web browser, and now you can see if we come down here, it actually is testing this line,
for example, is returning an error when it can't pass a non-existent template and the same thing down
here with Jet.
OK, so that makes things a little better, but I still am not really happy with this.
I want to have explicit tests for all of my functions, so I'm going to come down here below this one
and I will write another test funk test
render.
And I'm going to test render.
Go ahead.
This we have to go page function, key point or two testing DOT.
And this is pretty straightforward.
I can just say W as a son in the value of HTP test that new recorder and R and potentially an error
are assigned the value of http dot.
New request My method is get any URL email if error is not equal to nil.
Then just log there or fire off a T error.
And I can just save a little bit of time by coming up here and copying all of this and coming down here.
And I know this is a redundant test in one sense, but I am a belt and suspenders kind of guy when it
comes to testing.
I want to make sure I test very thoroughly, not 100 percent coverage.
I'm not one of the purists that has to test every edge case, but the vast majority of them.
And that should be sufficient for that one.
And now I can copy this whole thing.
Come down here, taste it again and say, test, render jet page, OK and down here, I don't need the
I need this to be set to jet.
Doesn't matter what route path is, but everything else should be the same.
So if I go into my render directory and say, go test the dot, give me a verbose test.
Everything past perfect.
OK, now there are a few more things we should probably take into account.
Let me just open up that channel again and go up to the root level of the Celebrity Directory and Typekit
make cover and this is where tests become very, very helpful.
So down here, at no point do I call return nil.
OK.
And that's because I'm not actually looking for the situation where renderers not to set to some useful
value.
Clearly, that is the potential for grief.
How can I address that?
Well, let's close this.
What I want to do is go back to page, not to the test necessarily, but go to render find that page
function and down here, let's put a default case in default.
I don't do anything.
OK?
Instead, instead of returning nil here, the only time this code will ever get called is if I don't
have my rendering choice set to go or git because nothing happens with the default.
So at this point, I can say return errors don't, you know, rendering engine specified or whatever
you want the error to be.
OK, so let's test for this now.
Let's go back to our render test and let's say, well, we'll go up to our render page here.
And the very end of this file, I can say test renderer dot renderer is equal to an empty string or
fish, anything other than go and jet.
OK.
And now I can do this again.
I can say, Copy this, paste it in here.
Make sure it doesn't have an invalid template name.
Home exists, so we'll go with that.
So we're testing our render page with home.
So this should now have a different result.
Let's type go test dashboard.
And I'm in the wrong directory, see the render go test Dash v Dot.
Everything passed, and that's because air is equal to nil.
So is that the result that we want?
Well, let's go back here and look at rendered out go again.
Figure this out.
So we come into page we we switch on the value of renderer.
If we have go, we do this.
If we have jet, we do this.
If we have nothing, then it just falls through and says return errors and no rendering engine specified.
So back at our render test, let's figure out exactly what we want to do here.
We set our test renderers, renders and nothing.
So that default case should be the one that's executed and we expect error and error to be returned.
So at this point, we do want to say error is equal to nil and we want to say no error returned
while rendering non-existent.
With with invalid renderer specified, that seems to make the most sense.
OK, now let's clear a terminal and go up to the celebrities package and type make cover and see if
that final line in the page template or page function is actually covered.
And it is.
So we have 100 percent coverage for that function, right?
OK, now clearly there's some other things we want to test here.
At some point, we want to handle passing data to the template.
We want to handle passing data to jet templates and all that sort of thing.
We haven't actually tried doing any of that yet, so we'll come back to this in a bit.
But that's sufficient to get us started with testing in any case.