So we're coming along with her tests.
But if you look at the in the render underscored test, don't go file inside the render folder inside
the Celebrity House package.
This test render underscore page function.
It's a bit awkward.
We start the function, then we test one thing, then we test another, then we test another, and this
will get long over time.
So let's improve this.
Let's take advantage of a really common convention in the go world known as table tests, and they're
relatively easy to use.
So what I'm going to do is right here just before this test render page function, I'm going to create
a variable and I will call it page data page because I'm testing the page function and data because
it's data for the test and it will be a slice of struct.
And the members of that struct will be name, which is a string.
And that's the name of the test, just to name that makes it meaningful to me.
So I know I know which test failed.
If something goes wrong and then we'll have the render render URL, which is also a string.
And of course, that will be go or jet or an empty string or something else.
Then what template should the test run when we run a given test and then also is a string, then we'll
have is there an error expected when I run this test?
Should error be nil or not?
So that's a Boolean.
And finally, what error message do we want to display, which will be a string?
OK, now we've defined that struct, let's populated in one step.
So each entry here will be an individual test.
So the first one will be just test to go pitch test rendering a go page.
And that's just my name.
What renderer do we use?
Well, obviously go.
What template should we render?
Well, the only one we have is home, so home seems like a good one.
Do we expect an error?
No, we don't.
So false.
And what should the error message been?
Say error rendering.
Go template.
So there's our first test.
Now we can duplicate this and say go page underscore no template.
So this will be the test where we try to render a go page, a go template that doesn't exist.
So again, a render will be go and.
We're not going to try to render the home page will render no dash file something that doesn't exist.
And do we expect an error?
Well, in this case, true.
And now let's change this to no error rendering non-existent template when one is expected now to save
a little time.
Our next two tests following the logic we have right now would be exactly the same thing.
But for jet templates.
So jet page and the render is just an error rendering jet template and then jet page.
No template.
The renderers jet.
We change this to nonexistent jet template.
And I'll put the word go up here just to be consistent.
Now our last one and I'll just duplicate this line would be rendering with an invalid renderer.
So invalid render engine.
And we'll make this fool.
It could be an empty string, but Fu does the same trick and we make sure this is an actual template.
Stay home and we'll change the error.
We do expect an error, so we want a true and we'll change this to no error
rendering with non-existent
template engine.
So now we have this data and we're not using it.
So let's just come down here inside.
Test, render underscore page.
And let's use that.
So I'll just give myself some blank lines because most of that's going to get deleted before too long.
What we do here is a for loop for.
We don't care about the index, but we do care about the current test and I'm going to call it E!
Is equal to range page data.
Now inside of this, what do we want to do?
Well, we still need a renderer and we still need a request and a response.
So I'll just cut all of this and paste it in here and fix it.
So let's move this over.
So this line can stay the same, we don't care what the URL is down here, we get a recorder, that's
good.
Our test render is not hard coded to go and that becomes E Dot renderer.
OK, so now we have our request, our response and our celerity variable set up.
So what do we want to do next?
Well, right here, let's just cut this a cut and paste because we do in fact, want to call the page
on the test, render a variable.
We want and we want to call the function page.
But this becomes its template.
And down here, we can't say if error is not equal to nil, that doesn't make any sense.
So let's delete that.
Instead, let's say if either error expected that we'll do one thing for expecting to get an error else,
we'll do something else.
And if we're expecting an error but don't get one, then we say if error is equal to nil.
And that's the condition where our test fails.
So we can just say T-Dog error and I'll use error f because I use a format string and I'll just say
string colon, space, string, colon space string, and I'll replace those with a name, the name of
the test.
So I know what test failed e dot error message, whatever error message should be supplied.
And then lastly, error dot error, which is a string.
OK.
And down here, it's almost the same.
Let me copy this and paste it in here.
But the difference is if error is not equal to nil.
So we're not expecting an error, but we get one.
And of course, we don't care about this and we don't care about this.
So let's see if we get this right.
Sometimes I get things backwards.
If we expect an error, but we don't get one.
Yeah, I got those backwards.
I always do that.
Let me cut this and paste that in here and cut this and paste it in here.
That's better because if you think it through logically, if error is equal to nil, then there's no
error to display.
And if error is not equal to nil, then there is an error to display.
So with that one change, we can get rid of all of this and format things just to make things a little
cleaner.
And you can see this is a lot less code.
And the nice thing is, of course, if I want to add additional test cases, I just add them up here
to my data variable to my page data variable and they automatically run.
So let's make sure we got this right.
Let's open our terminal and go into render and type go test dot.
And everything is fine, and let's make sure it's going to fail.
So let me change this to say.
I'll make this one home, too, and run the test again, and this time it should fail and give me a
meaningful message.
And it does render test go, so it says go page error rendering, go template.
And it says no such file or directory perfect.
So let's get rid of that too.
So we don't break our test.
And as you can see, table tests make your life ever so much easier.
You wind up with easier to read tests.
It's easier to add, modify or delete individual test cases.
And it just takes up less room on the screen, which is always a good thing.