So now we're going to take a look at a second crawl solution Daniel put together and Daniel I've been
super impressed by the code the student has become the master and I really love the concept that we
all have multiple intelligences and and that together we're stronger than we are individually.
And I could wax poetic about this for a long time as you probably heard me do in the past but I just
really love the solutions you created here and excited for you.
Excited for you dear colleague friend fellow adventure in programming excited for you to see the solution
so take it away.
Daniel.
Yeah so.
So we discovered on the first one kind of after running it that it only found 19 solution tweets because
the screen was an infinite scroll and so it wasn't able to actually get all off the page all at once.
And so go call we didn't doesn't really have too much of it away to really solve that.
It's not going.
It's not actually running a web server so it can't run the javascript.
When you scroll down enough to actually like load more stuff.
So for some sites this is the end.
There's not really much you can do about it for Twitter though there ended up being a solution.
I do want to zoom in.
Open up the dev tools and go to the Network tab and I refreshed the page so you can be loaded up and
I filter the Network tab to x H R which is basically requests that have happened not as part of creating
the page initially but of a script is making these requests way scroll down to the infinite scroll you
can see the requests the the Web browser is making to get the additional data and so if I click on one
of these requests I can actually examine the you URL that it's making the request to which has some
parameters.
After this question mark including one that's called Max position with a big long code on seconds so
you you got as you infinite scrolled you were looking at the network tab and you had it filtered for
X H.R. and then it was showing you the gets are coming through and then you clicked on the file is that
right.
Yeah.
And then are there any any anything on the line.
Okay.
Anything on the line.
And then over there it shows you the header and and so click on one of the requests and examine you
are also go.
So go over to the header go to headers area I'm just making notes here and then you examine you are
all sensible rats and you're looking at your request you were out here I can see is made up has a query
parameter after the question mark Yeah there's a several query parameters separated by the ampersand
but the one that seems to change when I click between multiple ones of these each one is basically the
same parameters except for Max position that sounds good and so Max position appears to be changing
every time to some new value but it's some value that I can't guess just by looking at it.
So it's gonna need some experimentation to actually figure out.
Besides this I also look at to see if I go over to Paramus I can actually see the parameter Firefox
at least has a brand's tab which shows the query string parameters in a nicer view.
I realize chrome probably has something similar somewhere too.
That's nice because when you click between them you could kind of really see the differences that Max
position changes.
That's cool.
If so then the other thing to look at here immediately is response takes a while to actually load the
response see the response is Jason data and I can look at this I can see that the response here for
this middle of these three requests the browser made it's got a min position which this Min position
string matches the max version string for the very next call if I if I if I take this.
This main position string and I go over to the next call it makes and look in the parameter list this
Max position is an exact match so for each call it tells you with the max position is going to be for
your next call to kind of get more data a second it's so there's also it has more items she can tell
which is I think could be useful to say Oh I'm done I finished loading.
So this one versus over here this one has no more items.
All right so it looks promising you're looking at you're looking at men position looked promising in
Max position and then also has more items right.
Yep.
And.
And then the max position in Max positions and parameters becomes your main position in the next call.
So yeah your main position is what they Twitter gives me and I give that as Max this next call so they
give me I'm in position and then I give them that as an expedition.
OK.
So then the final thing they give that seems so they've got this new limb a little bit confused on that
so call 0 comes in and on the first call for scale on the first call.
So I don't I can't actually see a first very first call I've already got they've already got my prams
list already has a max for this shot ready.
OK but its response has a min position and it takes a while to flip over to a response tab for some
reason it has a main position and that's DC.
And so that men position there they go over to the next call down and I go to Paramus this is that it
comes your main position because your max position does until it makes sense.
It seems like so I think it's max would be the end of the last call which then become the men of the
next call.
I think it's more I'm not actually sure why they call it that just so happen to be what Twitter ended
up calling them.
So maybe it confuses people who are trying to do this.
Maybe.
Doesn't it seem kind of like more intuitively your max on your last call be your man on the next call.
Yeah somewhat.
Yeah.
So the final thing that was looks interesting is this items H2 email which looked from a quick examination
just eyeballing it looks like the h email that gets put into this list directly so if I can just pass
this a shemale it's probably got the tweets that I'm looking for.
Oh nice.
So this is all.
So just just quick examining.
So one final thing I want to do before I do this is if I go back to this you or L here I'll just copy
the entire euro and I go search for a robot's t t value.
Save this for the next video.
I think that was a good video just crawling infinite scroll.
Okay.
Or you think robots he's pretty quick.
I like keeping things to concepts so that's that's crawling infinite scroll and inspecting the all the
information that's coming back as you scroll.
Using dev tools.
Anything you want to summarize about that or say more about that.
Not every page will have an understandable request response like some websites will basically are unprofitable
for casual crawlers.
There's always a way.
I mean the page has to fill itself up somehow but some sites will just be a little too convoluted to
have it work.
So in this case it ended up working.
It's got some pretty nice requests responses that seem understandable enough that we could probably
figure it out so we can keep going.
That really gives it a lot of respect and appreciation for what search engines have to deal with.
AK particularly Google right to be able to catalog all the information out there on the web.
They need to be able to automate away that even as sites are changing their code can grab the information
so they're they're probably running servers so that it's just you know they could run that JavaScript
and get.
They probably rolling on to do all that.
Yeah they're probably running some into some full web browser interactively for all right good.
See you the next video.
Yeah.