All right.
So solution number two.
Let's take a look at the code.
So solution number two actually starts very similar to solution number one.
I've got a a site you are all constant which is where I'm going to be crawling at.
In this case it's the crawl from this from the API calls from Twitter instead of the euro for the page
so the U URL from the API calls is is gone.
I hear in this conversation there are those that page is just status.
So we've got two files here.
We've got to go direct and scrape go eat.
I want to do this this is my go collie.
OK.
There's go calling God.
Yes.
It's the first solution.
All right.
So let's finish in second one.
Yes.
So starts off the same thing kind of just the general.
This is what site I'm going to be calling.
This makes it easy for me to change the URL if I decide I want to cross some other conversation at some
other point and then I got the tweet because my overall look what I'm looking to have at the end is
a slice of tweets.
So there's a tweet struct which is the exact same structure from up here.
So but then I actually start getting into the differences.
So this one goes straight in to go call and just scrapes this one.
I have to do a lot of stuff myself instead.
So what I put together is actually separated out into a bunch of functions that did stuff and in this
one you are not doing.
Go call you got go query.
Yes.
And this one I end up using a library called Go query to pass the.
The response from the.
From Twitter.
The responses had that items H2 e-mail items each e-mail.
And so I'm using the library called Go query to pass that.
OK.
So in go query is basically a search library built on top of an X HDMI out package from the extended
libraries.
All right I'm orientated now so I'm going to save my questions and let you drive through and then I'll
give you my questions in the next video.
So.
So go queries thing.
So I organized my code basically into there's three functions and the main function.
The first function makes a single request to this API the end takes in a single request.
The second function makes all the requests needed to get all of the items using the first function and
then this third function actually passes this items H2 email into tweets so the first one makes a single
request it takes in what the current Max parse it a position a parameter is and it will return a conversation
response which is this struct here which is got those three values from the response from the API that
I considered interesting and potentially useful.
So.
So I just say destruct here as a switch.
It's going to be I've got the Jason tags to match the name exactly to the Jason that they're responding
with.
And I'm using slightly shorter names for how they refer to them in my code doesn't really matter too
much.
You can name what you want to hear.
So I'm using your old values your ls one of the standard library things values is basically a map for
query parameters and we'll take care of everything related to the query parameters including encoding
it to fit you properly in such.
So make an empty programs map and then looking at this at the headers tab here for this request there
are or programs tab you can see there are four parameters in the query string these three are the same
every time I make the call.
So I just have those three they're there and they're just exactly as they are being used before.
And I've got Max expedition set to the input parameter because that can be changing every call and I
hazard a guess that probably the very first time this happened you make the call to this end point you
want a max position of empty string which ended up working out when I tried it out.
So it's trial and error they just ended up working first try so now they've got prams filled out.
I need to create I make the full euro the full euro is the sight euro for up here and then a question
mark to separate from the base to the create parameters and then the encoded parameters query query
parameter query include encoded parameters.
So I've got the full year output to make the request to this elegant.
Let's get the full Euro to make requests request to the ACP package from the standard library.
You can just make a request to that end point to get you'll get a response and an error.
Need to check the error.
And I'm adding in more detail to the error if there is one.
So I can have more detail on my error message if my error happened when I was trying to get conversation
data
defer closing the body of that response because you always need to whenever you get a response make
an HP request.
You need to close body.
The response is.
Straight up going starin library each we get in class.
Yeah.
Very standard.
The error from making requests in the going sphere library is just a network error.
So you also need to check the response the status code manually so all of these requests always respond
with the two hundred.
So I just do.
Check if it's not status OK.
Two hundred make an error throw back an error and I display what the error actual terrorist errors as
code what is the number form and I use the standard library HB status text to convert from the code
to the actual string.
That's equivalent to that code.
So two hundred OK over 400 beat that quest.
So that that way when I get the error message I can see what it actually ended up coming up with.
It's the response then after that the response I have the response at this point the source code was
correct.
After this point and the response is Jason encoded to back the response tab which takes a bit will sing
and song until it comes up.
Well it just came out.
So Jason.
So it's Jason response data.
So I create my response object and use the Jason decoder new decoder decode on it standard that again
add more detail to my error message that happens.
And then after this point I just return that conversation response.
So let's keep this video just kind of analyzing an introduction and then also analyzing make conversation
response and we'll pick up in the next video where we look at the next functions.
But the conversation response shows that data structure again that's right here.
It's got the moon position the more and the T.
We've got all that each team L in there and then we're gonna do something with that each team.
All right.
And we have them in position and more which we could pass in to future things we need to somewhere.
Yes.
Is that correct.
Cool.
All right.
So this one was looking at a conversation response function that Daniel created to deal with this.
This makes one request that Twitter API Yeah and then we'll pick it up in the next video.