So the next function is to get all the conversation parts because it needs to make multiple requests
to get the entire conversation.
So I've got a function to make a single request which will get however many responses.
I think trial and error determined it was about nine tweets each time but that it's not necessarily
guaranteed.
So I want to get all of them though so I've made this function get conversation to basically call the
make conversation request multiple times until I have all the information I need.
So that Max position mint position thing is create a variable called continue code to kind of manage
that because basically that's what it is.
It's a code that Twitter gives me to continue the request for more conversation parts.
So so I'm just calling it continue code.
This is basically the max position mint position thing and then what I'm looking to make is I just want
the items H2 email over all the other to do are kind of details for getting more information.
But the one I'm actually interested in is the items H2 email which is a string.
So I'm looking to actually return is just a slice of all the items H2 email that I get.
So.
So that's my response type and that's.
And so I create here messages which is a slice of string.
So the index zeroes can be the very first I make the request.
Next one will be the items they show off the second time and make the quest index to be the third time
make the request items each time out.
So that's what messages is going to be is the item that is the list of all the items H.G. knows.
Yeah and then I infinite for loop just forever until until broken in each time through the loop very
first thing I do is I call my conversation request with the continued code which starts off as empty
string.
And so that will make one request and that would give me back as a response this conversation response.
Struct
and if there is some sort of error I add additional information to the error and they return it which
bracing out the infinite for loop and out of the function backup to ever call this function once I've
got the response I can use response to H email was what was itemization email was up in the data structure.
H team l It's like items h t mail from the Jason so I can just add that to the messages.
Slice then if there are no there's not any more I can break out of the infinite loop and and go to just
returning all those messages that I found if there is more I update my continued code variable with
with what Twitter said the main position was and the robots that takes Steve said make waited a second
between each request.
So I just say time sleep time second to wait one second before it goes back to the top.
The for loop
that's awesome.
I was taking notes.
It didn't capture all that but basically continued code so I'm just going to do a little reiteration
here and read through it and you help me make sure I grabbed it you can t code obviously being set to
an empty string and get conversation.
Start at the top takes in takes in it returns a slice of string and an error in continued code.
Empty string and messages will be where you store all your e-mail and that's just gonna be a slice of
strings.
And then you make conversation requests and you're passing in continued code.
So if you look at the signature make conversation request up above it is wanting your max position and
what we are what we saw is that Max position when we are looking at the Twitter API the max it was the
men they gave back.
I'm in position and we call and we use that as Max position so he came back and then position and then
you called it Max position.
So in the MAX position was what.
And then Max position was what you get that you'd call it Max mission when you gave it back.
OK so maybe they think about that logically like Max position is the starting point.
That's that that's been ably the way they're thinking about it all right.
Possibly I'd probably add one hundred tweets and and they gave back men position and that becomes our
max.
Yeah.
That's just thrown.
That would've confused me.
Yes.
Still confused.
But so are you passing the continued code and the continued code that you're passing and roll back up
to the function the make conversation request is Max position which ends up being in the query unit
and that's in the parameter so that just says this is where we're starting from this point forward.
And you.
That's where you took the guess.
You hazard a guess.
I loved that phrase you use.
He hazard the gas of empty string band and then you get a response back from a conversation request
and that response make conversation request returns a response an error and the response is that entire
data structure that you had up above which was a conversation response and then more and and then h
t Mal and Co.
All right good.
Then more and each team out and and then that's your response back and then you pinned your message
you response each female straight forward.
And if there's nothing more you're done with this for loop and then continue code as response men position
and that becomes your max that you pass and this thing that Twitter uses.
And then just in just a second week because they requested that their robots just do it because that
was easy enough to implement and be respectful.
And so what I just did there too is something that I find myself often doing When people explain code
to me particularly if it's code where like okay I'm not just instantly grasping it like I kind of have
to.
Somebody will talk through it and then I got to talk through it back to them and and kind of like make
sure that I'm hearing it correctly and so I'm sharing that just inadvertently I did it because it's
like I want to make sure I understand this and then maybe add me going through it.
I'll help you understand it but not only might that be valuable to you but it might also be valuable
for you to see how I go about understanding code and so you can use that as a learning tool.
So part of what my job is as a teacher is to not only bring you information but also to help you learn
how to learn that information too often in academia.
They just give information right and expect you to learn it.
They don't ever show you how to learn.
And so I want you to also know how to learn effectively and so this is a technique that I use to help
me learn.
And so what you might do.
Here's the takeaway what you might do is you're going through this course when you hear things like
that after you watch it.
You could stop the video.
You can look at the code and then you can explain it to yourself to make sure you got it.
And in doing that like literally talk it out loud.
They call it rubber duck debugging right.
But you know you could talk to your water bottle your dog your computer screen but just say it out loud
and talk it through and then that engages different parts of the brain when you are verbalizing stuff
your brain's using different areas when you're hearing the words that you spoke.
Your brain is using different areas and then that help you know you're actually exercising it.
So that's going to help and bad that material help you understand this code more quickly so learn faster
you'll remember it longer.
So that's something to help you learn the code.
All right.
Because the our goal here isn't just to be like Hey look at the awesome code.
We're awesome.
Our goal here is for you to gain skills.
And that's what this is all about.
All right.
That's that's that's a good conversation and the next one we're going to this one is actually passing
that person over go back man.
This is beautiful.
I love what you created.
All right we'll see in the next meeting.
Anything you want to add.
No.
See in the next video.