So the third function that got made was a one to pass those aged e-mail messages that I've been that
I'm getting back from the API so the conversation turns a slice of strings which is each one is one.
Each team mail chunk so I created this function pass shemale which reads one of those chunks and returns
a slice of tweets.
All the tweets it found in that chunk of each team.
And so this particular function uses that go query library that I found online to actually examine within
that H2 e-mail.
So some way to examine each e-mail go length has a standard has an extended package X net each team
email I believe which show it has passing HD email.
Yeah.
This go green up.
So I just you know or I go dark and then each team out so you've heard of like the X-Men.
And like what is his name Zab year Professor Zambia and savior Xavier.
Like I said over 30.
Now maybe this is the go equivalent.
This is like where all the special really you know not yet in the standard library stuff lives.
So yeah here it is going forward X net HD email.
This package has all sorts of functions for passing through H.M. as you read it in or just passing through
a complete HD military but doesn't really let you have anything to search through it.
So the go query library is a search through meaning here is all of your Dom.
Yeah.
You know now when you get to this piece get to that piece it's not as it's not as easy with access to
your mouse.
Here with this x age you had to find a particular node you'd have to go searching through okay.
This node is a p tag of some sort.
Now you get to look at its shot children and siblings and find the particular one you're looking for
they personally call that.
So you go all the way down through the structure something.
Yeah.
So.
So my first I start I tried started doing this I originally was going through this directly and I started
getting into a stack overflow errors because the recursion was getting too deep.
Yeah.
And so I went I wondered if there's someone else had actually made something already.
And so I eventually came out to this go query library.
And how did you find that actually went through.
Go Kelly go collie.
When I looked at there on each team malfunction it wanted a go query selector and it had a link to that
go query library separately go go call the call he actually uses go query for searching your dom itself.
So that's almost like receiving you know it's like I don't know I'm not.
It's like authentication validating that somebody is a good person because they're a friend of somebody
that you know is a good person like OK.
Colleagues use it we know that's a good open source package.
And if they're including this and that's probably a good thing to include because this has had a lot
of eyes on it.
If you look at and get there's a lot of people who've started this and so that's one way you could sort
of vet whether or not co you're using getting back to that Russ Cox article.
You've got to trust the code that use if a lot of people are working on it and looking at it then hopefully
you could be assured that it's not gonna bad mojo in it is the word ice associate the rock and roll
by the way so I'm not a coding phrase so.
So what's the final.
Go go query similar to how I did code Collie I found there examples to kind of figure out what the functions
I should be looking at are new docket from reader find text and then I went to the go dark end and started
going through the actual functions their new document reader gets the document a document is also a
selection and so I can go through the selection functions that I could do the at the find find returns
and other selection.
And then there's texting each are in here as well.
So I so again whenever I find a new library I usually a lot of functions.
There are.
I just read every day so I wouldn't want to go looking through the go doc myself to figure out how to
use this.
But luckily I didn't have to because I had this example to kind of put me at the most important ones
and I could look for alternate ones if I needed something else.
Pat Epley so my code here for past age CML takes one of those ACL messages wear your seat back to Twitter
and you just go query to find all the tweets in one in that one message so since to go query needs me
to get the data to pass the documents from a reader I use the strings new reader function to convert
this string into a string reader.
Whereas past each e-mail being called in Maine and we're gonna get to that in a second.
Right.
Yes that's where.
Pass each emails call me.
And then just I got to say my questions the next video.
Keep you on.
Yeah right.
So.
So now I've got.
My message is now a straight reader.
And so now I can use go queries new document from reader.
Now I've got to go create document potentially an error while passing.
Now I create my slice of tweets that I'm going to be using as my response.
Now in my document I'm going to find all the tweets tweet class.
This is just the exact same as the previous.
Go call a version I'm looking for the DOT tweet class for each tweet.
It'll call this function with the index of which time it's calling this the first time it found its
second time it found it and the selection for that one tweet and then from that one tweet I'm going
to append a new tweet to the tweets list and the selection I can use the find function to find account
group full name and I want the text from that account group username I want the text from that tweet
text I want the text format and so that's the three values looking forward to put to fill out a tweet
and then after I've done this each has finished calling the function for every tweet.
Now my T S slice is now complete and I can just return that I found all the tweets from this message.
Genius I love it.
All right I'm going to have some questions on that and I'm going to walk through it make sure I understood
it but we're gonna do that in the next video because I like keeping these videos as short as possible
so we'll see in the next video.
Got anything where you want to add to this one new.
Great.
See the next video.