All right.
So now we're going to I'm going to kind of just make sure I understand this pass.
SHE MOUTHS.
So the first thing they're in line 78 you're passing in message it of its passing in is a variable that's
a type string.
And that that variables and message.
So show me just you to jump ahead and see.
Pass each e-mails used in what's being passed in and so pass each e-mail is when you you have range
ranging over your responses and your responses come from get conversation.
And so get conversation is that first to the second one is the second one that gets all the conversations
right and then the first one the first function we had was make conversation requests and the next ones
get all get conversations.
All right.
So get conversations returns that slice of string and then scroll down to the main and then get conversation.
Gives us that response which is a slice of string and then we range over that slice of string.
And for each wanting passing a message which is a string.
So that's just the way that each team now that was down there in depth tools that we saw.
All right good.
And so then you take that each e-mail and you say we've got to turn this into a reader so you wrap strings
reader around it and use go query new document reader and again you've got all this sort of from the
example that turns it into a selection or whatever new document reader right then gives you access to
all those other methods.
And so just go back to New document from reader for a second in the documentation and new document reader.
Right.
You got all those new document from reader gives you a document pointer to a document and the pointer
to a document in there.
We have a pointer to a selection since we have a pointer to selection.
We have all of those methods.
And so now we have access to all those methods is that correct.
Yes.
So back to the code.
Yeah they're all the methods.
We have the doc and then we just check that error and your error is return nil fund error K and returning
an error if there's problems passing it up through chain of execution and then you slice tweets told
all your tweets and now you could just use those functions you got this kind of from the example you
looked at zero.
You got work and find and each you pass all that in and just return your slice of tweets when it's all
done.
And that does that for each.
Each.
Each conversation basically right.
Yeah.
The other slice of conversation.
So you're doing that with the range in Maine.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Totally got it.
So this person just won.
One response gets passed with this.
And so then you have to put together all the slice of tweets back together at the end cool.
And I was going to save this this question for you know and this reflection for kind of questions at
the end.
I think it's a good point to say this but like I I'm excited that I even understand the code and being
able to understand the code like like literally like little endorphins go off in my head when I understand
it's like a Las Vegas sort of you know no endorphin positive reinforcement kind of thing like goo I
got it I understood it right.
And I think that's also I get that when I actually write code you know and it works it's like oh I got
it it works like there's a little bit addictive quality that programming for me and I know it's like
that for other people it's like it's pleasing when you create a solution when you engineer something
that really works well it's pleasing when you can understand something that somebody else engineered
that works well.
And and so but that's I also just wanted to kind of point out that those are the steps in being able
to do.
First thing is to be able to understand right.
Like first you got to see it and then you got to be able to understand how it was done and then eventually
you're going to be able to do it.
So just take heart wherever you are on that process.
If you look at this and you're like well a little bit overwhelming or if you look at this and you're
like Okay I understand it don't think I could write it like that is the process that you go through
to eventually being able to write it.
You know you think of other fields other industries you know like whether it's you know soccer you know
and people saw you know Pele do certain things and then they went and they practice it and then they
were able to do it.
But at first they couldn't.
And you know or or music you know you hear somebody else play something and you're like wow.
Then you go practice it and eventually you can do that too.
But the first thing is being able to see somebody do it and understand that they're doing it.
And and then applying yourself to it being able to do it yourself eventually you can do it to but how
long did it take you to be able to write write code like this since you're 13.
That was their teammates.
Started coding.
So that's that's a long time.
And but so it takes some time and.
But it's 13 years ago actually.
So my life.
Yeah.
But it comes if you apply yourself.
All right.
That's the low reflection when you have anything where you want to add.
Not about this but dreading I'm just jumping to Maine.
Yeah.
All right.
Let's do that.
See you at Expedia.