OK.
Let's see main.
And where it all comes together and then also run it and see you see the results.
Yeah.
So func main in a function like this where or in a program like this where you've got well-defined functions
with easy meanings main often becomes just hooking the multi yet.
And so that's exactly what this mean is it.
It calls get conversation to get all the convert to get the whole conversation.
That's that second function that I've got after this I've got the slice of strings.
First is the response I'm going to need to get all the tweets here.
So I create the tweets variable and then I arrange over all those h t strings in the for loop.
And each time through I call pass h t email to pull out all the tweets from that particular chunk of
HMO.
And then after that I append all those tweets into the bigger tweets slice and I'm using the dot dot
dot very attic to expand out this slice of tweets into this append periodic function so that I can put
this slice into this slice
so once that S is for loops done I now have a complete slice of all the tweets in this tweets variable
and so in this case I'm just going to use Jason Marshall indent to put it into Jason format in it with
enough whitespace to be more readable and I print out printed all that Jason out and then I must get
a printout.
How many tweets I eventually came up so awesome.
So if I run this go run script go it's going to take a little bit because it's gotta wait a second between
each call Twitter so it takes longer than call which is only making one call overall then it's done.
I now have 60 tweets and if I look at here my bottom ones see ICD automation server they go back to
Twitter and scrolling all the way down past it.
They want to do that scrolling all the way down past all the infinite scrolls spacebar is a nice way
to do that you know that depends on the page.
I don't want her typing in inbox true.
So the very bottom would see ICD automation server.
So that's after all the scroll.
Oh that's awesome well done.
Let's jump back to the code for a second.
You anything more you want to say there is room for expansion on this.
If I look here some of these replies have replies to them themselves that are not actually being pulled
in.
Try to find one
like here you've got another comment here and it's got its own reply underneath it.
Yeah.
So that's not being pulled in but that's not being pulled in from here either.
So but getting into that would then require much more complicated code to then follow that pathway down
and it seems reasonable not just to get kind of what was showing up on this main list here.
So that's all I ended up making nice.
So just so I'm going to do my little talk through get conversation gives you that get conversation scroll
back up to that slice of string.
There we go.
And and the slice of string on get conversation is going to be all the tweets everything right.
Yeah well the L.A. Daily amount and then we range over all that.
There we go in passing the message and we get past that.
We get that and we're going to pin that to our slice of tweet and and then we get all of our tweets
and then we're just going to put them to Jason and then we get a bite slice.
We turn that into a string so that we could print it nicely and then we see the length.
Yes.
That's all straight for awesome.
That's really well done.
It's fun to see.
And we got a little bit more for you in the next couple of videos.
Anything more to say about this.
For reals this time of year.
All right.
See the next video.