All right.
So just a couple of reflections that came up.
Sorry I STARTED OFF BY HERE THINKING BUT THE FIRST reflection was in the code used at Infinite Loop
and infinite loops have a bad reputation in programming rightly so.
So we truly are in an infinite loop then that never ends and your program hangs there and that's it.
You're in an infinite loop.
And so I have two anecdotes to share about infinite loops which I'll do at the end.
But this is not truly an infinite loop because you've got to break into that break is just a go laying
way of life.
It's actually pretty theoretical.
Most languages with loops will have break statements systems so yeah.
But it's not truly an infinite loop.
Yeah.
So.
So the.
You can have.
You can have a loop that's infinite so long as you've got a clearly defined place where it's intended
to end.
Yeah.
So I just wanted to iterate there make it clear there that this is not an infinite loop.
Even though the terminology that's being colloquially used is here's an infinite loop.
It's not it's not infinite loop because infinite loops and programming are bad.
Yeah right.
That's my understanding as I understand.
Yeah yeah.
So.
So one way to be safer here is this loop is dependent on Twitter giving back responses that I expect.
So if I wanted to be safer I could change this into a more standard I 0 is less than say 50 plus plus.
And that way it'll call Twitter up to 50 times so if Twitter just stood like start sending back garbage
data and make you always looping forever of everything I would limit myself to 50 call nine before exiting
nice so always have a clearly defined end point.
So this is actually probably better programmatically.
Yeah maybe you just never get that break.
Yeah yeah.
Could be that Twitter never actually says there's no more right.
So yeah oh that's a good good exploration.
Yeah.
More to say about that.
Nope.
Wait for the 50 is there any way to sort of like there's no way to get the length of it all before x.
We don't know such is infinite x.
You just have to say look we'll grab up to this many Yeah and then the next question I had is just kind
of like the design of this program what was the process that you used for designing it.
Do you have a process that used when you started thinking about this to modular eyes or I call it chunking
it up like to break it up into chunks.
What was your thought process for how you designed this code.
Architect of its structure.
I made this function.
I started off by starting to make a request.
Just a single request to get something from the yet from Twitter in my main function.
I just started writing in here.
But when I wrote deferred statement was when I decided Oh this should probably be its own function because
I want this by the clothes when I'm done passing off the Jason.
Not when I'm done with the entire program.
Nice.
And so that was a good good indicator to me when I said defer this should probably go to functions like
a more closely control when that defer is going to happen.
Because I want the deferred to end after the chase decode it because I don't need the body.
After that point so once I had that into a single standalone function.
Now I'm thinking about functions.
So when I go into the next part What do I need to do next.
I'm gonna need to call this bunch of times that's actually getting a little complex.
I start writing that in Maine as well I go oh I've got a big large for loop in here that's got a bit
of complexity behind when I'm exiting it.
Maybe I should pull that into its own function to just to make it more easily used nice and so that
became this.
And then when I started doing the pass HRT now I actually had that and a function by itself already
I figured passing each time I was going to be complex enough be easier than I expected but it's still
a little more complex I'd want the main function.
And then all that was left here for my main function was both just hooking it all together.
The only complex see the main function actually has this one for loop independent.
Nice I like your thought process that's similar.
Hi.
Do I just start trying to solve the problem and then when the code starts getting large in Maine I'm
like okay what components makes sense to kind of like have them be independent.
And I think it's also interesting that you've got one thing that needs to be done over and over and
so you said well that one thing that needs to be done which is to get you know the individual chunks
of tweets for each infinite scroll that will be its own thing.
Get it here get it here get it here and now I need something that's going to use that over and over.
Do it here and here and here.
So the first one where you get each one is I get conversation requests make conversation requests and
then they get conversation gets all of the all of those right and that's where I make conversation requests
gets called over and over and over until there's no more.
And then pass each email gets called out of Maine to deal with deal with all of those right.
Yes.
Yeah.
So that's a I think another piece to look at in terms of how it's structured.
One thing being called over and over and over.
Nicely done Daniel anything else to add has forgotten forgotten.
Welcome to the club.
If it's important we'll tell you about it.
The next videos.
Hey anecdote I forgot to tell you the anecdotes about infinite loop.
So if you look up the address for Apple Computer and I just got to make sure I'm actually recording
my screen.
We have been doing the thing on my screen Apple Corporation headquarter headquarters.
The address is is Where's the address headquarter.
1 Infinite Loop Cupertino California sets the address for Apple Computers.
Interestingly Facebook address is one hacker way.
So that's a interesting anecdote about infinite loops I forgot to tell you about when we're talking
about infinite loops and then the other deal that I want to share with you is a joke into the joke is
about the programmer who died in his apartment and he didn't show up for work for like two weeks.
And so the police went to the apartment they opened and they found the programmer dead in the shower
holding a bottle of shampoo and on the bottle the instructions said what hair.
Lather rinse repeat.
I tell you that joke.
And so you just kept doing that died.
So that's that's an infinite loop.
All right.
We'll see the next video.
We'll see what it's going to be we're going to talk about it.
See you the next video.