So now we're gonna do a little bit of analysis of all of the tweets and we're gonna just do a basic
word count and then count how many times each word has appeared in each of the tweets.
And so that will allow us to kind of look at all of those and see which ones you know appear the most
and give us a bit of an idea of what people are thinking in terms of what they'd like to see.
It's gonna be really rough.
And so obviously we're gonna have a whole lot of that but we'll also be able to kind of go through and
just kind of look at it visually pick out the ones which are making sense.
So take it away.
Daniel Oh and to do that by the way I think we've covered crawling and I'm actually going to show you
something on my screen here for a second.
We've covered crawling quite well enough and so I'm going to come into my project I'm going to launch
my terminal and I'm just gonna get rid of the setup that I had and so we had 0 3 here.
Todd Right.
I'll do this off screen and and then we're going to add analysis and I will switch over to Daniel's
error and the analysis is gonna be there under 0 4 scrape.
It'll be 0 3 analysis and so we'll just have a copy of all the files why you go ahead and you can get
rid of 0 3 Todd on years if you're gonna commit it on your end.
OK that's funny.
Yes that's good.
And you could just do 0 3 analysis and and and then take everything you did in 0 2 and drop the analysis
in there.
That's perfect
not people to just drag and drop through sublime It's a file thing it's not that great.
So I hear
so count the words I'm thinking map.
Yeah pretty much.
So plus plus.
So this is going to probably be more more stuff.
So one thing I would like to do is probably just say dumb tweets takes in tweets as a slice of tweet
that this maternal thing and I just think that this
so I got access to it later if I if I went back again.
It's just out of the way.
I like that and the next function maybe be a function word count.
So you're now.
And that's going to take and all the tweets and so this won't be more proper and potentially return
in it.
I don't think it actually needs to return an error yet but it will return that the word counts a map.
So I'm almost thinking the first we could make a data structure that can be sorted for that.
So we can have the word counts in descending order.
So I like that.
So need a strike for that word that info struct will have the word it's a string.
Yeah.
And how many times that shows up.
So count it.
And so this will return a slice of word info.
So in sorted order descending count order.
And so now I've got that.
And so I can start a actually doing counting the words.
So while counting them a map is useful.
Create a word map is a map from what the word is string to how many times it's shown up.
Yeah.
So maps are very useful here in this case while creating it.
And then we go back later and read restructure to the struct form slice it struct form which floor easily
sorted.
Yeah absolutely.
So weird map now I've got all these tweets so I need to loop through each tweet so
rage tweets.
So there t is an individual tweet and each tweet has a message teed up messages one message from the
tweets but we have no words.
Yeah.
So we're going to have to do this.
Strings package has that thing where you could split right that's fluid and it splits on whatever you
pass and I think what's the signature.
What are the parameters.
I think it's a you add a space called column space but if we look at strings package strings split I
remember that from Caleb dock C first first century what are we doing in the separator.
And gives you a slice of string that's what split islands.
It's.
So now I have a words nice and the C range everywhere I can move over words
and for each word I can do.
We're map and the word the word gets lost plus so one potential benefit can do also is you could do
strings start to lower.
Oh absolutely.
So that way it's case insensitive.
Good call.
And the reason we could just automatically start using an index a key on a map is because if no keys
there it's zero value right.
Yes and the zero value of an end to zero.
So everything starts out as zero.
And so you could just say hey you put this key in.
No keys there.
Then it creates that key and it goes from zero to one.
And if a key is there finds it and it takes whatever that is and it increments it up one.
So that's kind of what that little notation is.
I think it's totally nifty to explain that right.
Yeah.
OK.
So correct.
It's one of the more almost arcane parts of Go.
It's it's not that arcane but that kind of just tells you how simple the language go it is that that's
good.
That could be considered one of the harder to understand parts of it.
So now we've got the word math where each key is a word and the value is how many times that word shows
up.
So now we convert it and tell those lines 1 6 through 1 20.
Sorry I just cut you off.
1 16th through 120.
That just went through all the tweets and put all of the words from all the tweets into a map and counted
how many times each one is in there.
Yeah.
That's elegant and short.
Yes very sad.
Go on.
Sorry.
So.
So after that we now need to get it into this struct format so you can you can loop over a map too.
So each time through the map it'll give me the word and then the count so that's just key value.
So since Becky is the word and the values the count I can tell you can see to represent that this is
going off word map.
And so now each time through I'm going to need to make new wording.
Let's make that slice of return of word infos infos It's a slice of word info.
Now I can say for each time through this loop I can append a a new word info into that slice a word
of W and a C so now its own slice.
And now we can source the slice.
So sorting good like that word sort storage sort sort has a slice sort of a slice
which takes in a slice of anything here and then a function to compare two items in that slice and it
doesn't return anything.
It just does it place on this slice so sort that slice and I'm going to need to import sort
sought but slice my autocomplete and such you know not don't make my article the engine does not like
go modules so keeps crash needs.
That's why it's not working and we're coming up on two minutes I like to keep these videos short.
OK.
So to be continued.
Yeah we're going to see in the next video or we're going to look at sorting the slice.
I know we're pretty close but yeah I really like trying to keep this short.
So make a new entry and we'll see in the next video.