All right.
Now we're going to.
Sorry.
Yes.
Now we're going to sort the saga.
So we got word in fact we've got a slice of word infos.
Each one has a word and it count.
But now we want to sort it so it's in descending order.
We want the word info zero to be the most commonly appearing word in that way it's easily we can easily
look at it and read the values.
So sort of slice takes it a slice a slice as its first argument.
And the second argument it takes in is a function which obviously is an anonymous function to that function
it passes in to integers.
I and j.
It returns a boolean.
This function is a less boolean.
What you're trying to do here is you will return true if with I index i is less than with index J and
so and then whatever's less will become will be earlier in the slice when it's sorted so because we
want earlier things in the slice to be things with bigger accounts.
That means we want to say true if the count is higher
so.
So in this case so much return with i dot count is greater than with J dot count because we want the
higher value to be less and so be closer to the beginning of the sordid slice slice after this point
we can return with and that is now a sorted slice of word infos tossing and I look forward to seeing
the results.
So this function is actually getting complicated.
So if I had some time I would probably split this up into a couple of smaller functions like one to
do the counting one convert into this into a sorted slice but for now this kind of work says it is say
so now we can actually call this is called Word Count it takes all the tweets
and it returns back the sword to candidates
and does not return an error of anything it will always work no error returns so don't bother checking
that.
Now we just need to print that.
So I'm just going to range over assorted counts and just each time through I will print print f yeah
I was going to say the word colon the count New Line is the word and count it's now if I go back up
in run this
second Grace where I'm all saying
so lots of words that we should have once if you scroll way back to the top well a and to the four that's
to be expected nice there G.P.S. shrimp nine times here you see these big cloud cloud it's big project
you lots of you want to see you humanity's dog Daddy's big doctor like services graft graft well e-commerce
horrors rest yeah that's really interesting to look at.
Look at that.
See this is very basic just a word count is I mean there's lots of stuff there where you could merge
some words together like I know I saw near the very bottom there was a there was a there is a G.P.S.
lifeform gators yep the European gateways that could probably be merged with your PCI for the purposes
of what project to make but so it's it's very general of a count but I mean that gives us a nice idea
of what to aim for for what to build next.
That's really cool.
Well done.
Anything else you want to add.
I would go back to this and like I said split this work thing into two functions.
If I want to be more properly proper coding Yeah I'm going to add that I think you're awesome.
And that was a real pleasure to watch you code that.
Very nice.
All right.
We'll see you in the next section.
Next video next section we'll figure out what that's going to be.
We'll see you there.