It is Friday afternoon 324 P.M. and since I saw you last I went to the dentist.
My teeth are still hanging in there and we all a breed that were the size of small redwood trees.
I didn't finish mine.
I'm gonna save it for the winter in case I need to heat the house over a long cold winter.
I'll have something to burn.
But now we're going to jump in to Daniel.
We are like.
We'd like to give you a little bit more with that jar.
P.S. And and we were looking at the different articles that are already out there talking about JROTC
with GO and different examples and one of the things that you know a G.P.S..
Let me just see if I have it here quick and handy GAAP c can't.
Concepts.
So just a second we'll edit out the slope PART.
I'M LOOKING FOR.
OH IS THIS THE STREAM stream stream.
OK.
Cool.
Awesome.
Great.
And so you could set it up.
Where is just sort of call and response and then you could also set it up where you have a stream from
the client to the server.
You could also set it up where you have a stream from the server to the client and you can also set
it up where you got streams going both ways.
And so there's four different ways that you could do communication between the client and the server.
And so we want to give you a little bit more of an in-depth example than something is out there.
And Daniel is really leading the charge on this.
I would like to be able to say that the student has become the master.
That's absolutely true.
And but I'm I'm honored to have played a little role in your computer science education two of to have
been able to be your teacher but he's also done a ton of work on his own and taking a ton of other classes
of course.
But so anyhow and this is what we did.
Since the last videos Daniel with Daniel did as he explored what it'd be like to use TR he see I don't
know why I'm just tripping over that phrase for web dev and what that would look like and that actually
turned out to be a little bit fairly complicated a little bit too complicated for an example to present
here right.
Yeah.
In the browser in up being too complicated involved multiple servers and translation calls and ended
up being complicated.
Yes that's a that's a work in progress not something we're going to present right now.
But what Daniel did put together was a little chat server and so in the next couple of videos and this
video is just an introduction to this new section here we have a G.P.S. G.P.S. chat server and so just
to give you a little bit of a grounding and anchoring in the course outline.
We did GOPAC Getting Started GOPAC in action and then we're going to have a G.P.S. chat server and so
the next couple of videos Daniel is going to introduce you to that and between the last section and
the last video in this section and this video.
I also did some reading on what we might be able to present to you and what's already out there.
And so I really appreciated and enjoyed this article here from Nico Gua then.
I'm not quite sure how you say your last name Nico but I included a link there because I thought it
was a pretty cool example and a really well-written article with great descriptions.
Not to mention some really cool go for art of some of JROTC so that link there I think it's a worthy
article.
Check out all right you have anything more to add to the intro video are you ready to jump into the
next videos where we'll start going through all this.
Let's get started.
All right see the next videos.