All right so do you start with any G.P.S. program.
The easiest route is to look at the profile.
So I've got here in 0 5 G.P.S. for a chat.
I've got a chat folder with the chat dot profile.
And as you see it's actually very fairly small.
It's a very simple service protocol wise.
So got the typical syntax was Pro 3 in the service chat with one or one remote procedure called Chat.
But what this is different is that a chat can take in a stream of chat messages and returns back a stream
of chat messages so you can make a sharp as it's whenever you want and just keep going on the same chat
and the server can send back a string or chat messages when someone else chats just whenever.
So both the input and output are going through streams and a chat message is defined as two strings
a user in a message.
So like a user name or and then the message they're actually sending and one of the things that's interesting
I'm sure maybe we did or did not mention this but it is definitely worthy of being mentioned is there
on line three through five in our interface definition language.
You know that's like almost defining an interface there where it's like hey if you're going to be a
service you got to have this RBC method where chat returns this chat takes in this argument and returns
that right.
All.
So.
So whenever you've got a stream in the input or output the the function that you defining go becomes
very different.
So if I go to the generated code there's chat message which is as usual just a plain struct if I go
all the way down to let's see where it's such that server a chat server the chat function is just takes
in a chat underscore a chat server which is a really interesting method which if I hover over that that's
just an interface they send and receive message because it's a stream.
It doesn't actually have everything that it's a stream both directions so it needs to be able to receive
a stream of chat messages and send a stream of chat messages.
And so it's not it's not like a request response RBC message takes in the entire message as an argument
and returns the terror response as an out those streams instead it gives you this interface to receive
and send individual messages within the stream and then it returns possible error for the actual controlling
of the overall connection.
So this is on this chat server side it was at your chat method will receive a chat chat server with
the send receive.
If I go back up to chat client when you when you make the call to initiate this RBC if you give it the
context and it returns a chat chat client which has got the same mouth to method send and receive because
they're both streaming because both in both directions are streaming nice.
So your process is step one create your profile and then step two is to build that profile compile that
profile down into your product is this your protocol buffer right here.
This is the generated code PDB so it's got to be got go and and then take once you generate your code.
Take a look at your code and start making sense of it.
That seems to be OK.
Yeah.
So.
So the formulas for how it spits out these particular interfaces is consistent.
So eventually you'll learn what they are and you can just look at the profile without generating code.
But when you're not that used to it yet the the code is very complicated but there's just a couple.
You can just search for.
Okay.
I'm looking for the chat function so I could just copy that search for chat and let's see where can
I find a chat interface.
So like there's a chat something or other.
Yeah.
So.
So I just want to look for the interfaces primarily.
And then what was the code that you at the terminal to compile your chat profile command.
It's a proto C dash capital I.
So that when they get older.
Yeah.
Well that's older and Cash Dash go out equals plug ins colon GOPAC plug no plug ins equals to your colon
chat.
Yes plug ins.
OK.
Cool also.
That's what generates it.
So that those are the first steps anything you want to.
Else you want to add to the first steps there.
Writing writing your profile and then also generating the code and then taking the first gander at understanding
it.
Yeah.
That's it.
I think that's a good first video we will see in the next video or we will explore this further.