In this video we'll go over the code for the client for chatting because the server code is gets rather
complicated for this particular design.
And so and the client is a little bit simpler so.
So for the client I'm expecting you to put into the command line arguments the euro to connect to as
a command line argument and then your username as a second command line argument.
And so whenever you have command line arguments a good very first thing to do in your main is to make
sure your command line arguments are kind of valid.
So in this case I'm just doing a very basic do I have the right number of command line arguments.
If not print out a message to remind myself what those arguments are supposed to be.
Or the user after I've got those I'm going to be contexts most because GBC uses context whenever you
make calls.
So I get the context.
I'm just making a generic background context with nothing in it.
And then I dial to our server OS args One is that first argue command line argument so the users vector
type in like localize ADHD or some IP address.
And I'm not securing my server so but the client know that's expected defer closing the connection.
Create the new chat client over the connections and I got to see.
And now I need to initiate that stream on that chat RBC.
Both directions.
So I do see that chat and I give it the context and it gives me back this stream which is of type chat
dot chat underscore chat client which is Daughtry.
Yes chit chat chat.
So luckily we don't have to worry about that since goes good at figuring it out with the call and equals.
So now I've got the stream checked my error and then the since the stream can both be sending and receiving
I use one go routine to loop to loop over and receive all messages from the stream and then the main
go routine will write all the messages to stream with stream that sent so.
So I create a channel of empty struct I'm expecting this channel to be closed before everything ends
that way I can make sure the main function waits for this go routine to exit before the main function
exits and so I spend a sort of a go routine.
So this go routine loops forever each time through the loop it receives one message from the stream.
This will be a chat chat message a pointer to a chat chat message once you've got the chat message I
print it out with the user name Cole in the message it just goes forever.
The one thing to note is if the error I receive back is an IO and a file that means the stream is closed
in a proper manner.
So I should just shut everything down normally.
So I closed this channel to indicate this go routine is finished has quote has finished and I'm returning.
Out of the go routines that security is done.
Any other area.
I'm just panicking.
So in a more proper program you'd probably put some actual proper error handling code but for demonstration
purposes panicking works here.
The other half of the program I'm going to print out a statement basically saying that I'm ready to
receive messages and explaining how to exit the program so you can either type and quit or you can use
control C to exit the program
and I'm gonna use the buffer a new scanner to scan because font scan does not scan whole lines of code
words but bio scanner will let you get whole lines of code it a standard in is your input on the command
line.
So I'm gonna get a scanner and then as long as there's lines to scan I get that I get the line that
just got scanned.
If the line I just scanned was quick then I called stream close Senate which just closed it which sends
out all messages that have not yet been sent over the stream and closes it
and that breaks out of the for loop.
Ultimately if it's not quit I create a chat message.
The username is that second command line argument and then the message is the message that got typed
in the command line and then it goes back to the top to loop so each time you loop it gets one line
of command line checks if it's quit.
If not it sends it.
Nice and then after that loop ends because of this break.
If you're typing quit it closes the connection and then breaks and it will wait for this the go routine
to finish up which should be fairly quickly since you close the connection so I know you should be soon
yeah.
The only thing I have to point out in that code is context and context is something that well you know
a couple of things in there but context is something those covered briefly in my web dev course.
And we're also planning to cover that in a future course that we're going to create after this one.
So if you're a little bit like what is context that's the common experience and we're gonna go into
that in a future course unless args.
We've also covered in a previous course of intro to go course I believe I cover args but that's easy
to look up at the standard library and then also you know if it's the first time that you're seeing
a scanner there but fire package by fire and scanners so backfires.
Buffer input and output.
And please join in on this conversation and let me know if I articulate any of this in a way that needs
some modification
but a buffer is a storage area in memory and input and output.
So you know a printer spool buffer printer buffer.
Well you know your computer will often generate all the code the printer needs and then hold it in a
buffer and then as the printer neat so it does all that work and just puts all the stuff there ready
for the printer and there's the printer needs the next piece of information.
The next piece of information is ready to go and be fed and so but Fido is just kind of like a name
for this buffer area for input and output and then this is just the standard pattern for how scanners
work.
And so you Ingo and so you could take a look at how this was done with that 4 scanner scan and then
getting the text from the scanner and so you could take a look about awesome the standard library but
that's also something that you know if you're relatively new if you haven't seen it before can be.
Hey what's going on there.
All right.
So those are just some of the thoughts that came up for me as you went through it.
Very nicely done.
I like your code.
Great job Daniel.
Anything more to add to this.
Creating a client.
No.
All right great.
So next we're going to start tackling the server and now probably a couple of videos but it's probably
larger.