All right.
So next up after the client comes the server which in this case in this particular program is the more
complicated one.
So for a chat program the server has to receive a message from any connection and then send that message
back out to every connection.
And the problem is each connection is running on its own go routine.
It's a separate threat of execution they're all happening simultaneously.
And so to get that message that you're receiving from one connection you then have to be and should
get over to each other go routine so they can send it because you could only be sending from the GOP
see connections or streams are not threads safe to send multiple messages at once.
And that can be found if you actually go to the go dock for jihad you see
and you find
server streams it mentions under send message.
This to have a good routine calling send message.
And another go in calling receive message on the same street at the same time.
But it's not safe to call send message on the same stream in different Gerges.
How did you come across the I was looking up whenever I'm thinking go routines and I know I'm going
to have multiple go routines talking to the same thing.
I often check the docs to see if they have if they mention safety go routine and threat safety.
Thanks.
So so because every connection in a G.P.S. server is its own go routine.
I wanted to make sure to see and so I found this.
And so I knew I had to had to set up the thread safety myself.
And so what I did was I made a connection struct and the connection struct hell holds one connection.
That's the Chat chat server thing with the send and receive methods.
And it has a send channel and equip channel.
And when you create a connection with this new connection which takes in that stream
this will create the connection with two new channels and it will start this call the start method in
another go routine and then return it.
This is mostly so that you can now have this nice send method on this chart on this connection where
you can pass in a chat message and this will send the message through the send channel to the actual
to the start area where it will actually be sent along that connection and in a thread safe way and
this will also ignore any panics in case send gets closed because the connection got closed.
This particular send method will ignore the panic for trying to send on a closed channel so this way
you can now see the connection send and it will send the message and it doesn't matter go routines or
anything it will it will happen thread safe because all things that the only thing that will actually
send along the connection is this start method in its own go routine which you can which only send messages
along it through this channel
so this start message is just looping forever every time he gets a message from the to send channel
it sends it along a connection if it ever gets anything on the quick channel or quick channel closes
it ends the loop and exits the governor team.
So that's why you've got this nice we've got a nice close method here which I'm having a return in error
just to match other closed methods out there like all the IO close with it's you know it's always new
and this just closes that quick.
The close the quick channel so that way.
This will close and it goes the scent chain.
So connection will be close this close method.
So essentially no closed which which causes this to panic and recovers anything it's kind of trying
to send.
We'll move on and discover team will exit and then finally there's a get messages function which will
loop forever.
This is just receiving a chat message from this connection.
If there's an end to file close it there's any other error close it and turn the air.
What's got this message though.
You need to send it to all the connections.
And so this get messages function takes in a broadcast channel.
This is just a channel that you're only allowed to send on for chat messages and some other code elsewhere.
We'll be responsible for making sure that gets out to every send method for all the connections so this
message receives a message and then it sends a chat.
It sends the message through to the broadcast and I'm doing this in a good routine so that if the other
end of broadcast is not yet ready it will.
It can still start receiving the next message.
Well while this go routine waits.
But to make it end early there's that that quick channel that we use up here for the start.
So I I use select and it either sends to the broadcast or when quick closes.
So if it close connection closes we don't have a bunch of dangling go routines trying to send along
to broadcasting.
You're right.
This is meaty.
This is me.
He like it so me I'm just like.
Explain it.
Any questions I have I'm saving.
So.
So that's a connection a single connection.
It's got the actual connection through the stream.
It's got to send channel which is used to send from this send method to this start method.
That's Indigo.
That's in a separate go routine and it's got this get messages loop which receives messages and sends
it out through a broadcast channel
almost near a diagram to track all that.
Yes somewhat.
Yes go routines and channels can get that way very easily feel like we've gotten back to spaghetti code.
It's was way more organized in structure in my head just has to learn to work with that.
So I'm not I haven't spent a lot of time working to cover teams and then so that's the first top of
the part of the code is are more code down below.
So after this you're just the first introduction.
This is a single connection.
OK.
So yes it's a good starting point for.
And we'll see we'll see the next ones in in in the next video which we will see you in right now.
Hopefully.