Sweet.
Let's see it handling multiple connections as well we're going to look at this video and maybe answer
it.
So next up I've got the overall chat server which will have a slice of connections so the connections
being this all this other connection code up here with its own good routines the channels.
So the chat server will have a slice of all the connections that are currently connected and there is
also a I think new text of connection for connection LoC is a sync that new text.
So any time I access the list of connections I will use I will walk this lock and do my changes and
then unlock it afterwards.
So go always says channels but sometimes you just need a lock which is the old which is the pre channel
kind of way of doing sharing memory as a means of communicating.
Yes.
So beyond that I've got the big broadcast channel which the connections will send their messages to.
And so that this chat server will receive messages on the broadcast channel and send them to each of
the connections and then I've got a quick channel similar to a connect each connections got its own
quick channel.
I've got a global server server wide channel that's good thinking and so I've got this new chat server
function that returns the chat server.
It creates those two channels I don't need to bother with the slice of connections because append will
create that if needed and you don't ever have to actually create a sync mute text the zero value it's
valid for it so I just create these two channels I start the I run the start method in another girl
routine and they return the chat server.
So this start method is the broadcast handler basically.
So this will do a loop every time to loop it checks if there is there if there's a message coming in
through the broadcast channel.
Lock the connection lock loop through all the connections and for each one send the message in that
gherkin safe way I'm going to do it another go routine so that it doesn't lock up the entire server
if one connections being slow and then I unlock the the connection lock I like that alternately if the
quit Channel has to think through or if it's closed I can end this loop and close this script routine
to which I've got a nice helpful close function here to kind of abstract that away so.
So to shut down this code you'd call a close
so besides that I've also got this chat function.
This is the function that implements the prototype the prototype chat stream chat messages return stream
chat messages so it receives in a a chat chat server which is the stream and returns an error.
So first thing it does is it creates that connection from up above it walks the connection lock and
adds the connection to the left to the slice of connections that unlocks it and then it calls connection
get messages to.
That's the that's the loop in a connection that receives the messages and it gives that get messages
the broadcast channel so that it's able to broadcast back to the server.
When you get messages returns that means that channel.
That connection is done.
And so we can lock the connection lock again and look through to try to find our connection and remove
it from the list of connections and then unlock contextual lock in so connections will always be all
the connections.
When you where cash first comes in.
It gets added and then when the connection is closing it looks through and removes that connection from
the slice of connections.
So this is a little bit simpler than the connection part but it still has lots of Go routines and channels
and such.
So yeah I know there's a lot of literally moving pieces in that one in line 111 when you look at your
profile the profile interface definition language not being compiled one but the next whenever I see
that as like it's a function that takes in this and returns that right.
Yes.
And then if we look at line 111 it's a function that takes and I don't see the return on that.
So tell me a little bit about that.
That's that's where I had a question.
So how is that.
Whenever whenever you've got a stream whether in or out.
Yeah on a.
On a particular method in Gypsy in go it'll change that into a single ah input argument that's got the
send and receive now on it.
OK all right.
So that's fulfilling the interface.
Yes.
And all right I get that.
That's a nice program.
And then the main function is pretty much a copy paste from our server from before it just listens great
server registers and started to search it very nice Daniel anything you want to add to those two pieces.
We looked at this in two videos.
No that's we want to show it.
Oh yeah.
Let's see running it though in the next in the next video.
Right.
All right.
So we'll save any commentary we have and running it for the next video.
See you next video.