So here's our game plan for this video.
We're gonna get this up and running on my machine we're going get it running I'm Daniel's machine you're
gonna be able to see it running on both machines I'm just checking our clock and and then I also just
wanted to convey that there's two more pieces and so one piece is that this is kind of this is a media
example just took us I don't know 12 15 16 minutes and two videos took him that long to explain just
to sort of sit here just watch it and and and so we're not going to go through and explain every piece
of this.
You did get a more detailed explanation with the earlier GAAP example that we did where we walked through
all that and but with this one it's just something meaty an example the works that you could sink your
teeth into if and when you are ready for it.
And then what we will do though at the end of this video or maybe the next video depending upon how
long it takes us to kind of show it working is we're going to trace a message through the code and you'll
kind of see our message passes through the code.
So that will give you a little bit more insight into the code.
So the first step is to get it up and running on my machine and I've got all of my code here.
I'm not current SO I'M JUST GONNA MAKE SURE THAT I'M IN THE going project I'm going to do it get status.
Of course they'll tell me a little bit of information and so do I get PULL AND AND NOW IF I DO MY get
staffs all should be well that's some voodoo computing there for you.
And now that I have that code down here how do I get this up and running.
I need to go into this folder right into the chat folder yet so C.D. into your 0 5 0 0 5 0 4.
Yeah.
And then what I want to do that you're going to want to be in the client and so.
So over on my machine I will open up I'm in the 0 4 server.
I'm just gonna go run the server
now serving at Port 880 and I'm going to run the client ready for that.
So.
So in the client it's go or I may not go.
And it takes two arguments.
So the first argument is where to connect to.
So I'm on my computer and we use IP config on windows and my IP address is that 10 0 0 0 24 0 0 24.
Colon 80 84 88.
And then space.
And then what you want your username is going to be on this chat message.
So that's the hardest part.
So so you don't have GRC and all the various libraries.
Yes.
So it's go modules is automatically grabbing all of that for you.
Super nice.
Meantime on my machine I will do.
Go run main go in the client folder and I'm on my own machine so I can use local host 1880 and Daniel
for any
mind connected but over on Todd it says you've got the connection here.
And I think I knew what that it was actually.
It's my firewall it's windows blocking external connections so
Daniel's security conscious never.
So yeah he can rerun that command and it should work this time but it looks like it worked before you
cleared.
Yeah so it should I closed the server to restart it until the firewall.
So it should make this message here connection established a quick corrosive exit.
And now you can type in a message
and so it shows up there and it shows up on my machine and I can get something back.
Super cool.
Todd
is all working.
I love this.
So this is just the server is running on my laptop.
I'm connected with a client will close to my left to my own server and Todd's on his own machine next
to me.
And he typed in my IP address to connect to my server as well.
And so every time one of us types the message the server forwards it on to the other person or both
of us actually.
Yeah it's very cool.
Do we want to keep the video short so let's do the tracing the path of a message through the code in
the next video.
So this is just seeing everything running in the next video we're going to trace the path of a message
you anymore you want to add to this one.
Nicely done.
Really cool.
See the next video.