So when do dealing with concurrency and networking like this one helpful way to understand the code
is to try to see if you can follow the path of a mess of an action through the code across the multiple
devices to understand it.
So what.
What we need to have is when someone types in a message it comes in on this function and then eventually
on every computer it goes to this fine print line.
So but how does it get from this here to here is the question is climbs up.
So so so following the path is a nice way to kind of see how that works.
So the message comes in here.
Got message and it comes down in here the message gets sent out through the stream to the server so
over in the server that comes back in here.
This received message.
So on a connection through receives that's here's the message on the server what's best on the server
it comes down and gets sent out through this broadcast channel this broadcast channels other end is
here in chat server comes the message comes out the broadcast channel and then the server goes to all
the connections and for every connection it sends that message.
And so.
So now this the send is located up here connection.
This is just scrolled up a bit so it comes down here and it gets sent through to this send channel to
the send channel.
The other end of it is right here again in the connection.
So the message comes out here and gets sent through the actual connection so this then goes back to
the client up here the stream receives messages.
And now you get the message and it comes down and gets printed out a nice car I had so many questions
I don't even know if I want to jump into it.
Well done.
I'm not going to jump him to.
All right.
Anything you want to add to that now.
Good.
That's definitely code that's going to take even myself you know one of the we need the qualifier even
but that's kind of this can take myself a little bit of time to understand.
Thanks for that example Daniel really enjoyed it.