Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in this session, we want to talk about
go from concept.
What is an all around?
Before getting into the proper definition of law, and first, let me take an example, which we explain
the term in a better way.
So have you ever used this school database in your application?
And have you ever used this school queries to update, insert or retrieve the data?
No matter how the queries are?
So here comes the idea of object relational mapping or M, and it is a programming technique for converting
data between incompatible type systems using object oriented programming languages.
It means you can write database queries using the object oriented paradigm of your preferred language,
and there are many free and commercial packages available that perform object relational mapping or
acts as brackets between our developers and our underlying database technology.
They allow us to essentially work with objects much as we normally would, and then save these objects
without having to craft complex the school statements or insist the mapping between the set of objects
which are written in the previous programming language like JavaScript and relational database like
Skewer.
It hides and encapsulates this fuel queries into objects, and instead of school queries, we can use
directly the objects to implement this query.
Why to use or in and what are the benefits of lowering?
Now the question arises that if we can use like queries, then why to include the are frame frameworks
in between.
So first of all, you get the written language you are already using.
It is some time to try to skewer queries directly, and they are complicated in some cases.
So to maintain the fluency, we use the R and so that we can write in the language we know.
And second, it hides this dual or any other database query away from your application logic.
And third, for heavy database usage, like creating 10+ tables and using many queries in them, then
it is good to use R, as it read is the code and give a better understanding of the code to you and
as well as to your teammates, and it makes your application faster and easier to maintain.
Go on and or go blank or in pages.
The Gore team is fantastic, Autumn Library for Golden aims to be developer friendly.
It is an awesome library for dealing with relational databases.
This Goram library is developed on the top of database as cumulative package gone and is a developer
friendly or and and provides crud operations and can also be used for the initial migration and creation
of database schema.
A few more teams that go out and does better include its extensibility with native plugin support.
Its reliance on testing.
And one to one and one from many group of associations.
Go on and on to source Eskew Lite, MySchool Postgres and MSC you with the overview and feature of RMR
Full featured Aughrim.
Associations has one has many billions, too many, too many, and polymorph is callbacks before, after
create safe, articulate find paid loading, eager loading transactions, composite primary key skill
builder, lawyer and developer friendly.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.