Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about gore, concept and indecision.
We want to do an example.
Go line carrot using gore in and my school database.
We are going to see an example program to learn how to do database operations using INGO programming
language by the gore and and my school.
We have talked about Krait before, which is an acronym for Create, Read, Update and delete crud operations
or basic data manipulation of database.
In this example, we are going to create an interface as database front end to handle these operations.
We have a student that containing tated information like, i.e., name and age with this data.
We have to perform crop using Goram in my school.
In previous sessions, we succeed to create a student table in the MySQL database and perform craft
on it.
So we use the same student table built into the MySQL database in previous sessions.
Within this project, to connect to the Go program by Go are in.
In stunning gore and in a stunning school driver, because in this tutorial he used gore and and minuscule
database Vini to install gore in and minuscule driver in our project.
So first, we should prepare and install Gore and MySchool driver.
Or in a stunning gore and go to the terminal and simply wrong these syntax.
Go get.
That's you, gore in that I snatched Guam and fought in a stunning MySchool driver.
Run this command.
Go get.
That's you, gore.
And that i o ss driver is that miles?
Let's go to this school program to implement these requirements tools.
First, go to Package Explorer and go to a source folder and create a project folder named like you
are in the new folder.
Go on in before creating anything.
There are two things as requirements to do.
First, installing gore in second you starting my school train.
So go to the terminal and simply wrong for you.
Stunning gore and city to
run this command.
Go get.
That's you!
Go on and O Islam school, ah, and and execute this command before starting the project, I install
these requirements after execute this comment and installation is completed.
Install my screwdriver.
So Ron, another command.
Go get gas, you
go out and dance.
I know it's not there, either.
It's like my school.
After installation is completed to install the settings, close the V escort program and open it again
in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish youth and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.