So the next file system I want to support is WebDAV, and WebDAV doesn't get as much attention as it
probably should.
It's built into every major operating system out there, and it's an extremely useful extension to the
HDTV protocol that allows for things like sharing data.
Obviously, you can use it as a file system, and that's what I'm going to do right now.
But it could actually be extended to allow collaborative editing of documents in real time and things
like that, and I'll let you read about that on your own.
My focus right now is implementing Web Dev as a remote file system.
And it's pretty straightforward.
So to do that, of course, I'm going to go to the Celebrity Celebrities project.
The File Systems folder, then the Web Deb File System folder, and then we'll open up WebDAV, Dongo
and that's the stub.
This file consists of the stub functions we put together a while ago, and now we need to actually implement
them.
So just as we had to with Mineo and as we had to with SFTP, we're going to install a package which
gives us access to WebDAV file systems.
So I'll open my terminal and I'll start my application, make stop, and I'll make sure I get to the
right folder.
So I walk one level and then into celebrities, because that's the goal mod file I want to effect with
this command.
Go get GitHub dot com slash studio Dash B12.
Slash go web, dev.
Now there's other libraries out there, but this one is never let me down and I rather like it, so
I go and get that.
And there we go, we've got it added to our government file.
And that means I can start implementing my various functions now, as I did before.
I'm going to create a get credentials function so funk with a receiver of W or spell funk, right,
though.
W pointer to WebDAV and I'll call this one get credentials just like I did in the other one.
And it returns a pointer to go Web Dev, which we just imported Dot Client right there.
And I think the important for me and we'll just make this as simple as we possibly can, and it's not
difficult at all.
I'm going to get a variable, which I call C four cloned and that's assigned value from calling Go Web
Dev Dot New Client.
And it just requires three parameters.
The first one is the URL or the URL, which we get straight from our receiver host.
OK, the second one is W dot user or username, and the final one is W Dot Pass for password.
We return that.
OK.
So now I have my client, and that means I can start working on the put functionality and it is relatively
straightforward.
So what I'm going to do, first of all, is get a client client is assign the value of W Dot, get credentials.
Now she looks like I have my receivers all set to s, so I'll change those to W just for consistency.
Should have noticed that when I put these stubs in, but I just wanted to get it started.
That's better.
They're all W now.
So Client is assigned the value of calling W don't get credentials.
Now I have a client.
And I want to put a file up on the remote file system, so I'll open the file, file an error or assign
the values for by calling oast or open.
Right there, and I'm going to open file name, which is the full path to the file name.
I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil, then return the error.
And, of course, defer filed out close, so we don't have a resource leak next.
I just call the method on my client variable, which is my Web Deb file system, and I call the method
right string, which gives us an error.
So error is now equal to client dot right string.
We could use right, but I like write stream.
It works really well and it seems a little faster to me, but that's just anecdotal data.
So don't take it for what it's worth, and we give it a format as print out to build a string.
And my format string will be nothing more than percent se percent as.
And I'm going to write to the first place holder will be the folder, the half name.
And of course, that's the second parameter we get to this function.
And then I get the base name from filing.
So past updates
filing.
Right there.
And then I have to give it two more parameters.
What am I writing vile and what are the right permissions now?
These are the standard Unix permissions, and I'm going to go with one that I almost always use zero
six six four.
And those are, I think, relatively safe.
File permissions.
We'll check an again, so I'll copy and paste.
And that's it.
We now have the necessary put functionality in there now, before I forget, let's open the door on
file in my app and let's fill out the necessary information for WebDAV just to get it out of the way
right now.
So since we're using Docker, we're going to call it this way.
Each http now in production, this would be TDPs, but we're connecting to a local Docker image.
Now use 127.0.0.1, which is local host colon port one zero zero eight zero and my username.
This is offered by the same package or the same Docker image that's giving us SFP.
So it's a setup and the password is password.
OK.
So that's the first of the functions we have to implement, and it's also setting up our own site in
the next lecture.
We'll take care of list, which is relatively straightforward as well.