So this time around, we want to implement this function list for our WebDAV filesystems, and this
is really, really straightforward, and in fact, it's almost identical to the code we used back in
S&P with just a couple of minor changes.
Let's get started.
First thing I need to do, of course, is to get a client and that comes from don't get credentials.
Another way of a client, we can get a listing of all the files that exist in the directory stored in
the variable prefix, the one parameter passed to this function.
So files and I believe it returns an error.
Let's find out comes from client read dear.
And that returns.
Yes, file info and an error.
So read dear and we want to read the dear prefix that directory.
OK, so we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
I'll return my listing, which is the slice of file systems listing, which would be empty at this point,
but it doesn't matter.
And we also return the error.
But if we get past that, we just range through the file same as before.
So for.
And as always, we don't care about the index, but we do care about the individual entry, which are
called file.
Those are populated by ringing through files.
And then we only want to take care of or consider files who don't begin with a dot as usual, so if
not strings that again, strings dart has prefix right there and our string is filed.
Our name and are prefix is just a dog.
So it doesn't start with that.
And I have a typo there somewhere I have put parentheses around it.
I was writing JavaScript just before this lecture.
Those parentheses are redundant can go.
That's better.
Now we calculate the size same as we do before.
B is assigned the value of casting to a float 64 the size of the file that we're currently looking at.
File that size and then kilobits is assign.
The value of bytes divided by 1024 and megabytes is assigned the value of kilobytes divided by one zero
two four.
And then we create our current item, which I'll call current.
It's assigned the type of file systems dot listing and we populates fields.
So last modified, that's going to be filed on my time.
I'm not doing these in any particular order.
Key, which is the file name, is filed out name and we want the size, which is megabytes MBIE.
And finally, is it a directory?
And we do have to take that into account with this file system.
So file that is dear.
Now we have our current so we append that to our slice listing is equal to append listing and current,
and then down here we return listing in nil.
And that's it.
That should take care of before us.
So that one's virtually identical to S&P.
And down here, we'll do the delete function next and a following that will do the get function, then
we'll try things out.