So this time around, we want to implement the delete function for a Web file system, so I'm still
in the file WebDAV don't go in the folder, WebDAV file systems in the folder, file systems in the
projects hilarious.
And as usual, the first thing I need to do is to come down here in this function and get a client.
So client is assigned the value of calling W. Don't get credentials.
And now I have a client and all I have to do is to range through that slice of strings that we receive
as a parameter to this function.
So for ignore the index, but pay attention to the item, and that's populated by calling range items
to delete.
And we just delete each item one at a time.
So we'll check for error and that's assigned the value of calling from our client.
The method remove and we're removing item.
And of course, we need to check for an error, not read.
Dear is remove.
That's better.
And we check for an error.
If the error is not equal to nil, then we'll return false.
And again, you can return an error here if you want to.
So that takes care of the method.
Now, of course, we're not finished.
We need to go over to make this work in our code to our handlers, file in the Miami project and find
the delete function, which is here somewhere.
I guess I missed it.
Where's delete?
Billy, from first right here, and all I needed to do is to copy this and paste it here.
And change this to WebDAV and change this to WebDAV, I spelled them both right, and now we change
the casting from S&P to WebDAV file system.
Scott WebDAV.
And that should take care of it.
OK, now we won't test this right now, we'll test it when we finish the last function, which is over
here in WebDAV.
Don't go.
The the function named get the one that's not used very often, but it's nice to have when you need
it, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.