So the last function we want to implement for our WebDAV file system is to get function right here in
WebDAV Doggo.
So first thing we need to do as usual, is to get a client and that comes from calling don't get get
credentials.
And now I want to loop through all of the items that I receive as a very idec parameter at the end of
this function.
So four, don't care about the index, do care about the item, and that's populated by calling range
items.
Now what we're going to do inside this for loop is very similar to what we did in the SFTP get function.
And that is we're going to be opening some files and we want to close them.
So of course, the easiest way to do that is, again, to use an inline function.
So I'll populate the variable e r r by calling the inline function, which returns an error.
And then I'll have this return nil for now.
And then down here, you put in our two parentheses and we'll check for now.
If error is not equal to nil, then we just return the error.
And of course, that's just outside or just at the end of the four loop just before the closing parentheses.
And of course, the logic we want to do is all in here in this inline function.
So to make things readable, what I'm going to do is create a variable called WebDAV file path.
Call it whatever you want, but I think that's readable and I'll just make that equal to item, and
that makes it really clear what's going on here that I'll have a second variable local file path where
am I going to store things?
And that will be assigned the value of format as printout.
And my format string is just, as you might expect, percent as percent as the first substitution is
destination, which we received as a call to this function.
And the second one has to be just the file name of the current item.
So again, we use Path Dot Base and give it item, and that trims off everything.
That's not the file name.
So now I have these two variables.
What am I going to do with them?
Well, to start with, I'm going to create a variable called reader and check for an error when I call
from my client.
The method reads String and that gives us a reader, gives us an e-reader, or I'll read closer and
an error.
OK, I can use that, and I'm going to read WebDAV file past that file on the remote system and I check
for an error.
So if error is not equal to nil, I just return the error and we're all done.
OK, so that gives you my reader.
Now I need somewhere to write the contents of that reader.
So we'll create a file and we'll check for an error when we call Osako Create to create a file.
And I want to create local file path, which we just defined right up there online 88.
And I see a misspelled WebDAV and that will bother me endlessly.
So let me fix that.
OK.
Now we checked for an error, so I'll copy this error checking code and paste it right here.
And after that, we're going to call Defer Filed OK close, which is the whole reason that we're wrapping
everything in an inline function.
So now I have my reader, I have an empty file in my local file system, and all I have to do is to
copy the contents of the remote file to the local file.
Don't care about the number of bytes, do care about the error and we call Ioco Copy.
And we're going to copy into file the contents of reader.
OK.
And again, we'll paste it in our air check.
And that should be all we have to do here.
So that is our get function and we'll start testing things in the next lecture to make sure we get everything
right.