So before we can try out our new Web Deb file system, we obviously have to let celebrities know that
it exists.
So I'm back in the file.
Celebrities don't go in the Celebrity House package and near the bottom of that file.
We have this function, create file systems and we already have Mineo here and we have SFTP.
So let's add and I'll do so by copying this and modifying it.
Let's add our web to our system.
So again, we'll do a check here, and my simple check will be if the entry in the dot on file named
WebDAV Dot host.
If that's not equal to nothing, though, assume I'm going to be having a web dev file system.
So obviously I'm going to create a type web dev file systems dot WebDAV and I'll name the variable WebDAV.
The name this one.
WebDAV.
And give it the key web dev in all caps.
And that only has three required fields.
Port is part of host, so I just need to change this to Web Dev and the same thing for the next two
WebDAV host, WebDAV user and WebDAV Pass.
OK, so that's the first thing we have to do.
The second thing we have to do is to update the handlers in our Maya project that don't know about WebDAV
and right now delete from file system.
Does we did that in the last lecture, I think, but this one post upload to FS does not.
And this one's going to cause us a bit of grief, but I'll talk about that when we try that.
So let me paste that in here and modify this to say WebDAV and modify this to get the key WebDAV from
the map and cast it to the correct type, which is WebDAV file system web death.
OK, so that one's done, and I think the last one is listing the file system, which is up here somewhere.
Yeah, right here.
So we'll copy this one in the function named List EF-S and make sure you don't copy that closing curly
bracket or you'll have problems and we'll make this WebDAV
and make this web dev and this web dev.
And this one gets converted to WebDAV file system.
Dark Web Dev.
OK.
So those are the changes.
Now, make sure you have your Docker images running or the next steps won't work at all.
Then open your terminal.
Make sure you're in the right directory, the my app directory I am now, when I type make start, it's
going to work for me.
When you type it, it's probably going to give you an error message saying you need to go get the WebDAV
file system from whatever your calling your to project.
So just copy the go get command pasted into the terminal hit return and then type make start.
Mine should start up.
And it did.
So let's go over to our web browser and let's go to localhost four thousand or whatever reports you're
listening to.
And let's go to the file systems.
And first of all, let's try listing the files on the file system.
So let's make sure that minerals still works.
It does.
Let's try WebDAV and see what's up on the server there now.
And I currently have one file, and that should be exactly the same thing that I have on SFP, and I
work perfectly.
OK, so let's try deleting that using Web Dev.
So I'll list my web dev.
There's my, well, big.
I'll delete that.
And it's now gone, so that worked, so let's try uploading something.
And here's where we may run into a problem because Murphy's Law says if something can go wrong, it
will.
And in this case, it seems to be absolutely accurate because there are currently appears to be a bug
in either the SFTP go, the server we're connecting to or in the WebDAV client, because sometimes when
I upload to a web dev file system, sometimes I get an error 400, which isn't very helpful, but let's
try it.
I'll put up meta JPEG and see what happens.
And I got my error 400, and that's the only error it's giving me.
But if I log in to my SFP server using the username SFTP and the password password, I'm connecting
to localhost port 80 80 when I log in.
There's nothing there.
So let's go back.
Sometimes it works, and sometimes it doesn't.
Let's try choosing a different file.
Say, well, big and uploading that.
OK.
And now come back in here and refreshing this.
And there it is.
So there's a bug there right now, and what's happening is sometimes I'm getting an error back and sometimes
I'm not.
So for the purposes of this course, the easiest thing to do is simply wait for the fix to be applied
to either the client or the server.
But there is a bug there and it's one that apparently is being looked at.
So I'm not going to lose too much sleep about it because I know that I've written the code correctly.
And if you really want to make this work, you can simply go back to your code here and find the Post
Upload to FS Bid, which is down here.
Post Upload FS.
You could simply have this return, no error and comment out there.
So put a blank identifier there just the underscore and comment this out, and that would get you past
the bug that currently exists in my file system, but I don't think it's critical for our purposes.
We can simply wait for the bug to be fixed.
And chances are, most people are not going to be using WebDAV to put files up in any case.
And the reason I included it was just to show you how easy it can be to have multiple file systems.
So I'm going to let that one go for right now.
And when they've actually fixed the code for either the server or the client, I'll update this lecture.
But in the meantime, things seem to be working more or less as they should.
OK.
We'll move on in the next section to using Amazon's library for connecting to S3 buckets.