So this section of the course is all about responses.
And I'm right now, I'm looking at the documentation for Laravel and I'm looking at the HTP responses
section and there are some really convenient functions in here or functionality in here where I can,
for example, return a response as JSON just with one comment or say this response should be a file
download and again, a single command.
So we're going to implement similar functionality in celebrities.
Now, some of the things that you see up here, like redirects, for example, those are pretty specific
to Laravel and a lot of cases, but they're very easy to duplicate and go with.
The ones I'm really interested in are these other response types.
So let's see how we do that in celebrities.
And if we look at our code, we already have one function, right, Jason, that we used, that we wrote
what we did, the off token bit.
So we already have one response type in place the ability to respond as JSON.
Now we can do a similar thing and write a response as X amount, which is still using a lot of places,
even though I think JSON is in fact a much more intelligent data format.
Lots of people still use XML, so let's write a function that does that func see pointer to celebrities,
and we'll call this one not surprisingly, write X amount, and it will take a few parameters something
to write to.
So our response writer?
The status of the response, the status code we're going to give is as part of the response, which
is always an integer.
The data we want to convert to XML, we don't know what format that's going to be in.
So we'll call it data interface.
And we might want to put some additional headers in there, so I'll put headers.
Dot, dot dot and HTP dot header, not handler header.
That's better.
And potentially it returns an error.
So virtually the same signature as right, Jason.
And actually, the logic for doing this is pretty much the same as right Jason as well.
We still write an out variable and check for an error.
And this time we're going to call them out from the standard library dot.
And we want Marshall and I'm going to make it marshall and Dent.
Of course, you probably wouldn't do that in production, but I want to make sure that things look good
and I want the XFL to be readable.
So we're going to Marshall and Dent, and its first parameter is our data.
The second is a prefix, I don't want one.
And the third is, how do you want to indent this?
And I'll just put some spaces in there that'll be good enough.
And we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return it.
Otherwise, let's check the length of our headers.
If the line of headers is greater than zero, then we have a header.
We want to put in there and we'll put them all in.
For key and value, actually, this is exactly the same as this.
So why don't I just copy this and make life easier
there?
And next, we want to set our content type header and we want to write our status header and write it
out.
And all of that is exactly the same as this with one little change.
So we'll copy this will paste it in here.
Make an application XML and we're pretty much done with writing x amount.
So that's an easy one.
Another response type that we probably want to give is the ability to serve a file but force it to be
downloaded.
In other words, don't display it in the browser.
So let's make one for that Func C pointer to celebrities, and I'll call this response type download
file and it will.
Then we'll take a W HTP response writer.
We're also going to want the request in this, in this case, HDP dot request.
The full path to the file path to file and the file name, both of type string.
And again, we're going to check for now.
And this is pretty simple.
All we have to do is say, get the full path FP, OK?
That's going to be assigned the value of using the path package from the standard library dot joint.
And we want to join path to file and filing.
And now we want the file to serve, and I'm going to do a file perfect clean here just to make sure
that nobody's trying to trick our system and get something outside of a directory somewhere they shouldn't
have access to.
And this is really simple file to serve, which I have to spell right to serve is assigned the value
of file path dot clean.
And I'm cleaning up variable, I just declared on line 54.
Now we set the header type and we want this header to say, download this file, no matter what.
So we'll say W-, which is our response writer.
The header.
And this should not be a pointer to a response writer.
That's why that's not working typo w dot header dot set.
And we want to set the content type and because we want this to be downloaded.
We're going to use format dot se print F and R format string is going to be attachment eight to see
any anti semicolon space file name equals.
And then I'll escape my quote.
And in there I'll put a percent s and then I'll escape another quote and my substitution is just file
name.
So that gives me my header.
And now we just serve the file HTP da serve file, which is right from the standard library and we give
it W and R and file to serve.
And now we return.
Nil.
OK, so that's download file.
Now there's a few other things we may as well put in here, just things that will make it easier for
our users to to work with this package.
For example, what if a page is not found?
Well, I'll put in a really simple one that can be used for a lot of cases with a receiver of a pointer
to celebrities.
And I'll just call it error four or four, and that's just going to require the W, which is an ACTIVETO
response writer and the request, which is a pointer to dot request.
Now, at this point, I could write everything out, but I'm going to be doing a lot of errors.
Error 404 error five five hundred for internal server error, error, unauthorized things like that.
So rather than writing that same code out over and over.
Let's make it a generic function here below this one.
Func C pointer to celebrities and I'll call this one error status and it's gonna require the W ActiveTO
response writer.
It's going to require the request to point to ACP, don't request.
It's going to require the status which is in it, and all I'm going to say here is Typekit error error
or.
And I'll give it w h Typekit status.
Text which will translate our status into the appropriate text.
So I just have it status.
And finally, the status as in it.
OK.
And it turns out, I don't actually need the request.
So let's pull that one right over there.
So we don't need it at all.
Make it simpler.
And now up here for error of error four or four, I just call cdot error status and I hand it W and
a status not found.
Now I can copy this and paste it.
It just makes it clean and I'll make this one Air 500.
And call this status internal server error.
And again, I'll paste it.
And this one will be say error.
Unauthorized.
And this is HTP status status unauthorized?
And we'll do Forbidden, which is used in a lot of cases as well.
You're forbidden.
Status forbidden.
OK, so now we have all of these response types.
Now let's try a couple, a couple of them out, and in the next lecture, we'll modify the first page
on our celebrity application.
My app, that one and we'll put a link in to say, download a JSON file, download an XML file and download
a file.
And that should be sufficient to demonstrate this functionality, and we'll take care of that in the
next election.