So let's try out some of our response types, and right now I'm in the the My App project and I'm looking
at the file handlers and go, which of course is inside the handlers directory.
And what I'm going to do is scroll down to the bottom and I'll just write my handlers first.
So I want to have from the homepage a link to something that just renders some JSON just to try out
our right JSON functionality.
So it could a handler func receiver a pointer to handlers and I'll call this one.
Oh, say just JSON like that.
And it requires a response writer and a point of true request.
What we'll do is just make a little variable with the appropriate JSON tags, populate its values and
then write it out.
OK.
So we'll create a ver, which I'll just call payload as I often do when I'm working with Jason and I
use a lowercase l and it's a struggle and it has these fields just ID, which is an ID 64 and in JSON,
I want to call that ID and it has another one called say name and it's a string.
And in Jason, I'll call that content
and then hobbies,
which I'll call.
In Jason Hobbes.
Well, let's make that a slice of strings, OK?
The slice of string, because you can have more than one hobby and names, it probably would be called
name, not me, not content.
It will be.
It makes sense, even though this is just test data.
Now let's populate this information.
So payload died.
I'll make that equal to say 10.
And payload dart name.
I'll make that equal to Jack Jones and payload dot hobbies.
I'll make that equal to a slice of string.
And we'll give Jack a few hobbies.
So we'll give him, say, karate and maybe tennis and maybe programming.
Now we just write this out using our right Jason function.
We already had that function, but we'll put a link to it on the home page anyway, so we'll check for
error.
That's a sign of the value of H2O app Dot, right, Jason.
And again, you could write a helper function for this in the convenience package if you want it to
the convenience file.
But I'll just do it this way and that just requires W HP Dot status, OK, which is a good one, and
the payload I check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll just say each dot dot error log dot print line.
There, so that's our first one, that's pretty simple.
Now let's do one for X amount while we're at it.
So Funk and h pointed two handlers, and I'll just call this one x amount all caps.
And again, w h immediate response writer and our pointer to the GDP to request.
And here we'll do a similar thing.
But of course, the structure, for example, is a little bit different.
So I'll make a tip here.
Payload and it's a struggle.
And again, we'll give it an ID also and in sixty four.
And here in XML, I'll call that idea.
And name will be a string, and in XML, I'll call that name.
Here's a it's a little bit different.
I'll make hobbies also a slice of string.
But in XML, we'll make the hobbies and then a greater then sign and then hobby.
And of course, I'd close that quote.
So I have my tape.
Let's populate its values.
We actually need to declare a variable first of our payload of type payload there and payload i.e. is
equal to can again payload dot name.
We'll make that equal to John Smith and payload dot hobbies.
I'll just copy these ones.
What the copy savory typing them.
All right.
Now we have all the necessary values, so we just write X amount and it's almost the same as this.
I just copy and paste it down here.
But instead of calling, right, Jason, I'm going to call Right X amount.
Try that again.
Write X amount.
And that should work just fine.
Let's do one more.
Let's do our download one.
This one's really short.
First of all, do we have a file we can download or what's inside our public directory?
We have public images, and this alerts JPEG.
That'll work.
Fine.
OK.
So I'll create a function, and that's what I'll call.
Download file with W.H.
If you need a response writer and our pointer to HTTP request.
I can do this in one Line H Dot app Dot Ancestors' Receiver.
Of course, I left other H handlers H Dot app download file and I'll give it the information it needs.
And of course, what it needs is a path to that celerity file and the request and the response rate
in the reverse order w r and then the full path, which in my case will be dot slash public slash images
and then the file it, which is solara toss dot jpg.
And that should work.
All right.
In the next lecture, we'll go create links to all of these on the home dot git page and try them out
and make sure everything works the way that it should.