So we've created our three handlers to test our new response types.
Let's create some links in the home jet template right here.
Let's also create the necessary roots in our roots file right here in my app project.
So I'll create the roots right here first.
So I'll say it again because I can do that now and I want to get slash JSON and that will go to aid
handlers, thought Jason.
I'll duplicate that and do one, for example.
And that would take us to.
Well, duplicate that and say, download dash file.
It takes us to download file.
OK, now let's go back to our HomeKit page and create some links there.
So I'll just duplicate this one.
Make that one, Jason, and I'll label it Jason response
and duplicate that and call it X email response.
And it goes to slash X amount, and I'll duplicate that and make this one.
Download Dash file and download file response.
OK, so let's open our terminal and type, make restart or start or whatever you need to do to get it
running.
And go to our Web browser and reload this page.
Now I should click on Jason Response and actually get some Jason sent back.
And there it is.
So Firefox, of course, gives you this representation, but I can look at the raw data and there it
is.
Absolutely perfect.
So let's go back and let's try an XML response.
And there it is now, let's view, source and make sure it's actually XML.
And it looks great.
So hobbies.
Now has hobby three hobby entries.
Children of the hobbies entry.
And let's go back and make sure we can actually download a file.
So this should download celebrities start JPEG.
OK, so it actually displayed it in the browser.
Now that may be a function of Firefox, so what I'm going to do is open up Chrome and see what it does
in Chrome, because Chrome Firefox sometimes tries to be ever so helpful and it becomes a little too
helpful in some cases.
So I will go to local host four thousand.
And see what this does here.
So it looks like we might have something wrong in our response for downloading a file.
I'm going to go verify that and make sure we have it right.
So handlers don't go and I'll hide my terminal.
Download file, so that takes me to celebrities, so let me switch to celebrities package and find the
download file response.
Yeah, in fact, I do have that wrong, so I'm not going to set ahead or type to this.
Instead, I want to set the header to content disposition, so let's try.
Just I'll just delete that file in a moment.
W dot header dot set.
I always get this one backwards for some reason.
Content disposition.
And format Sprint F and here that's where I want the rest of it, so I'll just copy this part here.
It's not content type, it's content disposition.
That was a silly mistake.
So let's delete that and go back to our other application and open our terminal and type make restart.
And switch back to Firefox and try it out again.
So back on screen, reload this page.
Download file response.
And this time, if I refresh this, it should download it good, so it actually served the cache response
first with the content type instead of a content disposition, but when I reload the page, it did the
correct thing.
It tries to download it.
So those all seem to work really well.
Perfect.
So before we leave this section, there's one more thing I want to add, and that is the convenience
method that you find in Laravel that allows us to encrypt or decrypt a file with a single command.
And we should add that functionality to our helpers as well, and we'll take care of that in the next
lecture.