So there are lots of situations when you're working on a Web application when you need to encrypt something.
Let's say you're putting personal information in a database and you, like me are justifiably paranoid.
So you think, Well, I'm going to put this sensitive information in the database, and I know the database
is on its own server and it's behind an application firewall and a couple of packet filtering firewalls.
And the only access to it is physical or through a known IP address and an SSL certificate or a PKI
or something like that.
Whatever the case may be, but you still say, I'm going to put this information in the database, but
I'm going to encrypt it before I write it to the database and decrypt it when I pull it out.
There's lots of situations where you want to do this, and as you may know, Laravel makes that really
easy.
It's just calling a function encrypt and a function decrypt, and we can do a similar thing in celebrities.
So I'm back in the celebrity's package and I have the file helpers dot and go open.
And what I'm going to do is go to the very bottom of this file and create a a tape.
And I'm also going to create a couple of functions, one called encrypt and one called Decrypt.
OK, so I'll, first of all, create a type and I'm going to call the Typekit encryption, and it's
just a struct, and it only has one field and that field is key and it holds or is of the type a slice
of byte.
OK, and that will be the key we use to encrypt and decrypt all of our information.
Now create a function here, and the function is not going to have the receiver of see celebrities.
It's going to have the receiver of E a pointer to the type encryption.
So these are methods available on the type encryption.
And not surprisingly, the first one is going to be called encrypt, and it will take one parameter,
which I'll just call text a string and it will turn back or return a string and potentially an error.
OK.
And then I'll just duplicate this just to save some time and paste this here, and I'll call this one.
As you might have guessed, Decrypt not did encrypt Decrypt.
That's better.
And I'll call the parameter for that one, not text.
I'll call it crypto test.
So let's take care of this one.
First encrypt.
Let's give ourselves some screen real estate.
This is going to take a string, any string of any size, and it's going to encrypt it.
And then it's going to base 64 encoded so we can work with it and return that base 64 encoded encrypted
string.
OK.
So the first thing I'll do is declare a variable plaintext plain text and that will be assigned the
value of a slice of bytes text.
So we're converting what we get as a parameter to this function to a slice of bytes, and that's what
I need to work with, with when I'm when I'm working with the encryption packages.
Now I'm going to declare another variable called block, which is what we're going to use as part of
the encryption process, and I'll check for an error.
And then I'm going to call from the AEC package, which is available to us in crypto as part of the
standard library.
And from that, I'm going to call Lucifer.
And that is going to it requires some kind of encryption key, and it should be an easy key either 16,
24 or 32 bytes in length.
OK.
So I'm going to call Idukki now.
We don't have that yet.
Don't worry about it.
We're going to get it before too long.
OK?
We're going to have to have some value in there.
We don't get an error here because we're pointing to the receiver for this function.
But of course, when we instantiate this or when we try to encrypt or decrypt something, we need to
pass it.
A key and the key used to encrypt something must be exactly the same key used to decrypt something.
So we're going to have to get that somewhere.
And as you might guess, we're probably going to put that in the dart on file and make it available
to us.
So now I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll return an empty string and the error.
Otherwise, if we get past that now, I'm going to declare another variable called Cipher Mississippi
HDR Cipher text.
OK.
And that's going to be assigned the value of calling the make function.
I'm going to make a slice of byte is my first parameter and then I want it to be eight e s dot block
size.
That's a constant right out of the S package, plus the length of plain text that slice of bytes I created
up on Line 59.
So that creates the data structure we're going to use for our encryption.
OK, now next, I'm going to declare yet another variable called I've.
For some reason, crypto people always use Ivy for this variable team, and someday when I have the
time, I'm going to look it up and see what it stands for.
But not today.
So that's going to be a sign the value of ciphertext safe for text.
And we only want a part of it.
So we're going to put Colin Ace blocksize, and that gives me the part of that cipher text, which is
spelled wrong cipher text that gets me the part of that data structure that I want to work with.
OK.
And now I'm going to say if I'm going to ignore the first return value, but I am going to check for
an error error that's assigned the value of from the i o package.
Again, part of the standard library and I want read full read full right there.
And to make this encryption good, I'm going to call from the Rand package, which again is part of
the standard library ran dot reader and the second parameter is Ivy.
And then if the error is not equal to nil return, as you might expect an empty string and a message
saying whatever went wrong.
OK, now yet another variable, this one I'm going to call stream and I'm going to call Cipher CIPA
HDR, which is this one right here.
Crypto cipher from the crypto package Cipher Dot and the function name is a new c f be encrypted.
Now there's a bunch to choose from, so make sure you get the right one.
It's CSFB encrypted and I just hand it block and I've.
And now I'm going to say Stream Dot X o r key string right there.
And as you can see, it gives you a description, what it does here, how the encryption works.
So we're going to call that and we're going to hand it cipher text and in square brackets, the first
part of that data structure a block size column.
OK.
And then outside of the square brackets.
But before the closing parentheses, plain text and cipher text has to be spelled right.
Ciphertext, right?
And finally, we take that result.
What we get there and we return a base 64 encoded version of it, so we'll return and we're going to
use the base 64 package encoding base64.
You are all encoding.
And we want to encode to string cipher text and no error, so that return statement takes our data,
our cipher text in base64 encodes it encodes it to a string.
Make sure that you are all safe and sends it back and we return no error.
So that was a fair bit of logic, but it's actually pretty simple to encrypt and decrypt things and
go, it's got a great crypto package.
Now, it's not much use to encrypt something if you don't have a means of decrypting it.
So it's about the same amount of code and basically we're following the same process, but in reverse.
So we're going to declare, first of all, a variable called cipher text, cipher text, and we're going
to ignore the second parameter.
And those will be as a sign that's assigned its value from the base64 package.
And we want to call you are encoding base64 dot, the URL encoding, but this time we want to decode
a string.
OK.
And what we want is what was passed to this function.
Crypto text.
So now we have a variable called ciphertext.
Next, we'll get block and error again, calling a Saucony cipher.
And we want to use as its parameter the key, which we have to set up yet.
But we'll get there.
We'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, return an empty string and the error yourself, some more room.
So the next step is to make sure that the cipher text is of the correct length.
So we'll check if Len Cipher text.
Is less than a block size, and we're going to return an empty string in the air because this can't
be decrypted.
It's not the right length.
OK, so just a simple sanity check.
Once again, we'll get an I.V. and someday I'll find out why we're using I.V. for that variable name
cipher text, and we want to get a part of that.
So colon and the part at the end that is of length, a block size that constant from the U.S. Library.
And in this case, cipher text is now equal to cipher text escort block size.
OK, so now we're almost to the point where we can work with this.
Now we do.
The decryption stream is a sign the value of cipher dot new CFB Decryptor CFB make sure you get the
right one CFB decryptor, OK.
And we just had that block and.
And now stream Dot X for key stream once again.
And we had that cipher text.
Then we handed cipher text again, which might seem odd, but that's the way you decrypt things.
Cipher text at least A.
S encryption and decryption.
And now we just return and we'll just format this in the correct format we want.
We want it to be in the form of a string.
So I'll just use a format as print f and my format string is percent s lowercase s and my substitution
is cipher text and the second return value is nil, because at this point, everything should have gone
right, except that I have a mistake here somewhere.
I left, Colonel.
Yeah, that's a little better.
We want the first part of that data structure, so we're going to return this.
Now it's giving me a helpful warning, saying this argument's underlying type is a slice of bytes.
You use simple conversion.
All right, we'll do that then fine.
If it makes you happier, string.
OK, it is less programming.
So I'm going to side with the code on this one, but I'm so used to using the format package.
Sometimes muscle memory kicks in.
OK, so that was a fair bit of typing, but now we have the three things we need to be able to start
the encryption process.
We have the type encryption.
We have a method on that type or a function on that type to encrypt something and a function on that
type to decrypt something.
So the next step is to figure out how we populate the field key in the type encryption before we can
actually do it, because without that, we're not going to have anything to work with at all.
We'll have no means of actually successfully calling either encrypt or decrypt, and we'll get started
on that in the next election.