So we have our encryption functions written, but we can't use them until we have an encryption key.
And right now, I'm looking at the dot on file in my app.
And if you scroll to the very bottom of that file, you see there's a place to put that encryption key.
And it also has a comment that says it must be exactly 32 characters long.
Now, that's pretty straightforward.
We already have a function that generates a random string of characters of in length.
So we could just call that function with the number 32 and put it in there, or we could just manually
type out 32 random characters.
But I think the easiest thing to do is to switch back to the celebrity's project and open up the CMG
folder, then the Seelye folder and go to the main function.
And what we'll do, we'll add a command in our house helper that generates that string of 32 characters
for us, and we'll use it later on when we actually implement the new functionality.
When we build a new application using this binary and we can pre-populated a dot on file with a 30 to
32 character long string of random characters.
So it means we'll do that here right now and get started.
So in the main function of mean, don't go.
I'm going to go to do make and it's a very top here.
I'll just say case key like that, and we'll make this return a 32 bit random string or 32 character
long random string of bits.
That's a totally different thing.
So I'll declare a variable R&amp;D for Ferrand, and I'll just call Cel Dot random string and hand it thirty
two and then I'll print that out.
Color Dot Yellow
32 character encryption key and put in a percent s and we'll just put R&amp;D here.
Now, it didn't import color for me as long to try that again, color yellow.
Well, I'll just go manually, type it in here, and it is GitHub dot com slash f a t h slash color
there.
I fixed that.
And that's all I really have to do for that.
So now if I actually start my or open my terminal and type make build seal alive.
They should build it and put it over in my app, and I can switch over to my app and open the terminal
and clear the screen and type dot slash celebrities make key.
And it gives you my three Typekit, so about 30 security keys.
So I'll copy that and I'll paste it right here in the door on file.
Now I have a means of reading that information when I start my application.
So the question, of course, is where do I actually get this encryption key?
What?
We don't do it in my app.
If you recall, when we started our application, let's just find the main go here.
So mean Dongo, that actually calls the myth.
First thing the main function does is it calls in it application for if we go over here, that actually
here on Line 21, after we get the working path and after we declare a cell variable of type celerity
celebrities we call celebrities don't new.
So let's switch over to celebrities and let's hydro terminal and open celebrities don't go and find
that new function.
So this is the new function right here.
Now, one of the things it does, of course, is it populates values, insularity.
What I'm going to do is just out of field here, so I'll add a field right here called encryption key
of type string
and say that format it and down in the new function.
Say, after I declare the session right here, I can just populate see DOT encryption key is equal to
OS arms or get on, and I'm looking for cheap because this was called in the dot on file.
So now I have that encryption key.
So of course, now that I have the functions encrypt and decrypt and the type encryption and I have
an encryption key in my celebrity's variable, at this point, we should be able to encrypt something
and decrypt something on our inner My App application.
So we'll try that in the next lecture.