So we have our encryption key set.
We have the functions, insularity.
Let's try it out here in my app.
And the first thing I'm going to do because I need to make sure that my app is aware of this new encryption
functionality is I open my terminal and type of go mode vendor just to update the dependencies from
the other project.
And that should take care of it.
Now, how am I going to do this?
Well, I could if I wanted to write a handler and do all the hard work right in the handler.
But why don't we jump right to the convenience functions first, and I want to assume that.
And this just for the sake of this, this lecture, I'm going to assume that most of our encryption
will be done inside the handlers package.
So I'll open the convenience functionality in their convenience, Darko at the very end.
And you can put these helpers in any place you need to have them, of course.
I'll create a function with the receiver of a pointer to handlers,
and I'm going to call this one.
Not surprisingly, encrypt E and C are wiped, and it will take one argument text of type string and
it will return a string and potentially an error.
OK.
So how do I use this?
Well, it's actually pretty simple.
I'm going to create a variable called ink, and it's going to be assigned the value of celebrities dot
encryption.
That type I made a little while ago and I'll pre-populated.
It's one field key with what we have, of course, is our H Dot app dot encryption key.
But this needs to be in a slice of bytes, insularity, encryption, so I'll just cast it to a slice
of pie and it's going to have E or H Dot app.
Encryption key like that?
OK.
For some reason, this did not import celebrities for me.
So let's try that again, celebrities.
That's better.
So it part of that for me.
So now I have that ink variable.
And if you recall, everything we need to encrypt or decrypt is right on that variable.
Think EMC.
So I can say encrypted c r y e d and potentially an error come from ink, dot, encrypt and text.
I called it test up here and I wanted to call it text.
That's better.
Well, check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return an empty string and the error otherwise return encrypted
and no.
So that should encrypt something.
Now, if I copied this whole thing and make the necessary changes paste pasted in here and call this
decrypt.
And I'll call this variable crypto just because it's clearer and now I want to call Decrypt and crypto,
and that should do it for me.
OK, so we have these two helper functions or convenience functions available to us.
Let's go use them.
So we'll make this dead simple.
Will create a new handler, so we'll go to handlers and I'll scroll.
The very bottom of this will create a new function with the type of h pointer to handlers.
And I'll call it test crypto crypto W.H. Speed Up Response Writer and our is a pointer to HGTV Dot request.
So I'll just create a variable some text on it.
So plain text is assigned the value of Hello World.
Then I'll just write that right to the browser window.
This won't be a pretty page, but it will work, hopefully.
So I'll say format dot f print and we're going to print W and we'll print unencrypted
plus plain text plus because they're not writing HTML.
I'll just put a line feed in there.
OK, then I'll say encrypted and earth come from H Dot Encrypt and we'll encrypt plain text.
I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
I'll just write to the error log.
H2 app Air Log Dot Print Line, and I'll print out the air and then I'll call each dot.
Error 500.
Why not?
OK.
And that requires W R and that's it, and I'll return.
Otherwise, let's print that out.
Format dot f print and I'll print out W encrypted plus encrypted,
and that will decrypt it.
So we'll say decrypted and potentially there come from H Dot, Decrypt and I had that encrypted.
And I'll check for an error, so I'll copy this stuff, paste it in here, and then I'll print out the
decrypted text.
I better put a carriage and return at the end of that.
And a copy this and paste it down here and change this to decrypted the label and printed decrypted.
OK, so now I have a rather simple, simplistic, but it's testing everything I want to test because
plain text is only used when I print it to the terminal the first time or printed to the browser window
the first time.
And then I encrypt it and he never to use it again so that I print out the actual encrypted value a
base64 encrypted string.
Then I decrypt encrypted and then I print out decrypted.
So if this gives the same value at the very end as it does at the beginning, hello world, then everything
works as expected.
So let's open a reach for the let's test it out.
So a yet.
And I'll put it as crypto and that calls a dot handlers
dot test crypto.
So let's open our terminal window.
Make stop.
In case it's running, it was make start.
And I'm going to go to local host 4000 crypto.
So let's switch to our Web browser.
OK.
Just reload this to make sure it's working.
It is.
And up here, I'll just put slash crypto page not found.
I left the top off t.
Oh, so we have hello world.
Then we have the encrypted string and then we have decrypted hello world.
So that works exactly as it should.
And of course, if you need that encryption functionality, say somewhere else in your application,
not in your handler's folder.
Just copy those same two functions, change the receivers to the appropriate value, and you are good
to go.