So in this section of the course, we're going to go to some things that I have deliberately left until
now.
And you might've been asking yourself and I'm looking at the database right now in my Docker image.
Why do we have this remember tokens table?
And if we look at it, you know, it's a pretty simple table.
It only has an ideal user ID remember token.
And then the standard created an updated at fields.
And we've never done anything with this.
And of course, this table will be used.
When someone logs in, they'll check a box or flip, flip a toggle or whatever that says, remember
me, so they don't have to log in every time that they come to the site.
And this is a really common feature, and it's a really useful feature.
People like it.
So let's implement that this time around.
And the reason I've left it until this late in the course is because at some point you're going to have
to come back and add new functionality, and this is the kind of functionality you might be adding.
So let's go through the process of how we're going to make this happen.
And I'm looking at the My App project, and here's where I'm going to build the functionality.
And then after we have it working, we'll move it over to this layer toss package as part of the command
line interface.
So of course, this will be added to the make off functionality, but let's get started.
The first thing we're going to have to have, obviously, is in our data folder.
We'll have to have something that describes the model.
So we'll create a new file in here and I'll call it remember underscore token go.
And of course, it's going to have a package data
and we create a type that describes the kind of structure we have in the database type.
And I'll call it remember token and it's just a struct.
And now we put its fields in there and the first one is ID of Typekit.
And this is the primary key.
So we use the DB descriptor like this ID and umit empty.
I want to leave that one out or it's not going to work.
So we have the ID, we have the user ID, which is also mentioned in the database that's called user
underscore ID.
Then we have the Remember token, which is a string, and in the database, I call that remember underscore
token and remember that the descriptor in the DB tags has to match exactly what's in the database.
And I have created a lot of time dot time
and in the database that's called created underscore that cannot duplicate that and change this one
to updated it
and updated that.
So let's save that.
So there's the type and of course, we want a table function as well func.
And this one will have the receiver of T remember token and we just call a table and it returns a string.
And all we need to put in there right now is return.
Remember tokens, the actual name in the database?
Now we're really only going to need two functions associated with the Remember token one to insert them
and one to delete them.
And that probably should be sufficient for our purposes right now.
So let's make those I'll call this one func with the receiver T pointer to remember token, and this
one's going to be called insert token and it takes a user ID, which is in it, and it takes the token,
which is a string, and it returns potentially in error.
And we just follow.
Our standard way of using upper collection is assign the value of Upper Dot Collection, and that takes
one argument to the table.
So that returns the table name.
And that's exactly what we need and that will create a Remember token.
Remember token is assigned the value of type, remember token, and we fill in its fields and we leave
it empty because that's auto updated when we insert.
But we need to put in User ID, which is User ID, and we need to put in remember token, which is actually
the token received as a call to this function and created a will be timed right now and updated.
It will be timed on that.
So we have a variable.
We just do the insert.
We don't care about the insert IDs.
We ignore the first return parameter, but we do check for an error there.
Assign the value of collection, not insert, and we're inserting Iremember token.
We check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, return the error, otherwise return nil.
So that's the insert.
And we also need to be able to delete these funk t point or to remember token, and we'll call it delete,
and it just takes the Remember tokens string.
Remember, remember BR token, which is a string and it potentially returns in error, so we'll be deleting
by token.
So same idea collection is a sign the value of a perfect collection, and we call to the table to get
the table name.
We get a result and that's a sign the value of collection, the find and we're looking for up condition
and in curly brackets.
Remember token.
Followed by a colon, followed by the parameter pass to this function.
So we find it, and it didn't import up for us.
Let's try that again up and we'll just get the import from another model.
So we'll go to Tokyo and find out what up is.
It's this one less copy that and switch back to remember a token put that are imports
and close the parentheses there.
Now we have a result and we call error is a sign the value of resort delete if error is not equal to
nil and return the error, otherwise return null.
So we now have a data structure that describes our table and allows us to insert and delete tokens.
OK, now the next step, of course, is to figure out how we're going to implement the actual remember
me functionality and the far and away.
The easiest way to do this is to write some middleware middleware that checks for the existence of some
value.
If it finds it, it logs the user in, and if it doesn't, it just keeps going and doesn't allow the
user to be logged in.
So what I'll do is create some middleware.
And again, the model we created here in the data folder and the middleware we're about to create will
both be copied over to our template folder in a read only file system for the command line interface.
And when someone types make off, it will install these along with the things it's already installing.
But let's write the middleware first, so I'll go to my middleware folder and I'll create a new file
in there and I'll call it.
Just remember, don't go.
And of course, its package is middleware,
and we'll just write some middleware so func with a receiver of a pointer to the middleware, same as
the rest of them.
And I'll call this one check.
Remember, remember?
And it's middleware, so it takes a next parameter of Type H HDP dog handler and it returns any checkpoint
handler.
So of course, the first thing we need to check in here is whether or not the person is actually logged
in.
And of course, to do that, we have to check the session and check for the existence of a value in
the session called User ID with no case, I add an uppercase D, so that means I'm going to have to
write my middleware.
Like this return http dot handler func and have an inline function that gives me the two variables,
or at least one variable that I need access to, which is the request.
So W8 Sheetmetal Response Writer and our pointer to HTP request and now I check to see if the user's
logged in.
If not, then we'll use our Receiver M Dot app and then get this session.
Dot exists and we need to pass that are not context and we're looking for user ID like that.
So if that doesn't exist, then the user is not logged in.
OK, and we'll do something else.
The user is logged in, and if they're logged in, we're just going to call next dot, serve http with
W and R, OK?
But here's the part where we actually need to do some decision making to determine whether or not there's
some value we can look at and determine if it's valid and if it is, then let the person be logged in
automatically log them in and if it's not, do something else.
And what I'll do is I'll check for the existence of a remember cookie, a cookie that has some values
in it that allows me to determine whether or not the person is a valid user.
So I'll look for a cookie and check for an error.
And those come from right from the standard library.
Our cookie and we're looking for a cookie with a particular name, which means when a user logs in and
checks box that says, Remember me, we need to set that cookie.
And when we do use the same name there as we're using here.
And I think the easiest way to do that is to just write format as print f and we'll name the cookie.
And I'll start it with an underscore and then some string value and then another underscore.
And then remember and what I'll substitute for that percent s is the app name import app Apni.
So we're looking for that cookie.
OK, now if the error is not equal to nil, then there is no cookie.
So on to the next middleware if.
So all we do again is you say next, don't serve HDP, W.R..
And at that point, we're done that check.
But if the cookie exists, if we get past that, then we have an else statement.
We found a cookie.
So check it.
And what I'm going to do here is say the value of the cookie is stored in something called key.
So key is cookie dough value, cookie token value, and I'll create an empty user variable, which I'll
call you.
It's a type of data user.
Let's make sure it's doing the imports for us.
It is good.
And now we'll check to see if the data in that cookie has a length of greater than zero because if it
doesn't, then it's a useless cookie.
If Len of key is greater than zero.
OK, Cookie has some data so validated.
So what we'll do here is assume one of restoring some value in that cookie.
Some data in that cookie that will be separated by the Typekit, and I'll split on that Typekit.
So I'll call the variable I'm going to create here split.
And that's a sign the value of right from the strings package strings starts split and I'm going to
split the key on the pipe character.
That's straight line.
OK.
And I will assume that the user ID is the first thing in that split variable, so I'll call it UID,
and a hash is the second thing in that variable and that will be the remember me token.
And those are populated by calling.
Split.
Zero.
The first value and split one is a second value.
That's almost a store in there is the user ID, a pipe and then some token.
And now I need to convert the ID, the UID variable, which I'll get in the form of a string.
I need to convert it into an integer.
And that's easy, Heidi, and I'll ignore the error and we call Sturt on.
Not a I mean, we're passing a UID.
So now I have the hash or the token in a string and I have the user ID as an int.
OK, so now I'm going to have to call a function that says, is this a valid hash?
In other words, we're going to have to check for a member token that's associated with this user I.D..
And of course, the place to put that is over here in the data folder user ago.
And at the very end of this file, I'll just add another method another function.
OK.
So it will be a func with a receiver of you, pointed a user.
Same as all the other functions in here, and we'll call this one check for Remember token, and it
will take an IV, which is the user ID of Typekit.
And it will take the token, which is a string and it just returns Boolean.
And all we have to do here is create a variable.
Remember me?
I call remember token, remember token of type, remember token, and I'll create another variable called
R.T, which is of type, remember token, and I'll give it the curly brackets because it's just populated
with default values and I create a collection and the collection is Upper Dot Collection.
And this is why I created the art variable, because you need to get the name of the Remember tokens
table.
So I'll just call art table or Team Table, and that gives me the correct table name.
And now I just say result is a sign the value of collection dot find
and I'm going to use the update condition of user underscore ID is equal to it.
And remember, token is equal to token.
And now I say error is a sign.
The value of red dot one find one value and read it into remember token.
If the error is not equal to nil and we can't find it, so return.
Actually, all we have to do here is return.
The error return error is equal to nil, and that will return false if it can't find it.
And true, if it can.
And that's pretty straightforward.
So now we can go back to our middleware and call that function.
So we'll store the result of that function.
We're going to call it a variable called valid hash.
In other words, it's a valid token, and that is a sign the value of from the new variable.
The user we created up there on Line 22 dog check for Remember token and we handed ID and hash.
And now that will be true if this is a valid token and it will be false if it's not a valid token.
So I'll say, if not valid hash, then it's not true.
OK.
So I'll say at this point, I did find a cookie, but it's not a valid cookie, so I probably want to
delete it.
And the way you delete cookies in the internet world is kind of strange.
You don't just call the delete function.
You actually set a cookie with the same name and attributes, but give it an expiry in the past.
So I'm going to have to do that, and I'm probably going to have to do it more than once.
So I'm going to put that off in its own function.
So I'll call this func m pointer to middleware that says receiver, and I'm not going to export this.
I'll just call it delete.
Remember Cookie?
And that requires two arguments.
The response writer
and not surprisingly, the pointer to the request.
So let's give ourselves some room.
And the first thing I'm going to do is it's always good practice when you do this sort of thing.
It's just to renew whatever token you have in the session.
So I'll ignore the error and that's equal to M Dot after dot session dot renew token.
And I'm going to renew it.
You have to pass it, the perimeter, the context.
So that renews the token.
And that's just good practice.
And now I'll delete the cookie.
And as I said, to do that, we have to create a cookie, which I'll call a new cookie.
And that's a sign the value of HGTV dot cookie.
And we just said it's values.
So its name.
Well, and that's going to be exactly what it was up here.
Format or desperate have in all of this law.
Copy that and paste that here and its value also to an empty string and its path.
This just has to match the cookie that exists.
I'll just make it slash.
And that's what I'll make it when I set the cookie, when someone logs in and checks the Remember Me
box and I'll make it expire and expires.
It's going to be set to something in the past time.
Not now.
So the current time don't add and we'll add minus 100 times time to our, put it, 100 hours in the
past.
So that's it expires, and HDP only will set to true and the domain will be equal to import app dot
session dot cookie.
So Session Dot, Cookie Dot Domain and I will set it's max age equal to minus one again expire right
away.
Is it a secure cookie?
Well, that will be set to whatever MDOT app dot session dot cookie dot secure is.
So that'll be false in development and true in production.
And we need the same site attribute and I'm going to use A2DP dot same site, strict mode right there.
So we've created the cookie.
Now we just sent each Typekit set cookie and we handed the response writer in a reference to New Cookie,
which is what it requires.
And then we logged the user and they may not be logged in at this point, but just to be safe.
MDOT app dot session.
Remove, and I'm going to remove from our context, user ID like that, and then I'll destroy the app,
not session, not destroy our context, destroy the session entirely, and I'll renew the token one
more time, which I might not have to, but I'm paranoid about this sort of thing.
Imgur app dot session dot renew token.
And that requires just the context.
OK, so now I have a means of deleting the cookie.
So mark up here.
In this function, let's delete the remember cookie.
So we call them delete, remember cookie and hand the response writer and the pointer to the request.
Now we have a new session created right after we delete that.
Remember Cookie?
So I'm going to say, assume that you're probably going to want to give some kind of message to the
user.
So I'll just say M Dot app dot session dot put and had it the context or not context.
And hand it an error message and then whatever the message might be, so I'll just say you've been logged
out from another device, which is almost always the situation that takes place.
OK.
But you can put whatever you want for in your message there.
And now we call next sort, serve a trip with a response writer and the pointer to the request.
And that's done.
Otherwise, if it is a valid hash else, valid hash, so log the user in and this is the automatic log
in part.
And all we have to do is, say user a new variable and I'll ignore the error.
You can put error checking in if you wish you try.
That again equals.
You don't get and handed the ID.
Now I have the user variable in the session, I'll say M&amp;A app, dot session Dot put.
I'll just set the necessary variables for someone to be logged in.
So we'll put in the context and user ID and make that user ID, which I just pulled from the database.
Then I'll duplicate this whole thing.
I'm going to put another value in there and the value will be remembered.
Remember underscore token and I'll put the hash in because I might might need that.
Okay.
The Remember Me token.
And at this point, I just say next, does it serve HDP work?
And they're all logged in and on they go on their merry way.
Now, at this point, right here, this is the last part of the link.
If we're checking if the length of the key is greater than zero, if the length of the key is equal
to zero.
And else that's probably happened is that the key length is zero.
So it's probably a leftover cookie, and that usually takes place when the user has not closed browser.
OK, but whatever the case is, the key length is zero.
So I'm going to delete that cookie, which is useless now and delete to remember Cookie An and we'll
say next serve.
H GDP W in error.
And if we did everything right, this middleware can be added to our roots file and check to see if
someone is properly logged in.
But of course, there's one more step that we have to follow here, and that is we have to update our
authentication handlers to check to see if someone checks a particular checkbox in the form that says,
Remember me?
If they did, we need to write a value into the room, remember me tokens table associated with that
user.
And we also, of course, have to update the form, the form that displays the login credentials.
And finally, when someone logs out, we want to make sure that Remember Me token is deleted from the
database.
Otherwise, there's a potential loophole where people can get into the system without being authenticated.
So we'll take care of those steps in the next lecture.