So let's get started with some of the changes necessary to make our remember me functionality actually
functional.
So I mean, I can my app and I'm going to look under The View's folder and I'll go to log in jet and
I'll add a little toggle there.
So I'll put it right here before the forgot password bit and say, and I'll just use bootstraps.
Nice little toggle.
So Div class equals form check.
Formed a switch.
And I'll close that, Dave, and in between, I'll put the two required fields input class equals form
dash checked dash input type equals checkbox value equals and I'll use the word remember all lowercase
for the value.
And its ID equals, remember, and I also need a name, of course.
Name equals remember, and I'll give it its label label class equals formed check, dash label and four
equals, remember?
And I'll just put remember me.
Label.
So let's see how that looks.
I'll make sure my application is running.
Make restart.
OK.
So it's running.
Let's go to our web browser.
And go to local host four thousand.
OK, so I'm not logged in, so I'll get a log any user.
And I didn't quite look the way I wanted, so I made something wrong there.
Let's go back and fix that.
It should be four months which.
Try that, save it, go back to our web browser, reload this.
And that's better.
So now I have a remember me toggle that's on.
That's off.
Perfect.
Doesn't do anything yet, so let's go fix that.
So the next thing I want to do is to go to my auth handlers.
So let's open off handlers.
It's under handlers.
Most handlers and let's find the part where the person actually logs in right here.
So that would be right after this check if matches.
OK, we have invalid password when we return, but if we get past that, presumably that can be logged
in.
So at this point, we need to decide.
Did the user check?
Remember me?
And it's a form checkbox.
So all we have to do is to say if our dot form dot yet and we're looking for remember.
And because it's a checkbox, this will only be populated if it was actually checked.
Otherwise, it's an empty string, if that equals, remember?
Then they checked.
Remember me?
So what do we do if they checked?
But we need to create a kind of token they can use to log in using the cookie, so we'll create a random
string.
So we'll just create a random string, which is sufficient for our purposes.
So I'll store that in a variable called random string.
And that's assigned the value of each dot random string with a length of 12.
And then we'll create a hasher.
And that's a sign the value of s h a 256 right from the standard library dot new.
And then we'll ignore the return value, but check for an error and say that is a sign the value of
hasher right?
And it requires a slice of bite.
So we'll take our random string and cast that to a slice of votes.
Random string.
And if the error is not equal to nil, then we'll just give them a bad, bad request short app dart
status, the error status.
And I'll call it W, R and H football status bad request, which is sufficient for testing purposes.
And what's it giving me here?
Too many arguments, right?
Studies only requires a W in the status.
We don't need the the R, so we get better there, there and we'll return.
But if we get past that, then let's create a variable called Shah and we'll use base sixty four from
a standard library that you are all encoding the encode to string.
And we'll hand that Hasher Dot song with no arguments.
No.
And that will create a Remember token, Ahram for Remember token is of the type day to remember token.
With empty, curly braces.
We'll check for an error when we call our import insert token and we'll insert the user ID.
And I say check.
Now, let's make sure we actually have that user because they don't recall if we.
Yes, we did, we got the user up here in Line twenty seven.
So we have that, that's good.
So that's a valid thing.
And again, we'll check for an error.
So a copy this error checking code and paste it right here.
So we've inserted the token and into the database now there, remember me token that we have to set
a cookie and the cookie must be exactly the same format as the one we use for our delete cookie token.
So we'll get that right.
First of all, it's the expiry for it.
So I'll say this cookie expires, expire is assigned the value of time done now, and this will be whatever
you want for the rules for your cookie.
Try that again.
Time now.
And I will add, and in my case, I'm going to make it last a really long time.
Three hundred and sixty five times.
Twenty four hours times.
60 minutes times.
60 seconds times time dot second.
OK, so that will be the expiry for our cookie.
Now let's create the cookie.
Cookie is assigned the value of from GDP, the type cookie, and we populate the fields.
So the name and this has to be exactly what we use before that will be format as per death and our format
string will be an underscore and a string and another underscore.
And then remember, and we're substituting for that H2O app, Apni.
So that gives me the correct cookie name, which exactly matches what I used everywhere else in referring
to this cookie.
And it needs a value.
And if you recall, what I'm going to sell for the value are two things separated by a pipe.
So format as pretest, and I want an integer and then a pipe and then a string, and I'm substituting
for those user ID because I need the user's I.D. and then I want shot.
You want a comma.
So that's name and value.
The path I had set to the root level of the application expires in this case is expired.
HGTV only asset to true.
Domain is H Dot app, dot session, dot cookie dot domain, max age.
I'll make that equal two seconds in a year, which is three one five three six zero.
Zero zero zero.
Secure is equal to each dot app, dot session, dot, cookie dot, secure faults in development, true
in production.
And the last thing is same site and that's set to HGTV Dot same site, strict mode right there.
That defines the cookie.
Now let's set it aside, Peter said Cookie.
And that requires the response writer in a reference to the cookie we just created.
And then I'm going to save hash in session.
If you recall, I called it remember underscore token.
So start app the session that could not pop put.
And we need context.
And we're going to call it remember underscore token.
And that's shot.
And at that point, I should be pretty much ready to go.
So if they've not checked, remember me, none of this code gets executed, but if they have checked,
remember me, then that's good.
OK, so that that takes care of logging the user in now in log out.
We have some other things to do as well.
First of all, we want to delete the Remember token
if it exists.
And that's really simple.
We just say if each app dot session dot exists and we check using our context and we're looking for,
remember, underscore token if that exists.
Well, let's get rid of the Remember token.
Artie is just a variable and declaring of type data dot remember token, and I'm only declaring it so
I can call a method on it.
Like, ignore, the error is I don't really care if it doesn't exist or not.
And I call delete and I handed each Dot app dot session.
Get string, and that requires the context, and it requires the name I'm looking for, which is remember
underscore token.
So that should delete the token from the database if it exists.
OK.
And now I need to delete the Remember Me cookie.
So delete the cookie.
I can check to see if it exists first, but I'm still going to have to set a cookie even if it does.
So I may as well just set a cookie that expired.
So we'll copy the cookie we have here and change its values just to save some typing.
Paste that in there and I'll call it new cookie and I'll make its value an empty string.
But its name has to stay the same, so its value is empty.
This is the same, except expires is time now, and we use the same logic we did before that ad, minus
one hundred times timed our set it now 100 hours in the past that stays the same.
That stays the same.
This becomes minus one because we want it deleted.
We want it to be expired.
That stays the same and that stays the same.
And then we set the cookie HDP Dot set cookie.
And we handed W and a reference to new cookie.
And then we can renew the token, we remove user ID.
We may also remove, remember, underscore token.
And let's destroy this session H2O app, which I think I should have done before session got destroyed.
And that just requires out of context, everyone knew that took it again, just because I'm paranoid
about that sort of thing.
I think that will take care of that.
So at this point, we have our off handlers updated, we have middleware available to us.
We've updated our form to put the appropriate toggle in there.
So the last thing to do is to actually try it all out and see if it works and we'll give that a whirl
in the next lecture.