So let's try it, our check, remember functionality, and right now I'm in my app and I'm looking at
the roots go, and obviously one of the first things we have to do is to add the necessary middleware,
which is as simple as adult use.
And I want a middleware Typekit check.
Remember?
OK, so that adds the middleware to our roots.
Now, if we go over to our dot on the file and we go to the session bit.
You can see that I'm using a recession, and if you're not switchers to read, it's just that we're
doing the same thing.
Now let's go back over to celebrities that project and see how long sessions are set to last.
So over here and celebrities, if we look at the part where we actually in it, things, so we have
our celebrities to go and we look at new.
So here's the new bit.
Let's find the bit where we initialize our sessions.
So our session lifetime is set to see de-conflict cookie dot lifetime.
OK, so if we go back to our dot on file, it will look at our cookie lifetime that's set to one thousand
four hundred and forty minutes.
So change that to one.
OK, so it'll be one minute.
And now I'm going to open my terminal and make sure that my Docker images are running Docker compose
up dash.
And that should start Docker for me.
Now I'll run my application.
Make start.
OK.
So it's running.
And let's go back to our Web browser and reload, this page localhost four thousand.
OK, so I am not logged in, which is good.
Now let's try logging in.
I'll log in as me out here dot com with the password password and I will check.
Remember me and log in.
OK.
So I'm logged in now, I'm going to pause the video and I'll wait a little more than a minute and then
I'll refresh this page and I should still be logged in even though my sessions are set to one minute.
So I'll see you in 60 seconds or so.
So a little more than a minute has gone by.
So my session should have timed out by now, and I'm going to reload this page and you can see I'm still
logged in.
So I remember me functionality seems to be working as it should.
So the next thing I'd like to do is to take care of this.
Let's go log out here and click on forgot password.
Well, don't click on it because there's nothing behind it right now.
What I'd like to do next is to implement that functionality as well, and it's really simple, so we'll
get started on that in the next lecture.