So this time around, we want to implement password resets.
In other words, someone is trying to log into the system and they can't remember what password they
used.
So they click on a little link labeled forgot password.
Enter their email address.
The system checks to make sure we have a user with that email address, and if we do, we generate a
secure email with a link in it and send it to the user.
The user clicks on that link and enters a new password.
Verifies the password.
Click Save and their password has been changed and they can log in.
So to get started, we're going to need a couple of views.
And if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a zip file you can download called
Forgot Dash Views or something like that.
Extract the contents and you'll find two files.
One is called forgot jet and one is called Reset Password.
So extract these zip file and put those two jets jet files right in The View's folder in my app, and
let's have a look at them.
So here we have one called forgot.
OK?
And forgot his very straightforward.
He uses the base layout, we set a title.
We have nothing in the CSE's block and in page content is a simple form and it has.
You'll notice here something called dot error and that doesn't exist yet in our template.
So we're going to have to add that in just a moment, and we will.
But this is a very simple form they put in their email address.
They click, send password, reset email and we do something on the back.
So that's the first one.
And the second one is called Reset Password Dot Jet, and it's pretty much the same.
Only now they enter their password, they enter their new password and they click Reset password.
OK, so the first thing we're going to do is we'll create a handler that displays this page forgot dot.
Just before we can do that.
Of course, we need to add that type error to our template data, and we don't do that in my app.
We do that over in this file.
Render Don't go in the celebrities project.
So bring that up.
And let's add a few fields to this.
We'll add some that we'll be using later on anyway.
So the first of all we want is called error, and it's just a string.
OK.
And we're also going to put in a flash, which is again going to be a string, and that'll be a message
that goes to the session.
Just briefly, it goes there for only the next request.
It's called a flash message, so we can do something with that in a bit.
OK, so let's save this, and then let's switch back to our other project.
And now that we have our views where they need to be, we obviously need to go to our handlers.
So let's go to art handlers.
Don't go inside the handlers folder in my app.
And let's just write a really simple handler that displays the forgot page.
So funk with receiver of pointer to handlers, and we'll call this one forgot.
That's simple enough.
It should be paid off response writer and as a pointer to issue tip request.
And all we're going to do here is just render a template.
So that's as simple as errors.
Assign the value of each dot render and we give it W and her the name of our template, which is forgot
because ours is called forgot dot jet and nothing for data.
And we check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And I'll just write to the log file each Dot app.
The error log dot print line,
error rendering with the error, and then I'll call say, H Dot app.
Dot your status.
Air 500, that's a good one.
And what does that require Air 500 requires?
The W in the air.
That's it.
W R and that's it.
OK.
So now, if I go to my roots, Farro, which we have to have a route to as first of all, let's find
out what link we have on the in page.
When someone clicks on forgot password, they are going here slash user slash forgot password.
OK, so I've got the link.
Now let's open our routes file.
And I'll put it right here with the rest of the user roots, so I can just type aid on, get and give
it the route I want, so I'll paste that root in there and it goes to aid our handlers but forgot handlers
there.
So now I should be able to start my application.
Let's start.
OK, so let's go back to.
Web browser, and I'll click on, log in the user and make sure this page renders the way that it should.
Alex Cook.
OK, so you have to enter an email address and off you go.
Now that was the easy part.
Obviously, we need to do a bit more work once someone actually puts in an email address and clicks,
send password, reset email and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.