So now that we have the form that shows the I forgot my password page, we need to create the handler
that actually takes the post request from that form.
So let's get started and I'm back in my app and I'm looking at the file off their handlers don't go
and I'll create a stub handler, so I'll just copy this one and paste it here and rename it.
And I'll call it post.
Forgot, OK?
And I'll just comment about the entirety of it, and then I'll go over to my roots file just to get
this out of the way.
And I'll find this route right here on Line 26, the one that displays the I forgot my password page,
I'll duplicate it changed to a post and I'll make sure that the handler that is called is post forgot.
OK, now back to our handlers.
Obviously, we're not displaying a pager, so this can go away entirely, actually.
Let's think about what's going to happen here.
What has to happen is, first of all, we have to make sure that they have an email address in that
form and then we have to actually look up to see if we can find a user that matches that email address.
If it does, if we could find that user, then we need to send back an email, send an email that has
some instructions in it and directs them to click on a particular link.
And that link needs to be specific to this user.
I mean, if we just made it a generic link and said anybody can fill in an email address and then fill
in the passwords, people can change passwords whenever they wanted to for anyone, and that would be
bad.
So we need to make sure that it's secure and there's lots of ways of handling this.
One very common approach is to generate a token, save it in the database, have it tied to that particular
email address.
And when someone goes to that page, of course, they're submitting a token with part of that link will
be writing the URL, and we verify that the token in the link matches the one in the database.
That's a lot of work, it seems to me.
It's a lot simpler.
If we actually use what's known as a signed URL, you are that is effectively tamper proof and that
we can validate when it comes back to our system.
So we'll take care of that in it, of course, to do that.
We could put all the logic for generating signed URLs right in my app, but that seems kind of pointless
because we want this to be available to all users of our Celebrity House package.
So let's switch to the Celebrity House project.
And over here, I'm going to create a new folder.
I'll put all of my URL signing logic into its own package.
You are a signer.
That's what I'm going to call it.
URL aside GDR and inside of that folder, I'll create a new file, which I will call sign or ago.
And of course, it has the package declaration of URL signer.
Now, in order to sign emails, what we're going to do is import a very small third party package.
OK.
And I've used this in other courses, so you might be familiar with it if you take in some of my other
courses.
So I'm going to open a terminal window and I'll clear my screen and type.
Go get GitHub dot com slash BMW M8 R R n slash and go dash alone.
And this is a dead simple signing package.
And if you want it to, you could copy the logic from this into your own code and not even import a
package because it's relatively small.
But I like to give credit where credit is due.
So I've added that it's now available to me.
So what I'm going to do is, first of all, create a type and we use this when we create this package
or instantiate this package.
I'll call it Siner, and it's just a struct, and it has some secret.
OK, I see CRT and that will be a slice of bytes and we need to get that from somewhere.
OK?
And we'll get that very shortly now.
I'll create my first function, which will have a receiver s pointer to sign her, so it's available
any time we create a variable of the type signer and we'll call this generate token from string.
And it takes one argument data string and it returns a string.
OK, so this is pretty simple.
First of all, we're going to create a variable URL to sign and it's a type string.
Now I'll create another variable called crypt for cryptography here.
Why Piti and that is assigned the value of from the package we just imported.
Go along and see if it'll find it for me.
Sometimes it does.
Sometimes it doesn't.
Nope, didn't find it.
That's no problem.
We'll just go and put it up here after the package statement.
I'll create an import statement and I will import GitHub dot com slash bw m a r i n slash go dash palo.
OK, so go alone dot new.
And for its arguments, it will take my escort secret, which is of course populated when we create
a variable of the type signer.
And what's also going to take go along Typekit timestamp.
So we want that URL that we're sending the users to expire after a certain period of time.
Now remember, we're generating a URL and a URL may or may not have some get tokens.
In other words, question mark value equals something else.
It may have those in the URL, or it might not.
So we have the trap for both cases.
And that's really easy.
So we'll say if string start contains right from the standard library, if the URL we want to sign,
which is, of course, data, if that contains a question mark, then there are already some tokens
there because I'm going to be putting tokens at the end of the URL in order to sign it.
So that's my first case.
We'll do one thing.
Otherwise, we'll do something else.
OK.
So if it contains that, then we're going to say you were able to sign is equal to and I'll use the
format package format dot print f and my format string will be percent s, followed by an ampersand.
Hash equals OK.
And my substitution for the percent, as is, of course, data.
Otherwise, let's just copy this.
Otherwise, we're signing a URL that does not already have parameters.
So why do you have to change a little bit?
So basically, the ampersand becomes a question mark.
OK.
And that tells the browser that these are the bits of data I'm passing along with this URL.
So there now I have a URL I can sign and signing.
It is really easy.
OK, I'll say token bytes.
I'm just generating a token that I can verify, which will be appended right to the URL we're signing.
Token bytes is a sign the value of Crypt Dot sign, and we're going to sign as a slice of bytes you
are all to sign.
And now my token, which is what I would be returning, that's a sign the value of string token rights.
And I'll return that and I could have done that one line, but this is quite readable.
Return token that allows us to generate a token from a string.
So we handed a URL.
It then appends a hash that our system knows about to the URL to the URL and sends that back.
OK, so that's the first thing we have to do.
The second thing we have to do, of course, is verify tokens.
And that's equal easy func as pointer to signer.
And we'll call this verify token.
And it takes one argument token, which is a string and it returns a Boolean.
Either it's valid or it's not.
So again, we create a crypt so I can copy this line.
And pasted here that gives you my my tool, and then I ignore the first return parameter.
But I do care about the error and I call.
Crypt done unsigned, and then I take and cast to a slice of bite my token.
And I checked for an error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Something went wrong.
So I'll just return.
False.
OK, otherwise I return truth, and that's as simple as it can possibly get.
So that's one thing we have to take care of.
The last thing we have to take care of is in some cases will be using signed URLs that have an expiry.
OK, so we'll just check for expiry.
Funk it again, funk s pointer to signer and we'll call the function expired and it takes a token.
And it also takes minutes until expire, which is an IT and token as a string because I have to put
the tape in there
and it returns a Boolean.
So once again, I'll paste in my crypt, which I still have in my clipboard, and I'll create a variable
called T-S four times since and I'll call Crypt Dot Pass and hand it the slice of bytes token.
And now all I have to say is return time dot.
Since and I want to start timestamp, which was populated when we called Crypt Pass and make that greater
than time dot duration.
Return to the standard package minutes until expired times.
Typekit minute
right there from the Standard Library.
So if it hasn't expired yet, it will actually return, if true, and if it has expired, it'll return
a false.
And that's really simple and here is telling me, of course it wants to should return.
Equals now.
I like it this way.
I like it.
More readable.
What it wants me to do.
And you can see it right here is to put it in one line.
Return error is equal to nil.
Equals equals nil.
But I like this.
I think it's readable and it's entirely up to you.
All right.
So this is created.
This package is now available to us, and in the next lecture, we'll start using it to generate a signed
URL and email that off.