So we have our usual cider package complete, and now it's time to use it.
So let's think about what we're going to have to do here in our stash.
Handlers don't go in with my AMP project in the post for Forgot Handler, which is just currently an
empty handler.
So the first thing we're going to have to do is write some comments so we can think it through here.
We're going to have to pass the form which you always should do any time you receive a post requesting
a handler.
So we're obviously going to have to do that.
Then we're going to have to verify that supplied email exists because if it's not in our system, then
we don't want to go any further.
OK.
And then we need to create a link, create a link to password reset form.
OK, and that's going to have to start with a ship or a GPS and then our server name and then some URL.
It'll probably be something like slash users slash reset dash password.
Right?
And then we're going to have to sign each sign the link, sign the link.
And finally, we're going to want to email the message and redirect the user.
So those are the steps we're going to have to follow in this handler.
Now, the one that's troubling me right now is the one where we have to create a link to password reset
form because we actually don't have the address for our server.
It's nowhere in our configuration whatsoever if we open our own file, so you open up and look inside
of here.
We have a server name, but there's no HDP anywhere except down here for the Maler URL, so we're going
to have to supply that.
So let's put a value right here at the top of our applications on file and I'll call it app underscore
URL and that will be equal to, in my case, HTP colon slash slash local host park four thousand like
that.
So we have that anywhere.
Now, of course, we need to put that somewhere in our app variable for our handlers.
In other words, these celebrities type.
So let's switch over to our celebrities project.
And in here, I'll open up, say celebrities that go wherever that is there is, and I'm going to create
another type here or call it type server and make it a struct, and I'll give it some fields.
So we'll have, for example, server name and that will be a string.
And we may also keep track of the pork, which will also be a string.
And are we using a GPS?
So is it secure or not?
And that, of course, will be a Boolean.
And finally, what's the URL to our server?
And that's the one we need right now.
That'll be a string.
OK.
So let me save that, and then I'll add the server type, which I'll call server of type server right
to sell our TOS, and I'll save that.
Now, of course, I want to populate it.
So let's go down to where we're populating our variable.
And right here, after I do the config part, let me set secure equals true.
I'll just create a variable local variable called secure.
It will default to true, and then I'll check in the dot on the file to see if secure is false.
So I'll say if strings start to load.
And I'll call Oast don't get arms and they'll look for secure.
If you check your dot on file, that's in there.
If that is equal to false.
Exactly.
So it can be uppercase or lowercase.
But as long as it's the word false, then I'll set secure equal to false.
Now that I have that value, I can say C2 server.
The type we just added to celebrities is equal to the type server and we just fill in its fields.
So we have server name and that's going to be asked get ons and we're looking for server underscore
name.
And we want the port to be equal to us.
Don't get on.
Try that again.
Get on hard.
And secure is just secure.
And the URL is now of equal to us.
Don't get on.
And we just added up underscore if you are up there now, I have a means of getting the valid URL to
my server right from the dot on file.
Perfect.
So let's switch back to our other application and close this dot on file.
Go back to our handlers.
And now, just to make sure that my local copy of Celebrities in the vendor folder is the latest version,
I'll open a terminal window and take Gomaa defender.
And sometimes when you Typekit go mad vendor, as I'm sure you've noticed, it takes a little bit for
visual studio code to catch up to you, but will forge ahead in any case.
I hope it catches up to us pretty quickly.
So this is what we need to do.
Our first step is to pass the form.
That's easy.
We know how to do that.
Here is a sign of the value of our passport.
And if there's an error, if it's not equal to nil, then we'll just do something appropriate here.
We'll say each short app got error status.
And of course, it's catching up to meet its error status while just putting error status and say.
W and HIV status, bad request, something went wrong, OK, and I'll return, but assuming I got past
that now, I need to get the email that was posted and verify that it's a valid user.
So what I'll do is create a variable you type pointer to data dot user an empty user variable.
OK, because I have to call a method on it and I'll get the email address that was supplied as part
of the post request.
Email is a sign the value of art form.
Not yet.
And I'm looking for email.
We just got it steamed in the form.
And at this point, I say you an error are assigned the value of no, they're not a sign, they're equal
because I already have those variables equal to.
You don't get my email and I had email.
Now, if I can't find that user, then I'm going to get an error back, right?
So I'll say if error is not equal to nil, then I'll do exactly the same thing.
And of course, you can do whatever you want here.
You can redirect the user back to the form.
It's entirely up to you, but I'm going to put that in here just to get us going.
OK.
But if we have the user now, we need to create a link to the password reset form.
Here's where we finally get around to using that URL sign or package we just created.
So the first thing we need is a string to send off to it a link to our server.
So I'll say a variable link is assign the value up from the format package as positive as print f and
give it a format string, which will be starting with a string of some sort.
We're going to substitute our URL in there and then I'll make the path to reset the password form users.
Reset Dash password and then a question mark and then email is equal to another placeholder.
And I substitute each Dot App Dot server, which is now available to me right there.
Dot.
URL, Earl.
It looks like it hasn't found it yet.
It was you, wasn't it?
Yes, there caught it.
And email is my second substitution.
So now I have a link that I can send off to my signer.
But of course, I can't just call the signer directly.
First of all, I have to create a variable, so my variable will be signed and it's assigned the type
of URL signer.
Hopefully, they'll find that.
Earl Sinar not left to import it manually, but that's OK.
But I'm going to call Signer.
That's the type I want.
He did find it good and secret is the one feel that it has, and that requires nothing more than our
encryption key.
And I already have that dot at dot encryption key.
So it didn't find the URL signer.
That's no problem.
That's better.
So didn't find you were elsewhere.
That's no problem.
We can go import it right at the top of our file.
So we'll add the import, and it is going to be a GitHub dot com slash TESOL or, in my case, slash
celebrities slash URL sinar.
And that should show up or save this.
The only irritating thing about a visual studio code is sometimes it's slow to update.
OK?
It looks like I did it for me.
So now I want a signed version of my link, so I'll create a new variable.
Signed link is assigned the value of sign dot.
Generate token from string on the string, I want to pass it, it's just like the now I have a sign
link.
So at this point, let's just print it to the console.
OK, so I'll say H2O app, dot info, log dot dot print line signed.
The link is and print out sign link.
OK, so it's still showing me an error up here.
Yeah, but.
Com slash TCR slash failure to slash all sign it.
And that is the correct path.
Maybe I need to take Gomaa my vendor again.
Go on gender.
OK.
Let's just see if our application starts.
Make sure.
Eric did catch up to me good.
So I do have an error here, and it's an art handlers go line 153.
It says I cannot use a Dot app on encryption, key type string as type byte in field values, so I have
to cast that to a byte.
So let's go down the line one hundred and fifty three.
This sort of thing happens when an application can't keep up with that.
So encryption key is a string and it needs to be a bite.
That's no problem.
We'll just cast it to a slice of bytes slice of byte.
There it is and close that.
OK, let's try running it again.
Let's start.
So a comp. That's a good sign.
Let's go back to our Web browser.
And let's go to log in a user and try forgot password, and we'll put in me out here dot com, the only
user we have in the database and click Send Password Reset Password email and I should get a blank screen
screen or an error.
And we got a blank screen, which is good.
Let's go back to our I.D. and what we have here is.
There it is.
Signed link is it should be local host 4000, which is correct.
Users reset Dash password question mark.
Email is my email and then we have the signed link.
Perfect.
OK, so now that we signed the link, we can actually send an email.
So in order to send an email, of course, we're going to have to have a template password reset and
we can make that in just a moment, but first of all, let's set up the necessary code.
So I'm going to have to pass some data to that template.
So I'll create a variable say.
VAR data, which is just a struct, and it has one field in it link, which is of type string,
and then I'll populate that data variables link member with my signed link.
OK.
And I would just create a message MSG is a sign of the value of Maler dark message, and I populates
fields.
So we're going to have to put in a tube.
And that would be to you.
Dot email, user email and subject will be password reset.
But we're going to have to put in a template and I'll put in password reset, which doesn't exist yet,
but it will in a minute password reset.
And data will be data.
And we're going to want to from and that will just be me here.
I can't use that will see at admin at example icon.
I want a different email address.
It doesn't matter what it is, so I'm sending this to a test server in any case.
So I've created the message.
My next step is to send that to the jobs queue, which is easy app dark mail dot jobs gets me cheap
and we wait for the response.
Rez is assigned the value of whatever comes from a short app.
Typekit mailed out results
and we'll say if resort error is not equal to nil, then we can just do the same thing we did before.
We'll copy all of this error code right here and pasted in here, unless something goes wrong, will
add extra logging files.
OK, so that's the email, the message part.
So I can take this comment and put it right up here, and I can take the sign the link part and put
it right up here.
And get rid of this blank space.
OK, now the last thing to do is to redirect the users to the log in screen.
So that's easy enough to HDP to redirect.
And we want to redirect with an urge to slash user slash logging and HDP status.
See other.
OK.
So I would think that the last step we have to do is to create this password reset template.
OK, so we can do that.
Let's open it to open a terminal window and go dot slash celebrities make male.
Then I call it password reset.
And that should create two empty templates for me.
So let's open them up.
Password reset HTML.
That team will end up cleaned up.
So make this really simple.
We'll start with the plain text version, and I'll just put it in here.
Hello.
You recently requested a link to reset your password.
Visit the link below to get started.
Note that the link expires in 60 Minutes and we haven't done that yet, but we'll do it when we get
to the actual link itself.
OK?
And we'll just put in here Dot Link, which we passed as data to this form.
OK.
So there's that one.
Now let's go over to password reset.
Each time out, we should be pretty much the same thing.
So down here, I'll say in the first paragraph, tag hello.
And another paragraph tag, and I'll just copy and paste for the other one in a minute.
So we'll go over here to password reset, plain copy this text back to the HTML version pasted in here,
and then we'll have another paragraph
with a closing paragraph tag and copy the second line just to save me retyping it over here.
Paste it in, and then we'll put the link in here.
OK.
This should be all we have to do for that.
So in theory, I can now restart my application, make restart.
Good sign, everything compiled.
Let's go to our Web browser, here we are.
And now open another tab and open my mail client, which are mail server by Test Mail Server, which
is Mail Hog.
So local host.
Four eight zero two five.
OK, it's empty.
That's good.
Back here to the celebrity's page.
Click on Log any user and said I forgot my password.
And now I'll put me here dot com, which is the only user I have in the database.
And if we did everything right, this should work.
OK, so it took me back to the log in screen, which is what it's supposed to do.
And over and male hug, I have a password reset like now I can click on that link all that I want.
And I probably should have made that in a rough, and I will go fix that right now.
That was sloppy.
So let me go back to Visual Studio code and make this a trip equals with a link in there and then click
here to reset your password slash pay.
That's just better.
So the next time we do that, that'll actually show up as a link.
But it doesn't matter right now because this link currently doesn't work, but you can see it is the
correct sign link.
So the next step, of course, is to actually take care of serving up the page that allows users to
reset their password and then reset their password.
And we'll get started on that in the next lecture.