So we're sending out emails with password reset links, and now we have to write a handler that actually
accepts those links.
So I'm still in my app and I'm an art handlers.
Don't go.
So let's go to the bottom of this file, create a new handler, and I'll call this one cloak h with
a receiver, a pointer to handlers as usual.
And I'll call this reset password for and give it a response writer and a pointer to request.
And what do we want to do in here?
Well, we need to get the form values.
We also need to validate the URL to make sure the URL hasn't been tampered with and that it's valid
and came from our system and all that sort of thing.
And then we need to make sure it's not expired.
And finally, if we pass all of those tests, then we display the form.
OK, so let's get started doing that, right?
So some room.
First of all, we can get the form values, and there's really only one value coming with our request
email, and that will be Arnaut URL.
That query don't get email because we're getting that email as a query parameter.
So we have that.
Then we'll get the URL because we need to validate the URL.
The URL, which I should probably write this way, is a sign the value of that's just our request.
You are.
And that comes in the form of a string.
OK, and now we need to create a world to test that against.
So test you URL is assign the value of format printouts and what our format string is.
Just two strings join together and the first value is the URL of our server, each app dot server
URL.
And the second value is the URL, which we just got on the previous line.
And that's the URL we're going to test because the URL that's signed is the full URL, including the
server and the protocol, or oops.
So now we create a sign and that comes from your URL signer, dot signer and we give it.
It's one required field secret and that is a slice of bytes each dot app dot encryption key.
OK, so now we validate the URL, so let's move this up here, just so our comments are in the right
spot.
That's better.
So valid is simply assigned the value of calling Sinar Don't verify token and we hand it test URL and
that will come back.
True or false?
So if it's not true, if not valid, then something has happened.
OK, so I'll write to the error log h after the error log dot print line invalid URL.
So somebody tried to change the URL or something like that has happened.
And all I'm going to do at this point is just call H Dot app dot error unauthorized.
You're not allowed to come to this address if you've tampered with the URL and hand it in her and we'll
return.
We don't want to go any further.
But if they get past that, of course, now we need to make sure that the token has not expired, that
less than 60 Minutes have gone by.
And when we created that signature that we appended to the URL that actually has the timestamp built
right into it.
So it's pretty simple to make sure that it's not expired.
So we'll say expired.
She's just a variable I'm creating and it will be a Boolean is signer dot expired and we hand it test
you URL and the number of minutes until expiring.
So 60 Minutes.
That'll be our default.
And that's what we said in the email.
If expired, if it has expired, then we can do the same thing.
We'll just copy all of this and paste it in here.
And just so we can see what's going on, we'll say Link expired, OK?
But if we get past all of that now, we want to display that form.
And of course, one of the things that you'll notice is that we're resetting an email based upon an
email that's passed as a query parameter.
And what we don't want to do is actually embed that email in the form of displaying as plain text,
because at that point, somebody could just open the browser or change the value of that hidden field
and change anybody's password, reset it to whatever they want, and that would be bad.
So instead, let's encrypt that email and put the encrypted email on the form.
So if you look at the form that we have here and it's over in our views and it's called a reset password
jet, here I'm putting a hidden field named email on Line Thirty three in this code and I'm not putting
the actual email in there.
Instead, I want to encrypt it and then I'll decrypt it when this form is posted.
So back to off handlers, let's just encrypt that email.
So we'll say encrypted email
and potentially an error, which I'll ignore, and you can just catch that error if you want to, and
I'll just call each dot encrypt.
And I handed him out.
OK, so now I have that information.
So now I need to pass that value to my form.
And that's as simple as saying Mars is assigned the value of make.
And we're going to make a jetport of our map.
And then we'll just add that email to our of our map, so verse dot set.
And I call that email on the template, so I better call it email here, and that's encrypted email.
And now, as we normally do, we just run to the forum error is equal or assign the value of each dot
render and we'll render with W and R, and the template we want is called reset password dot jet.
But we leave the dot jet out.
Of course, we had a diverse and neal for the fourth parameter.
Fifth parameter.
And we'll check for an error, and I'll just copy this error message right here and paste it in and
get rid of the airlock.
And get rid of the unauthorized, and it looks like I already have an error somewhere.
Now, if error is not equal to nil, that's better.
So this is created.
So let's go to our roots file and and a root.
We'll try to sow here right after the forgot password link.
I'll put in a dog and cat and I'm going to go to the URL we gave them.
Once users reset the password and we call eight handlers don't reset password form.
And if all goes according to plan, I should be able to compile this now.
So let's go make restart.
OK, so a compiled listening on Port four thousand, let's go to our Web browser and go back to celebrities
and reload this page.
And I'm not logged in, so let's go to log in user.
And I'll say I forgot my password, and I'll put in me at here dot com and send the email.
So that should have sent it.
Now I go over to my mail hog.
There is my link from my email inside, but I have a link, so I click on this.
It opens a new browser window and it worked properly.
Well, let's try changing the email.
So up here in the URL location bar, I'll change me at here.
RT.com to me to adhere.
I'm trying to change somebody else's email and I hit return and I get unauthorized.
Perfect.
So that seems to work as expected.
So obviously the next step is to create the handler that takes the post request from this form on the
previous page.
So once I click Reset password, this has to go to a handler that once again does all the necessary
validation and resets the user's password, and we get started on that in the next election.