So we have a forum to reset passwords displaying properly.
And now, of course, the last step we need to do is to actually reset the user's password.
And that's pretty easy at this point.
So I'm still in my app and I'm still looking at after handlers talk, and it's very bottom of this file.
I'll add a new function that allows us to reset the password funk with a receiver of h a pointer to
handlers.
And I'll call this post reset password and it takes W Active Response Writer and our pointer to request.
And of course, what are we going to do in here?
Well, we need to pass this one and then we need to get and decrypt the email and then we need to get
the user and then we need to reset the password.
And we want to redirect.
Now just a note about this redirecting bit.
You may recall that at one point not too long ago, over here in the celebrities project in the render
dark go file inside the render package, we actually added error and flash to template did it, and
we never did anything with those.
And now's a good time to do something with those.
So what these are going to be, of course, error will be an error message and flash will be some kind
of message.
But then the sort of message you only want to display on the next time a request is sent to the server
and comes back from the server.
So in other words, it's a sessional variable that only exists for one more request.
And that's really easy to do.
So here in the default data function, this is the data we're passing to every single template in our
system.
We're just going to add value here, aren't you?
Two of them will say to do an error and that will be equal to see dot session.
Pop string and pop string, we can roll over it and read about it.
Pop string actually returns the string value for a given key and then deletes it from the session data,
and that's exactly what we want to do.
So we'll handed context and we'll look for the word error as the key in the session that we'll duplicate
this and this will be TDK flash, which is another message I want to display only once.
But it's not an error, and we'll look for the key flash in the session.
And that's all we have to do in is to make this available to us.
So back over here now, when I get to this redirect part, let's actually put a message in there.
And if you look for example at the Reset Password Dot jet file, you'll see I've already put some logic
in here that does that sort of thing.
Now, I'm not taking advantage of it.
I'm leaving server side error validation up to you because you already know how to do it, and it's
really easy to implement and there's no point in you watching me do it.
But this is the kind of thing I want to be available say.
For example, I want to send a flash message on the log in screen.
So while I'm here, I'll copy this from Reset Dash Password Jet.
I'll just copy it and then I'll open log in chat and I'll put it say right here after the error, but
before the form.
OK, so if that variable flashed exists in the template data and is not an empty string, then I'll
display that flash message and that's really kind of helpful and very easy to implement.
All right.
So that's out of the way.
So let's go back to our handler and implement this logic.
And this is really easy.
So again, we pass the form errors, assign the value of our Dot Pass form, and we check for an error
if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll just say each dot app got error five hundred and give it w an error return.
I can't pers the form.
Something has gone wrong.
Now I need to get in decrypted email, and I can do that in one step with an check, so I'll create
a variable called email and I will check for an error and those come from calling each dot decrypt and
I'm going to decrypt our dot form.
Don't get email, which is what it's called in the form.
And again, I'll just copy this error.
Check and paste it here.
That's part of why I'm not there to perform, that's better.
Now I need to get the user, so I'll create a variable you, which is of type data, not user, and
I'm just creating that so I can call a method on it and I'll get the user and check for an error that
comes from you, dot.
Get by email and I handled the email, I just decrypted.
OK.
And I'll pursue my error check.
And if I get past that and then I can reset the password.
And that's as simple as saying error is equal to user reset password and that requires the user I.D.
Sorry, have I just pulled the user out of the database and the password that was posted to us?
So we'll get that from the forum post art form Typekit.
I'm looking for a password and again, I'll check for an error.
And here when I do the redirect yourself some room.
At this point, I can pop a value in the session, a message that will now be displayed when I redirect
them to the login page.
And that's as simple as saying a short app that session.
That put in give it the context and context and call it flash, which I have to spell right or won't
work, and I'll just say password reset.
You can now log in and I'll redirect the user to the appropriate page.
Repeat on redirect.
And that requires W and R the path to go to slash users slash log in and some status in the 200 range
issue status.
See other.
OK.
Of course, there's one more step.
None of this is going to work until we actually create the necessary route.
So let's open our routes.
And go down to here and I'll just duplicate the password reset route and modify it.
I'll make it a post request and I'll call the handler post reset password.
Now I should be able to open my terminal, say make restart.
Perfect.
Now let's switch for a Web browser, reload this page, go to log user and I'll start the whole process
over.
I forgot my password.
My email is me at here.
Dot com.
Send me a link, OK?
And again, you could display a little message up there that says, check your email by popping in a
flash variable.
So I'll go to my email client or server my fake one.
There's my password reset email that just came in a few seconds ago.
I'll click on it and I will open this in any tab and switch to that tab.
And there it is.
So I'll put a new password password on the Republican S.W.O.R.D. to the S.W.O.R.D. to see if I got those
the same.
I did, and there's my message, password reset, you can now log in.
Let's make sure it actually worked me out here.
RT.com Password two and I log in.
And everything works exactly as expected.
OK, so there's how we reset our users password.
Now, obviously, we want to take all of this logic we just built.
And we want to put it into the Celebrity House package and add it whenever a user types celebrities
make off.
We want all of those handlers, all the views, all of the middleware, everything to be copied over.
Most of it's already there, but some of it needs to be updated and some needs to be added, and we'll
take care of that in the next lecture.