So now that we've put all this work into password resets and things like that, let's make sure our
command line applications celebrities in the Celebrity House project is updated to take advantage of
that sort of thing.
So what I'm going to do is switch to my desktop and I have two windows open here.
On the left hand side is my app that has the latest versions of everything I need.
And on the right hand side is hilarious and I need to copy things over here.
So let's get started.
First of all, we're going to need the mail templates.
The password reset stuff, and that's inside the mail folder.
So these two files I'll copy over to the CMD folder, insularity, tasks and then Seelye and then templates
inside of Mailer.
So I'll copy them in there.
And I also need the handlers so that inside the handlers folder, the art handlers, and I'm going to
copy that to the Handlers folder inside the Templates folder.
And I also need my forgot and reset templates, and those are inside views, so I have forgot right
here and I have reset password both jet files.
They get copied to the Views folder in templates.
I don't have one now, so I'll create one.
So inside of templates create a new folder called views, and I'll copy these two over to the Views
folder.
Now, go back up one level.
Now I need to copy my middleware for remember token.
And see what we have in center middleware right now.
We have off token and off, so I won't remember a copy that in there and then insert our data folder.
We'll have to copy the Remember token over so data.
And remember token.
And I'll put a text at the end of that as well.
OK, so all those files are copied over now, you can see I have a few errors here, so I'm going to
refactor this and rename it to remember, don't go to text just to and get rid of those errors because
these are just templates.
They don't get compiled and rename that one to go to next.
OK.
So I think I have all the necessary files copied over to my templates.
Now, obviously, we're working with off don't go in the CMD Seelye folder, and so far we're copying
over or we're doing the migrations and then we run the migrations and then we copy user and token over
to a data folder.
So I'm going to copy this and we're going to have to copy over.
I remember one which is called Remember Underscore token logo.
So remember?
Underscore token, go to text to data.
And I want to call it remember underscore token, there's that one.
Now let's look at our middleware in our middleware folder.
We now have remember underscore or go dot.
We need to copy that over.
So copy this and paste it here.
And we want to call this.
Remember, don't go to text to
remember ago MBA.
OK.
So there's that middleware done.
And we also want to copy over the views and the handlers.
Let's do the handlers first.
So I'll copy this whole thing and paste it here.
And my handlers are called, Where are they off, dash handlers?
OK, so we're going to copy from handlers and we want off dash handlers.
Don't go to text to handlers
of dash handlers.
Don't go.
OK, so there's our handlers now we want our views and we have views in the views folder and views in
the mailer folder.
So let's copy this and we'll do the ones in the mail folder first.
So we're copying from Mailer, which is what it's called in templates, and the file is called Password
Dash Reset HTML that tempo.
Two male and we're calling this file
password Dash Reset Dash HTML the template, now we'll copy this whole thing and do the plain text version
and scroll up a bit.
And this becomes plain and this becomes plain.
OK, so we have the male templates now we have to do the reset templates and the log in template in
the Views folder, so I'll copy this and paste it here and we're copying from views.
The IWC what do I have my views folder?
Did I remember to copy over the log in one?
No, I didn't.
So let's go back over here and go down to views.
We also want the login page, so we'll copy that over to up one level views.
So log in, goes to views there.
OK, so the first one we want is from views.
Log in, Georgette.
Two views.
Log in, D'Achat.
And I will copy this and paste it twice, once, twice.
And the second one is not called log in.
It's called for God jet, which becomes for God jet and reset dash password dot jet becomes reset dash
password dot.
All right.
So that should copy all of those files over.
Now there's one more thing we need to do.
Let's go back over to our other project and that is my app and look inside the data folder.
I believe we added a function.
Yes, we did to our check.
Remember, we added this function to the user's dgo data in the data file, so I copied that function.
Now I'm going to switch back here and open up user don't go, don't text and paste that right here,
there, and that should take care of all of the heavy lifting.
So let's try compiling our seal on.
Make sure everything compiles make build, underscore seal seelye.
And it did.
OK, so I'll leave it to you to test that, but that should work exactly as expected.
And of course, in order to test it, you have to go and delete the necessary tables from your database
and then delete all of the things that are copied over in the data directory, in the mail directory,
in the handlers directory, in the middleware directory and the views directory.
So once you delete all the files that are installed, when someone typed celebrities make off and you
remove the necessary migrations and the necessary tables in the database, you should be able to run
this and everything should work as expected.
Now, I'm not going to bother testing it in this lecture because we're moving on in the next section
to building a make new functionality into our celebrity voice command line application, and we'll test
it at that point.
And if we got something wrong, it's not going to be anything major.
So let's move on to the next section.