OK.
Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about this concept.
S structures and go like.
Golonka structure is a data tie that allows you to restore different properties under a single variable
name.
It is similar to a class in object oriented programming that has only properties.
It's very similar to a structure in C programming.
Airstrike is the collection of data feeds, we declare data types.
Golan has the ability to declare and create own data types by combining bong or more types, including
both building and user defined types.
Each data field in an airstrike is declared with a noun type, which could be a built in type or another
user defined type, as are the only way to create concrete user defined types and go and a strike.
Types are declared by composing iFixit of unique fields as throngs can improve modularity and allow
to create and pass complex data structures around the system.
You can also consider asteroids as a template for creating a data record like an employee record or
an e-commerce product.
Declaration of a strong time.
The declaration is SaaS with the key more tight, then a name for the Newstrike.
And finally, the key vote a struct within the of righteous.
A series of data feeds are specified with a name and a time.
Now you can see the syntax.
Let's go to this good program to illustrate how to create and declaration extract.
First, go to Esplorare and create a project folder, for the example, is relax and created fine like
me, but go create package name and main flash, OK?
For the example, we create a strike name address.
It has a state seat and zip code fence now declaring a striped
tie and address and striped curly brackets and set the field.
For the example, estate Typekit is a strange city type, is a string and zip code and type of it.
Is it?
In the above, the type keyboard introduces a new type.
It's followed by the name of the time address and the keyboard to try to illustrate that your defining
is right there.
Strong contains a list of various fields inside the killer braces.
Each field has a name, and at times we can also make them compact by combining the various fields of
same time, as shown in the below.
For example, in the Commons, these strong and defiant and others strike began to address a strong
category, says the state and city type of two fields is a string and zip code.
Type of it is fields.
The address is strong and its fields are not exported to either packages because identifiers or a strike
name are a start with and lowercase letter and golang identifiers are exported to other packets.
If the name is source, we add attributes that are otherwise the accessibility will be limited within
the package.
We could define struct in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.