Hello and welcome to the and programming language course in the previous session, we talked about assigned
default value for restaurant field.
And in this session, we want to talk about the others a strong concept.
Compare SARS with the different values assigned to data fields.
Airstrikes of the same time can be compared using calm person operator.
Let's go to the escort program to illustrate the concept of this strike competition by using equals
to operate or.
First, define astronaut, named a student and sit feel for it
tied.
Just to the restaurant and set feels to me it's rude and age and sad comment for export at this war.
Now go to main function.
Creating two variables of A-student the structure and initialize them.
The student one column equals and the student's
name key and age 27, and define second variable and initialize its same variable for the student to
call it equals the student.
And they came at age 20, sir.
Now checking if a student born is equal to a student to or not by using equals to operate or reformat,
the court said the project and go to the next line.
If the student long equals to student to
print a message for us, if the variable is student, one is equal to that of the student to an adult's
coffee, this line
sat here and said is not equal to where even the student who can't reformat the code and save the prosaic
execute the program.
Do you the school?
Now we can see the output value.
Even a student vong is equal to variable.
A student to the two variables are equal to each other, and we could compare to a strike instance together.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.