In this section of the course, we're going to focus upon multiple remote file systems.
And since we're building a sort of clone of Laravel lingo, let's have a look at what they have.
So as you can see, they have the local driver.
I'm just looking in the documentation for Laravel.
They have a local driver, the public disk, they have Amazon buckets and they have other ones as well.
OK.
And here's what we're going to do.
And this is a finished version of what we'll be doing in this section of the course.
And we have a new menu up here which will be adding momentarily.
We're going to go to the file systems and choose list files.
And from here, we're going to support four different file systems in addition to the local file system.
The first one is an Amazon S3 bucket, so I can choose that and say, show me the files that are on
that remote file system and then they're OK and we can delete them if we want to.
I'm not going to right now, but we can.
So we'll support Amazon S3 buckets and also Mineo, which is a very useful piece of software that allows
you to create your own Amazon S3 buckets without paying Amazon.
So we may as well support that, and it uses its own driver, which is why it's a separate file system.
Also, SFD secure FTP protocol that'll work exactly as we expect, and we can treat this as a local
file system with our code.
And finally, one that's not used a great deal, but I just wanted to show you how to create multiple
file systems using a single type WebDAV, which some people still use.
And it actually points to the same directory as SFTP because the one will be using supports web dev
and FTP and unsecure FTP, which I refused to implement because it is insecure by default.
In any case, we'll be able to list things more loss and delete them, and we'll also be able to, of
course, upload them.
So I'll be able to choose which file system do I want to upload to.
So if I'm choosing, say, SFP, I'll be able to browse for a file, choose something, there's a picture,
let's upload it.
And now that's been uploaded to FTP and I believe it was called lorem.
Let's see if it's there.
We go to SMTP and list and there is a lorem ping.
Now I can delete it, so I deleted.
Yes, and it's gone.
OK, a fair bit of work to implement all of this, but let's get started in the next election.