So before we can work with remote file systems, we obviously need some file systems that we can connect
to, and we're going to do that using Docker and I presume that you have Docker installed, but if not,
you can go over to this URL, Docker WWE Gawker.com slash products slash Docker Dash desktop.
And if you hit it on a Mac, you'll see this screen with the two buttons.
Download the one appropriate for your file system or for your computer, and if you're on windows,
you'll see the download for Windows and Linux and so forth.
OK, so install that.
Then once you have that installed, go back to your project.
And right now, I'm going to look at the My App folder in this workspace, and let's open up Docker
compose.
Don't worry, I'm out now.
There are three services in this in this file right now.
The first one starts Postgres, and it expects to find a folder called DB data at the root level of
our application, and inside of that a folder called Postgres.
Now I could create those here.
But one of the really irritating features is if I create an empty folder like clicking over here in
my app and seeing create a new folder and I can do the first one DB data.
And I need that because I have DB Dash data right here for the mounted volume for this Postgres Docker
container, and I can create one called inside of that a new folder called Postgres, and that works.
But if I create another one, often it creates an inside of Postgres, so I'm going to create the rest
of them right from my desktop and you can follow whatever procedure works for you.
We just need these folders.
OK?
Now, if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a complete Docker wire ml file
or Docker Dash composed by EML file that you can download.
But we need a few new services.
First thing I'll do is comment about MariaDB because I'm not going to be using that.
I'm going to be using Postgres, so I'll comment there.
Then, right underneath Redis.
I'll get a blank line.
Then another blank line, then I'll backspace twice to get to the right column.
And I already have on my clipboard the two new Docker images.
I want to make part of my Docker compose file as well.
Paste them in and you'll get these from the course resources for this lecture.
So the first thing we're going to have the first new service is one called SFTP, and that will actually
provide both SFTP and WebDAV services.
And again, that requires two folders inside the DB data folder, one called SFP and one called home.
So I'll switch over to my desktop here and I'll open up my DB data folder and create a new folder called
FTP.
And another one called Home.
OK, so now if I come back here inside the DB data folder, I don't have home postgres in 150 people.
Now, the next Docker image that we're including is one called Mineo, and I'll talk about that in a
minute.
OK.
Now this one by default listens to two ports 9000, which is the actual service that we can connect
a minute with, and 9001, which is the web interface.
Now, in my case, I need to change the 9000 to an 8000 just because I already have something running
on Port, 9000 on my system.
Right now, I actually am being forced to work on a project for a client, so I have the fpm running
and that's taking up Port 9000, so I'll just use eight thousand instead.
And of course, this also wants a folder called Mineo inside the DVD data folder, where it's going
to store its data.
So I'll come back here and create a new folder called Mean I'll.
OK.
So with those changes, I should now be able to start up Docker so my terminal and make sure I'm in
the correct directory.
My app, I am and I'll type Docker compose up dashboard to run it in the background and hopefully everything
will work.
Now that might take you a little bit longer as it pulls the darker images, but it's running now, so
if I go to my doctor desktop right over here the dashboard.
I should see my app running, and it's got all the appropriate services Reddish, SFP, Mineo and Postgres.
Now if I wanted to stop them, I just come down here and typed Docker compose down and that will actually
stop them.
But I'm going to leave them running right now because in the next lecture, we'll configure accounts
on both Mineo and SFO.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture.