So before we can use Mineo, we need to set a few things up, and fortunately, it's really, really
easy.
So right here in my Docker compose, don't why HTML file in the Mineo section?
If you look under environment, I have the route user's username set to route and the route user's password
set to password, which is fine for a local development.
But of course, you'd never do that in production.
So Mineo, let's go over to our web browser.
And first of all, this is the link to the Mineo web page.
And it's pretty easy.
It's min dot i o.
And there's all kinds of documentation, all sorts of things you can look at here and you can buy services
for them if you wish.
But of course, we're not doing that.
We're actually going to just open a new tab in our web browser.
And if I go back to my Docker compose, don't why email, which is right here, you'll see that I'm
looking at listening to two parts.
And of course, here in the port section, what's on the left side is my host machine.
In other words, my computer I'm working on.
And what's on the right side is the port that it's listening to on the back end in the Docker image,
and I want to connect to this port nine zero zero one.
So back in my web browser, I'll simply go to local host code nine zero zero one and that takes me to
a login screen.
And here I put my username root and my password, which is password, and I'll log in.
And the first thing I'm going to do.
There's all kinds of things you can do here.
You can configure almost anything you want setting up policies.
I am policies.
All I want to do right now is create a bucket.
And I'm going to create a new bucket, which I will call not a very inventive name, but it will suit
my purposes.
Test bucket all one word.
And I'm going to leave versioning off object blocking off.
Quota off.
We're just going to take the defaults, OK?
And of course, I can't make these changes because I'm using a single desk setup.
One of the nice things about Mineo is I can actually install it on multiple machines in the same data
center and share the disks.
And that makes sure that my information, my data is available even if one of the servers goes down.
So I'll say this now.
I've created something I can connect to and we'll take care of actually connecting to it later on.
Right now, we just want to set it up.
OK, so that one's done.
Next, we have to set up our FTP and we'll do that in the next lecture.