So we have Mineo configured, and now we need to configure SFP secure FTP, and again, I'm looking
at my Docker dash composed why EML file inside the My App folder of my workspace?
And here you can see I'm listening to three parts 80 80, and that's what we're going to in just a moment.
That's where we're going to configure a user to connect to our SFP Service 2022, which is actually
in production that would be Port 22, where that's what you connect to using FTP and one zero zero eight
zero and in production, that would be 80 or 443 if it was secure.
And we'll be using that port for Web Dev.
But let's switch over to our web browser.
And first of all, let me show you the home page for this.
This is a Docker hub, and this is the Docker image we're using to provide FTP services, SFB services.
And I'll put a link to this in the course resources for this lecture.
And of course, you can read about that at your leisure.
So let's open a new browser tab and go to HDD Collins localhost port 80.
And the first thing it's going to ask me to do is to create an admin user, so I'll create an admin
user called admin with the password of password.
Again, not something I'd ever do in production, but sufficient for our development purposes.
Now we've created that user, but that's the admin user.
The admin user actually can't connect to SFP, so we need to create a new user.
So by default, it takes me to the view and manage user screens while creating new user by clicking
the plus sign.
Then I'll call this user SFTP with no description.
It's an active user, no expiration date, and I'll give it the password of password.
So just remember what you use for username and password here, and we're not quite done.
We need to give this user some permissions, and I'm going to give the user right here in the permissions
section or select the asterisk the star and make sure that person has all privileges.
List, upload, download everything we need to do.
OK.
And I'm going to change the home dear.
By default, it would use the home folder that we created in the DB data FTP folder, but I'm going
to change that.
And if I go back to my Docker, why AML or Docker compose?
Why AML file?
This is the folder I'm going to use slash M.A. slash data.
Copy that you don't have to, but I'm going to and I'll paste that in here.
OK?
And then I school the very bottom and click Save, which is way down here in the lower right hand corner.
Submit.
So now I have a user I can connect to as well, and that user has no quota.
And again, just as was the case with Mineo, there's all kinds of permissions you can set here and
all kinds of things you can.
And there's actually a really good package.
If you ever need to set up an SFD server, you might want to use this one.
But in any case, we now have this configured, so it's time to move on to actually writing some code
for the first time.