So now that we have our remote file systems, with the exception of Amazon S3 buckets, which I'll be
handling separately now that we have those set up, it's time to start writing some code and we'll just
ease into things now.
This time around, I've opened up go land instead of Visual Studio code, but it should make absolutely
no difference to you because what we're doing will work equally well in either environment.
So over here in my left hand panel, I'm going to open the hilarious project and let's think about what
we want to do.
Ideally, we want to have one body of code.
One thing we can call that will do all the basic operations for dealing with a remote file system and
the sorts of things we're going to want to do would be to put a file to put something up on the remote
file system to get a file from the remote file system to list all of the files that are available to
us and to delete things.
So put get listed, delete.
And obviously, the simplest way to do that is to set up an interface first and interface that each
of our various file systems must satisfy in order to be usable.
So we're obviously not going to do that in my app because we want all of the logic or as much of the
logic as we can manage to exist in celebrities.
So every time we start a new project using the celebrity's package, we'll have access to it.
So what I'll do is right click on celebrities and create a new directory.
I'll create a new package within my celebrity's package, and I'll call it file systems, plural.
There's no spaces.
So it creates a folder there.
And inside of that, I'll create a new go file, which I'll call file system.
Start go.
OK.
So it has the package name of file systems, and what I'm going to do is, first of all, I'm going
to define a type which I'll call FS for file system, and it's not going to be a struct.
It's going to be an interface.
So we'll define one interface.
And of course, all we have to do with this interface definition is list all of the functions that something
must implement in order to satisfy this interface.
So we're going to put that'll be our first function, and there will put in, say, two parameters file
name.
What are we putting?
And the second one will be, where are we putting it?
Which I'll call folder, because that's something that most people will immediately understand and that
will potentially return an error.
So that's one required function.
We're also going to one get which won't use that much.
Typically, when you're working on a web application like this, rarely do you get something because
that would get it from the remote file system and pull it down to the server.
I suppose you could do that.
You could say, I want to get something from the remote file system, pull it down to the server and
then send it to the end user.
That's really something you're not going to do very much.
But still, there are situations where you might have to get something from the remote file system to
your own server.
So where are we going to put it?
Destination.
That's our first parameter that will be a string.
And what do we want to get?
You might want to get more than one thing, so I'll say items dot, dot, dot string, very attic function.
We can get one or more items and potentially that will return an error.
OK.
We also want to list things now for parameters.
I'm going to have one which I'll call prefix string, and the prefix, of course, would be a folder
if we were going to say a remote file system like S&P.
But in other cases, Amazon S3 buckets, for example, there really is no such thing as a folder.
Instead, all of the assets that exist in a bucket have a prefix.
So I'm going to call them prefix instead.
And that's going to return to things, OK?
The first thing is your return is a slice.
Try that again, a slice of something I'm going to call listing.
OK.
That's a type that doesn't exist yet, but it will in a minute and potentially an error.
OK, so we're going to find that listing type in just a moment.
And the last function I need to implement will be delete, and it'll be again one parameter items to
delete, which will be a slice strings and that will return.
I'm going to use a bullet in this case, OK, because when you try to delete a non-existent file, we'll
just return false instead of true.
Now, the next thing I want is another type, and this one is going to be listing and it will be a struct,
and it only has five fields.
And these five fields correspond to all of the kinds of information I get from whatever file system
I'm connecting to.
One is an E tag, and you're going to get that from Mineo.
You're going to get it from Amazon S3 buckets and it's just a string.
OK?
That's a tag associated with a specific file.
Last modified.
That will be timed on time.
OK.
So that did the auto import for me.
And make sure that your ID ID also part of the time package.
Like minded online.
Three.
When was the file last modified?
The key?
And I'm using the word key for the descriptor here, because that's what Amazon uses.
That'll just be a string.
That's the filing the size and that will be a float 64 just to handle really big numbers.
And finally, here's a boolean.
Is this a directory which will be ignored by Amazon?
But it's something we'll be using, say, an SFP or WebDAV.
So is Directory Boolean true or false?
OK, so we'll format this.
I'll give it some comments.
So the first one first is the interface for file systems.
In order to satisfy this,
the interface
for all of its functions must be exist.
That's enough.
And the listing listing describes one file on a remote file system.
OK, so now we've got our type setup for our interface set up for the file systems, and we have a struct
that we can use to store files that exist on remote file systems.
So let's get started.
Now, in the next section, we'll start with Mineo, which is relatively easy to work with, and once
we have that one implemented, we'll move on to the other ones that we're going to include in this course.