We've already talked about.
If you're using like if you're already working with go and you have an established project and you're
using some sort of versioning or dependency management like glide or dap dap that's its name right.
That you when use go modules will automatically attempt to convert that for you and maybe with success.
I haven't done all any of them.
Just read about it but now we have an example Daniel put together here where we're gonna see what happens.
So walk us through this example.
All right so I've got a package in my go path my go path is to see users in Daniel go.
And so inside here I've got a source folder inside the source folder I've got to get a dot com or does
DEP upgrade.
This is not an actual package on actual GitHub.
I just put it in my debt in my go path.
I haven't actually pushed this on to get hub and so inside this folder.
I have a valid DEP program I'm using the hello and hello test from the very beginning of our go modules
things where we're just using version one of quote with quote Hello.
And same test with just the Hello test Hello.
And I've got the DEP go packet shut Tomoe which says that we're using our CIO quote version 1 5 2 and
overwriting the indirect dependency sampler to force it to be one third one instead of one ninety nine
ninety nine.
So this all works if I go test it it's it's all valid it's using go path mechanisms because it's in
a go path and it does not have a go module go down modifiable so it passes the test there's a vendor
folder where DEP has put all the dependencies it's a standard DEP program so to upgrade this from DEP
to using modules you just use go mod in it and you do not need to give it the name of the name is facing
it can figure out the namespace it's already on the go path so it can figure out the name spacing from
that and it's able to automatically just import from the go package file what dependencies it needs
to see now it's got to no go mod it's got the module just figured that out from the go path and it's
copying requirements the go package shop walk which was created by debt and so now if you look in the
folder we now have a go mod file and so if I if I put that into my editor you can see it's got the requirements
it's got the module correctly it's got to go when 13 it's got the versions of different various packages
quote in sampler or correct it managed to pull them all over if I do go test in this case it actually
does pass and I can do go list dash em all to show it is using go modules systems for doing stuff because
the dash and only works if you've got good modules working
you have more now so that's it yeah.
So in this case it input in this case it imported automatically everything was correct to do note that
versions may be off like for example my go package Tom will never actually mentioned anything about
ex text and so it should not have been 0 3 2 it should have been if we'd gone through the go more interesting
from the beginning it would have just been the random commit that a sampler or quote required as an
indirect dependency it found a specific version because it was trying to import off DEP which DEP always
goes versions in left forced otherwise so it was trying to match DEP a little more closely as far as
the indirect dependency so do keep keep an eye on your versions they may be incorrect just use your
go list dash them all to see all your versions of everything make sure everything's working if you've
got your go tests which you should you can test run them make sure it all works still.
So this is automatic import it's a convenience it is not magic there is possibility of error.
So what.
No magic.
All right.
So check it over once you've done it.
Yes test everything.
Make sure it still works.
Yes it's pretty cool though that it will automatically do that.
Nice you off not about the upgrades.
All right.
The next video we're going to introduce you to what the module mirrors just so you have a little awareness
of it.
See you the next video.