So now we're going to talk about the module media and privacy and fortunate for you and for me.
Daniel is a huge privacy advocate and I don't.
The number of individuals with as as high of a focus in a security conscious mind it.
I don't know if that was all grammatically said the right way.
But Daniel is is very tuned in to privacy and security.
And so that's a great thing because you want to make sure that the code that you write is robust and
doesn't get broken or you don't accidentally put things out there that you don't want out there.
And the module mere and privacy two things we're going to learn about in this video.
But the module Mir is basically a proxy of all of the packages that are publicly available so that they're
all always available.
And and if there's a package somewhere that people are getting and that location goes down as happened
with the node package manager left pad.
Right.
People are using left pad and then left pad became inaccessible and I remember is that correct story.
And and then you know tons of people's code broke.
And so with this proxy all those publicly available packages are going to also be cached also be stored
over at this proxy.
Proxy is one of those words I'm always like what is proxy mean.
And it's kind of a stand in for somebody else the authority to represent someone else especially in
voting a figure that can be used to represent the value of something in a calculation.
So a proxy server or proxy location is just another location of something else.
Is that it's my understanding of a proxy.
So this module Mir is a proxy server for all of the publicly available modules so that they're always
accessible you don't have to rely upon some dude in his mom's garage computer being turned off and he's
lost access to code that you needed like anything that's publicly available will also be on this module
Mir and go is built up with security in mind.
So there's a video right here that you can watch as well as this article is going blog post right here
which you can read which talks about that but that's the first thing to take away from this video is
this idea that there's this computer where all of the you know packages that are publicly available
are also being put onto this computer.
And and then that brings up a privacy issue because what if you don't want your code to accidentally
be put out there in public for everybody.
So Daniel is going to talk to that a little bit and share any thoughts on what we've already.
Yeah I guess so.
So you had the Mir the Mir is available it is it is on by default for go 113 and up you actually have
an environment variable go proxy which which lists what your proxy that you're connecting to IS.
SO YOU COULD SEE THIS SCO proxy.
So your go proxy over variable list separate with commas what it should try.
So first thing it tries it tries the proxy first then it tries a direct connection to the original place
where the module is located.
So you going then direct the proxy the going Mir is available to for your own use.
So if you wish to download it and put it on your own systems if you're like a company or something you
can do so as well and then you just adjust your go proxy to point to your own personal Mir instead of
to the general going one for most people though just the general going one is works just fine.
Now the downside of the proxy is if you've got private repos the proxy can't really access them.
And so you can't bounce through the proxy to them.
So to avoid that there is now a new environment variable for who called go private.
So if you have private repos like here's a repo that's private and you know like I have it on github
it's under private repo I don't want that to end up on the proxy.
Does the proxy automatically know not to look at my private gab repo or do I have to set this flag.
I'm not entirely sure.
I think the private the proxy is not actually able to access it because it doesn't it's private.
Yeah you're you're private.
Yeah.
When you're doing it direct it's able to use your sage or your HP connection to connect to it and grab
your private repo.
But the proxy doesn't have access to your SDH private key and so it can't do that.
OK.
So but to tell you go to not even bother trying it is the the go private environment variable so which
a.
Right.
Which I don't actually have any value in but there is a go help topic on this module private.
So if you do go help module private there is a big large amount of information starting from here going
down about how to properly keep private code private and so go private is the easy environment variable.
If you just set your go private to some value like for example if I want to say my get hub or overdose
and I've got some private repo private repo.
Now if I do go in the go private I can see that's there.
And so now whenever I have a module go modules go modules ever looks at looks for this module it will
skip it from the proxy it will it will try to do it direct from my machine it will not cache it in any
way it can't in any way possible it'll just try to keep it just for my own device.
So you can use asterisks as well so if you actually have access to like I'd get hub organization that
so like for example if I've got access to a whole like Hub Group that's private private group and it's
got a bunch of repos in there I can use an asterisk.
So now everything that's in that group is now private as well.
Or will also be skipped from the proxy from attempting the proxy for this.
So as I said I'm pretty sure the proxy can't actually access the private code but without the go private
you will still tell the proxy that because that there's a repo that exists at that you URL which you
probably don't want to do.
And of course you're losing time because every time it's trying to go through the proxy ask call the
proxy before trying the direct connection if it's not in a private.
All right.
So two takeaways from this video is that one there's this incredibly great service which keeps all packages
publicly available packages available and it's known as the module Mir and it's proxy for anything that's
stored out there in any location.
And and if you have stuff in a private repo then it's not going to be seen.
But it's also good to specify explicitly if you have something that you don't want to end up on module
mere to set to look into this go private variable and set that variable that you stack of that.
Yeah.
There's actually a little note here to go private might be abused by other by other tools like for example
if you got an editor that makes packages clickable link to a go doc page it might look at the go private
to see if that particular package is public or not and if it's not public there's if it's private.
There's no good off page it doesn't need to bother even trying to make a living at Nice.
So go private is kind of good to have set in general just in case some other tool use the tip.
All right.
So that's a that's the model we are in go private.