So now we're going to take a look at modules and get comment versioning and then we're going to look
at get forks and module path replacement and then we're going to do review commands and kind of review
everything we've learned so far.
And Daniel's got some information here to share with us about modules and get commit versioning.
I'm looking forward to learning it myself and see what it is.
So.
So you may wonder if you have seen the this releases page on on github for RC quote and all the other
get all the other modules will have releases as well with version numbers.
How do you do for your own project by go to this going project and look because your releases so to
do it is it's following get tax so which is just a part of kit itself.
So if I do get tagged they'll say we've got no tax on our system.
So let me make just make sure real fast.
I am on the master branch.
I'm up to date so to create a tag is actually very simple.
It's simply get tag and the tag name.
So what we've got so far here is what a get tag is just something you're tagging your a particular commit
to this particular amount.
OK.
Yeah.
So.
So get tagged just lets you tag a particular commit with basically a name that can be used for in the
future so to create a get tag it's just get tag and then the name of the tag.
So for going modules your tags should follow the semantic versioning.
So for this case we could say this is this particular commit here with the go modules example for complete
we can call this version zero point 1.0 nice.
So that creates the get tags now and you get tag it's there.
However I can not able to push it by default with just to get push it does not work.
Well you have to do instead is you can either use get push origin and then the tag name.
Zero point one point.
So this would work for pushing up a specific tag Alternately you can get push dash dash tags to push
all tags so which is what I will do here.
So now you can see it says new tag v 1 0 1 0 is pushed and if I go back to the Hub page and a refresh
the page it now says there is one release if I click that I can now see the version is now available
version tag so I'm making little notes here of the commands and the first clan you can see is create
a tag and we get tag tag name and then we have show to show a tag for whatever the current tag you gave
is.
So get tags shows a list of all the tags can get brown tail branches show a list of all the tags and
let's just get tagging them to push a tag we can do get push origin and tag name or we can do get pushed
dest hash tag is all right.
Really.
Yes.
This is dash hashtag.
All right good.
Any other command dash dash tags with net tags within that.
And.
And so anytime we're ready to go to a major minor patch we just add that tag and then that tag starts
there that tag it's now attached to whatever committee you are currently on.
So make sure you're on the right branch that's awesome.
And and if there things that we are committing at the same time we would do all of that with get push.
Dash dash tags because they'll do the push and then also include the tags the tags it says all tag bring
it on all text you have to list amount with the get push origin technique Excellent.
So that's a modules and get commit versioning and then this this allows us to start adding versions
to our module so that other people would be able to then using modules import one of our versions or
the latest version as opposed to just the random commit.
That was the least that point in time.
Do you have anything you want to add to this.
No.