One question I have is if that works for a minor or a patch and we want to go Major we got to add that
new V.
How do we do that.
When you go doing a major update it's you tag it still.
But you also have to go into your go mod and add in your v into the Go on.
Because this is your namespace C gets spit specifying your go mod as well.
So before you get hub dot.com or Florida's replays like where's our mod for this project.
So for good modules there.
And so this one is just going project.
We are ready for v 2 we would add V to there we'd add V to there we go into all of the files that would
if we had a file that imported some other package it's also in this module we would need to update that
to be the V to import as well.
So if we had an import of our packet that comes and goes
smell too.
I've been doing checked slash dot com in slash comment or something and now B we would now need to add
in a v2.
OK so so you'd have to update all your own imports and then you have to update your your good months
and namespace and so that doesn't refer to folder.
So it's not like we need to take everything there was in version 1 and put it in the V 1 folder and
take everything we want in version to copy all that put into two folder.
Now the V1 V2 is not talking about those folder.
No it's it's the name it's part of the namespace.
OK.
Call.
All right.
Thanks.