Say you got some package that's using some other package like say here I've got I've just created a
simple may not go it imports are a go goes to heaven going projects going all the way down to zero zero
three go modules zero for upgrade energy dependency and I'm just using that.
Hello.
To make this work because this particular folder is package hello it's like you to load up hello do
you call this function.
Yeah it's package Hello Function Hello yeah.
So if I in that and this is a go module so if I go run mean dot go.
Yeah I think it is say I didn't see it in there.
No I gotta go back out and see it's over to replace so go run main go so it will stay I'll start finding
that package so it prints hello world and you can see there's the Reporter Where's your main go where's
that same.
No this is any this is not in going OK it's somewhere else.
Yeah I got somewhere else with it's own go mod which is now which is requiring the ghost eleven one
indirectly so which is God.
So that just pulled it off of the Mir Yeah it's or we could probably probably.
Yeah probably added to the Mir site probably actually it put in it got the zipped version zero stuff
so I might actually want to run go get on that to see about.
Nope it's still looking at the latest version I'm not I'm wondering why it's like going to calling it
v 0 1 0 if you go get the 0 1 0 with it do it good try the 0 1 0 finding
did we push me 0 1 0 yes it's it's here Oh yeah.
There it is Delanie extracting it is nice.
All right so now we're using the D 0 1 0 of this thing and so you run it go run may not go and go oh
I really don't like having a comma or a period there or there's a bug in the function or something you
need to fix it but it's going to take too long for the original owner to fix it so you go OK I'm going
to fix it myself so you fork the repo
which takes however long to fork just a few seconds yeah yeah yeah it's done and so you can clone this
so I'll just go back out I got to go back out and get a quote here
um do I actually have just testing real fast.
Yes that is a quick shortcut to open up my editor to this location so now I decide ok well I want this
to not have the period where the comma so let's fix this I just want to say hello world when I type
when to call that Hello Function and then presumably at this point you would get you'd add that you'd
get commit this
better wording on
function and oh you would also want to update here to make sure your tests still work
so make sure that everything still works in this project um because this is an 0 0 3 0 4 Go test.
Make sure it's the test still works because you're fixing something you've already added you need to
add again.
Yeah.
Yep.
So for that.
So now fix her remove punk shoe Asian from low.
Shen And I push this to your foot to my fork which is not affect fact the original repo
so that my fork says it's one commit ahead.
So presumably at this point you'd create a pull request as well.
But in the meantime going back to your original project
you still need to figure out you still need to make sure this particular you fix the punctuation here.
Now one thing you could do is you could adjust this import.
I could change this to a lower dose and this would work but that's not really viable if you got a really
large project where you got the import everywhere and so modules has a way to basically alias it an
import to some other module and so you can find this out by looking for go help mod a C there's a edit
an edit command for go mod Edit So I you go help mod edit you will find all the information on the edit
command including a new a comma a dash replace so you can use this dash replace to replace an old to
a new so if you do go mod edit dash replace and the old is the old module with this module not the whole
package old module is going to be replaced with a dot com slash or dose slash going project which is
my fork.
So this this will be replaced with that
um UN version to a new path must be local directory so at m..
So now if I look in here and if I I my import still says goes to eleven but if I go into the go mod
I now has it still says requires goes to eleven going project but now there's also a replace goes to
eleven with or alerts going project and if I test this go run main I go it'll now start looking.
It doesn't it doesn't have my word it's going project for so now it's nice to go find it and download
it
that's pretty cool yeah says hello world without the comma in the period.
That's pretty cool.
And so when you would then you'd also have your poorer class and whenever the original person merges
your poor request you can then just go into your go module and delete the replace line would you have
to take it was it did it get set in an environment variable.
No it's just this replacement.
Okay.
It's very nice.
Well done.
Higher level stuff.
Let's get to know about C..
This should be rare but every once in a while some package has a bug and you can figure out how to fix
it in 10 minutes but it's going to take a day take a week for the pull request to be accepted.
So this will let you keep working while that happens.
Nicely done.