So now we're going to take a look at just sort of review some of the commands that we've seen through
this section and then we're going to move into some hands on exercises and I'm looking forward to those
hands on exercises because I love working the challenges and problems in myself but the commands that
we've gone through so far as go mod a net and so go modern that is how you create a go module and you
want to do that in your root directory your read directories if you're working on it or if you're using
get it's going to be where you're hit and get folder is empty the directory from which all the other
directories in your project merge or transcend or originate from or under the tree structure.
So go modern IT CREATES A go module.
Do you have anything more to say about go modern.
It also gives you your go mod file.
Yep.
Yeah.
Come on.
And it creates them on file.
You have to name the namespace yourself unless it can figure it out based.
Because if you're on your go to have that to figure it out so add your namespace to that by example
dot com forward slash hello or get hub dot com forward slash user name goes to Levin forward slash repo
name so whatever your namespace is if you're on your go path already it'll figure out the namespace
path.
So you it in that case but under most circumstances you'll need to put that there and then go build
and go test another package building commands add new dependencies to go mod as needed and and then
we can see what's in go mod by opening it up or carrying it or we can list all of the current modules
dependencies.
Those would be direct and indirect dependencies.
So we've learned what that is.
And we've really learned quite a bit going through all this about package management direct tendencies
and indirect dependencies and go modules and keeping track of which packages and specifying which packages
you could go get a package name and you can also add in an at you know with the version or latest.
So that's not being R but close.
So there's some examples down below where it says it so go get the package and they'll bring in the
latest.
You could add in ladies if you want or you could specify an exact version and then go mod tidy removes
any unused dependency dependencies and adds dependencies for other platforms as Daniel pointed out earlier
and then we have go doc package name where we can look at the documentation for package.
Anything you want to add to all those do we leave any thing out.
Only if you want to put in something about the the added the replace or the get tag yeah that's that's
so kind.
They're kind of fancy here.
Yeah.
That the added The get tag is import get tags important and it's fairly easy.
But yeah let's get into the replaces replace is is that advanced.
Yeah look it up when you need a good tag and then we have the tag name right.
Yeah.
And so those commands are all right there.
Create a tag Share list of tags I guess we'll just list each of those out right here.
That's good to happen down there.
So we have.
So we'll just put these under tag tags.
Let's do that.
Black tags and we'll have the commands right there because they're all related to the same deal and
we'll make those red.
I will make those red on my own time but that is.
Those are the commands we've learned through this.
I think it's for me handy to have all those commands there and just remind myself how everything we
learned it's really comes down to using these commands.
So all right.
Anything else.
We will see you in the next videos with hands on exercises.