So now we're moving into some new sections.
My glasses were about fall off my head and we just finished these hands on exercise and we're going
to look at go modules and so go modules is actually a pretty big change for the go programming language.
And one of the great things about go.
I recently had a student I created a course my first online course was several years ago once tunes
like Hey these videos are still here and you're online course are they still relevant.
And I'm like Yeah.
They're absolutely relevant.
That's why it goes great.
It doesn't change that much.
They really made sure that the design of the language was built solid from the get go and and because
of that they've added incremental changes but there haven't really been any large significant changes.
The initial architecture of the language was solid built by geniuses built by luminaries in computer
science.
KEN THOMPSON Rob.
Rob Pike and Robert Gregg summer right.
Some of the same people who created C Unix UTF 8 the bedrock of comp science now created this language
created at one of the best soft fringing engineering firms to have ever existed.
Google so it's a really well built danger language doesn't change that much but one of the things that
has changed and this has been probably the most significant change in the language is that we used to
have something called Go workspaces that were tied to your go path environment variable and so that
go path environment variable if you come from you know if you programmed and go before this point that
go path environment variable defined your go work space.
And it was recommended that you just have one workspace and in that workspace he had a bin folder you
had a package folder and then you had a source folder and then inside that source folder you had your
name spacing which was often related to some domain user name and maybe a repo.
And that's how you namespace different code in different packages.
Well one of the big changes with the language was that they needed a more effective way to do package
management or dependency management whatever you want to call it.
And we're gonna get into all the details of what package management dependency management is and the
terminology and we're gonna walk you through all the fine to details.
This is just an introduction to go modules and go modules is actually really simple in practice.
However there's a lot of depth to it.
So we want to show you that depth.
Show you the power and if you're using some other versioning dependency management piece of SOC software
like glide or is it go depths or depths because it's called dat.
Yeah.
Def right if you're using something else he'll automatically do a pretty good job sometimes a good you
know you'll be a perfect job automatically go modules will convert those other package management if
you're using it to go modules and so go modules is a new way of managing your go work spaces so you
can have many workspaces and managing your code and your dependencies and so it's really cool easy in
practice but with a lot of depth.
So by the time we get through all this material you're going to have an awesome understanding of doing
package management using go modules and it's all built in and it's got a lot of really cool features
and security features.
So you're going to avoid things like that JavaScript NPM deal that they had which was what is it called
left that left pad where like you know millions of people are relying on this one little dependency
and like the person yanks it like code everywhere just fails.
Right.
So so it's pretty cool.
So here's just a little bit of an overview.
This is the introduction.
We have three sections we're going to look at we have a go modules intro section right now we're at
the overview video and then we're going to have a go modules deeper dive and then we're gonna have a
go modules.
Good to know and we're going to learn what package management is so if you're new to package management
we're gonna discuss that and explore what package management is because I remember at this point my
tie at a point in time in my life where I was like what package management.
And you're going to read some documentation one of my favorite things to do is like you know let's get
the definitive source of information about what this is all about we're going to give you resources
to that we're going to create a new module we're going to learn about go mod and get repos and adding
a dependency and security assurance that's provided by go modules and we're going to learn all about
understanding versioning and upgrading minor dependencies and specifying dependency versions and adding
a new major dependency and upgrading major dependency and removing unused dependencies then we're going
to take a look at this automatic conversion thing which I just talked about with if you're using DAP
or glide or others we're going to learn about something called the module Mir and modules and get commit
versioning and get forks a module path replacement and they're going to review all those commands.
So that's what's common.
It's Friday late in the morning later in the morning it's 11:00 a.m. Friday and Daniel and I are both
really committed to providing you a great cause so committed this is what we're doing with our time
and we've studied this.
We just spent a lot.
You know like I spent the last couple of days just really diving into go modules so I could really understand
it.
And Daniel's got a lot of great practice and was awesome studying and it's also got a lot of great practical
experience using go modules.
So we're really excited to be offering this information this material this course to you so that you
are most best equipped to move out on your journey with coding to create the best code projects repositories
possible.
That's that's intro.
You anything you want to add.
So the go modules is a big change from go path but go path still exists in the go go 1.0 guarantee I
believe will mean go path will always exist in some form or another just in case you want to use old
old code or old tutorials so go modules is the new way of doing things.
It's the recommended way of doing things go path will still exist if you are dependent on it.
That's why pair programming and teaching is awesome because when you have many minds you get better
solutions.
And that's many not am I and I but many am a NY many minds often result in better solutions.
Different perspectives.
Yeah that's really good important that.
All right.
So anything else.
We'll see in the next video where we're going to jump in to discussing package management.