So now we're in the next video and amazing when we move from one video to the next video.
And sorry just try to keep it fun package management.
We're gonna talk about package management so what is package management mean to you.
How would you describe package management somebody who's never familiar with the concept.
So I would consider package management as in You've Got a package of some code that may be useful in
package management is how you organize the pet the the various packages needed to grant to make your
program.
So if you are making.
If you're making a program it may have it's you may have other packages of code made by other people.
And how do you audit organize it in a repeatable way.
You want to make sure other end that you can always get the same package every time.
But you also probably don't want to copy the code because that just means extra code that you have to
keep track of yourself.
You want to have the original person who made the code the package to keep working on it not have to
basically take ownership of these other packages in order to do yourself.
So package management is usually very very tightly tied to dependency management.
It's what does your code need in order to run in other packages and how do you manage that organize
it I like that distinction that you just made between packages and dependencies because there is a subtle
distinction there.
And so packages like originally when people began writing software they just had one big like document
with code and there is go to statements and it is really difficult.
And it became one of the ways that was described as like spaghetti code.
And so one of the big themes in the evolution of software engineering and software design has been to
modular rise code and so you modular ize code by instead of just having one big file with a bunch of
code where you know that said it's one file and there's a lot of code you break that code up into chunks.
And so we break code up into chunks and those chunks can be a function.
So here's a function that you know maybe takes text and makes it all capital letters.
And so that's a chunk of code or there could be a chunk or several chunks of code.
You know another chunk we could have is to get everything related to working with strings into like
one big package.
And that name it could be called a package.
It could be called a module.
It could be called a library.
That name is like here's the here's a collection of code that's like related together.
And so the first thing just understanding that word package is like you know or or it can be called
module or be called library it's just a bunch of code kind of wrapped together that could be useful.
And it's usually if it's done well organized around some sort of a theme some sort of a purpose so a
package a library a module for working with strings a package a module a library for working with printing
whatever it might be.
And so that's that's the package.
Then when you create software when you create software you could take your software and break it up
into these packages.
So you have different packages that work together to do what you want your software to do.
And instead of writing all those little packages yourself you might go out and find somebody who's written
a chunk of code for you already they have some package that does something and then you could bring
that code into your software project and use it.
Licensing and everything permitting and so your code becomes dependent upon all of these packages.
They are dependencies your software project is dependent has these dependencies reliant upon these different
packages packages you wrote packages other people wrote.
And now what happens if you know the package somebody else wrote they upgrade it so they make some changes.
Sorry I keep putting my hand in front of your face for my demonstration.
They upgrade it.
So that's my understanding of packages and dependencies would you have anything that you would add to
that.
Sorry.
Two packages modules libraries.
Their concept means same thing but different languages might use individual words for specific more
detailed meetings.
So go actually has a difference between a package and a module.
Thank you.
Even though they're in general their concepts are the same.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So those words are all pretty similar pretty interchangeable.
And because that again change our outline here and take out modules from these worlds have the same
meaning and leave package libraries and other people's code your own groupings of other people's code
groupings of other people's code and groupings of your own code.
I think I'll add those in their groupings of your own code.
What else would we want to say about packages.
Anything else to say about package management.
I've got a few things to read before I jumped in to reading it.
Not particularly.
So this was from if you go to your terminal and you type in go help and then type in modules because
we're gonna be learning about modules here is documentation about some scrolling through my commands
documentation about modules and so this is one source of documentation for modules and a look at other
sources as we go through what we've outlined here for you.
But here is a description of it which I put here which I really like this description.
So a module is a collection of Go packages.
So there's that distinction Daniel's just making modules are the unit of source code interchange and
versioning.
So interchange means that this is code that could be the way I interpret that used between projects
or between people.
It could be interchanged exchanged used and versioning is like the code.
We'll have different versions that you use the go command has direct support for working with modules
including recording and resolving dependencies on other modules modules replace the old go path based
approach specifying which source files are used in a given built built and the go path still work as
we've discussed in the previous video.
There's a really important note here which I thought was great and there's an article there's written
by Rusk Cox and this article is called our software dependency problem.
And so the one of the main things that really stood out to me from the sorry decline linked to here
is anytime you're using other people's code you're bringing somebody who's code into your software project
and you That's like bringing somebody into your house you need to kind of be comfortable with who you're
inviting into a place which needs to be security conscious and so you know correctness of their code
the security issues surrounding using other people's code and then also licensing issues are some of
the issues you want to think about when using anybody's code any other person's codes.
This applies to all dependencies not just go modules but definitely something worth thinking about.
And in the previous video we alluded or mentioned briefly the node package manager.
So node package manager NPM is for node javascript node is for how packages are manages manage with
JavaScript node and with NPM there's the left pad story.
So what happened with that.
We didn't share that entire story.
Somebody created this labs had this idea there was there was a left pad function it was very small.
I think it was only like five lines of code it was a very tiny package which is a single function in
it that would pad Pad with spaces on the left to want to write a line text.
It was very small dependency but it was used by other dependencies.
This package some other package would depend on left pad and in some other package should depend on
that and in some other package depend on that.
And then you yourself may never have actually used left pad in your package but you may use something
else which then depended indirectly on left pad.
And so at some point the creator of left pad had some issues and so he pulled all this code away suddenly
the entire node package universe basically all collapsed because left pad was such a deep core dependency
for so many other package is that basically the entire chain of dependencies is a very very large proportion
of the all the packages just kind of all die because they couldn't get to left pad.
And so there was a fairly big panic until finally someone had a local copy of left pad and re uploaded
left pad and the note NPM people were able to tie it back in to the same spots that all the other dependencies
could find it.
And so it just it was it was a major thing because all these packages depended on left pad and the creator
left pad just kind of pulled up there could and then one of the neat things about so so that also we're
going to talk about direct and indirect dependency.
So you could have a direct dependency directly depending upon this chunk of code but that chunk of code
that package that you're using might also have dependencies of your own which then become indirect dependencies
for your project.
And so like left pad that indirect dependency for many people disappeared and then all these projects
just stopped working.
How does go go has a way of getting around that.
Right.
And somewhat there's still depart direct and indirect dependencies and such goes got a proxy to try
to prevent issues with packed with packages disappearing.
It's got there's there's copies of of the code sort of the original code disappears.
And here it depends on it can still get access to a copy of it.
Yeah.
So that's nice.
And the last thing we have here in this video is a note as modules are usually one to one with a repo
that there are ways to put multiple modules in one repo.
So usually you have a repo somewhere and then you're that's going to be a module.
So that will be accessible.
Do you have anything you want to say about that.
No.
All right great.
So that's a little bit about package management.