Room vroom vroom.
All right.
So right after this video we're going to show you how to use modules we're going to get going with go
modules.
But I just want to give you some documentation resources and one of the places you can look for.
Go modules documentation is the go to Ling blog.
So that's a great resource.
If you go there and then go to the blog index you'll find articles on modules you could see module Mir
and check some database launched and stuff like that migrating to modules and then down here using go
modules.
So a lot of the curriculum we're going to teach you is built off of using go modules right here just
because they have excellent examples.
And we thought if we paralleled this blog post you'd be able to later come back and reference this blog
post and easily sort of synthesize the information because you've been exposed to it.
So that's one of the resources for documentation.
Another resource for documentation is the go command.
And one of the ways you can learn about that is coming here to do that a little bit slower going dot
org then go to documents and then command F to search the page and I'm searching for command on the
page and if I come down I see command documentation.
And so here's documentation for different go commands.
I'm going to go to the go.
Command right there.
And if I command F to find a word on this page and search for module you could see all the different
places modules modules module or talked about on this page.
That's good to know about.
And then the last resource I'm going to give you for documentation is here at the terminal if I type
go help I get help for the go command.
And here are here's the usage.
And so the usage is go and then pass in the command and arguments and the commands are and here a different
go commands including go mod.
So we're gonna learn about that.
And plus I could use go help command to search for help on this command or any of these commands.
So I could do.
Go help M O D.
Go help IMO D.
And this is going to give me help on.
This is where I typing go help anybody.
This is gonna give me help.
On the Go mod command.
So I'm going to go back to go help and take a look at the rest of this and we just looked at this stuff
here.
Go command the commands are and there's the go mod command and go help command for information about
a command and then additional help topics.
And down here we have these module things there and go help topic for more information on this topic
so could you go help modules and you already saw that in a previous video or any of those other things
related to modules and I could read about that.
There is also a good up mod help topic to a little bit of to mod help topic up there.
So there's there's a lot of new documentation here around modules because it's not a small deal to have
good dependency management.
So that's the documentation.
Just want to make sure that you have access to it.
Anything you'd like to add.
No.
Nope.
There's there's a lot of blog posts about good modules though because it was such a big deal so you
can also just search go modules and you'll find plenty of medium articles to explain how to use them
or in the nuances behind it too.
But after these videos you should be fine.
Yes.
And last thing I'm going to say here is there's a link here for semantic versioning.
So there's a way to do software versioning where when you look at the versions it has meaning.
And I believe we talk about this further and if not we will talk about it further and if I don't have
a deeper dive OK deeper dive we go into semantic version versioning so you can learn about that but
there's a link there to read about semantic versioning and then also a concept that's really important
to all of this is name spacing.
So here is a link to name spacing and so name spacing just means that we use names to identify things
in the real world.
That's how humans work.
And then we also use names to identify things we actually call them identifiers.
It's another word we can use to refer to them.
You know encoding and so a namespace means that like here is a way that we could say this is where this
stuff lives.
And so you know one namespace might be like a get hub account get hub dot com user name and then repo.
Right.
That's a namespace and that's not going to conflict with anybody else's namespace.
So you might get help.
Use your name is different than Daniel's GitHub user name.
So even if our repo names are the same the namespace dick get hub dot com username repo name is going
to differentiate R and R repos.
And so this idea of name spacing that things have unique names is also important too important to using
packages and modules and not having the names conflict.
So that's that's a little bit about go notation for modules.