All right.
So we're going to parallel as we kind of teach you about go modules we're gonna parallel this blog post
right here.
The blog the GO blog using go modules and the first one is there some sample code we already added this
to get.
So if you go take a look at get hub you will see we have 0 3 Go modules and then I put Rusk Cox's article
there and 0 0 button 0 1 we have create a module Hello test go and hello Doc go.
And so we're gonna use those examples because those examples parallel the article now be a good reference
for you to come back to later and now we're going to create a go module and Daniel's gonna show us how
to do that.
So well first things go module gives you your name spacing it tells your project where your code exists
amongst all the other code in the known universe or just released on Earth.
Yeah is the same thing.
There might be some aliens with the dot com interface intersex super interest or.
But this this namespace will be unique to this module that you're going to create an inside that module
you'll have a package or packages of code correct.
And usually it's one module one package is the best practice not necessarily one module month one module
to one repo.
But there may be multiple packages in a module.
OK.
So you can demonstrate this by we've got this hello I go in this Hello test stuff go if you run go test
to actually run the tests it'll tell you this is what it thinks this particular package is called which
is a rather ridiculous package name that's dependent on my foot my file system which is not what we
want.
So to help this I will go back up dance before I go my before go modules.
So going back up to going project here I can now declare this going project here is my route of my get
my get repo.
I can do go mod in it and I give it the the namespace of this particular package which in this case.
For most and get repos can simply be the path to the repo get hub dot com goes celeb and going project
do not include HP yes if you're in some end be careful you're not in some pub subculture with additional
stuff to it you are the path to the reach of the route so go mod in it get up dot com ghost club and
going project and this namespace could be any namespace that you choose and so doing something with
it have connected to a repo is a good way to do it but also if you're at a company configure it for
your own organisation.
So the only kind of general rule of thumb is there should be some way to link the namespace to where
you can find the code on the Internet so which is why the euro is such a good idea.
So this creates the new go to mod so if I open up my editor I can find the go up mod it's here it's
a very small simple file just says this is the namespace and it was built go 113 originally.
So this is just kind of a new way of thinking about things when we had the go path and go with the source
folder and the source folder we'd have you know get hub dot com goes to Levin and the repo name and
that was the namespace for all of the code that was in there and now anywhere on my computer I don't
need to be in like you know the go workspace with Source Been package folders anywhere on my computer
I could say I came in and create code in this folder and write in the root of that folder I just to
go modern net and then whatever the namespace is and now it knows that everything I'm doing here is
connected to that repo that's namespace.
And so we can demonstrate this by going back down into where we've got the code and I can run go test
again and we'll test it again.
Now you can see the path to this package is now a more general follows the namespace and then the sub
folders within their recall.
That's the first step in working with go modules
much but.