So the next thing we're going to do is we're going to add a dependency and just to anchor anchor you
in the course outline.
Here's where we're at.
We're adding a dependency and the code that we're going to add we had.
Hello go and hello Tesco.
We're going to now pull in a package and it's R.S. C dot I O forward slash quote.
And if you go and you look for that online to see what comes up what you will find is its package quote
here and to import it.
We need are a C I O forward slash quote.
This is in go dock which has documentation for the standard library and third party packages from other
people.
And so we're going to import this package and we're going to run func Hello.
Right here.
And so that's what we've added.
We've changed our code to include return quote Hello which returns a string and import this package.
So I now have that in my editor right here in 0 2 adding a dependency we added in this file and I can
go to my terminal and my terminal I'm going to see which directory I'm in and C.D. and 2 0 0 3 0 2 and.
And then I'm going to do a go test.
And when I run this we're going to see all of the dependencies so the first time you add a dependency
and on your local machine it needs to go out and get that code and bring it back.
You're going to see that process happen.
And so your editor did it when you open up the file Oh my editor automatically did it for me when I
opened up the file.
Yeah I notice to go to some show up in your as I have it all.
Sometimes this stuff happens in the background to see what would have happened if my editor hadn't done
that for me would have found RCI quote don't download downloaded that and all of that.
And so what it's doing when it does that is it's if you import a package library not yet tracked by
go module by default go adds it to go mod using the latest version.
So the latest version of whatever package you're wanting to use is defined as the latest tag stable
laser tag release version or latest UN tagged version so it gets the latest version and you could see
the version of RSA quote by cashing out that go mod or opening it up.
So if I opened it up here here's my go mod you could see I'm now requiring R A C I O quote version one
point five point two.
And and so that's that's my latest version.
And there's also two types of dependencies.
Right.
So only direct dependencies are recorded and go mod so direct dependency.
This is the direct dependency but there might also be indirect dependency so are a C I O forward slash
quote might itself be using other packages and to see those direct and indirect dependency.
So just distinguishing differentiate between direct and indirect dependencies we go we use go list dash
M forward slash all.
And so if I bring that up and you go list dash M go list dash jam all I think I set forward slash all
but go dash m all we could see all of my dependencies and so here is my direct dependency here's my
indirect dependency another indirect dependency is right here.
So I have all of those dependencies for my project and you're looking at something there anything you
want to add to that or anything you want to show I believe the indirect dependencies will be within
your go mod if that's if you're going through a compatibility with a non module so are a C quote has
a go module I'm trying to figure out how to go back to the correct version on get out of here it's a
one point five point two one five two that's this C for
permit number C for D for etc..
So if I go to MITs and go to look for C or D for right now it out by your test that was that I view
the code at this point in the get repo it's got to go mod and you can see it's of its own dependency.
So this is your indirect dependency the sampler.
Yeah.
So the only reason.
So this does not show up in your go mod because it's listed a go my SO if you are importing some patch
that's not modules yet.
Your go mod will include the indirect dependencies to
I'm confused.
Again.
So because RC quote is the go module your go module does not have to list the indirect dependencies
because RC quote has has its dependence has its dependencies listed in its own mind.
Oh right yeah.
So if you import some package let's not go modules yet.
Yeah your module will be responsible for getting its indirect dependencies too.
I got it.
All right.
So since since this package uses go modules it's got its own go dot mod file and you could see here
that the dependencies of this package.
This is on Daniel's computer.
You know the dependencies are the module is ours.
See Io forward slash quote and its dependency is RISC diode forward slash sampler and that's one point
three and when I bring in our AC Io for its last quote.
So that's the version I brought in their version one point five point two and we can go look at that
and second their direct dependency is my indirect dependency.
Right.
So coming with this are the dependencies of that which is this.
That's very direct.
Is that what you're trying to say.
Yeah.
Got it.
So.
So it's not sure.
So but the indirect dependency does not show up in your work.
Oh my God the goes to up and go going project because it's already listed in this go mod.
Yeah but to see them I I go list dash em all.
Do this command right here and that shows them onto me and then.
So but if you imported some package it's not a go mod you see you would see their indirect dependencies
in your mind because they have to you have seen some go mod whether it's yours or till he makes some
other one and then go back to where we saw the versions and we could see that this is version one point
five point two releases and version one point five point two is that C.D. C for D for 2 3 6 which is
that one and and so that's the same version that I downloaded and that came down as latest right it
automatically came down as latest yes because of the list of dependencies your import statement was
not saying you needed a v2 version so tries to find the latest stable released version.
So this went.
So these ones are V2 which we said we wanted.
We didn't say Fuck version so defaults to version 1 so it doesn't have any of these it doesn't get this
one because this is a prerelease version of some sort.
It doesn't get this one because this version is not a proper version number.
So it gets this because the newest properly tagged stable version one version and we'll learn how to
specify exactly which version you want but by default it gives you the latest version one unless you
specify the exact version you want by default.
All right so that's a little bit surprising to me because when I read the documentation if you import
a package library diet tracked by go mod by default go adds it to go mod using the latest version.
I would think the latest version is 3.0 1.0 but it just as latest based upon one server so that it goes
based on the weight.
So with go modules the the major version the first number is a part of the input path.
So because you don't have the version number in your import.
It goes for version 1.
I got it.
That makes sense so the reason it's version 1 and we're gonna see this is you could specify version
number 4 version 2 or higher but then that becomes part of the import path.
And so since in my code my import path is RISC dot Io forward slash quote and it's not foreign slash
quote the two which would be version 2 or v 3 version 3 which by default would give me the latest version
to hear version 3.
I'm just doing that which says it's version 1 and it's getting me the latest version one since I didn't
specify it there.
Correct.
Cool.
We're figuring this out.
So that's that's adding a dependency.
And again that's paralleling this article and so we're just kind of going through and showing you what
they're showing you here and the next one we're gonna see how to do security assurances but go some
and we're gonna see what goes some is we're going to learn a little bit about that.
You have anything you want to add to this video.
I do not believe so.
See the next video.