So now we're going to talk about go some and so go some as a security check just to make sure that the
code that you download is the code that's expected to be downloaded.
And if you look at the resources that we gave you four go modules.
And again a lot of this stuff is good to know so you have a thorough understanding of how modules are
working.
But at the level of using modules it's pretty straightforward and easy.
Just do that go on a net and then you are L some name spacing for it and then you're working with modules
and it kind of all happens behind the scenes but it's good to know like what we went over in the last
video so that when you add a dependency you know the import if the import has a forward slash me two
or four slash v three or nothing forward slash right.
So we saw saw this import here in the previous video.
Ah I see that I have quote that's going get the latest version of version 1 and if you have a future
version like version 2 or version 3.
Right.
That's going to be specified in the future version and then also something that stood out to me which
we didn't speak to is you have require.
Right.
And so the require is something that you know saying hey this is what's required for this project.
And so it's always going to use this code for my project that I'm building here that's bringing in different
packages different modules from other people or maybe I created them.
And so it's always going to get that specific chunk of code so if that code move forward there's a version
to a version 3 of this I could bring in the code I need for my project and And just interestingly to
point something out which is interesting if you look at where that is stored like where is all this
gets stored when you download a module somewhere and all the reading I found this documentation that
modules already downloaded are cache locally in your go path under package and mod and so that's kind
of an interesting place to put it because the CO path is like hey we're not using Markov anymore for
our own workspaces but modules is still using the go workspace you have anything you say.
Any thoughts on that.
I know we didn't talk about this before.
It might it might be kind of almost a legacy because like other package managers that were before go
modules for go like DEP would actually use the same place for their cached files and if we look in there.
So right now you could see I did a print working directory and men might go workspace which is connected
to you know my go path environment variable I'm in the package folder and then the mod folder I say
hey what's in here.
I got get honeycomb but I also have RC dot Io which is this package that I'm working with right here.
So it's downloaded that code and storing it on my local machine.
So one of the things that you want to know is that the code you're using is secure hasn't been changed
and the code that you downloaded a week ago is the code that maybe a month from now or a year from now
you download its exact same code.
It wasn't intentionally or maliciously changed right.
You're still working with the same code that code hasn't changed and the way that that is tracked is
with something called Go sum and there's a level of security that's built into this and this is also
interesting reading.
I don't think I ever showed you that link undergo modules intro.
We gave you some resources and one of those resources under documentation was module Mir and check some
database launched.
And so this is a really interesting article which just talks about the security of packages and how
they have thought through and they have this really interesting tree structure that they're using based
upon the Merkle tree and hashes backed by trilling and it looks really fascinating.
I don't totally understand all of this but but what it does is it's comparing everybody's hashes to
make sure that this version of this code has similar hashes across the whole universe of people using
it.
And so that that helps me maintain the security.
What would you add to that.
Not really much.
So the main point is that your version one you keep the the go mod is kept you want to keep it around
because it states your namespace in your version of course and your dependencies and it knows this version
is the one that you've been working with.
If a 1 5 3 shows up later on your code said that it was working with 1 5 2 so it will automatically
update to 1 5 3 until you're ready to check if it's 1 5 3 still works for you in the go some is to make
sure that 1 5 2 has not changed the person has not gone and recreated their get repo and declared a
new 1 5 2 with the separate with different code.
No it's still it that would have a different hash.
And so it's able to tell 1 5 2 is this is cryptographic rehashed as this and that's the version we need
and not changed a hash is a one way encryption where you put something in and it produces some output
and the output is always going to be the same.
And so if the inputs the same the outputs the same so the input changes at all the outputs always going
to be different.
So you could use a hash because if you're putting the same thing into the hash you're going get the
same code hash code out.
But if you put something different and you'll get a different hash code so if that number there change
you would tell us that the code that we're putting in changed.
But if it stays the same then the code is the same.
So that's that's good to know last thing which I think would be interesting is here in my in my go mod
it showed that I had version 2 and version 3 and this is common it is an indirect dependency of version
1 maybe.
I'm not sure why those came down this came because your editor is auto was trying to autocomplete stuff.
So when you put in that slash B and slash B 3 in your head your editor was trying to be your editor
was try to do stuff in the background to keep you up.
So you got to autocomplete stuff and then if I see the end to RISC I don't know if this has been brought
down here yet but if I look in here I could see here I have quote virtual one point five to which is
what I'm using but some of these have already been pulled down and you could see that there are different
directories right.
So different versions of that code base been brought down so those are being stored locally different
directories there.
So that's kind of interesting to look at.
All right.
So that's a little bit about go some and security assurances and then that article which you could go
take a look at if you want to see a little bit more about the security that's built in to go modules.
Anything else.
No.
So I guess just a summary here since it's the end of this like intro to go modules for go modules you
say go mod in it and you give your namespace at the root of your module and then you can just start
importing and using and writing code you can just.
And you don't have to look in the go module file at all if you want to.
You just start writing code and it's all in it all just automatically happens as a whole lot of talking
for just super simple just go modernist in the URL you're good to go.
So.
So there's lots of details and such behind it to keep it secure into note version to use and all that
but for the most part that happens behind the scenes.
So you only really need to know if something wrong happens Excellent.
All right.
See in the next section I'm thinking that I don't know.
Do we need a hands on exercise.
It's kind of fun to have hands on exercise maybe after an inspection maybe that's more stuff to happen.
All right we'll see in the next section where we're going to a little bit of a deeper dive go modules
even deeper.