So to understand modules and we're moving into the new section here and I just break these sections
up so each section doesn't have too many videos but the next section here is go modules deeper dive
and it's important to understand versioning.
And so the standard for versioning it's called semantic versioning and there's a link to it right here.
So you could click that link and you can learn everything you want to know about semantic version versioning
and all kinds of different languages but semantic versioning you could see even this has three numbers
here separated by dots.
And so this first number is the major version.
The second number is the minor version and the third number is the patch and I outlined all of this
here.
So for example you had these 0 1 2 the major version is 0.
The minor version is 1 the patch is 2.
What's the difference 3 major minor patch Major is backwards incompatible changes add it.
And so maybe the name of a function changed.
And so anybody who'd been using that function in the previous major version.
Now they need to have a new name and their codes going to break.
If they start using this new major version and so they're gonna have to go through and rename their
function in their code based continue using the next major version.
So there's backward incompatible changes and we're gonna see that illustrated example coming up and
then a minor change is backwards compatible changes are added and then a patch is just backwards compatible
bug fixes.
And so you know you might see this patch number going up and then you might see the minor changes being
added to minor versions.
Number going up and then this one.
But that's how semantic versioning works.
What happens if we get up to like past nine you go to 13.
Yeah.
It doesn't go to eleven.
You can have it made did it into C want it.
In there it's not just it's not just single digit.
So there you could get two.
You could have version one point two hundred fifty seven point thirty six.
If you wanted although I do wonder how long you've been working on this project if you get your minor
version and high and then if we see if we're relying upon a dependency I have a little question here
for discussion and let's say it's dependency major version 1 and goes to major version 2 what what should
we do at that point we see oh there's a new major version of this code it doesn't automatically go modules
doesn't automatically start using version to right still going to import whatever we specifically specified
or the latest of that.
Correct.
Give us the latest of that major release.
But if we see a major version two is out I guess the thing we'd want to do is figure out what are the
backward incompatible changes between this major version 2 and the previous major version one and then
figure out what we need to do with our code base to get it to be able to use the next major version
if we wanted to move forward so that we get the right thought process.
Yeah.
So overall the thought is for a patch and probably minor versions as well.
You can actually probably have an automatic system for upgrading the versions in your system just like
have a hybrid computer every week just automatically look through and see if it's possible to update
if you've got go test set up properly so he can confirm that it hasn't broken with the major version.
It's probably gonna require human intervention to do that.
Great.
All right.
So that's understanding versioning.