When upgrading a minor dependency there for whatever reasons go does not automatically update minor
and patch dependencies mostly just in case the creator of your module of your dependency.
If they made a mistake about which version number to upgrade go will not do that will not upgrade automatically
it requires you to explicitly upgrade the minor dependencies so so for example here.
If we do go list dash and all we can see all the dependencies direct and indirect of our object here
is that we can see we've got specific versions for quote and sampler.
We do not have a we're not using a tagged version for going to work slash X slash text.
So if we wish to upgrade to that we actually use go get so go get what previously before go modules
go get was download this code into your go path.
Now go get is if you're in a go module go get is how you adjust your versions in your code.
My file as as well as downloading and pre caching pre downloading the file so you can manually go into
the go out not file and edit it if you wish but you should probably avoid that when go get does it better.
So go get you can just say go get and you give the name of a version of a packet.
Module and that will add that as a that'll download it as normal and it will add it into your require
list here.
Note that it adds this as an indirect dependency.
This basically states to your module to go module your code is not directly importing it but it needs
to be this particular version to work anyway.
So our CIO quote or one of its sub dependencies is required requires text but you're saying you want
text to be this version at a minimum.
So it's now version 0 3 2.
You after you whenever you update your dependencies you always wanna make sure your code still works.
So if you've got proper go test setup that's it then you can just simply run your tests see our tests
still all pass which since we've got tests testing everything thoroughly that mean it's good enough
that we could probably push this code changes and if we run Go go list dash and all we can now see text
is now got a specific version on it and suddenly we need tools because apparently this version of text
did not require tools but this version text does require tools and then those are on Tag Versions.
Right.
So what does that mean.
It's on tag version there's no it's v 0 0 0 and then some sort of date and a hash behind that time stamp
date contact version so that would be just a comment at that repo at some moment in time but no version
number was assigned to it.
Correct.
And so they they specifically designed the this to be a date so that a newer commit would be.
It could easily tell a different difference a newer and an older tag to commit.
So even if somebody is not using versions in their code base there or using modules or versions at all
and you're pulling that code and it still is a way to identify that unique comment for GitHub at least
maybe other places to go like this in general this is getting getting general has all this features
isn't to get it I think I got it.
So there will possibly be other slight changes if it's if it's through SBN or some other version control
software but since gets the most common and use and generally what go use in general this is all we
did show as an example.
It's it's a it's untapped versions they stick a v 0 0 0 so if a new if an actual version comes in later
that will immediately register as being greater.
Yeah.
Then after that they put the date.
So if there's if you could try to compare the dirt stream to different commits it can check the date
differences to see which one's newer and then some unique hash.
I'm not actually sure what's this what this number actually comes from.
I don't think it's the commit number.
All right that's fine but if it's some value so you shouldn't have to deal with it you can just go get
your stuff yesterday.
Now you can see in our go mod we now have that version.
So if there was some update to two texts that had another version higher like 0 0 3 3 then getting that
would just be again just run go get on that package and that will just immediately go straight again
to the latest.
Tagged or you'll go to the latest version and following that those rules of latest tagged state release
latest tagged prerelease and then tagged latest Yeah.
So we just got the latest version so we just said hey bring down the latest version and and so brought
us the latest in the next video we're gonna see how to specify an exact version and so we'll see that
next video.
Anything more to add to this one.
No.
All right.
See in the next video.