So one of the main takeaways from the last video was that we saw how by default it brings down the latest
version of a package and we're learning that the packages are named spaced by their major version.
So anything over Version 1 e.g. that is Version 2 version 3 version 4.
It's going to have its own name spacing.
And so when you say something like go get go laying that or forward slash export slash text that's equivalent
to saying go get that out latest.
And so adding this at tag lets you specify the version that's the default tag it gets the latest version
of the major release.
And in this video we're going to see how specify you could specify a dependency version using like app
and added and say version one point three dot one.
So we're gonna see how to do that here.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to go to my terminal and I'm going to do go list dash
all and it's going to list out all of my direct and indirect dependencies.
And when we started this out we we said look we want to bring in our AC Io quote and version one point
five point two was what was brought in.
And then as part of that we also brought in our seed out Io sampler version one point three point of
an indirect dependency.
So if we go look at this this dependency which we asked for this direct dependency if we go look at
this we could gain some insight and some interesting stuff.
So I'm going to go to go dark dawg go dark dawg and I'm going to search for our seed out Io forward
slash quote because that's the one I brought in and it brings up this package and here I could click
on right there and they'll take me to get hub and get hub I could go to releases and then it releases
I could see the different versions we brought in one point five point two so I could click on this little
hash right here and that takes me to that one comment where I could see those files by clicking browse
and so when I look at version one point five point two and I look at the MoD file the module file on
this it says it's requiring RSA seed Io sampler version one point 3.0.
So that becomes an indirect dependency since this is a direct dependency of mine.
And since this has that as a dependency this becomes an indirect dependency for me.
And in that one point three dot o maybe we want to try getting the latest version of that so we can
go see those different versions of that one right now.
And one of the ways we could see is we could just go to get hub and we could look it up.
We can start out at go dark actually.
And so we'll just work our way to their sampler and then go to get hub and at get hub we can look at
the different releases.
And so right now I'm on release version one point three point 0.
There's also one point nine nine point nine nine.
And also one point three point one.
And so we have a couple of other versions so if I ask it to go get the latest version we could see what
happens to our code base.
So right now I'm in the Girling project and I'm going to CDE into 0 3 and then in there I'm going to
see into 0 2 adding a dependency and if we look at that code in 0 2 adding dependency the code that
we have there is we're using quote Hello our seed Io quote and and when we run go test on that.
So make sure I'm in 0 2 I'm going to go test on 0 2.
Everything is working fine.
I just want to show you everything's working fine because now I'm going to use this code here go get
our seed audio sampler and it's going to go get by default.
The latest version just as if I had the latest here.
Right.
And so I could do it with latest or I could do it without I'm going to do it with just for fun.
See what happens just to prove the point.
And so it's going to get the latest version which means it's going to go and look at the releases the
latest version one is going to be one point nine nine nine nine.
So I'm going to hit do it.
It's going to do it.
And if I do a go list dash I'm Dashiell dash them all.
I now have version one point nine nine nine nine.
And now if I do my go test like I upgraded my dependency my indirect dependency and it broke the code.
So now I could specify an exact dependency and maybe if I roll it back from 1 9 9 2 1 3 1 it will work.
And so to do that I'm going to use this one right here.
Go get.
And then at version one point three point one.
So I'm going to run that and it brings down a different version.
And now if I go list my versions I've got version one point three point one.
And if I do my go test my test passes.
So originally I started out not with one point three point one I started out with one point three point
zero I went to the latest.
By doing that go get latest.
Right.
And by default I could have just its latest by default I could just put that in and it brought down
the latest version and then when that didn't work it failed right.
I said Hey go get version one point three point one.
Let's see if that works and I got that.
And then it passed my test.
So I ended up at one point three point one and I started at one point three point zero but the main
thing that you're taking away from this video is you could specify an exact version version one point
three point one and the other main thing you're taking away from this video is that I go to get or wherever
you're getting your modules your packages your code from and you can look at the different versions
if that module that package I'm using module package interchangeably.
Right.
I need it.
We need to load terminologies disintegration which we're going to do it in this video but you can go.
Let me just finish this point and go and if it's been well done you could see the different versions
you could see what you're getting.
I hope this is becoming clear it's definitely becoming more clear to me this is newer territory for
me modules is new and so it's great to be able to figure this out with another friend to help me learn
it also and in some of the main takeaways that stand out to me at this point is that the important thing
of like major version numbers are gonna be at their own your ell so you know V to v three v through
four it ends in those.
That's one of the main takeaways.
Another main takeaway is being able to see all of your direct and into direct dependencies with go list
dashing em all.
And another good takeaway is being able to specify with this dot with this app thing which version you're
bringing in and seeing what versions are available when you look at the repo.
So one more thing to note is the app that at you can do a version number you can also do the name of
a branch.
So if the person has more code they pushed but they haven't yet tagged it with a specific version number.
But you still want to get that latest stuff you can do at Master to get the absolute newest commit on
Master despite the fact that there's versions available.
Mm hmm.
Nice and now let's just do a moment of terminology disintegration between module and a package.
So a module is often aligned one to one with a get hub repo so one GitHub repo should have one module.
That's best practice and then a get have repo could have several packages and there we could have package
Hello package quote package string package print whatever packages.
And is it a best practice to have in one package for repo.
That seems kind of like if you're trying to get something for people use maybe a good idea.
Right.
Like if we look at this it depends.
You can almost consider packages within sub packages than repos to be more specific points of what you're
doing.
So for example the stripe repo to access stripes API.
They've got the top level package which is contains general code flight connecting those API.
But then they have sub packages for payment or saving credit cards or charging people think fees monthly.
So it's all related to connecting to the API.
But then more specific specifically you might need a sub package that has more stuff focused towards
this specific part of the API.
Okay.
So the terminology disambiguate given is a module could have many packages and and for a best practice
it doesn't necessarily mean that one module needs to have one package but just whatever makes sense.
Okay.
All right good.
So that's that's the next one is specifying a specific dependency version.
Any other thoughts.
Just at this 1 9 9 9 9 email the version number is rather ridiculous and most just there to kind of
prove that the version to have a high enough version number for this demonstration.
People do make mistakes the minor and patch versions are supposed to be backwards compatible but sometimes
they are not.
As you could see.
So this is user error.
If you find something like this go to their repo go to their issues tab and report it tell them about
it.
It's a problem.
And then go back use the stick version number or a specific or the app master if you need to and and
get your own code to good to a good spot.
Use your tests go tests are important because they want you quick.
They let us quickly and easily determine there was a problem with this version that was good stuff to
add.
Thank you.
Seeing the next video.