So now we're going to add a new major dependency and major dependency.
You know if you remember the the versioning.
We have major would be that one.
We have minor.
And then we have a patch.
And so with a new major version here like we have three versions of a package three major versions of
a package.
And this would be version one.
And then if his version two or version three or so on is going to be followed by a V to V Three.
And you could have one of each of these.
So you could have code from the first major version code from the second major version and code from
the third major version but you can have code from two like you know like major version one point six
and one point eight.
You can't have two minor versions or you can't have patches right.
One of each of these.
And so having one of each of those allows you to upgrade incrementally and upgrading incrementally means
that you know maybe you're using one version too came out well you could still use some of the code
from one you could still use some of the code and you could use some of the code from two.
And so here our code is going to change and we'll have our CIO quote and then we're gonna ask CIO quote
version 3 and we're going to import that with an alias of quote version 3 and we're going to be able
to call this proverb function and some proverb is pulling quote version 3 concurrency proverb and and
then that's coming from you know version 3 whereas this right here our CIO quote is bringing in this
one right here quote.
Hello.
So we're pulling from Version 1 and from version 3.
And so you could get different major versions and pull code from each which allows you to upgrade incrementally
and then we added a test for the proverb.
So that's the idea with the code and to see that in action.
Do you have something you'd like to add to that.
No to see that in action.
We've already created that code base here it's a 0 3 add a major dependency.
So I'm just going to navigate there on my terminal take a look at working directory see where I am and
go into S.D. 0 0 3 modules and then 0 3 add major dependency and then come back and do me just bring
this down a little bit.
So you could see the commands as I do.
Do you go test.
So I'm testing that code at all passes I could do a cat to see what's in my go mod file but I have to
come up a level and there and be right there and I could see now that I've got our AC quote version
one point five two.
And we also have our AC Io quote version 3 and that's the version three point one point zero and then
the one that we specifically specified in the previous video was our CIO sampler version one point three
point one which we still have here as one of our indirect dependencies.
And so that's doing the CATCo mod and we can also see all of those by doing goalless dash them all.
And also here's an interesting little notation that you could use if you wanted to see just are a C
Io quote right.
What are those that my module depends upon either directly or indirectly and it will show you OK.
Anything to say.
No no I got it all yes.
All right.
So that's that's adding a new major dependency.