So now we're going to finish the upgrade.
So you should you while you can have two major versions of the same module at the same time in your
code it's probably not a good idea to keep it that way because they're not really compatible with each
other very much.
Sometimes they can be but not often.
And so you should probably finish your upgrade as soon as you can.
It also means less that needs to be downloaded.
When you're trying to download all these dependencies for the module so to finish the upgrade we removed
the quote version one import which said the version 3 because we only have the one we got rid of the
alias because it means you don't have to remove the Alias.
It works if you keep it around.
But it was nice.
Is simple enough to remove the alias.
So now quote quote quote grunts appearances still.
And now Quote v V3.
So hello.
Got renamed to Hello v 3 as opposed to Hello.
That was the breaking chain that backwards incompatible between the major versions.
So you can see this by running go dark RCD slash quote slash the three.
You can see the list of all the functions that this particular package has.
No this is package not a module.
And so this particular package has a below B3.
So that was your backwards compatible change so to make this upgrade had to rename the the function
here where you're calling it.
So now that changes are made you can run go test and it's in passing still like that.
The Go Doc shows you the documentation you can drop.
Go Doc and then put in the the path too.
I would have normally say repo but we could also say module here you're right.
So go doc takes the path to a package specific.
Okay so if there was a sub package of RC quote V3 slash something else you would have to put that entirely
right.
Yes.
Finding the right terminology there and go doc is you go doc takes in a package and if we wanted to
see that we could still just use your computer we could do.
Go help see the documentation on that.
Just go help Doc even and avoid that one step and then in there we could see this budget example go
doc Fu show documentation for food in the current package.
So that's a function.
You can do good doc shows your current package go doc and then something in your package shows something
in there.
Or go doc for some other package like standard library you can do it and then you can use.
Also use that would be for documentation method.
Yep.
So just says the F I go back to that I go doc RC quote The three ESB all these and then I can do dot.
Hello.
The three it was and then it gives me the documentation specifically for that function with nice.
The other question I just had about go Doc there is wouldn't work.
We did go doc quote because that's the name we're referring to the package um is kind of curious.
Some to try simply and so that didn't bring out the same ones so that's something different.
That's probably what the version one and if we do the go list dash cam all this shows us in our mod
file our mod file it shows us our dependencies and we have two quotes there.
So maybe in the next video after we've cleaned up because we could no longer use using version one point
five point two of our seat out Io quote right we're only using version 3 now maybe in the next video
we're gonna clean up our dependencies and then after that if we ran good out quote quote It would pull
in the version 3 maybe I don't see.
All right.
See in the next video where we're gonna do removing any unused dependencies do you have anything you
want to add to this video.
Just that this go dark band is the exact same stuff as the go dark web site.
Gets.
Yeah.
So if I actually went to if I actually took in our CIO quote v three to the go dark web site it would
give me all the same information.
All right see the next video.