So removing unused dependencies is going to be a little bit tricky because we have those dependencies
are still used in other folders.
So we almost have to create another repo and kind of throw it all in there and then go through the whole
process.
So let's do that.
I'll lead the charge you ready.
OK.
All right.
So this is throwing all caution to the wind here and here's the situation because we want to show how
to remove all unused dependencies.
And Daniel are you current on GitHub if you pushed everything.
Yes.
And so he's pulled in now get get status and let's add that that's my works.
That's fine.
So that's your name.
So you don't need that so I'm going to pull everything down get pull and already up today.
And so if I do that go Liz dash em all go list dash em all.
I could see our dependencies and for our most recent version of the code base which was 0 4 here.
And if we look at Hello we are all Hello we are only importing a CIO quote version 3 and we are no longer
using RCI quote version one point five two.
In this example but because we're keeping this in a hierarchical structure we're saying look here's
the first step.
Here's the next step here.
We're still using those other versions in these other steps.
So to kind of fully illustrate how you clean up your code base I'm going to create a new get hub repo.
I'm going to go through some of these steps right here.
Get those packages that I need in earlier steps.
Go to the later steps and then I'll no longer need those earlier packages.
And then we'll clean it all up in the way you clean it all up is you just do go mod tidy and go mod
titles get and pull everything out.
So let's just look at that right now.
Because when I do go list dash I'm all right now.
Here are my dependencies.
And then we're gonna run go mod tidy and we're gonna see if anything changes between those and so I
went from one two three four five six to one two three four five six so exactly the same because those
dependencies are still needed in these previous examples.
So to see that get cleaned up from this point forward in the video maybe you got everything you need
from this video which is great.
All it is is go mod tidy.
So that's what it does.
But to see it in action we're going to quickly kind of walk through those previous examples again.
And also you're going to see just creating a get hub account all of that once more.
So I'm going to go in here and create a new hub account a new repository.
Sorry and that new repository I'm going to call it go modules example.
Actually I just found out you can create a goldmine here.
So for Yeah it's Dublin.
All right.
Make sure you take a lead.
Show us what you discover.
So.
So what I did was I ran go mod in it inside the 0 4 folder with the full namespace down including the
sub the sub folder packages.
And so that created a go mod file here in this sub folder.
So this in this folder is now a sub is now a module in and of itself separate from this go mod outside
this etc. from the go.
So it's keeping track of all the dependencies and everything it's software.
Just this one folder.
And so this got the quote v 3 in there by itself.
So if I if I roll the code back roll the claim back to what Scott
Robert would back to the courthouse today.
Go.
Test
so there's still work to do.
Go let's go.
I've got that.
So you're going this way.
Oh so this one also includes the indirect tab dependencies like text and sampler.
You got one point five two and three point one zero major minor patch.
Yep.
So now if I then read re re re upgrade this to the v 3 only go test to make sure it's still all working
go list.
Dash and all so you can see those.
It's got all the dependencies including it still has this one even though this is no longer in use anywhere.
So now there's a go mod tidy cleans it all up.
So now if I go this dash and all the version one is no longer there.
Yes awesome genius.
So and then as we were discussing last video you go dark R S C I O slash quote.
It's this version.
This is.
Nope.
That's still a pretty one I still version one.
And so if I just do what if I just do quote that's again still the spiritual version you to quote slash
v 3.
Interesting.
All right.
So yeah.
Good to know.
Yeah.
All right.
Well I think that was clear enough with go mod tidy.
That was the point of the video was to see Argo muddy muddy how go mod tidy works to go mod tidy.
Also has another side effect too.
If there is a dependency that only work is required on a particular OS or architecture so say there
some package it's only imported on Linux for example go mod tidy will add it to the go mod file even
though I may be on windows and so different actually downloads and runs it thanks.
So if you're on Windows you run go mod tidy and something is needed for this to run on Linux.
It adds to the code base it adds to the game and files dependency list and and then if somebody was
to down load your your packages your module and they're on Linux then have everything need it.
OK cool.
So yeah so go my tidy tidy that up to the smallest complete list of dependencies for all platforms.
Thanks.