So we've put a fair bit of basic functionality into this project.
We have excellent access to the database, we have caching, we have sessions, we have mail, we have
all sorts of functionality.
And even if we went no further, you'd have a great starter module you could use for every new project
you begin.
And with one command, you have a lot of the core functionality that you need, including user authentication.
But there's lots we could add to this.
And right now, I'm looking at the Laravel site and I'm looking, for example, at the file storage.
And this is a really useful function you find in Laravel that allows you to write to an FTP server or
to an Amazon S3 bucket and all sorts of file systems.
And we could duplicate that or actually improve upon that pretty easily, simply by including a package
like this.
Viant AIFS And if you scroll to the very bottom of this module, which you can import right into a go
project, you can see that you have lots of different file systems you can write to so you can write
to file in memory CPP or SSA to web servers.
TERS, IWC and it would be really simple to implement this and add this functionality.
And of course, there's other things as well.
Laravel jumps through some rather serious hoops in order to implement web sockets pretty easily, and
they call it broadcasting an echo and things like that.
And of course, this is relatively simple to implement in Go.
And in fact, I have a course on web sockets up on Udemy already, but adding that functionality would
make our project ever so much more useful.
In the same way, Laravel has great testing functionality.
Now we've already written some tests, and you see it's relatively straightforward to testing and go.
But one thing they do have is something called Laravel Dusk, which is browser based testing, which
actually takes a snapshot of the web page when you encounter an error.
And I've already written code that implements this functionality in Go, and it would be relatively
straightforward to add this to our project as well.
And finally, Q's and this is just an overview of the sorts of things we could add to this in the future,
because Laravel is written and it doesn't handle parallel tasks or synchronous tasks and very well.
That's the nature of PHP, and you can do it.
It's just a lot of work and it's error prone, whereas go with go routines handles this sort of thing
right out of the box so that a lot of cases you don't actually need to implement queues.
But in some cases you do.
You need to connect to rabbit MQ or something like that.
And that, again, is the sort of functionality that would be convenient to have in celebrities, and
we could add that easily enough.
Now I'm already planning a follow up course to this one, and if there's enough interest in this course,
I'll actually do it.
That will add at least this functionality and more as well.
But in any case, this is just a suggestion to point you in a few directions if you want to expand on
the code base on your own.
All right.
Take care.