In this section of the course.
We'll continue with the code that we worked on in the last section, but we'll take care of the handlers
that actually allow a user to subscribe to a plan.
And here's where we're going to add some actual concurrency, more sophisticated concurrency to our
code base.
So what we're going to do, we're going to write a handler that fires off a couple of go routines.
One will generate an invoice and we'll just write a simple stub handler that generates a dummy invoice
because that's not important for what we're doing in this course.
But that will run in the background and we'll also have another go routine fired off that will open
a PDF file, say a user manual.
We're going to assume that when you buy a plan from this service, you get a customized user manual
sent you as a PDF.
So we'll open an existing PDF and we'll modify it, save that PDF and then send it off to the user as
an attachment.
And these things will run concurrently.
And of course we will also subscribe a user to a plan.
So let's get started.