Okay.
So this time around we need to work on is this handler subscribe to plan and this is the one that fires
when someone clicks on the select button next to a plan on the plans page.
And my first comment says get the idea of the plan that is chosen.
But if you think it through, that's not really the first thing I have to do.
I actually have to do the same thing I do down here in choose subscription, which is to make sure that
the user's authenticated.
Now, I could copy this and paste this up here and that would work fine, but I'm doing this twice now.
It might be simpler to go back to middleware, this file over here, middleware ago and just write a
little bit of middleware and then we can apply that middleware to any route we want to protect.
And it's very, very simple to do.
So I would declare a function with the receiver of app pointer to config, not channel config.
And I'll just call this one off and it's middleware so it takes a parameter next HTP dot handler.
And it returns and htp to our handler.
Okay.
Now, what I'm going to do is I need access because of what I want to do is check the session to see
if that off I.D. key exists in the session.
So do make that happen.
I need to return an HGTV dot.
Handler.
Funk handler.
Funk right there.
And then give it a function with with the response writer because I need access to some of this stuff
and the request request.
Okay.
And inside of this, I can do the session check if not.
And from the receiver app session.
Dot exists and we need to give it the context, which is why I had to wrap everything in this return
statement.
Asked context and I'm looking for a user ID like that and that doesn't exist unless redirect the user
after session got put their spell session.
Right got put.
And we're going to put using our act context and we'll put an error message log in first.
So that's in the session now.
Now we just do a redirect, htp dot redirect with W and our to the login page and say you repeat on
status temporary redirect and we return otherwise outside of this if statement, we just go to the next
in the chain.
If any next dot serve HDP with w inter.
Okay, so we have this middleware now let's go use it.
So go to our routes file and what I'll do is create another function below this one that I'll mount
as its own router func app pointer to config.
And I'll call this one authorizer and it takes no arguments, but it returns an HGTV dot handler.
And inside of here I'll say create a new router.
Max is key.
Assign the value of key dot new router.
And for this particular router, I'll use the authentication middleware maxed out use and it's capped
off.
And now I put in the rights that I want and of course that's these two.
So let's get these out of here.
We'll have to make one more change after this.
And I'll paste these right here, and then I'll return Mark's.
And then up here just before the return statement, I'll say muck stock mount and mount that river and
what to mount, but it has to have a prefix.
So I call it slash members.
Only members can see these pages and we use apt author.
Okay.
That means that the URL slash plans is now slash members slash plants.
So let's go fix that in the name of BR.
So now burn up herschel.
Don't go HTML.
We just change this to slash members slash plans.
And the other thing is going to have to change of course is on the plans page.
Our location dot trip here in the JavaScript section at the bottom of plans dot page dot html.
This becomes slash members slash subscribe.
Okay.
So I think that is a little cleaner.
Now we can put any route that you have to be authenticated for in its own router.
Okay.
And then a couple of ways to do this.
But this works.
Now let's go back to our handlers.
That means here in show subscription, I can just remove this entirely because that's all handled by
the middleware now.
Okay.
And up here, I don't need to do anything to make sure that this is actually secure, that you have
to be authenticated to see it, because that's all taken care of by the middleware.
So let's get started with the first three of these things.
Okay.
Now, when we finished this code in this lecture, we won't be able to compile it because we'll have
variables we haven't used.
But we'll we'll take care of that in subsequent lectures.
So, number one, let's get the ID of the plan that is to be chosen.
And of course, that's trivial.
We'll say it is a sign the value of our URL, the query don't get.
And I want to get it.
Like that.
And of course, I want to use that ID to look up the plan in the database.
So let's convert it to an integer plan ID and I'll ignore the error.
And you probably shouldn't, but I'm going to assign the value of from the start conf package alpha
to integer a2.
Ah, and we can do it.
So now I have the plan B, I want to get the plan from the database.
I know how to do that.
That's trivial.
Now plan an error come from calling app dot models.
The plan don't get won by ID and that's plan I.D..
Okay.
Now I have the plan.
We'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll just copy what we have up here and change it as necessary.
Paste that in there and just say unable to find plan.
Okay.
And we're going to go back to the slash members slash plant.
Now I have the plan.
So let's get the user from the session and that's pretty easy as well.
User and OC come from calling app dot session dot.
Get using icon text.
The key I want is user and I'm going to cast it to a data user.
Okay.
If not, okay.
Now we can't get the user from the session, so we'll just copy this and paste this.
And this time I'll take them to the login page because if I can't get the user.
Chances are they're not logged in.
And we'll just say log that again, log in first with an exclamation mark and get rid of the period.
Okay.
So now I have the plan, ID the plan and the user.
So as I said, we can't compile the code right now, but we've got the first three things done and we've
simplified protecting pages to ensure that users users are authenticated before they can see it.
So in the next lecture, we'll move on to generating an invoice and sending an email.
Okay, so let's move on.