So the next step in our process is to generate an invoice and send that invoice to the consumer, to
whoever bought our plan.
Now, I have a comment here that says Generate an invoice, and then I have a comment that says send
an email with the invoice attached.
But let's simplify this.
In an actual production environment where we're selling real things, we'd have to calculate tax and
there's all sorts of things we'd have to do.
So we'll just simulate that.
We'll just generate a simple email and send it, but we'll format the code in such a way that you actually
might be calling some invoicing service or generating a rather complex invoice.
But in our case, we'll just say, generate an invoice and email it.
Okay.
So to make that happen, I'm going to make this run in the background.
I want this to happen concurrently.
So what's the very first thing I need to do?
Well, if you think it through, I need to add one to the weight group.
That's part of the config variable that we have as the receiver to this function.
So app dot and we'll wait dot, add one.
Okay.
And then we'll create a function, an inline function like this func and we'll close off key function
with its parentheses and we'll pretend the word go to that thing to make that run in the background.
Okay.
Now, the next thing I have to do, since I've added one to the weight group, is when this function
is done.
Let's decrement that weight group.
So defer app weight.
Try that again.
Weight got done.
All right, now let's generate the invoice.
So what we'll do is will call a function that doesn't exist yet.
Then we'll go make a really simple function.
So invoice will be the invoice for creating an error or come from calling a function that doesn't exist
yet.
App dot get invoice and we'll have handed the two things you would need to create an invoice, the user
and the plan.
Okay.
And we check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Well, what do we do at this point?
This is running in the background.
We have an error, but we have no means of getting that error back.
So what we might want to do here is send this to a channel.
But what channel do we want to Cynthia send the error to?
It seems to me that this is a really good opportunity to go over to our file config, go in, add a
couple of channels here, kind of centralized channels for error handling.
So we'll create one called error channel and that's a type channel error.
We'll create another one called Error Chan Dun Chan Mo.
Okay, so let's save that.
Now we've created these, but these don't exist yet.
So we need to go over to Main Go and at the very top where we create our configuration once and those
two channels and we can add them just as easily as this error.
Chan That's going to be make Chan error and then error chan done is make Chan bool.
Okay.
So those are created right now, but we still need to listen for errors.
So let's go down here just outside of this main function and create a new function with the receiver
of app pointer to config.
And we'll call this function listen for errors,
okay?
And it takes no parameters and it simply runs in the background.
We'll call it momentarily with a select statement inside an endless for loop select.
And our first case will be getting an error which is assigned a value when anything comes into after
error chain.
Okay.
So that's our case.
What are we going to do with the error?
Now, here's where you do something like notifying a Slack channel or sending a text or writing it to
the database, whatever you want.
But all we need to do for our purposes is apt error log.
Dot print line and the error.
Okay, so that's one case.
The second case will be we're done.
We get anything from app dot error can done.
And what are we going to do in that case?
Return.
Get out of this function.
Okay, so we have this function now, so let's listen for it.
We'll simply say listen for errors
and we'll say go app.
Listen for errors there.
The next time we start it up, that will run.
Now, is there anything else we need to do?
Well, of course there is.
We need to close things down when we're finished.
Let's find that function where we're shutting things down right here.
Okay.
So we're closing one channel here or telling the application it's done.
So let's say app error channel done.
It's a true.
And then down here, we'll close it close after error chain and close after error done.
Okay.
So now we have that.
So let's go back to our handlers.
And now that we have this, we can replace this comment with after error can get sent here.
Okay.
So we still don't have our invoice function.
Let's write that up and then we'll worry about sending the actual email.
And this is just a dummy function func with the receiver of app pointer to config and we're going to
call this get invoice and it's going to take two parameters.
View of type data dot user.
And plan, which is a pointer to dated our plan.
Now, here's where you do the heavy lifting in a production application.
But all we want to do is to generate some kind of content to send the information back to the user in
an email.
So all I'm going to do is return a string.
So string and we'll build a string and we'll say return.
And all I'm going to do is, is return the actual price of the plan.
So plan dot, plot, amount, format.
Okay.
And you might be building a much more complex invoice here, but this is sufficient for our purposes.
So you see, we're checking for an invoice and an error.
So we've been able to just do this here.
We're checking for a string and an error.
So this has to return that.
And here we return a nil.
Okay.
And in an actual complex function that's doing all sorts of math, you might be trapping for errors.
So this is just a kind of a dummy function.
But in any case, we now have the invoice up here.
So the next step is to send the email.
So let's create a message and it's a type message and we're going to specify two and that's user email
subject.
Your invoice.
Data will be invoice, which is just a string, just the formatted price of the of the actual invoice.
And then they want to specify a custom template because we don't want to use the default template.
Okay.
So the template here is going to be say invoice.
And then we'd send that.
We'll have to create that invoice in a moment and it'll be very simple.
But now we can just say app dot, send email and hand it and you.
Okay, so let's go create the simple templates.
So in inside the templates folder, I create a new file which I'll call invoice dot HCM and I'll go
to HTML and I'll create another one again, another one called invoice.
Start playing dot and go HTML, make sure you spell those right or this won't work.
So to save a little time, I'll copy the existing mail.
Dot html, dot HTML and I'll paste that into invoice html dot go html.
I'll just changes to say your invoice and then it'll put the actual price there.
And of course this would be formatted with all the appropriate information for a real invoice.
And I'll do the same thing for the plain text.
A copy mailed up plain Doug go html copy that pasted in the invoice dot plain go HTML right there and
change this to your invoice and we'll all pretend there's some complicated invoice in there.
Okay.
So if we go back to our handler now, there should be no error.
The next step and this one will be a little bit tougher is to generate a PDF manual.
And what we'll do is we'll just take a simple PDF file and we'll open it up in go code.
We'll write some information to it and we'll send the changed version of that as an attachment to our
end user, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.