Okay.
So now we're sending on an email with a rather simplistic invoice, and the next step is to generate
a manual.
And as I said in the last lecture, this one's a little more complex, but it's not that difficult.
We actually want to open an existing PDF, write some information to it, and then send that PDF to
the user.
Now there's many ways to write PDFs in Go or in any other language you can use a service.
The one that I like to use is this one.
We have to go get a couple of packages, so let's open your terminal and make sure you're at the root
level of your project and go and get and I'm going to paste it in because I have it on my clipboard
github dot com slash p hp dave one one slash go f pdf go get that.
And this is a library that allows us to write PDF files.
Okay, then I'm going to hit the up arrow and get a second one and this is the same URL.
And then at the end I add slash contrib for contribution slash go f p d.
All right.
So one is a library that allows us to create a PDF and the second one is one that allows us to open
an existing PDF and use that as a template.
And of course, that's what we're going to do.
So I have those libraries installed now.
That means I have access to them.
So back in handler's dot go in the handler we're working on right now, the one that subscribes the
user to a plan.
The next step, of course, is to actually go and generate that PDF.
Now we need one to work with.
If you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a PDF file you can download.
And it's not terribly exciting, but it's an example of just a PDF that we can open and work on.
So it's called Manual Dot PDF and put it as I have at the root level of your project in a folder called
PDF.
So inside of pdf I have manual dot pdf.
Okay, very simple file and we'll be seeing it before too long.
So right after this go funk that we worked on last time, let's just write another go funk.
Now, I could and I'm sure that you've already noticed this.
I could have taken all of that logic right here in this first go funk, where I defer and I create an
invoice and then do an email.
I could have put all of that into a function, but I didn't.
And that was entirely a decision on my point, because I'm going to assume that get invoice is its own
functionality and has a lot more logic in it than just returning a string.
So we'll do the same thing here for manuals.
So once again, I need to update my weight group by adding one to it.
So after wait, don't add add one again.
I'm just doing one thing.
And then inside of this, of course, I want to defer app.
Don't wait.
Not done.
Okay.
And then make sure that my weight group is updated appropriately.
And inside of this is pretty straightforward.
So the first thing I'm going to do is get a PDF.
When I call a function that doesn't exist yet.
App dot and we're going to generate a menu.
Okay.
And once again, to generate a manual, I'm probably going to need the user and I'm probably going to
need to plan.
So this function doesn't exist.
So just like we did last time, let's come down here and work on this function before we do anything
else.
Funk app with a receiver of pointer to config and this one is called generate manual and it takes you
which is a type data point user and plan which is app type pointer to data plan.
And it's going to return a pointer to make sure you get this typed right.
Go f pdf dot and the one I want is actually called f pdaf right there.
Okay.
So that did the import for me.
And now inside of this function, what we're going to do is define a PDF, set its size and its margins
and things like that.
So let's create a variable called PO and that comes from go f pdf which I find really hard to type dot
new and I'll specify a few things about it.
It's in portrait, okay?
And it's going to be we're going to count things in millimeters.
It's letter sized paper.
And the last parameter I'm going to leave empty is unimportant for our purposes.
Okay.
Both pdf i do find that hard to type.
Go f pdf.
That's better.
Okay.
We have that now.
We'll set some margins, pdf dot set margins and I'll set them to reasonable defaults.
Okay.
Ten, 13 and ten.
And those are all in millimeters because that's how we're measuring things.
Now I want to import an existing PDF so I'll create an importer.
It's just a variable name I'm choosing right now and that's a sign.
The value of this one is go fp d i dot new importer right there.
Okay.
And it takes no parameters.
So we have an importer variable.
Now I'm going to simulate the amount of time it might take to actually create a PDF.
You have a really complex PDF and you're doing a lot of substitutions and maybe some math.
It might take a second or two to produce this.
So just to give us a little simulation of a complex task for sleep for ten.
No, five times timed out second.
So I'll make this take 5 seconds.
Okay.
So we have our importer.
Now I'm going to create a variable T, which I'll think of as template, and that comes from importer
dot import a page.
Importer dot import page right there.
Into PDF.
That's my first argument.
And then the location of that page.
Well, it's in a dot slash pdf slash menu dot pdf.
That's the one I want to import.
Okay, not finished.
There's another parameter which is one page number one.
And the last one is the.
The box and this is weird, but this is because we're working with PDFs and they have their own logic.
We need to call it Media Box with a capital M and a capital B.
Can I have this T?
And it looks like I have a typo there somewhere.
Which pdf did it import for me?
Okay.
So it's not that one did the wrong import for me.
I have multiple versions of this imported.
You shouldn't contrib slash go fp the.
And go f pd f slash contrib slash and go a pdf there.
Okay.
Probably you didn't have that multiple versions of go FPI installed, but I've been working with it
for a long time and that was an over.
So this is the correct one.
Now let's get back down to our function right here.
So I now have my importer and my T is my template I'm going to be working with.
So the next step is to add a page to our new PDF variable.
So it's simple enough PDF to add page and page right there.
So now we have one page in there.
And now we tell it to use the imported template for that page.
So we'll say importer
dot use imported template right there.
Using PDF with a variable t, we just created an zero and zero and 215.9.
This is just getting it centered on the page proper.
So those are the dimensions that those are the coordinates we're going to put it on.
Okay.
So now we've imported that, that template manual dot PDF that we just write on top of it.
So I'll say PDF and I set my X and y coordinates and you do this again, set x, you do this by getting
it a ruler and measuring where you want something to appear on the page.
So I've done that for you.
X should be 75 pdf to set.
Y should be 150.
Okay.
And now I can do things like setting the font, so I'll just choose one that I'm pretty sure is installed
on every computer out there.
PDF to set font.
And I'm going to choose the font.
Arial and it's not going to be bold or italics.
So I leave that empty and I'll make the point size 12.
Okay, so I now have a font and now I just write things.
So the syntax is a little awkward for this if you've never worked with it before, but it does make
sense.
PDF to multi.
So we want to write a cell that may span multiple lines.
Zero is the first parameter, four is the spacing, so the first one was the width zero.
Just figure out how why you need to be on your own.
Four is the spacing between lines.
And then I put string to I want to put there.
So I'll put the user's name format or s print s s print F and I format string is percent s and space
percent s and then I get the users first name and last name.
So you got first name and you don't last name.
Okay.
So that's the, the, the string that I want printed.
I want nothing else applied to it.
I want to center it.
You can use L for left C for center R for right and false.
Don't apply any shading to this.
So okay, so we have that now.
I'll print a blank line pdf dot l n and it does require some kind of argument so I'll make five five.
Mm.
That's a good space and then I'll print another one.
PDF.
Multi cell.
Multi cell again with zero and four.
And this time I'll just print out the name of the user guide.
So again, use format s print f.
Now my format string is percent s space user guide, not guild guide and the same for the last thing.
Nothing C and no shading.
Okay.
And then I return the pdf.
So now I have my pdf constructed and I received it and the variable up here.
Now I'll just write it to a file so I'll write it to a temporary folder at the root level of my application
and I'll have to create that folder, but I'll do that in a moment.
So we'll just say error is a sign the value of pdf dot output file and close.
Okay.
And we're going to print it with a specific name format, sprint F and I'm going to use a format string
of dot slash, temp slash.
Then percent d which will be the ID of this user underscore manual dot pdf.
That way you know you're never going to have one user generating two manuals at the same instant.
So this way I know that by pretending at the user I.D. at the beginning of this file name, that it
actually won't overwrite somebody else's file.
And my substitution for that is user id.
Okay.
So we check for an error if errors not equal to nil.
And now we have somewhere to send this error.
We just go to app dot error channel and that receives here.
I don't want to go any further, so I'll return.
Okay.
But if that all works according to plan, then let's create a message.
MSG is a sign the value that again, MSG is a sign the value of type message.
We'll fill in and fill in its necessary fields.
Okay.
So two will be user dot email.
Same as before.
Subject will be your manuals manual.
Okay.
The data will be, just say your user manual is attached and then I want to add an attachment.
Now I just wrote a PDF file named in the case of this user.
One underscore manual dot pdf, which is great for my purposes, but it would be more useful if I could
actually attach that message or attach this file to that message and just call it manual dot pdf.
Now I could, you know, split on the underscore and hope for the best, but let's go back over to our
mailer for a minute.
Let's fix this so we can actually embed attachments in an email with a custom name.
And let's also take care of something that was a bit of an oversight when I wrote this a while ago.
So, first of all, let's go to the top of this file.
And in this type message, we have attachments.
Let's put in another one called Attachments Map, because sometimes you want to attach something and
override the name.
So attachment, I think it's singular.
So it's closer to the other attachment map and that's going to be a map with a key of string and a value
of string.
Okay, so let's save that.
So we have this type.
This is going to allow me to construct a map with two pieces of string information.
One is the key and one is the value.
And this allows me to take advantage of a second way of actually embedding attachments in an email message.
So let's go down to where we're attaching our our attachments, which is.
Right down here.
Okay.
And let's add another thing here.
If the length of MSG dot attachment map is greater than zero, if that map is not empty, then we'll
go to for another for loop.
In this case, we will want both the key and the value.
When we range through the MSG attachment map.
And it's very much it's very similar to how we add attachments right here.
But we actually do it like this.
Email it at attachment.
And we can actually give it the value, which is the physical name or the name of the physical file
stored somewhere.
And key is what we're going to call it when we add the attachment.
Okay.
Now, the only other situation we need to take into account here is if we're sending an email and that
map is not.
It doesn't exist.
It's just an unknown initialized map, and we'll get an error.
So we need to come back up here to the top and we can say if MSG dot attachment map equals nil.
Then msg attachment map equals make map string string.
Now I'm not sure I have to do that, but you know, it's not going to hurt to do this.
And I'm a built in suspenders kind of guy.
I just want to make sure that what I'm trying to arrange through a map, that it actually is an initialized
map, even if it's empty.
Okay.
So that's one thing.
Now, the other thing that I want to draw to your attention, and I'm sure at least some of you noticed
this when we're passing data to our email templates, we're actually not doing it in a very effective
way.
Okay.
To start with, what we're doing here is we're creating a map of string INI and storing message data
in it.
So basically, if when I'm sending an email, if I specify message data map to be something, I'm completely
overwriting that and that's not appropriate.
So instead, let's comment this up and we'll get rid of it in a minute.
Instead, we'll do it like this if the length of MSG data map is equal to zero.
Then try that again.
Put this parentheses where it belongs.
That makes a little more sense.
Then we'll create a data map.
So we'll say message data map is equal to make map string any.
Very similar to what I'm doing up here.
Okay.
Just making a an initialized empty string, and then I add down here, instead of overwriting everything,
I'll say message that data map with message that key which I have to spell.
Right.
That's better is equal to my short data.
That way I can have more than one thing in that map, and I can pass multiple bits of information of
any kind to a template.
And that was just sloppy coding on my part.
Quite a while ago now.
In any case, it's taken care of at the moment.
So let's go back to our handlers, and now we can add an actual attachment with the custom name.
Okay.
So we can say attachment map right there.
It's equal to the type map, string, string.
And we just populate one value in there and we'll say we're going to call this manual PDS.
That's what it's going to be named when we attach it.
And we're going to attach the same thing we have right here, format as print.
All of that.
So I can copy this pasted in here.
And it takes a column, not a comma and a comma at the end.
Okay, so now we have the message.
And now we'll say apt.
Send mail, send email, we'll send message.
And while we're at it, just test the errors charm.
Remember that that application wide error channel we had.
Let's say test app error champ.
Now we can do that just by saying app error can not get sent.
Errors dot new.
And that should do the import for me some custom error.
Okay.
So now we generated a manual.
So put this comment right up here where it needs to go.
So it's in the right place.
So if you look at our code now, when we get to this, this handler subscribe to plan.
First of all, we get the ID as a string.
We convert the idea of the plan the user is choosing to an integer.
Then we get the plan from the database by plan ID.
If we can't find that plan, we give them an error.
But assuming we get past that, we get the user from the session.
If we can't find the user in the session, that means somehow they went to this plan's page while they
were logged in.
Then maybe they walked away and had a coffee and went for a walk and took the dog inside, came back
inside.
Their session had timed out.
That's the only way you can get this error.
But whatever the case may be, we take them back to the login page if we've lost their session.
Then we add one of the weight group and we fire off a go routine that'll run very, very quickly.
In our case, that generates and emails an invoice.
And then we generate a manual again.
We add one to our weight group.
We decrement it with a defer thing here.
And we run this function in the background and that generates a PDF and emails it off to the user.
And then it has a little test of our error chain as well.
Okay, so what happens next?
Well, what happens next, of course, is we need to subscribe a user to account.
I'm going to skip that right now and I'm going to redirect let's do the redirect because that I can
do without any worry about populating your database with spurious information.
So we'll say after session dot put using our dot context and we'll put it in a flash message and we'll
say subscribed, which isn't true because we haven't actually subscribed yet, but we just want to see
if the PDF and email actually work.
And then we do a redirect issue of redirect using W in our to slash members, slash plans and hdp dot
status C other.
Okay.
So if everything goes according to plan, this should work.
The only thing I have to do now or it's not going to work is to come back to the root level of my application
and create a new folder called Temp Temp because we're going to be writing our PDFs to that temporary
directory.
Okay.
Now, we've written quite a bit of code since the last time we actually tried to run anything.
So undoubtedly there's a problem in there somewhere.
But in the next lecture, we'll try to fire things up and see if we got anything wrong.
Okay, let's move on.