All right.
We've written quite a bit of code since the last time we tried this, but let's fire up our application
and give it a try.
So I'll open my terminal window and I already have Docker running, so I'll type make start and that
should build it hopefully.
And it did and it started it up.
So let's go back over to our web browser and give this a try.
So I'll go to local host and that's so far so good.
I need to log in.
So let's log in as admin app example dot com with the password.
Very secret and I'll log in.
And now if I go to plans, I already have a plan I subscribed to some time ago when I manually entered
that information into the database.
But let's switch from bronze to silver.
Now, of course, it's not going to save the changes.
We haven't done that bit yet, but hopefully it will fire off two emails, one very quickly with an
invoice, a rather simplistic invoice, and then another one a few seconds later, because we put that
artificial delay in the should give me a manual and that manual should have my name and the name of
the plan put on the front page.
Let's see if it works.
So I'll click select and click subscribe.
So far, so good.
Let's go over to Mail Hog and there's my invoice.
Then there is my manual.
So my invoice looks like this with no dollar amounts in there.
So something's wrong with that.
We'll have to fix that.
And let's go back and try the manual.
My manual is attached.
If I go to the mine midterm here I should see a PDF and it's named a manual PDF and if I download that
then we have something missing there.
But at least it generated a manual.
So we're missing something in here and we're missing the invoice amount in the plan.
So let's go back to our code and see if we can find those two things.
Okay, so back to our code and we'll switch to the handlers right there.
And the first thing is it's not printing the amount on the invoice.
So let's see where we get that invoice.
An error is after and invoice, user and plan.
Do we actually have the plan?
So plan I.D., query, get I.D..
We should be passing an ID as a parameter with the plan ID after it.
Let's go look at the templates.
And find plans and make sure we're actually doing that.
Slash Members.
Slash Subscribe.
Question Mark idea equals that so far so good.
So ex.
And up here we're calling select plan with the ID and the plan name.
I'm not seeing anything there immediately.
Let's just go put a comment or a log in our handlers see what we're getting wrong here.
So let's put a log dot print line,
plan I.D. with plan ID and let's actually check for an error here.
Every time I say to myself, Yeah, I'm not going to bother checking for an error.
I always regret it later on, or I often do.
If error is not equal to nil, then.
After an error log dot print line
error getting plan with the error.
Okay, let's restart this and try that again.
So make restart.
There's one good thing we got this.
Some customer error passed to our centralized error handling channel.
So that's great.
But we still need to get these other things working.
So let's try this restarted.
Come back over to my web browser and I'll just choose a different plan.
So select this one again.
Subscribe.
Okay.
So we subscribed.
Let's go look at the error log.
We got plan I.D. and no error, so we know.
That's right.
So let's get rid of this.
No problem with that.
And his plan.
I'd put that in there.
So we're getting the plan.
Then we're getting the user from the database.
So here we're getting the invoice.
Let's see what that's doing down here.
Let's find that get invoice function.
It's.
And we'll say log line for after after info.
Log the line.
Amount is in the we'll go with plan the plan amount format it.
Let's run that again make restart.
An imported and not used law.
So we'll just save this.
That should fix that.
And restart this again and should compile.
Let's go back over here and choose the silver plan again and see if we actually get the currency amount.
Amount is nothing.
Okay, so there's something wrong with that.
Now let's figure out what that is.
We're actually getting the plan.
Up here when we call.
Top models to plan to get one.
Okay, so let's find that and see what's wrong with that one.
Oh, I'm actually not populating that field.
That would do it.
So people come in here and say, plan that plan I'm out formatted as equal to I'm out for display.
And that should take care of that.
So let's restart this make restart actually on that field in the type for plan.
But I never populated it in that function.
That's an easy mistake to make.
So we've restarted.
Let's select it again.
Subscribe.
Go back here, look at our console and we have $20.
So now when I go to my mail hog and look at the most recent invoice right here, $20.
Perfect.
Okay.
And what was the other problem?
So let's go back to the inbox.
Look at the manual.
Look at the mime, look at the application PDF, and we're missing something from the name there.
Okay, so let's go back to our code and find out where we're generating that string.
So I'll hide this in our handlers generating the manual.
It's not calls generate manual down here and I never put it put the actual substitution for this and
that should be from plan dot planning.
Okay, that should be it.
Let's try to restart this one more time.
So the web server is running.
Let's go back to Mail Hog and delete all the messages and we'll select silver one more time.
Subscribe.
And I will go watch Mail Hog.
And there's my manual.
And let's look at the source or the mine for that.
Admin user.
Silver.
Silver Plan.
User Guide.
Okay.
So little works.
So now now that I know that works, let's go over and actually subscribe a user to a plan.
And that's actually pretty easy.
So we'll subscribe user to a plan.
All I have to do now is say error is equal to and I'll call from app dot models.
Dot plan dot subscribing user to plan, and that requires a user and a pointer to a plan for the value
of the plan.
I'm taking it out of the pointer there.
Okay.
And we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll just copy some error checking up here.
This is fine.
We'll copy that.
Paste this down here and say error,
error, subscribing to plan.
And we're going to take them back to the slash numbers slash plan page, and that should be enough for
that one.
Now, we have subscribed this user to the plan, but remember, we have a user in the session and the
user in the session actually is still subscribed to the old plan.
If they changed one or two, no plan if they didn't have one.
So what I need to do next is to update the user in the session and we can do that pretty easily.
We just need to get a fresh copy from the database so you an error are assigned values by calling app
dot models dot user don't get one and we hand it the user ID and that's user ID.
The ID in the session hasn't changed and that's where we're getting user ID.
Okay.
So we'll copy this, paste this here for error, check error, getting user from database and get rid
of the two plan part.
Now that we have the new user, we just update it in session after session that put using marked context.
We're looking for user and we're going to put in youth.
Okay?
And in theory, this should all work.
So let's restart our application, make restart.
You can go back to my web browser and I'll get back to Mail Hog and delete all messages.
In this time.
Let me just reload this page to make sure everything is current.
I currently have the bronze plan.
When I click this, it should subscribe me to the silver plan and when this page refreshes.
This should say current plan and this should be a select button.
Let's see if it works.
And it works perfect.
Okay, so that's enough for this time around.
So in this section, we've managed to take a slightly more real world application and apply concurrency
to it.
And you might have noticed over here in the Handler that I'm actually firing off two separate go routines
and each of them fires off yet another go routine when it sends email.
Now, you might have been asking yourself, why didn't you just put all of this and all of this into
the same go routine?
And there's a simple reason for that.
This way, generating an invoice and generating a manual, they both run concurrently.
If I lost them together, they would run sequentially.
First of all, I would generate an invoice, and when that was done, then it would generate a manual.
Now, in our case, it's very fast to produce both both of the invoice and the manual, because, you
know, this is simplistic code and it's just an exercise to show you how how to make things run concurrently.
But in the real world, it might take a couple of seconds to do an invoice or a couple of seconds or
even more if it's a very complex PDF to generate a manual.
Let's say you're producing a manual for an API and you want all of the examples in the API to have code
that exactly reflects what that user would use.
So they're API key, all of that sort of thing.
Well, it can take quite a while to produce a PDF like that.
So this way I have them running at the same time.
Now the only situation where I couldn't do that is if I needed some information from the first go routine
in order to make the second go routine run.
But in this case, all I need is the user and the plan for both the manual and the invoice.
So there's no problem having these to run at the same time.
All right.
That's enough for this time around.
Let's move on to the next section.