So let's get started setting up our project structure, and right now I have a an empty window in visual
studio code open and I have no open folder.
So the first thing I want to do is open a folder that's going to hold both my package that will be building
and I'm calling mine celebrities and the actual application that uses that package rebuilding building.
So I'll go to the explorer and open a folder, and I've already created a folder inside a visual studio
projects called Go About.
So open that one.
And the very first thing I'll do here is open or create a new folder, and I'll have one for my package,
which I'll call silver and toss, and I'll have one for the application out there.
I want it at the root level inside of this folder, right beside Celebrity's House new folder.
And I'll just call this one of my app and the first folder celebrities will hold the package we're going
to build.
So it will be one that is imported by some other application.
And the other application in my case is the one called my app.
Now, the first thing I'll do is I'll open the terminal and I will go into the celebrities folder,
OK?
And inside of that, I'll initialize go modules, go in it, and I'm going to give this a useful repository
name.
And I suggest you do as well if you don't have an account on GitHub.
Then go create one or find your favorite git repository and use that.
So the name I'm going to give it is a name that doesn't exist yet on GitHub, but it will.
Before I'm done so I'll call mine GitHub dot com slash my username, which is T sa slash celebrities
so that initializes go modules for the celebrities package.
And of course, I have to do the same thing in my app go mode in it.
And this one, it doesn't matter what you call it, so I'll just call it my app.
There go modules for now initialized for both of these folders.
Of course, the problem is in my app, I want to import GitHub dot com slash t solar slash veritas,
which doesn't exist.
There's nothing on GitHub with that particular URL.
So what I'll do is open my app and open.
Go on the Gomaa file for that.
And at the bottom of that file, I'll Adeline and I'm going to say replace any time your you get a request
to go to this address GitHub dot com slash TESOL, or make sure you spell it right celerity.
And also make sure you're not using my URL.
Make your own anytime you get a request to get that package instead.
Go up one folder and use what you find in the celebrity's folder.
Now, any time I make that request, go get that URL, GitHub dot com slash TESOL or slash Solaris house
instead of going to GitHub.
It'll just take the contents of that folder and use it instead.
OK, so that's set up now.
There is one irritating thing about Visual Studio code as I record this lecture, and that is that you
can't have two projects open in the same window.
And that's no problem.
What I'll do instead is create a new window and I'll maximize it and I'll open a folder.
And the first one I'm going to open is that Solaris House one.
So in visual studio projects go Laravel Solaris House, I'll open that folder.
Now, let's create a go file in here, so I'll create a new file.
I'll just call it celerity up.
And of course, of course, it has a package name package celebrities.
And for right now, we're going to create a couple of test functions, so I'll create ones called funk.
I'll give it a capital letter.
So its export test funk.
And it takes, say, two.
It's a and B of type integer and it returns an integer.
And all I want to do is say return a plus B.
OK, so that exists now.
So now I'll open another window in visual studio code and I'll maximize it.
And I will open a folder, and this time I'll open the My App folder, so in visual studio projects
will lavell my app.
And I'll create a new file in there called May Not Go.
And of course, it's a package main.
And we'll give it a main function from Main, and I will open a terminal and I will say go get GitHub,
NJ.com, which I have to spell right slash TCR slash hilarious.
Perfect.
So it got it, and it got it from the local folder.
Now I'll call a function in that package and of course, there's only one.
So I will say the result is a sign the value of from the celebrity's package dot test funk and give
it to integers one and one.
And I'll say format, dot print line.
Result that we should be able to run this sit down on my terminal, I'll clear the screen and go run
dot, and it worked beautifully.
Now let's switch back to that Solaris horse window right here, and let's add a second function func
test funk too.
And again, it'll take two and A and B, and it returns an integer.
And of course, that has to have a type.
And I'll return a minus B.
Now, let's go back to our map window right here.
And let's try using that function.
So
now result is equal to celebrities, and you obviously doesn't see test too.
And that's a bit of a problem.
And the problem, of course, is that because we're using a package that's in a folder beside the Maya
folder, we have to go get that code base again every single time we update our code base in the solar
task folder.
So let me delete that line down on my terminal and say, go get GitHub icon slash solar slash celebrities
and hit return.
So now it's updated the code.
So in theory, I can come up here and say result is now equal to celebrities dot test, book two and
give it to things say two and want a visual studio code has still not updated.
But hopefully it will at some time.
Let's try this down here.
Let's say go get you GitHub dot com slash t solar slash celebrity.
Does that air go away?
No, it didn't.
And that's one of the irritating things about Visual Studio.
But we'll get this working right now.
Let's make sure our code runs.
We actually have to print that out, of course, format or print line result.
So let's see if it runs.
Go run dot and it runs beautifully.
It does exactly exactly what we want.
So what we want to do, of course, is to somehow force visual studio code to update when we want it
to.
So we don't get errors like this as working through this project, and that will be really kind of frustrating.
Now, if you're working with goal land or some other idea, this problem probably won't appear.
It doesn't.
When I use Goal Line, which is my editor of Choice.
In any case, what we're going to be using Visual Studio code in this course.
So we'll figure out how to make those errors go away and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.