So as you can see, after a very long time, my application realized that test funk too does in fact
exist in the celebrity's package, but that's going to be really irritating if I have to wait a long
time for errors to go away.
So let's make things a little bit simpler.
So right now, I'm in the My App project and I'm going to go to the terminal.
I'm going to type go mod vendor.
And what this will do is instead of fetching the repositories I'm using and just putting them where
it normally does, instead it will create a vendor folder.
So I'll put it return.
And if you look up here, we have a vendor folder now and inside of that it has a GitHub dot com folder.
And inside of that, there's one called Tischler, and there's this alerts package imported locally.
So what it's doing is keeping your local copy of everything that I'm building right here.
So things should be much faster.
So let's try it out.
Let's go back to the celebrities application and add a new function funk test funk three and it will
take two aunts and be it, and it will return in it.
This time, I'll return the product of those two eight times be OK.
So if I go back here now and type go mod vendor in the terminal again in my app go mod vendor, I should
go and get the new version of that, which means I should be able to come up here and type result equals
celebrities.
And there it is.
Test Funk three and it takes two things say two and two and I'll print them out.
Format dot print line result.
And if I run this now, go run dot, everything should work as expected and that is much better.
It means that I don't have to worry about errors hanging around in my code that aren't actually errors,
and that would get confusing in a hurry.
But it's kind of a pain to have to type go on vendor.
Every time I make a change to the celebrity's file, I want to run my code.
So instead, let's use a make file.
Now, if you look at the course resources for this lecture, you'll see two files you can download.
One is called Make Files Dot Mac, and if you're on a Macintosh or on Linux, that's the one you want.
Otherwise, there's one called Makefile Windows, and that's the one you want.
If you happen to be on windows, download that and open it up in your favorite text editor and copy
the contents and then create a new file at the root level of the My App directory called Make File with
a capital M. All one word.
OK, now I've already got a copy of that on my clipboard, so let me paste it in and I'll be showing
you the one for my Mac or Linux machine, but it's almost identical.
All the change you're going to have to make is very, very simple.
So this is the make file, and as you can see, it has these commands build, run, clean test, start
stop and then finally restart down here.
And the only change you're going to have to make is what you want to name the binary right here in line
one.
So I'm calling mine celerity app.
Now, if you're on windows, you might want to put you probably want to put Dot EMC at the end.
Otherwise, Windows might not run it for you.
But I'm on a Mac, so I'll just leave it as celerity desktop app.
And as you can see, when I say make run, if I type make run on the command line at the root level
of my project, it will run.
This puts on Line nine and it says Run.
But before you do that, run build.
So it goes up to build and right there it calls go on vendor for me.
OK, then it echoes some text, builds the binary and it's going to build binary name.
In my case, Solaris House app and then run will say, OK, start that up in the background.
So let's try.
So open the terminal window and it's going to run an exit because it's just printing to the terminal.
But this should work.
Make run.
It builds it.
And there it goes.
And that worked beautifully.
And of course, it's exit it now.
So things will be much simpler with this Makefile.
Over time, we'll be able to run our tests.
Know, obviously we don't have any tests at the moment, but we'll be able to do that.
We'll be able to start our applications, start, stop our application and life will be ever so much
simpler.
All right, let's move on.