OK, now that we have our basic project structure set up, let's get started writing some code.
So right now, I'm looking at the My App project, looking at Mango, and the first thing I'll do is
clear out all of these functions are these calls to functions because they're useless and I'll save
this or the import should go away and we have an empty main file.
In other words, package mean with the func meaning that does nothing.
Now let's switch over to our celerity this application that project and delete these three functions
because we're not going to use those.
Those are utterly useless.
So we're starting right from scratch.
And the very first thing I want to do is create a type and I'll call this type.
Not surprisingly, Solara tasks, and it's just a struct that's going to have quite a few members over
time for right now.
We'll start with really simple things app name.
What's my application called?
And that will be a string.
And then we'll have debug.
Are we working in development or are we working in production?
So that will be a Boolean if it's true.
We're working in debug mode or development mode, and I also put a version in the same version, which
is a string.
OK.
So there's a very simple type.
And of course, this will become more complex over time.
Now let's put a constant in here.
I'll put it right here.
Concert version is equal to one point zero point zero.
So now we have something we can put in this field right here version.
And I'll also create a function here with the receiver, see which is a pointer to celebrities.
And this will be called new, OK, and it's only going to take one parameter, which I'm going to call
route path.
And that will be the path that we are in when we start our application.
Where are we on the file system?
And that will just be a string, and all it's going to return is potentially an error.
OK, now there's quite a few things we want to do when someone calls the new function on the type celebrities.
We're going to want to create some folders or make sure the folders exist.
We're going to want to want to initialize the application.
We're going to want to do all kinds of things.
But for right now, let's make this as simple as we possibly can.
So what I'll do just to keep my code nice and modular, so it's easy to test is I'll create a new function
down here func with a pointer to the receiver of a pointer to celebrities.
And I'll call this one in it and it will take one parameter and it's going to be, I'll call it P,
and it's going to be a bit of a type that doesn't exist yet, which I'll call in it paths, and it will
potentially return an error.
Now what is in it, pat?
Let's go create the type that I'll talk about it.
So to create this type, I'm going to create a new file right beside celebrities, doggo.
And I'm going to call it type stucco.
And that's where I'm going to put it all of my types or most of my types.
And this has a package declaration package celebrities and I'll create a type in here called init paths.
And it's just a struct, and it only has two members root path.
What's the root path to this application, which is a string and I'll create one called folder names
the list of folders that I expect to be available to me, and that will be a slice of strings.
OK.
So we have that type created now, which means when I go back to celebrities, don't go in it, paths
that air went away.
Now what do I want to do in in pads?
Well, to start with, I want to get the root to the application, so I'll call that root.
And that's a sign the value of dot ridpath.
And that is now a string that holds the full path name to the root level of my web app of my application.
Now I want to go through the list of folders in that slice of strings, in the type init paths and make
sure those folders exist and create them if they don't.
So I'll just say four and I don't care about the index, but I do care about the individual entry,
which I'll call path.
Those are assigned the values of ranging through peaked folder names.
And what I want to do here is create the folder if it doesn't exist.
OK, now I can put all of the code right in here, but this is actually the sort of thing you're going
to want to do a lot of the time.
So I may as well make that available function.
So I'll create a new file and I'll just call it helper stucco.
And again, that's in package celebrities, and I'll create a function here and something as simple
as this.
So func with the receiver see pointer to celebrities create dear if not exist, and it takes one parameter
path, which is a string and it returns potentially an error.
And we just use the standard mode of creating.
Directories in GO and its principles are but a constant here mode is equal to say, zero seven five
five, which will be good for our purposes, and we just do a simple check to create the folder if it
doesn't exist.
So if we don't care about the first return parameter, but we do care about the error, those are assigned
the value of OS x stat.
Hopefully it'll find it.
For me, it did OK.
OS x start the path followed by a semicolon, then OS Dart is not exist with her as its parameter and
then in curly brackets.
Error is assigned the value of OS x McDeere and we're going to make their path and mode.
If error is not equal to nil,
then we'll just return the error.
Otherwise, it's created and we can just say return nil.
So now that this is available to us, we can go back to celebrities, don't go and actually create that
folder if it doesn't exist.
And it's as simple now as calling errors.
Assign the value of C Dot Create tier if not exist, and we handed Root, which is the full path name
of the application, followed by a slash followed by path, and that will create the directory if it
doesn't exist.
So if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil, return the error.
Otherwise, when we're done, return nil.
So in it does that for me so far, and that's the only thing that it does.
But of course, we need to call it it.
So backup at our new function, we can just create a path config variable.
So path config.
Is a sign the value of in iPads.
And we'll give it its members, so route path.
I'm getting that as the parameter to the new function, so that route path and then folder names.
And for that I will make a slice of string and populate it with the folders that I think I might need.
Now what folders am I going to need in a web application?
Well, let's just create a few.
Just make sure it works.
We're probably going to want handlers.
We're probably going to want, say, database migration.
So I'll call that folder migrations.
We're going to want a place to put our views.
So I'll create one called views.
We're probably going to want some place to store models and information like that and not call that
data.
And we can always change this later on if it doesn't work out for us some place to put static assets.
Maybe the public folder is a good place for that.
A place to put some temporary data, Tempe, a place to store logs.
And maybe we're going to have some middleware that's enough to get started anyway.
So I've created this path config variable.
Now let's do something with it.
So I'll create and I'll look for an error and I will call C Dot in it and hand it path config.
And we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return it.
So that's the first thing I'm going to do.
And of course, down here, I can say return nil.
So at this point, if I was to create a web application that imported this celebrity type and then it
called the new function on that celebrity celebrity type, it should go and create a handlers folder
of migrations, folder views, everything you see in that slice of strings.
It should create empty folders at the root level of that application.
If they don't exist, but there's a fair bit more we want to do before we're done.
But this lecture is getting quite long, so let's stop it right now, and we'll pick it up in the next
lecture.