So let's try out the changes we made in our celebrity package in our my app.
And the first thing I'll do is I'll create a type.
And just as a word of warning, we might have to fight with the Visual Studio code a little bit to get
this type to work, but we'll figure it out.
So a credit type called application and it will be a struct.
And this is going to be the type that holds all of the things our application needs, and we'll share
it with the parts of our application that need that kind of functionality.
So this will have one member and I'm going to call it app for application, and it will be of type a
pointer to celebrities, not celebrities.
OK, now if I type go go mod vendor, will it go find it for me?
Go mod vendor.
Sometimes the very first time you do this sort of thing in visual studio code, you have to fight with
it.
So all important manually GitHub dot com slash TESOL or slash.
Juice.
OK, now it found it, so that's good.
We're good to go.
You might have to if that didn't work for you, you might have to go to your terminal and just go get
GitHub dot com slash whatever your username is, slash whatever your package name is.
But we got it in there.
So that's where it's working.
All right.
Now I want to keep this main function.
Everything from line nine to line 11 right now, as simple as I possibly can.
So I'm going to put all of the heavy lifting off into separate functions that I can call as necessary.
So what I'll do is create a new file at the top level of this project, and I'll call it in it.
Dash solicitous dot com.
OK.
And of course, that's in Package Main and will make this function pretty straightforward.
So func in it application.
OK.
And it will take no parameters, and it will return a pointer to the type we just created application.
So there's certain things I absolutely am going to have to know for my web app to function properly,
and one of the first things is what's the working directory?
Where did this application start?
Unfortunately, it's pretty simple.
I'll say path is a sign the value of from the and potentially in error they're assigned the value of
from the OS package.
Get working directory right there, OK?
And we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then at this point, I want to say logged, not fatal.
And I wanted to just die is if we can't find a working directory, something's gone wrong.
So now I have the path, the root path to the application, and now I want to initialize celebrities.
So let's put a comment in in it celebrities.
And here's where we call that function we made.
But of course, we need to select celebrities variable.
So I'll call it cell for celebrities.
It's assigned the value of a reference to celebrities, not celebrities.
And the opening and closing curly brackets.
Now we'll check for an error.
Let's get rid of those spaces.
We don't need that
on the next line, I'll check for an error and that will be equal to Cell York-New.
So we're calling that function we just created.
And of course, that expects to find the root directory at the path to the working directory.
And we have that in path and we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Again, something's really gone wrong.
So let's just die logged fatal error.
So cell is there right now, and can I populate any of its values?
Let's have a look at that type again.
The types of alerts back in our other window.
The types of alerts has an apt name, debug and version.
Well, let's go back here and just populate some of this information.
Cell dot apni.
We can do that, and that will be my app and say Cell Dot Debug.
We'll make that equal to true for right now, and that's enough right now.
And now let's build our application.
Variable app is assigned the value of a reference to application.
And we'll populate its fields with the things that we have.
Well, right now we have up and that's equal to so and now we'll return up.
OK, so let's go back to our main function to make sure we have that.
All right.
Well, we obviously need to call that application function, and that's easy enough in its application.
Now, with no other changes.
Let's see what happens when we run our application.
So down on a terminal window, I will simply say make start and let the Makefile do all the heavy lifting
for me.
And there it is.
Look, it created all of the folders that we expected to find there and then it just exited because
we didn't tell it to do anything else.
But that's a good start.
We know that the connection between our main application, my app is working with calls to the celebrities
package.
All right, in the next lecture, we'll keep going and get to the point.
Eventually, before too long, we're actually serving up a webpage.