So let's keep going.
So right now, so far in our mean God Go file in the My App project, we have nothing more than a simple
type application that has one member, which is of type celebrities don't celebrities and we call in
it application in our main function.
And all that that does is get our working directory and then create a celebrity's variable.
It's a reference to celebrities start celebrities here on Line 17 and then we call new and new all that
that does.
Over here in the celebrities package, new does nothing more than give us a list of folders we expect
to have available for a web application and assign the root path to a variable called path config of
type in a parts.
And then we call in it.
And all that it does is create those folders.
So let's keep going.
Well, obviously one of the things we want to do is to get our environment set up.
And if we follow the same model that Laravel uses, we'll have a dot on file.
So let's get started doing that.
So in this new function, after we create the folders right here, let's go a little bit further.
Let's make sure that a dot on file exists.
So we'll check for an error.
And that's going to be equal to a function that doesn't exist yet.
And I'm going to call it check dot on.
OK, and we'll pass it ridpath so it knows where to look.
And of course, that's the root path of our application, not of celebrities.
And we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll simply return the error.
Now let's come down here below this function, below the init function and create that checked on function.
Func with the receiver, see celebrities, check dconf and it will take a path which is a string and
that's a root path.
And all we'll do here is say error is assign the value of and we want to check to see if that file exists.
So see Dot and we have one already create dear.
If not exist, let's create a new one in a minute.
We'll name it right now and then we'll create it in a moment.
So we'll call C Dot and instead of calling, create dear, if not exists, because that doesn't exist,
we'll create a new function and we'll call it file.
If not exist, and I'll put an s on the end and that will be looking in and we'll just use the format
on this print package.
We'll be looking for percent s, which is a placeholder we're going to replace in a minute.
A file named dconf and in there will pass in path.
So that will look in the root level of our application to see if a file called port exists.
And if it doesn't, we'll return an error.
So we'll give a return type here.
Error?
And we'll see if there does not is not equal to nil return the error, otherwise return nil, said article
create this create file if not exists.
And of course, we'll put that in the same place that we expect to find things helpers dot com.
So we'll create that function.
Func see celebrities, give it the name, create file if not exists, and it will take one path, which
is a string and potentially return an error.
And this is really simple.
So Vir will ignore the first return value and error or assign the value of from the OS package.
Step.
And hopefully it will find it for me.
Apparently not.
We'll import it manually in a moment.
Osun state and path.
And of course, we can't use the assignment operator.
That's why it wasn't funny.
There we are.
And if O.C Dot is not exist with error.
I will say create a file variable with potentially an error are equal to lawyers, don't create path.
If error is not equal to nil, just return the error.
So we'll make sure we close it properly.
Defer func.
File and lots of type OS file a pointer to that we don't care about the return value and we'll make
it file doc close just to close to when we're done.
And of course, we have to pass file to that deferred function.
And when all that's done, we return nil.
So that will create an empty dot on file for us if it doesn't exist.
So back in celebrities, we have this create file, if not exist.
We've done that.
Perfect.
Now up here, of course, once it exists, we want to read it.
Even if it's an empty file, we want to read it because at some point we're going to populate that dot
on file with lots of information.
So the next step is to read the dot on file on.
Now we could if we wanted to create all the code necessary to read the dot on file.
Just reading in a text file, go through it one line at a time.
Set the environment variables.
Or we could take advantage of a well known and often used package, which I'll show you right here.
It's at GitHub dot com slash j o h o slash go dot arms and it is dead simple to use, so let's copy
the code to install it right here.
Go back to our ID.
Open a terminal window and go get that package.
So we'll go and get it there.
It's now available to us.
So let's read the dot on file and you can go through the documentation on your own, but it's really,
really simple.
All you have to do is check for error and call go dot on dot load and pass it the full path name to
the dot on file.
So I'll pass it Route Path, which is the route path of our application, plus Slashdot on and we'll
check for an error if error is not equal to nil, return the error.
Now that has already with that one line, plus the error check, of course.
Read the dot on file found all of the entries and put them into our environment, which is pretty straightforward.
OK, so of course, we probably should have a dot on file.
So let's go back to our other package.
My app and create a new file in here called Dot Arms.
OK, now if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a starter dot on file and
it has lots of entries you're not going to use for a little while, but it's a good starting point.
So I've already got mine copied to the clipboard.
Let me just paste it in here.
So there it is.
And as you can see, there's all kinds of comments here that tells you what these various entries are
for, but let's go through a few of them just to get started.
So the first thing on Line two is app underscore name, and that's just a string with no spaces.
The name for your application, a unique name.
And on line five we have debug which is either true or false when we're in development.
That'll be true when we're in production.
It will be false.
Line eight is what port will our application listen on?
And I'm going to use 4000 because that's an unprivileged port and you shouldn't have much difficulty
using that one.
111 is what is the name of the server.
So it's domain name or it's fully qualified domain name.
In my case, I'm going to use localhost because I'm in development line 14.
Should we insist that we use HTTPS, in other words, a secure connection and in development, I'm going
to set the defaults.
Then we have our database configuration and we're going to support Postgres or MySchool and then Redis.
We're going to be using Redis for various things.
So we specify the connection values for that, the cache.
We're going to be using a cache in this course and we use Redis for the cache.
Then the cookie settings, the session settings, the mail server settings, how we're going to render
our HTML and an encryption key.
And we're not going to get to a lot of this for quite some time, but this is a good starting point.
OK, so now that we have a dart on file, when we run our application, it'll create all of these folders.
It'll check to see if a dart on file exists.
If it doesn't, it'll create an empty one.
And then it reads all the values from that dot on file into environment variables for application.
So this is a good start will continue in the next lecture.