So we've created some folders and we've created the dot on file and read its values into the environment
for application, so let's keep going.
So I'm back in celebrities to go in the celebrities package and I'm looking at the type of celebrities.
Let's add a few things here that we might be using.
OK.
So for example, let's put some bloggers in.
Let's put an error, log in there and we'll make that type.
And this is right from the standard library, a pointer to long dot logger.
And we'll also put an info log in there.
This will allow us to print things to a log file or through the terminal or wherever we want, and it
will be logged out longer to.
And we should also put our route path in there because we might need that, so route pass.
And that will be a string.
Well, that's enough for now.
So let's use this.
So a format this.
All right.
And let's come down here and use some of these things.
So back in the new function, well, let's create our loggers first.
OK.
So we might as well say, create loggers.
And for now, I'll just say in full log and error log, which are two new variables I'm declaring right
now, they'll be assigned the value of.
And as I often do, I'm going to put this in its own function just to make it easier to test.
So we'll create a function or call a function that doesn't exist yet.
See that start loggers.
OK.
So we're going down to the bottom of this file.
And I'll just say func, see celebrities is the receiver and we'll call it start loggers, and it returns
a pointer to a logged off logger and another pointer to logged logger.
And we'll make this dead simple for our info.
Log is a type lost pointer to a logged out logger, and VAR error log
is a type pointer logged logger and we'll just create them and send them back.
So Info Log will be equal to log dot new OS Dot stdout.
We're going to print it terminal and we'll prefix it with info in a tab and we'll make it logged until
date to get the date.
Printed and logged all time.
OK.
And our error log will be equal to logged on new and again we'll print predict to standard post on stdout
and we'll prefix it with error, you know, caps and a tab.
And we'll put in here a little more information log that l date log l time.
And we'll also put logged on L short file, which gives us some information about where the error actually
occurred and we'll return this info log and error log.
Now, the reason I declared variables here is because a little later on, when we're not in debug mode,
when we're in production, we'll write this information to files instead.
So that just saves me a little bit of correction later, later on.
So those are now set up so we can come back up here and now we can do something with it.
Well, we added those types error log and info log to our typed celebrities.
So let's get started using those.
So we already have the typed celebrities as a receiver on this function, so we can just say, see dot
info log equals info log and see it on air log equals air log.
And we can also, since we now have the environment variable debug available to us because we read the
dot on the file, we can say See Dot Debug equals OS X, get on and we'll look for debug, which is
what we called it in our dart on file.
But of course, this is a string.
Anything we call from our dot on that's right into our environment is actually a string, so we need
to convert it to a Boolean because that's the type in celebrities for the debug field.
And that's easy enough.
We can just add right here, ignore the error and put in stir calls dot her bool.
And then wrap this whole thing.
In quotation marks or in parentheses, and it's okay, don't get on there.
Now we have our loggers and our debug value set in our celebrities variable.
And of course, we can do more than that.
We also have, for example, if you recall up here version, which we're not using, well, we may as
well populate that as well.
So see, dot version equals version our constant.
So now all of this information is available to us on the front end.
So if we switch back to the front end, for example.
So back here in our main application, we can try using some of the things we've set, so let's open
a terminal and make sure we have the latest version of everything going on vendor and Hyder Terminal.
And let's go over this in IT application and see if we can call some of these things.
So here's where we have our security variable we created on Line 17 in in it application and then we
call new and handed the path.
And at that point, we should have some information available to us so I can get rid of this, for example.
So don't debug because that should be set by the time I finish calling new.
So down here.
Let's see if that works.
Let's try.
Format dot print line
Debug is set to and then we just put Cell Dot Debug.
Let's try running this and see what happens.
So down here in my terminal, I simply type, make start, build celebrities.
And it says debug is set to true, which is perfect.
OK, so that means I also don't have to use format print one.
I could instead say sell the info log script line and run this application again.
And this time it shouldn't just print.
Debug is set to true.
It should put some more information that our info log pretends to it, for example.
So make start.
And we have imported not used format over insularity, so of course.
So let's just say this, and that will clean that up and try that again, make start.
And there it says info, plus the date and time and then debug is set to true.
So as you can see, every time we add new functionality to our solar toss package, any application
that uses that functionality will have access to it, and that's the entire goal of what we're trying
to do here.
All right, that's enough for this time around.
We'll move on in the next election.