So things are coming along, but we have a lot of work left to do.
And one of the things we have to get out of the way pretty early on is actually setting up the configuration
values for celebrities, not for a web application necessarily, but for the celebrities package itself.
So in order to get that underway, what I'm going to do is back here in celebrities start go in the
celebrities application or project.
I'm going to create a new type and these type will not be exported and it will just be called config
and it will just be a struct.
And this will hold all of the configuration values for this package, and we'll just put a few in there
right now.
So we're going to want to know things like what port are we going to listen on?
And that's a string.
So when we start the application, when the final binary is built is going to listen on some port and
we'll get that, of course, from the environment variables.
We also will want to know what renderer.
Are we going to use so renderer, which is a string now that's referring to what template engine we
want to use, and in this course we're going to support to.
We'll do a little bit first with the standard go templates and then we'll spend a lot more time on another
renderer, the jet package.
So we're going to want that for certain, and that's enough right now.
We'll be adding more to the config type as time goes on.
So we have this type, so let's use it.
So we'll come down here after we set all these values.
And while I'm at it, I mean, this will set secret path and that will be equal to past week.
I forgot to do that last time around.
Let's set the application config.
So what I'll do here is go back up to celebrities and add another type here, which I'll call config.
And I'm not going to export that because there's no reason that any application that import celebrities
should have access to the config, so config will be of type config.
OK, so that's available to us now.
So we come down here.
Just after I set the path just at the very end of the new function, and let's say see config is equal
to the type config and we'll just populate its values.
And of course, all we care about right now are the port, and we get that from the environment, which
we read when we read our dart on file.
OS don't get arms port all in uppercase and the renderer will be equal to again from our OS.
Don't get on because this is right in our dart on file.
Render it, make sure you spell it right or it's not going to work.
So that's available to us now throughout the entire application hour.
Anywhere that we share this in our Securitas package will have access to all the configuration variables
if we need it.
And of course, we're going to add more information to the config, like the database and the cookie
type and the session type in our Redis configuration and all that sort of thing.
But we'll add those as we need them.
Now, of course, our ultimate goal is to start a Web application to start a web server and listen for
requests.
And that's not terribly difficult to set up a basic one, and we'll get started on that in the next
lecture.
But right now we have our configuration, we have our lockers, we have all kinds of things that we
can use.
And I think the next step, just so we can see some tangible progress, will be to start a web server
from our Celerity House package and just serve something back.
So we know that it works and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.