So let's get started implementing a very simple Web server and, of course, will improve on this as
time goes on.
So I'm back in the Celebrity House package and the first thing I want to do is create a new file.
And I want to create a new file right at the root level of the celebrity's project.
And I'm going to call it Roots Dot Go.
And this will be the default routes that are available as part of the celebrity's package.
So let's give it its a name package, celebrities.
And what I'm going to do is create a new function, and this will have the receiver of C Pointer to
celebrities, and I'm going to call it simply roots.
It's not exported, and it will return the type of http dot handler handler with an on the end not handle.
OK.
And this, of course, is going to return all of the routes that are available to our application by
default, if any and any middleware, we want to implement things like that.
Now we could use the built in rooting functionality that's part of the standard library, but that would
get awkward very quickly.
And if you take in any of my other courses, you're probably aware of the fact that I'm a big fan of
this package.
So let me go over to my web browser.
It's the cheat router, and that's the one I want to use, and I'm going to implement this as the basic
routing package that we use as part of our celebrities package.
So I'll copy the installation command right here, and there's a link to this on the course resources
for this lecture, and I'll go back to my celebrity's package, opened my terminal window and paste
that in and it goes and gets cheap.
Version five.
And if you want to follow along, exactly even if there's a later version of this.
Stick with the V5.
Otherwise, you might run into difficulties because there might be a breaking change.
OK, so I have it available to me now as part of my Go Dot Mod file.
So let's use it.
And it's really simple to use.
We'll create a variable rate inside the function called MUX for multiplexing, and it's equal to cheat
Dot New River right there.
And hopefully that imported version five.
No, it didn't.
So we'll make that slash V5.
I had an old version available, so now we've created that and I'm also going to take advantage of cheese
middleware package.
So to use that, I'll open my terminal window and I'm going to type or paste in here.
Go get.
And it's almost the same URL.
It just ends with slash, V5 slash and middleware.
So I'll go get that because there are some really good middleware that's available by default when you
import that package.
So I'm going to use some of that.
I'll say Mark start use.
I guess I'm missing some parentheses here.
Let's try that again.
Mark, start use.
And I want to use from Middleware
Dot.
Request I.D..
And then I'll also use Macs don't use from the middleware package, real IP, and only when I'm in debug
mode, I want to actually log things to the console.
OK, so I'll say if see that debug, which is available to us right from the celebrity's receiver.
So if Cederberg and I will say Macs don't use middleware logger.
OK, and then I'll just say return marks.
So there are no actual routes in here, but what I've done is add some default middleware.
OK, I'll add one more here.
Two, if things panic, we want to recover gracefully so Macs don't use middleware recover or and that
will actually recover if our application should panic for some reason.
So the first one request ID, if you look at the comment, it's a middleware that injects a request
ID into the context of each request.
A request ID is a string of the form, and it gives you an example, and it allows us to easily take
advantage of request ID and the context.
The second one actually gets the real IP where the request is coming from, and in lots of situations
you want to know the IP address of your visitor.
The logger just writes to the console, in our case, every request that comes in and that will be helpful
as we develop.
And finally, this one recovers from Panic's.
OK, so we have this available to us now.
So let's go back to our Solaris Housego Go File and close our terminal, and now I'm going to create
a function.
I'll put it right right after the init function.
Why not?
OK.
It doesn't matter where it is as long as it's available to us.
And this will be a function with the receiver of C, a pointer to celebrities.
And I'm going to call it listen and serve.
And this will actually start our application, our web server, OK and keep it running in the background.
So we'll create a variable called SRB for server server, and that's assigned the value of a reference
to HTTP server right there, and we'll populate some values we're going to need.
What's our address?
So ADT are OK with a Capital eight, and that, of course, will be what part we're going to listen
on.
So we'll say format Sprint F, Sprint F, and we'll give it this formatting string a colon followed
by percent s, which is a string and we have from our own don't get on the port we're listening on.
So that will give us, in my case, a string colon four thousand and that tells the that will tell the
web server.
Here's where you listen.
This is the port you'll listen to and we want an error log and we have one of those we can use C Dot
Heirloom and we want handlers.
And this is where we call C Dot Roots.
And finally, we want we're not finally, we want an idle timeout, and we'll just put a reasonable
value there, say 30 times time dot second.
And we also want to read timeout 30 times timed second.
And comma there.
And we want to time timeout, which will certainly say 600 times times Dot second.
I'm just going to make that really long for development purposes and if necessary, we can change that
later on.
OK.
So from here, let's right to the log file, see dot info log dot print line.
And we'll just say, let make that a print if.
Listening on Port Percent s and here will substitute that with don't get on the port.
OK, so now we can start our web server, so we'll say error is a sign the value of service.
Listen and serve and we'll check for an error.
See Dot analog dot fatal error.
So something goes wrong.
We'll know what happened and we'll give this a comment.
Listen and serve starts the web server.
OK, very good.
Now we actually want some means of testing this, so let's go back to our roots file.
Let's just put one test route in here.
So we'll say Max, don't get and we'll make it just the default slash.
OK?
And we'll just put an inline function here.
Func, W.H Response Writer Because every handler and this is an inline handler has to have two parameters
the response writer and our which is a pointer to HGTV Dot request.
And when we hit this route, we'll just say format, dot print and we'll give it a writer, which is
in our case, and we'll just say welcome to celebrities just to make sure that things are actually working.
OK, so this will actually start a Web server.
Now we're not going to be able to do anything except get the request to the home page and get some text
written back to us.
Not even true HTML, but it's a start.
But how am I going to get access to these routes in my front end?
Well, let's go back to celebrities.
Don't go.
Let's go to the very top where we define our celebrity package.
And let's put another value in here roots.
And that will be of type in our case, she mugs, because we're using the cheat river.
So let's save this to format it, and let's go all the way down to our in it here.
And let's populate that.
So I want see dot roots right here and be equal to.
And I can call the function cedar roots lowercase right there.
But as you can see, that's not the right type because that's returning in football handler.
So what I'll do is simply cast that to a pointer up to G Dot.
And now the roots are available to us.
OK, so let's switch to the front end and find our main file right here.
Mandago.
And after we end it, the application.
Let's store that value in a variable called see for celebrities and then call See Dot App Dot.
Listen, answer OK.
So this should, in theory, start the webserver, so let's open a terminal window and type, make a
stop to make sure nothing is going and it shouldn't be.
It's not and totemic start.
And there it is, it's listening on Port four thousand now we actually have no means of doing anything
exciting with that, but we can go back to our web browser and open a new terminal, open a new browser
window and go to HGTV colon slash slash localhost port four thousand.
And it says, Welcome to celebrity chefs.
Well, that's a great start.
Now, obviously, we want to do more things than this if we go back to our code.
For example, we have this view's directory right here, which is currently empty.
And what I want is I want the end user who using this package to be able to populate that view's holder
with views of some type go templates and later on jet templates.
And then just call a simple, built in function that's part of the Celerity House package that allows
them to render a page, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.