So in this section of the course, we want to implement a second kind of cash, we already have a red
is cash, but this time I want to implement a badger cash and we'll get started on that in a moment.
But before we go too much further, there's a couple of things I want to clean up.
And right now, I'm in the My App project and I'm looking at the file models and go inside the data
directory and right here in the new function.
This works right now for us, but it won't work in a certain situation.
Ultimately, when we complete our command line application and we have that functionality that says
celebrity's new and then some project name, we want to install a project that doesn't have a database
hooked up that doesn't have a cache specified that has the default cookie session.
In other words, the bare minimum and we want users to specify things on their own and the way that
we have this right now, it just won't work, and it's because of what we have here in the new function.
We have this statement if OS get on data that database type is equal to MySQL or MariaDB, then we initialize
upar with the MySchool driver.
Otherwise, we do it with the Postgres driver.
And of course, if you don't have a Postgres database, the application actually won't start.
So let's make this a little simpler.
Let's make it a switch statement switch and we'll switch on OAC.
Don't get on.
And again, we're looking for database type
and we'll have our first case be either MySQL or MariaDB.
And in that case, then we'll do the upper minus on my actual news or copy this and paste it right here.
And our second case will be Postgres or PostgreSQL.
And again, for that one, we'll take this driver
and paste this right in here.
And then we'll have a default case that does nothing,
which we don't actually require, but I like to make my code is readable as possible.
So now if we delete this if statement that will work when they start up the application with no database
specified in their dot on file, it just won't initialize the upper.
It'll just leave it set to nil.
And that's perfect for our purposes.
So that's the first thing I wanted to clean up.
And the second thing is inside the handlers folder insert in the file convenience, don't go.
And it's just a naming thing here.
I copied and pasted Decrypt from Encrypt.
And of course, we want this to be decrypted and it's just a name.
So let's change that to decrypt it and change our return value.
And that's a little bit better.
OK, now let's get started with our Badger cash, so I'll create a new file over in my celebrity's project.
Let's go there and I'll close these two because we don't need them right now inside cash.
I'll create a new file, which I'll call Badger, vide your dash or underscore cash taco.
And of course, it has the package cash now in order to make this work.
Of course, because in our Cash Dog Go file, we have at the very top this interface cash.
All we have to do is basically implement all of these functions for Badger.
OK.
So before we do that, of course, we have to install the necessary driver.
So let me go over to my web browser and I'm looking at the GitHub repo for Badger and the there's a
link to this in the course resources for the page.
Badger is a very, very simple, and it's well tested and reused a great deal.
It's a an embeddable, persistent key value database written in Go.
And the great thing about it is we can embed it right in our package and not require an external database
for a cache.
Now, Badger is very fast and it works really well.
And of course, there are many other ones we could use which are just as good and maybe even better.
But for our purposes, we just want to learn how to implement more than one type of cache, so we need
to install this.
So let's copy this.
And as usual, if version four is out, stick with version three for this course and upgrade to version
four after the fact, because version four, according to semantic versioning, is not compatible with
version three.
So everything we try to do probably won't work.
So let's just be safe and copy this and go back to our IEEE and open a terminal window and paste in
the command in our celebrities project and go get that.
And of course, it kept a dollar sign in there for some reason, so we'll get rid of that.
That's better.
So goes and gets Badger for us.
And it's added to our Goldman file, and now we can use it.
So the very first thing we're going to have to do in our Badger Cash and Badger underscore cashed out
go file inside the cash directory instead of a tape, and the tape will be called not surprisingly,
badger cash.
And it's just a struct, and it has the same sorts of things we had for our other cash type reddish
cash.
It has a con, but in this case it's a type pointer to badger the the package we just installed and
we'll get the right one version three DB and it also has the prefix, which is a string.
OK, so we have the type and now we just have to implement, has and get and set and all of those things.
So to make things a little bit simpler, what I'm going to do is open up, cashed out and go and copy.
All of the functions.
So has.
We don't need in code because we're going to be calling that existing function right from Badger, so
I'll go back to Badger Cash and paste this in and change its type to magic hash.
OK.
And all of this is error.
So don't worry about that.
We'll fix that in a minute.
Let's just go back to Cash Dog, go and copy the remaining functions, and we'll just change their receivers
to the appropriate type and then implement the actual individual functions.
So we need everything up to and including empty.
So I'll copy those and go back to badger cash and paste those in and change the receivers to badger
cash.
For all of this, and I'll delete the contents of each function and write them as necessary to use Badger.
I think this is the last one here.
Perfect.
So let's get rid of this, all of this inside of empty and all of this inside of here.
And she will keep the return gnome because it needs that.
And we'll do the same thing for forget.
And here, set in the empty.
And here that'll throw us in error until we specify item, but that's fine and has.
OK, so now all we have to do is to implement each of these functions.
So the first one is really simple and you can read the documentation to badger at your convenience.
But I'm also going to do one more thing I'm going to do copy all of this and do a search which is here
somewhere.
Find and replace and I'll replace the receiver c badger cache with the receiver b badger cache, which
I just like better and will replace all the badger starts with the B sort of receiver means it will
be a lowercase B and that will be really simple.
So what we're going to do, first of all, is implement the has function and in Badger it's really simple.
We're going to ignore the first return parameter.
We are going to check for an error and we call Vidot get STR, which are received here.
And we don't need to worry about prefixes here, even though it's included in here.
I just want to make this tape match the other type.
OK.
So we have a we try to get it.
And if we can't get it, we say if error is not equal to nil, then return false and will ignore the
error because we're not going to do anything with it.
It just doesn't exist.
That's all.
And here it will return.
True and nil.
All right.
We've now implemented has for the Badger cache, that was easy now in the second one.
Yet again, it's not very difficult.
We have our key in the form of a string and we don't need to append a prefix to it.
You can if you want to, but it doesn't actually do anything of value, so I wouldn't bother.
So we'll try ver.
We'll create a variable ver from cache and that is of type a slice of bytes, slice of byte.
And now we try to get it.
And here's the syntax for running badger transactions because everything in Badger is effectively a
transaction.
We check for an error and we call from a receiver b dickon dot view, verify, check.
Some view that's better.
And in here we have an embedded function func, and we need a parameter for that which is transaction.
I'll call it text and for transaction.
It is a type a pointer to badger text in right there.
And it potentially returns an error.
And the body of that function.
That should be funk Texan
techs and pointer to Badger Texan.
That's better.
And here we want to get an item, so I'll call it item.
And again, we're checking for an error.
And that's assigned the value of from Texm.
Yeah, and the parameter requires is a slice of bite.
And we just took a steer that was passed right to this function and we checked for an error if error
is not equal to nil.
And we just say return the error.
Otherwise we have the item.
So we'll say error is equal to item value.
And again, it takes an embedded function and we'll see this a lot in Bachir, but you get used to the
syntax pretty quickly.
Again, it takes an embedded function.
And it takes one parameter value, a slice of bytes,
and it potentially returns in error.
And now will you take that variable?
We declared up on Line 19 from cash that will now be equal to append.
A slice of bite, that's the type, all the values we get in there.
Dot Dot.
And return nil.
And we check for the error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return the error, otherwise return nil.
So what we've done in here is we tried to get a value from the cache and got all of the bytes that matched
that in the cache and appended them to from cache, which is itself a slice of bytes.
And down here, of course, after we get through this, we check for an error for the overall transaction.
If error is not equal to nil, return nil, return nil.
And the error?
That's better.
But if we do have a value in there, that slice of bytes, we now have to decode them and we'll just
declare a variable decoded.
And we check for error and their assigned values by calling that function D code that we wrote over
in the red is cash, but it doesn't have a receiver, so it's available anywhere in this package.
And we convert our from cash to a string.
We check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we return nil and the error otherwise item is now assigned the value of decoded and string.
And we return the item, so that should, in theory, be the completed version of our get function.
Let's go down to set and take care of that one.
So again, the basic logic here is fairly simple we have to serialized an object and put it into Badger
with an optional expires in seconds.
That's the basic functionality we have to do.
So we'll create an entry of type entry.
Entry is assigned the value of an empty entry.
And will set entry.
SDR equal to whatever we received as value in this cult of this function.
And now we encode it encoded in error or assign the value of ENCODE.
And we want to encode entry.
And if there's an error, we return the error.
Try that again.
Otherwise, we can keep going.
Here's what we check for the expiry.
If the line of expires is greater than zero and there is an expiry.
Otherwise, there is no expiry.
So let's do the first case here.
Something is going to expire.
So here we call error, or we set the value of error equal to from our receiver b we call con.
And we want the method update, as usual, that takes an inline function with this one parameter called
T.X and of type pointer to badger 40 percent or dart transaction, and it potentially returns in error.
And it's pretty simple to do this.
We say E, which is just a variable I'm calling or creating right now for entry is Badger Dot new entry
and we fill in its parameters.
The first one is a slice of byte and we want to get it using our key SDR, which we received as a call
to this and encoded.
That's what we're putting in there.
And now we call with time to life, and that will be time.
Second time's timed dot duration.
Expires the first entry.
And air is equal to 10 said entry in our entries.
And we returned the error, which might be no.
Hopefully it will be otherwise.
It's very similar.
We just copy this entire thing pasted in here and get rid of the with total part.
And everything else should be pretty much the same.
So we now have a get in a set and a has let's move on to forget and forget is pretty short.
All we do is check for an error when we call Beacon Update.
Same as before with an inline function funk texm of type pointer to Badger.
And that potentially returns an error
and we say error is assigned the value of 10 delete and we delete.
We have to put it into a slice of bytes
just here and we say, say, return error.
And outside of this function, we return the error so we get rid of this return.
Nil.
And that should take care of forget.
Now empty by match.
I'm going to leave for a moment, OK?
And empty.
I'm going to leave for a moment, and instead I'm going to come down here and write another function
just to help her function.
And what it will do is drop entries that have either no prefix your.
Your key, in other words, is empty or which begin with a given prefix.
In other words, your key is not empty, and I'm going to call this function, which will not be exported
from empty and empty by match.
So I'll call this one func with a receiver.
Be a pointer to badger cash.
I'm going to call it empty by match with a lowercase, and it will take one argument one parameter SDR,
which is a string, and it will potentially return an error.
OK.
This one is fairly lengthy and it will look complex, but it's really not.
It's just a little irritating the way we have to write this.
OK, so the first thing I'll do is search the entire badger cache for the keys that we have to delete.
OK, so create a variable.
I'm going to call it delete keys, and that will be assigned the value of a function.
Keys four delete will be the parameter it receives, and it's a slice of a slice of byte and it potentially
returns an error.
So this is a bit of a recursive function, will say if error is assigned the value of bitcoin.
Update as usual.
And this is going to take again an embedded function funk with the parameter of text and a pointer to
badger dot text, and it will potentially return in error.
And in here, we're going to have a little for loop.
So we'll say for we don't care about the index, but we do care about the key there.
Assign the value of range through keys for delete, and we'll say if error is assigned the value of
text and delete.
And what we want to delete, of course, is our key.
And if the air is not equal to nil,
then we'll return there.
So there's our for loop and we'll return Neal if we get past that.
And then after the if statement, we'll just put a semicolon.
There is not equal to nil return the error.
And then finally, if we get past all that, we return nil.
So that's our first thing or delete keys, which is basically a function now to make things speedier.
I'm going to say collect size, and this will just be a variable that determines how much of the cache
we should handle at any given time.
I want it to be fast, so I'm going to set it to one zero zero zero zero zero.
OK.
And we'll be using that variable right here.
Here's where we say error is assign the value of and again beacon dot view.
And we want to have it in an inline function, funk T.X end of tape Badger Dot Texan.
And it potentially returns an error and will create some options.
UPS, which you need for for this particular operation in Badger.
So my variable is called ops, and I was going to use the default iterator option straight from Badger
Badger Dot default iterator options.
OK, so I'm going to be iterating through things and I'm just telling Badger just do it the way it normally
would.
But I'll specify a couple of additional parameters to the Badger default options.
So I'll say ops, and it has a number of things we can we can check for here.
I'll say all versions and mechanical defaults, OK?
And you can read about that right in the Badger documentation.
The second thing I'm going to set is upstart pre prefect values, and I'll pretty much values, not
XYZ values.
And again, I'll set the defaults, OK, because we're deleting things here.
We don't really care about that.
And our iterator will be assigned the value of TSM, which are received as a parameter to this anonymous
function.
New iterator with the options, now we have an interior.
Scroll up and give us some room.
So now we're going to declare a new variable called keys for delete, and that will be assigned the
value of using make.
We're going to make a slice of a slice of byte b y t zero and collect size.
That's how big to make it OK.
And we'll say a second variable keys collected is assigned the value of zero, and now we'll use our
iterator for it.
Don't seek it is an iterator we're seeking.
And the first parameter is a slice of bytes
and we want to steer the parameter that was passed to this function, which might be an empty string
in this case.
And then we'll put a semicolon and then iterator validate valid for valid for prefix right there, just
straight out of the iterator itself.
It's a method available to us and it requires a parameter.
So we're going to give it again a slice of byte and SDR.
And then the third one is it.
Up next, go through the entire list and we'll assign a variable key will declare one key, which is
assign the value of it to item and we have to call key copy.
And this is a syntax that Badger requires, and we can give it nil for its parameter.
OK.
And then we want keys for delete is going to be equal to append keys for delete, and we're appending
cheat and we increment keys collected by one keys collected plus plus.
And here's a case you have to check for if your keys collected it, keys collected is equal to collect
size.
In other words, we've hit the 100000 limit we specified in line 115 and we'll just delete them all.
So we'll say if error is a sign, the value of delete keys because we don't want to go more than 100000
items at a time and we'll never hit that 100000 is a safe number.
So delete keys keys four delete error is not equal to nil, then return the error.
Otherwise, once we get past that, we check to see if keys collected is greater than zero.
Then again, we do the same sort of thing we just did right here, so I can copy this or paste it here.
So all that this line here these lines are here is just to ensure that we're not trying to delete more
than 100000 items at a time, because that might take a little bit of time and we're not going to hit
that ever.
But it's always good to put this kind of logic in here.
You never assume that the best case scenario is going to happen, but once we get past this, we just
delete everything this greater than zero.
OK, so that should be outside of the four statement I have in the wrong spot.
I was sloppy.
We don't want to do that every time.
Here we are.
That's better.
So once we get outside of that for a loop, we're going to have 100000 or fewer items to delete.
So we just delete them all.
And here we return.
Nil.
Inside of these this statement
and below that we return
Earth, which hopefully will be nil at this point.
OK, so that is our empty by match function.
And now up here, where we have empty by match, we're going to say return VDOT empty by.
With whatever we received as a parameter call to this function and here in empty, we do exactly the
same thing.
But now we return the empty by match with an empty string.
Delete everything in the cache and that should take care of it.
Now we have some typos or something in there, but we'll try this in the next lecture simply by writing
some tests.