So we seem to have implemented all the necessary functions for our badger cash, so let's test it out.
Let's create a new folder inside the cash folder because we need somewhere to put our Badger database
in.
It writes it to discuss or create a new folder called test data.
And of course, that's ignored by the Go compiler.
And inside of that, I'll create a new folder called temp temp.
And that's where I'll put my Test Badger database.
And of course, to make that happen, I need to update set up tests inside of the cache folder.
Now, right now, what we have is a very, very simple.
So after the defer of closing the Redis cache, let's put some more code in here.
And what I'll do, first of all, is when I start the tests, I want to make sure that any badger database
that exists test database is gone.
So I'll just call OS removal, which will delete a folder and all of its contents if it happens to exist
and not delete from the current directory.
Slashed test data slash temp and I will delete the badger cache entirely.
Actually, I'll put Slash Badger after it there.
That way, the temp folder will still be there and I won't have to recreate it, so that deletes it
if it exists.
And of course, the first time we run the test, it won't be there and that does not matter.
And now we need to create a badger cash cache, create a Badger database.
And it's pretty simple if they ignore the first response, but I do want to check for an error.
Those are assigned values from the West STAT and I want to create dot slash dot slash test data slash
Tempe just to make sure that exists.
And then OS Dart is not exist with an error and we'll create the necessary folders.
Errors is assign the value of OCR McDeere and we want to make dot slash test data, slash Tempe with
some mode and I'll just put zero seven five five and that's perfect for our purposes.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll just log fatal.
Logged on fatal.
If I can't write to the file system, then the disk is full or something bad has happened.
But whatever it is, I want to stop.
So that creates the necessary folder and now I'll make a badger folder.
So I'll just say error equals OS Dart McDeere and I want to make it in dot slash test data slash temp
slash badger again, zero seven five five is perfect, and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I got an equal sign.
Again, log fatal error.
But if we get past that, we have the necessary folders now all created Badger Database DB and nothing
will ignore.
The error is a sign the value of from the Badger package not open.
And this will create the database if it doesn't exist, so are created with Badger Dart default options.
And I'm going to create it, of course, in dot slash test data slash temp slash badger.
Now I also need to create a test by badger cash.
So up here at the very top of the file we're at right after I declare my British cash, I'll say our
test badger cash is a type badger cash, and that's the one we use for our tests.
So down here, after I've created the database call, I really have to do is say Test Badger Cash dot
com is equal to the DB we just created and you can put the prefix in there too, if you want to.
We're not using it, so I'll leave it at and that should be enough.
Now, just as a note, when we're using a badger cash in production, we do need to run a periodic cleanup
task on it.
But we'll take care of that when we connect to Badger because it's really simple.
So we've created the necessary set up test.
The next step is to write the actual test themselves, and we'll do that in the next lecture.