So let's write the tests for our your cash.
So what I'm going to do is in the cash folder, I'll put this in their own file.
You can put them in the cash underscore test if you wish, but I'm going to call this one badger dash
cash underscored cash don't go just to keep things separate.
And of course, the package is cash, and we're going to write some tests.
So let's, first of all, test the has function, so I'll call this one test.
Badger cash underscore has, and it should have.
An uppercase T.
And it takes one parameter T pointer to testing 40.
And it doesn't return anything and get rid of that extra parentheses.
So let's, first of all, make sure there's nothing in the cache.
There's not, but we'll just do this anyway.
Test errors assign the value of test badger cache.
Don't forget the same logic we use when we test the other cache and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll just say the error here.
OK, so that makes sure that there's nothing in the cache that's called Foo.
Now we'll try in cache is a variable, I'm declaring, and again, we'll look for an error and we just
call Test Badger Cache has and we look for food.
And if there's an error again, we'll just copy this and paste it here and now the actual test, if
in cache, if that's in the cache and something went wrong because it shouldn't be there ketone error
and we'll just say Foo found in cash and it shouldn't be there.
That's sufficient.
Now let's put something in the cache.
I don't care about the result, but I'll call Test Badger Cache Dot set, and we'll set Foo equal to
bar and will again populate encash and error equal to test.
Badger Cache has foo and paste our error check and if not in cash, then something went wrong.
Keena error will say Foo not found in cash and you can vote whatever you want for your error message
there.
So let's just now run this test and see how it goes.
So I'm inside the cache directory.
Yes, I am.
So I can just type go test dot.
And everything passed, perfect, so let's read our next test.
Actually, what I'm going to do first is forget food just to be safe.
Error equals test badger cash.
Don't forget, and I'll forget.
Now let's read our next test, our next one is to test to get so funk test badger cash get again t a
pointer to testing dot t.
And what we'll do, first of all, is set a value error is assign the value of test badger cash not
set, and we'll set Fu equal to Burr and I'll paste my error check.
And now I'll say X and error X is just a temporary variable.
Test Badger Cash don't get and I'll get food and paste my error check.
And I'll say if X is not equal to Burr, then title error did not yet correct value from cash.
And again, you can put whatever you want for an error message there.
Let's run the test again.
Make sure they still work.
Control go.
Test don't.
And everything passed so far, so good.
So after get, we want to try forget that we've already called forget and didn't get an error, but
let's write a test for it anyway.
Funk test badger cash.
Forget Tea Party or to testing our tea, and what we'll do here is set a value in that.
So we'll say error is a sign the value of test badger cash set and I'll set Fu equal to Foo.
This time doesn't matter what it is and check for an error.
And now we'll try forgetting it.
Error equals test badger cash -.FOR or Test Badger Cash Cash.
Don't forget, we'll just replace that one.
Forget and check for an error.
And I got to forget Foo.
Who?
And then we'll try to get of the cash.
We'll see if it's in there in cash, in an error or assign the value of test badger cash.
Dot has.
And look for food and check for an error.
If in cash, then we have an error as it should be gone by now.
We just deleted it on line 55 to error and we'll just say food found in cash
and it should, shouldn't be there.
And that should be sufficient for that one.
Let's run our tests again.
Go Test Dot.
Everything passed, and after this one comes empty
funk test, badger cash, empty T pointer to testing dirty, so set a new value in there.
There's time I'll just copy this code and paste it here, and I'll call this one alpha with a value
of beta or beta if you prefer and will call empty badger cash there equals test badger test test badger
cash.
Empty.
And we'll check for error,
and we just want to see if something is in the cache, so I'll copy this entire block of code and look
for alpha as alpha and alpha found in cache, but it's not there or shouldn't be there.
Run our tests again.
Clear the screen go test.
And we have an error and what is the error?
Unclosed iterator at time of P.X and discards, so we have an error somewhere in.
Where is it?
Badger Cash Dog Go Line 94, let's find that Badger Cash Dog Go.
Which is not in Senator Badger test data.
It is Badger Test Go Lying 94, Line 94.
So somewhere in here, we're calling empty by match with nothing.
In the air is.
Unclosed iterator, a time of TFS and discard.
So it was in Badger Cash Go line for.
One hundred and fourteen.
Let's find that one.
So somewhere in this block of code.
And it's right here.
So we created our iterator here, but we never actually closed it.
And you have to do that.
So that was an oversight on my part.
All we have to do is to put in defer it close.
OK, so now if we come down here and clear the terminal and type go tests done.
Much better.
OK.
This is why we write tests because we often leave things out that we ought not to back to our badger
test go.
So we've tested empty.
So let's try empty by match think test badger cash underscore empty by match parameter T pointer to
testing T and it has no return values.
So again, we need to set a value here, so I'll just copy this one alpha and beta and paste that in
there and now paste that again and make this equals operator and we'll set Alpha say to make that better
too.
Doesn't matter.
And that we'll try to empty by match, but we probably should put something else in there as well.
So we'll paste that one more time and call this one beta, and it doesn't matter what the value is.
So now when I start the test, I have an alpha in the cache and alpha two in the cache and abetted in
the cache, and I won't call empty by match error equals test badger cache, badger cache dot empty
by match the uppercase one.
That's the export of one.
And I'm going to look for anything that starts with NG and I'll check for an error
and paste that in here and now I want to see if certain values are in the cache.
So let me copy these copy this one first.
And paste this in here, and we'll check to see if Alpha is in the cache and it shouldn't be if it's
in the cache, we have error.
Perfect.
Now a copy of this again and paste it again and change it to an equals operator and look for Alpha two,
which we put in right up here in Line 98 and that should be gone.
The two should be gone in the cache and then will copy this whole thing and look for better, which
should still be there.
Better, better, not found in cash and it should be there and make this a not.
So we have this right?
So we put in alpha and alpha two and beta.
Then we empty by match anything that starts with a check to see if Alpha is in there.
If we if it is in there, then it shouldn't be.
We have a problem.
If Alpha two is in there, then it shouldn't be and we have a problem.
Better should still be there.
So if it's not in the cache, then we have a problem.
Perfect.
Let's try running the test.
Go.
Test not.
Perfect.
So there are all of our tests.
So in the next lecture, we'll actually connect celebrities itself to Badger if the appropriate value
is set in dorms.