So we're going to now try to connect our celebrities package to Badger if appropriate, and I'm looking
at the file celebrities don't go in the celebrities package and the very first thing I'm going to have
to do is to declare a variable here ver and I'll call it my badger cash.
Even if we don't use it, we have to have it available to us and it's a type pointer to.
Cash Badger, cash from our own cash package.
Now, if you recall, if we scroll all the way down here, we have a function that creates a client
reddest cash somewhere right here.
We're going to need another one.
Just like this, of course, is for Badger.
So fund with a receiver of C pointer to select house and we'll call it create client badger cash.
And it takes no parameters.
And it will return, of course, a pointer to Cash Dog Badger Cash.
And this is pretty much the same logic as we used before.
So we're going to have a cash client which will be assigned the value of the type cash.
Badger, Cash, Cash Dog and Badger Cash,
and we'll populate its fields and then we'll return it.
Now we're going to return right here, return a reference to cash client.
But of course, we also have to create the necessary pool of connections for Badger.
So we'll do that right here just after create.
Read us pool.
And I'll call this one because it's not really a pool of connections, funk receivers, c pointer to
celebrities.
I'll call it create badger con and it will take new parameters, but it will return a pointer to Badger
DB.
And this is dead simple.
It's exactly the same sort of thing we did in our setup test, so we'll say DB and potentially an error
or assign the value of Badger Dot open and we'll open with Badger default options once again.
And this time it will be secret path, the right path of our application plus and we'll just go slash
temp or put it in quotation marks slash temp slash badger so could have created the temp folder.
You can put it wherever you want, but this will work for our purposes.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return the error return nil.
We're not returning an error with this, otherwise we'll return the DB.
OK.
And you might want to have that return in error in addition to Badger DB.
It's entirely up to you.
Well, we can come back up here now and create our badger cache by populating the one thing that we
need, which is a connection.
As I said, I actually put in that prefix and I didn't need it, but I like to have my types basically
matching in the number and kind of field whenever possible, and that's a personal preference.
You certainly don't have to do it.
So see, does it create?
Badger can't return, so that creates our client, Badger Cash, so we're going to have to have that.
But where do we call this function?
Well, let's go back up to where we're creating the one for Reddit's, which I believe is right before
we set all the variables in here.
Here it is.
So here, just like we're checking in The O.C., get on checking the data on file for the cache, being
able to read us or the session type, being able to read us, we do a similar check right here.
We'll say if OCR don't get on.
And what we're going to look for, of course, is cash.
If that's equal to Badger,
then we have to do some work.
Pretty simple.
We'll say my badger cash is equal to see Dot create client badger cash.
So that creates that.
And then we set our cash seed out cash.
Try that again.
See that cash equal to my badger cash.
Now, here's where we need to do a lot of a little bit of periodic housekeeping.
It's basically garbage collection on the Dodger Badger database, and we need to run that once a day.
Now there is, in fact, the timer class available in the standard library in Go and I find it really
difficult to work with.
And there's a really popular and well tested and widely used package available that we can actually
import.
So I'm going to switch over to my web browser and show it to you.
It's called rub thing slash cron, and there's a link to this in the course of resources for this lecture,
and it's very easy to use.
So I'm going to copy this yet.
Version three and I'm going to switch back to my web browser or to my ID, opened my terminal window,
clear the screen and paste setting and that will go get some Figs Chrome package for us.
3.0.1.
Perfect.
So now that's available to us.
We can actually use it.
And if you think it's true, OMG doing here is I'm going to schedule garbage collection once a day.
But scheduling is something that's actually kind of common in web applications.
You often have things you need to run on a regular schedule, so maybe it makes sense to go back up
to our celebrities type and make this available to our end users so they can use it if they want to.
So I'll add something called scheduler like that, and I'll make it of type pointer to Cron Dot, and
hopefully it'll find the package for me.
Cron.
There it is.
Dot, Chrome and I'll save the format.
Then I'll go back down to where I am checking to create whether or not I have to create my connection
pool for for Badger and I'll use it.
So and it's as simple as this.
I'll ignore the first return parameter and I will pay attention to the error.
That's equal to see celebrities dot scheduler right there,
and I'll add a function and I want this to run every day so daily and I'll just run this function daily.
I'll ignore the error and say, my bad, your cash.
Dot com dot run value log GC.
That's the garbage collection, and we'll give it 0.7.
You need some parameter to say how strict should I be with garbage collection?
And I want it to be pretty strict, strict.
So I'll go with that and I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, just return the error.
And that literally should do it.
So if we've done everything right, we should be able to go back to my app.
Actually, I see an error there somewhere.
Could not import this.
No required slashing V3.
Yeah.
You probably didn't get that.
And that fixes that, so if I had that because I have a very old version of Rob Things Cron package
installed before he started using the slash v syntax.
But that's the standard now, so you probably wouldn't get that error in any case.
But if you did just add slash three at the end.
But now I should be able to go to my app, change the dot on file to say, use the Badger cache, start
the application and everything should work, and we'll give that a try in the next lecture.