So we're almost ready to try our Badger cash, but there's just a couple of things I want to do before
we do that, and I'm still insularity start go in the celebrities project and this time I'm looking
at the function listen and serve.
You'll notice here on Line 205 and my code, we're closing our database pool, but we can't assume there's
going to be a database pool.
So it will be polite to wrap this in an if statement.
If Cedar DB pool is not equal to nil, then we've actually opened a database connection.
So then and only then do we want to defer closing it, and we actually want to do a similar thing with
Badger.
So we can say if our badger connection is not equal to nil, then close that and the same thing with
Redis.
The problem is we actually don't have access to those variables.
So what I'm going to do is go to the top of this file and create some new variables.
So I'll create one for Redis pool or mine or just I'll just.
Colorado's pool is a type pointer to redistrict dark pool,
and I'll do the same thing for Badger Verb Badger Con as he is of type pointer two Badger DB.
OK, so those are now available to me.
So let's go down all the way down to where we actually check to see if we're using Redis, which is.
Right here.
So at this point, I know I'm using Reddit, I'm either using it for the cash or for the session or
for both.
But all I have to do now is to populate that variable Reddit's pool, make that equal to my reader's
cash token.
OK, so now I have a means of actually deferring a close and making the same thing with Badger.
If we get Badger here, we can see Badger Corn is equal to my badger cash dot com.
So now if we find, listen and serve again, wherever that is down here somewhere.
We can defer closing those if they're not set to nil, if red is pool is not equal to nil, then defer
rent is pool that again, British pool got close.
And similarly with Badger, if badger pool for Badger Conn is not equal to nil, then defer Badger Conn.
OK, just a bit of housekeeping.
So now we can switch over to our my app.
And find our dot on file, which is here somewhere.
There it is.
And find our cash and change that to badger and change the comment to British or Badger.
And I should be able to start my application assuming that all of my darker images are running and I'm
pretty sure they are.
Make start.
And it does a government vendor build celerity house, everything should be current.
And we have an error.
And there is.
In its letter, Tostart Go Line 21.
And it's and celebrities don't go line 110, so let's see what we got wrong there.
Let's switch over to celebrities.
Don't go look at line one hundred and ten.
So it's right here where I'm adding the function daily.
OK, we left something out.
OK, so let's go back up to the part where before we create this, although I populated the scheduler,
I never actually set it.
So let's create a variable scheduler and make that assign the value of crime new, and that was silly.
And now we set seed on scheduler equal to scheduler.
That was an oversight on my part.
You can actually schedule a crown job until you've created a new Cron object.
So we'll switch back over here and try running this again next year.
And hopefully this time it'll at least compile.
There it's running.
So let's go to our Web browser and open a new tab and go to localhost four thousand.
And let's try our cash and see if we got it right.
So we'll put in ABC with the value of saving cash, and it apparently saved it.
Let's try getting it.
ABC And that worked and let's delete ABC delete from cash.
It is gone.
Everything seems to work as expected.
Perfect.
So now we have two kinds of cash is available to us, Reedus and Badger.
So let's move on.