Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about database concept.
What is data?
Data is nothing but information that is collected in various formats, such as numbers, text, media
and others in the context of computing, data can be converted into a binary digital form that enables
flexibility to be moved around and processed efficiently.
The term data can be used either as singular or plural from time to time.
We come across the term raw data.
It is nothing but data in its most basic digital format, as data grew potentiality over the years.
The units of data measurement continue to grow as well.
Databases, database management systems or VMS and relational database management systems.
Or are they business quickly rounds to organize all these data?
What is data this?
The database is a systematic or organized collection of related information that is this stored in such
a way that it can be easily accessed, retrieved, managed and off date.
It is where all data is stored.
Very much like a library that houses a wide range of books from different genders, think of data as
books in a database.
You can organize the data in rows and columns in the form of a table.
Indexing the data makes it easy to find and retrieve the gain as and when required.
Many of its sights on the World Wide Web on engaged with the help of databases to create a database
so that the data is accessible to users through only one set of software programs, database handlers
are used more obscure, obscure server MongoDB, Oracle database, post-career school informatics,
seabass and etc. are all examples of different databases.
These modern databases are managed by the IBM's.
The Structure Query language or eschew it as it is more widely known, is used to operate on the data
in the database.
A database is typically represented by a cylindrical structure.
Database languages.
A deepness pill was appropriate language to use it to help quell databases and updates.
It essentially creates and maintains the database.
Some examples of database language are Stuart ORADUR, DBAs, A. Access Sports, Bryan, etc. Database
languages are commonly divided into data definition, language or detailed data control language or
DCA data manipulation, language or email and transaction control language or TCO data definition.
Language, or DDL, has defined data and the relationship to the other data types and creates databases,
finds tables and data dictionaries within databases, data control language or DC, and controls access
to data and the database.
Data manipulation, language or DNA, supports basic data manipulation operations like allowing the
user to insert, retrieve updates and delete data from the database.
And transaction control language, or C, manages changes in the database made by the DMR, the statement.
Types of databases.
There are various types of databases used for storing different varieties of data.
Relational databases, it is the most efficient way to access the structured information.
The data is organized into a set of tables that has columns and rules object oriented database.
Here, the data is represented in the form of object as in object oriented programming.
Distributed database It has two or more files located in different places.
The database may be in the same physical location on multiple computers or is scattered over different
networks.
No Escuela database.
Noel Stewart is a no relational database that contains on a structured and semi unstructured data.
It rose in popularity as web applications came to be commonly used and became more complex.
Graph database It installs data in the form of entities and the relationships between then centralization
database CPB DB is located, is taught and maintained in a single centralized location, for example,
a mainframe computer or desktop or server CPU operational database, also known as Old TCP or online
transactional processing database.
It is designed to create or update big amounts of data, and this sort transactions performed by multiple
users in real time data warehouses.
It is a central repository for data.
It holds current and historical data in a single location for analytical reporting throughout the enterprise.
Advantages of databases.
Minimum data redundancy.
Improved data security.
Increased consistency.
Lower updating errors.
Reduced cost of data entry.
Data storage and data retrieval.
Improved data access using haast and courier languages.
And higher data integrity from application programs.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.