Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
database concept, and in this session we want to talk about the other database concept.
Crud operations.
Corot is an acronym for Create, Read, Update and pilot.
Craft operations are basic data manipulation for database craft are the four basic function that models
should be able to do at most when we are building upon.
We want our models to provide for basic types of functionality.
The model must be able to create, read, update and delete resources.
Computer scientists often refer to this function by the acronym craft.
A model should have the ability to perform a these four functions in order to be complete.
If inaction cannot be described by one of these four operations, then it should be potentially be a
model of its own.
Create this would consist of a function which we would call when a new object is being added in a table
in the database read.
This would consist of a function which would be called to see all or a number of the objects currently
in a table in the database update.
There should be a function to call information about.
An object must be changed in a table in the database and delete.
There should be a function to call to remove an object in a table in the database.
My school database.
As we know that we can use Maya's school to use its strong circle language to store the data in the
form of our debate in this issue, it is the most popular language for adding, accessing and managing
content in a database.
It is most known for its quick processing province, reliability eases and flexibility of use.
The application is used for a wide range of purposes, including data warehousing, e-commerce and lodging
applications.
The most common use for my school, however, is for the purpose of a web database.
My Escott provides a set of some basic but most essential operations that will help you to easily interact
with the MySQL database, and these operations are known as crud operations.
Eschew a database, tables tables are used to store data within the database.
There are its main component and without them, the database would serve any other purpose.
Tables are uniquely named within a database.
Many of operations, such as queries, use these names.
Typically, a table is named to represent the type of data stored within.
For example, a table holding employee data may be called employees.
A table consists of rows and columns.
Columns columns are defined to hold a specific type of data, such as dates, numeric or textual data.
In the simplest of definitions, that column is defined by its name and data type.
The name is used in schools statements when selecting and ordering data, and the data type is used
to validate information is stored columns.
Names cannot be duplicated in a table, so having two names column is no rows.
In relational databases, Andrew is a digital record within table.
Each row, which represents a complete record of a specific item data holds different data within the
same structure.
A table can contain zero or more rolls.
Then there are zero.
It's said to be empty.
There is not a practical limit on the number of rows a table can hold.
However, remember the tables primary key may have some influence of this.
What I mean is that if your table holds the states and the primary keys is this taste abbreviation,
then by definition, since there are only 50 states in the union and you cannot have duplicates in the
primary key, your table is limited to 50 rows.
A single entry in a table is called a tuple or a record or row.
A tuple and a table represent a set of related data.
For the example, the above employee table has two Typekit or records or rows.
And what is an attribute?
A table consists of several records or rows.
Each record can be broken down into several smaller parts of data, known as attributes.
The above employee table consists of four attributes I.D. name, age and salary.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish.
Then we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.