Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
relational model and indecision.
We want to talk about the others database concept.
Crud operations in school database as we know that we can use my school to use this to alter query language
to restore the data in the form of relational database management system.
This cure is the most popular language for adding, accessing and managing content in a database.
It is most known for its quick processing problem.
Reliability eases and flexibility of use.
The application is used for a wide range of purposes, including data warehousing, e-commerce and lightning
applications.
The most common use for my school, however, is for the purpose of their database.
My school provides a set of some basic but most essential operations that will help you to easily interact
with the minuscule database, and these operations are known as crowd operations.
In this tutorial, we will implement our database based on minuscule database and explain the relationship
between the GO programming language and my school.
But you can use any database you want.
Query.
Equerry is a request for data results and for action and data, you can use it quickly to answer a simple
question.
To perform calculations, to combine data from different tables or even to add change or delete table
data.
As tables grown in size, they can have hundreds of thousands of records, which makes it impossible
for the user to pick out a specific records from that data with a query.
You can apply a filter to the tables data so that you only get the information that you want.
Queries that you use to retrieve data from a table or to make calculations or can't select queries.
Queries that add, change or delete data are called action queries.
You can also use a query to supply data for a form or a report.
In a well-designed database, the data that you want to present by using a form or report is often located
in several different tables.
Then three key part of queries is that you must understand how to construct one before you can actually
use them.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.