Hello and welcome to the golden and programming language course in the previous session.
We talked about insert into and select queries and indecision.
We want to talk about the other queries.
Updates recourse, this fuel update query is used to modify the existing records in a table, you can
use the very close with the update query to update the selected rules, otherwise all the rows would
be affected.
Now you can see the syntax for execute this query.
Go to MySchool database to create a new query.
We want to update data record of student table values in person database so before write the new query
select database by the comment use database name so right use person semicolon.
Go to the next line.
In this case, we want to change the value of the name and age fields in the record.
Whose idea values is equal to one?
So first, select a student table and see a student's information whose its ID is one.
Select a star from the student semicolon and execute the query.
Now we can see the student table for the IED number.
Vaughn name is change and age is twenty five.
And we want to change these values for name to Edward and for the age is 14.
So clear.
Select Query and write our query for Update.
Update.
Student.
Said, write the names of the fields whose values we want to change and mention the new value of each
one in front of the name of each bill like name equals
at what?
Coma and age equals 40.
And now, right condition or otherwise, there are records whose values are to be changed.
So be right there.
I.D. equals one semicolon now execute the query.
And again, select on this student table, select a star from a student and execute the query again.
Now we can see the values of name and age of the record whose idea values is equal to one has changed
the name.
Edwardian age is 14.
Now go to a site and continue.
Delayed Operation Discuter Delayed Quarry is used to delete the existing records from a cave.
You can use the word close with an idyllic query to delete the selected rules.
Otherwise, all the records would be deleted.
You can see the syntax now.
Go to my school database to create a new query.
First, clear, the last query, we to delete a record of a and table values in person database.
So before writing new query select database by the common use database name used person, in this case,
we want to delete the record whose idea value is equal to one.
So we try delete from a student and now write condition or otherwise.
The records whose idea value is wrong and is to be removed from the student tated where I.D. equals
one and set semicolon now execute the query.
Now, clear the delete query and write the Senate query for display the changes, select a star from
the student and search semicolon, execute the query.
Now we can see the record whose idea value is equal to one has removed from a student today.
So far, we have been able to perform crud operations inside the MySQL database in future sessions.
We will examine the relationship between the GO programming language and the MySchool database in order
not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.