In this section of the course, we want to implement basic validation to give our users tools that makes
it easy for them to validate forum posts or request to the API, whatever the case may be.
So I mean, this hilarious package right now, and the first thing I'll do is create a new file at the
root level of my project called validator.
And of course, that's in package celebrities.
Now, there are lots of different ways that we can implement validation, but there is no question we're
going to need a type to start with a type which I'll call validation type validation.
OK?
And it's just going to be a struct.
It's only going to have two members data and this will be used for forum posts and it'll be a type URL
right from the standard library values.
And as you can see in the help file that shows up in my I.D. value maps a string key to it to a list
of values and is typically used for query parameters in form values.
So very straightforward.
We're going to have euro values is our first one.
And we're also going to have a place to store errors and this will be a map of string string.
So if something doesn't pass validation, there will be a corresponding entry in the errors.
Map error singular.
Actually, I'll make errors plural, but sounds better because you have more than one error.
And the next thing I'm going to want is a function with the receiver of C pointer to celebrities.
And this will be how we initially are validator.
And I'll call it validator validate, validate data like that.
And it will take one parameter called data of type URL values, and it returns a pointer to the type
of validation that we just created.
OK.
So this is very simple.
We'll just return a reference to validation and we'll fill in the fields.
So errors will be make math, string string and empty map and data will be, you know, what we would
ever receive as a call to this function.
OK, now basic form validation can be a pain, and there is a really useful package.
Let me go to my web browser.
It's a really useful package that is used by a lot of go programmers, and I'll pasted all in there.
It's GitHub dot com slash slash and then the last thing that I'm not even going to try to pronounce.
Go validator.
And it's a very easy to use package, so you can read the documentation at your leisure.
There is a link to this in the course of resources for this lecture.
So I will go and get this copy back to my I.D..
You know, open a terminal window and clear the screen and paste in that comment.
And that goes and gets it for us.
This is a really useful validation package that has an awful lot of different kinds of validation that
can be implemented, and I'm only going to do a few the most basic ones, OK, to start with, I'm going
to use this function.
I'm going to create a function with a receiver of V pointed to validation, and it's going to be called
simply valid.
Invalid takes no arguments, then returns a Boolean and all or returns is the length of V errors equal
to zero.
So return LEN of VDOT errors is equal to zero.
So if there are no errors, then returns true.
But if there's at least one entry in that map string string, then it return false.
OK, so that's a pretty easy one.
Now I'll also have to have a means of adding errors to that map.
So func the pointer to validation, and we'll call this one an error and it will take a key and a message
both of type string and it returns nothing.
So we'll we'll do it if statement to make sure we're not adding something that shouldn't be added if
we don't care about the first return parameter, but we do care about exists.
And that's a sign the value of the errors looking for key and if not exists, then we just add that
error to the to the map.
The errors key is equal to whatever the error messages, and we receive that as a call to this function.
So we have a means of checking validity change by means of adding an error.
Now, let's do a simple one.
Let's do one that doesn't use go validator.
So we'll say funk with a receiver appointed a validation that again, the quantity validation.
And we'll check to see if has if the request.
This would be for form post.
If it has a particular field, so we'll look for a field i.e. bounty of type string.
And of course, we need the request as a pointer to a request.
And that will return a Boolean true, if it's in the request vaults of it's not.
So we just look in the form request to see if it has it.
So EX can call this variable.
Whatever we want is a sign the value of our the request, dot, form, dot and get.
And we're looking for fields which are received as a call to this function.
If X is equal to nothing, then return false.
Otherwise, it's in the request, so we return true.
So checking to see if a particular value is in the form post and what's this?
You OK, so we'll fix that.
Should return, that's fine.
I like it this way, I find it more readable, so I'm going to ignore that error.
You can make it a one liner if you want to.
OK, now we'll add a check for required fields.
And again, we can do this without go validator.
But we'll be getting to that in a moment.
So we'll call this one.
Func V is the receiver for type validator validation and we'll make certain fields required.
And again, this is typically for form post.
So we're going to need to request our pointer to actually beat out request, and we're also going to
need what fields are required.
So we'll make that very edit fields.
Dot dot dot string.
And it doesn't return anything.
So this one's as simple as ranging through our fields, so for we don't care about the index, we do
care about the field, so we use field.
Singular is a sign the value of range through fields.
And here we check for the value that's in a given field, the smallest store that in a field in a variable
called value.
And that's a signed art form.
Don't get.
And we're going to get filled and we say, if and here, I'm going to trim spaces just to make sure
we have something more than a blank space.
So I use the strings package dot trim space right there.
Value, if that's equal to nothing, if you take the blank spaces away, if there's nothing there,
then we'll just say that error.
And here's where we're adding an error.
We don't add error for field and we'll just put in this field cannot be blank.
And that's sufficient for our purposes.
You can put whatever you want for an error message there.
OK, now a very general purpose function, and this one will get used a lot b validation.
And we'll just call this check.
And all it's going to take is OK, which is a Boolean.
A key the fielding question and the message, which will be both be strings, and this is a very simple
function, but it's incredibly useful.
We can simply say, if not, OK, then we don't add error.
Key message and key, of course, is the name of the field in question, and this is useful both for
foreign posts and also for checking things like posted Jason on an API.
So what you pass this function, of course, is some condition something that can be evaluated to true
or false.
It could be as simple as if LEN of the field is less than two or greater than two than return true,
otherwise return false.
And that would be good for at least two characters requested or required in a field.
And we'll be using this, you know, sample code here before too long.
Let's get it out of the way.
OK, so you've installed that form validation package go validator or that validation package, but
we still haven't used it.
So let's try one.
And here we can use Go Validator, and we want to make sure that something is a valid email address
or at least in the form of a valid email address.
OK.
A simple one func the pointer to validation and we'll call this one is email, and it will take two
parameters the field that we're checking, the value that we're checking both of string.
OK, and here we can say, if not, if you were using the go validate or package and it's really, really
easy to use.
Go Validator Dot is email.
And we hand it value.
So if that's not true, then we had an error vetoing that error and we'll add the field and an invalid.
Invalid email address, as simple as that.
OK, let's just get a few more, so maybe you want to make sure that a value on a forum post is an integer
so long we want you to.
Validation is int field and value again, both of type string.
And here we can ignore the result, but check for an error and try to convert.
That was to an integer so stricken right from the standard library.
Got a two hour value and we say if error is not equal to nil, then there's an error.
So let's just add it to our map feed at error.
The field is the key and the error messages, this field must be an integer again, whatever you want
for an error message.
So let's just do a few more.
So we'll say funk again, the pointer to validation and make sure that this is a float.
Pretty much the same is float.
So we have field and value, both of type string.
I was going to copy and paste this and modify it because it's virtually identical.
So instead of calling a toy, we call pass float and we'll try to pass it to say a 64 bit float.
Doesn't matter.
Long as it can be passed to a float.
But we do need something here, so I'll put 64 and my error message will be.
A floating point number, so let's try another one for data formats.
And again, we'll just use a simple one, func the pointer to validation and I'll call that is data
ISO.
I'm in Canada, so I like the ISO date format, but you can use whatever format you want value string
just as before.
And we simply say ignoring the result, checking for an error and we call Time Dot Pass and we pass
into this format using Go's unusual date formatting syntax.
2006 zero one zero two And we want a pass value.
And again, if there's an error, I'll copy and paste this and modify that.
Must be a date in the form of Y, y y y, and you get rid of that extraneous space.
And last one, somebody you want to make sure that there's no white space in a particular field, so
we can do that really easily.
And again, this is using go validate or func the validation, and we'll call it no spaces and it takes
a field in a value both of type string.
It doesn't return anything.
But here we say, if GO Validator Dot has white space, no, no.
It has lowercase as white space.
There are value and there's white space in there and there ought not to be.
So we just add an air V2 at air field
and spaces are not permitted, and that's enough.
So now we have a validation package and in the next lecture we'll try using this and you will discover
how easy it is to work with this sort of thing.