So let's try to validate her and see how difficult that is to use.
Now I could and ultimately will build a web page that has a form on it and invalidation that way.
But I just want to make sure that things actually work as I think they should.
So here in the Maya project, I've just opened up the rootstock and go file, and I'm going to add some
validation logic to this route.
It's a get request to slash update user slash ID.
And if I look at my database, I have one user right here.
So in the user's table, have an ID, one with a first name, last name and all that sort of thing.
And what I'm going to do is just initialize a validator and run a check and make sure it works as expected.
So I can do that.
First of all, I have to make sure I don't run a government vendor, so I'm just going to say make restart
and that will build a binary and make sure it runs.
Go mod vendor.
And now I should have access to that validator package.
So let's see if we do so right here.
I, first of all, get my URL parameter, which will be one in my case, I get the user and I change
the user's last name and right here before I call the update.
I'm going to run some validation and it's as simple as this.
I'll create a variable, which I'll call.
Validator seems like a good name, and that's a sign the value of.
A$AP App Validator right there validator and a once a year old params, but I'll just hand Neil.
And that works just fine.
OK, so now I have this validators and now I can actually try something so I can say, for example.
Validator, don't check that kind of catch all useful utility, and that requires a few parameters,
and if you rolled her mouse over, it'll tell me exactly what they are.
So at once an OK, which is a condition to check, then a key, then some message.
OK, well, the OK easy.
I've set the length of last name to a random string of 10 characters, so let's put a condition that
will fail.
So Len of Say You, the last name is greater than 20.
I know that's going to fail and we're going to check the field last name, which doesn't matter.
We just want this to fail and we want an error message.
Last name must be 20 characters or more, which is very unusual.
You would never do this, but I want this to fail.
I know at this point I can say, if validator valid, then do something, otherwise do something else.
So what I'll do instead is say, if it's not valid, if we fail validation, then I'm going to print
out an error message, OK?
And what I'll print out is something as simple as format dot f print f print on W and just say failed
validation.
OK, and I'll return.
I don't want to go any further.
Otherwise, I want this update now in our situation, of course, this code will never execute, and
that's fine.
I just want to make sure the validator works the way that it's supposed to.
So I'll say make restart.
And I will go to the update user pass.
So get it back to my web browser and change this to slash update dash user and then one.
The one idea I have in the database, and if this works, I should get an error message printed the
screen failed validation and it failed validation.
Perfect.
So that looks pretty straightforward.
Now, obviously, I can call any of the functions that are available to me.
Some of them won't work because this is not actually a form post, but those are available any time
I need to validate data.
Now it would be it would be great if I could have default validation rules on individual data models.
And it turns out we can and will do that sort of thing in the next lecture.
We'll add some validation rules right to the user model.