So as I suggested last time, sometimes it's very helpful to have validation right on data models and
we can do that.
It's pretty easy.
So right now I'm looking at user don't go in my app inside the data folder.
What I'm going to do is right here just after the table function and before they get all that.
It doesn't matter where it goes, but I'm going to put it here, put a validation function.
And again, it takes the receiver of you, pointed a user, and we'll call it validate.
And it will take one argument of type.
We'll call it validator of type a pointer to select a toss dart validation.
And it doesn't return anything, even though it's validation.
So we're going to have rules for a particular data model.
Now, if you think it through.
What kinds of things do you want, no matter what you're doing and in search or an update?
Well, we'll just put a few in here and you can modify them to whatever you want them to be.
So I'll call my validator function, which we received as a parameter to this function.
And I'll call check on that and I'll make sure that you don't last name is not equal to an empty string.
And the field I want to check, of course, will probably be called last underscore name, and that's
a convention you would have to follow in order for this validation to work.
But it's pretty straightforward.
And we'll give it an error message.
Last name must be provided.
And I'll duplicate that.
And if the same thing for first name.
First name.
And first thing,
then I'll duplicate it again and assume that you also want to have the email included so you don't email
and the field would be email.
Am I convention is whatever these field names are matches what's in the database and it keeps things
dead simple.
And will change this to email must be provided, and we'll just do one more validator Dot is email.
And that just requires the parameter email, the field, your checking and the value you email.
So now that I've added this validation function to my user model.
It's available to me anytime I'm working with a user.
So in the next lecture, we'll try it out and make sure that this works the way that we think it's supposed
to.