So we've added some validation right to our data model users and the rules are last name must not be
empty, first name must not be empty, email must not be empty and email has to be in the form of a
valid email address.
So let's try it.
So we'll go back to our roots.
Don't go right in the Maya project.
And again, I'm going to work with this update user route.
So we created a validator.
This time I'm going to delete this one rule that we have for validation, and I'm going to, at this
point, change the last name to an empty string.
So I'll say you don't last name is equal to an empty string.
And I know that's redundant because I said, it's value right here, but it doesn't matter.
I just want this validation to fail.
So now that I've already created my validator variable, all I have to do is call you is I have a model's
user right now.
Don't validate and hand it validator, and everything else should stay pretty much the same because
my validation should fail at this point.
So let's try it out.
That's the only thing we're checking is a validation on the data model.
So I open my terminal window and I type make restart.
And I go back to my web browser and I go to slash update slash user slash one because I have one user
on my database with the idea of one and validation should fail at this point.
And it does things work exactly as expected.
Now the great thing about this is I can put validation, basic validation on all of the models that
I'm working with on a regular basis.
And calling validation, no matter where you happen to be, is as simple as calling.
Whatever the variable is, you for user, for example, don't validate and hand it an instance of the
validator.
Now this is all well and good, but it might be helpful at this point to actually build a web page and
try a real form validation as it should exist.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture or two.