So let's try building a simple form and use the validation rules and tools that we have at our disposal
now.
So in the course resources for this lecture, you will find a file you can download called Formed Object
and put it here in the My App project, right in The View's directory.
So I'm going to create a new file called Form Objets.
And I've already copied the contents of this form to my clipboard, so I'll paste it in.
You get it in there in whatever way works for you, and you will notice that there are a couple of bugs
in the jet plug in for this.
But I think I can make those go away just by changing the wrapper for this to a single quote.
And that would end right here.
Yeah, that looks better.
So I'm going to change it this way and I'll change it on the file.
Here as well.
OK, so now those errors go away.
So this is a pretty simple form.
Third place is right here.
There, the jet plug in got confused and thought there were too many double quotes all over the place.
Changing the quotes for the actual class attribute for each of the three inputs makes the air go away.
OK, very simple layout.
It extends based jet and I give it the browser title of form.
It has no custom CSS, but I need to put that block in there.
Otherwise it won't compile and it page content.
I have a simple form now.
It's virtually a simple bootstrap form with a couple of additions.
Let me draw those to your attention.
The first one is here in the value and it has a first name and last name and an email field.
In the first name field, for example, I have the values set to user dot first name.
And as you might expect, I'll be passing a user model as data to this template.
And then I have here in the class, a simple decision.
One of the nice things about the jet plug in the jet templating engine is that it allows us to use the
is set.
We can check to see if a variable is set, if it is, do something, otherwise do something else and
it comes in the form of a ternary here.
So is set validator errors first name.
So you can see I'm also going to be passing the validator as an object or as data to this template.
If the errors, which is a map string string, if the Errors Map Index first name is set, then display
is invalid because there's an error associated with this field.
So I'll be adding the class is invalid to this input and that's bootstraps validation classes.
Otherwise don't add anything.
I do exactly the same thing for all three of these fields.
And that's the only difference, apart from the invalid feedback which I'll talk about in a second.
The only difference between a regular bootstrap input and the kind that I'm using here in this template.
And of course, we also want to display error messages, if any.
So each of the three fields first name, last name and email also has a div class equals invalid feedback.
And again, I use my ternary.
My is set as a.
If there's an errors in the first name field this time.
Display the contents of the validator errors map.
So display the error message right here unless otherwise displayed nothing.
So very simple template.
And I'll let you review that at your leisure and play with it.
But we also, of course, need some handlers.
So inside of my handlers folder, let's create some handlers.
I'll put them in their own file so they're easy to find our common form for our dash.
They'll dash handlers don't go.
You can call it whatever you want, but form validation handlers make sense or form ball handlers.
And of course, this is in package handlers and we're going to need two handlers one to display the
form, which is easy and one to submit the form and validate the data.
OK, so let's do the display first.
So we'll say func.
And it has a receiver, of course, a pointer to handlers, and I'll call this form, call whatever
you want.
This is going to display my form and it takes a W of a type H-He response writer and ah, as a pointer
to actually beat up request W4.
Write an hour for read or request.
So verse, first thing I want to do is declare a variable called verse, and this is straight out of
the documentation.
If I want to pass data to a jet variable, I think we've done this already.
I just say make jet verb.
And that should do the import for me.
And it did.
OK, so now we have this verse.
And what I'm going to say is validator creating a validator.
That's a sign of the value of each app.
And because the app has a function called validator from the version validator, I can use that and
I'll just pass it now.
So default value is nil.
Nothing in that validator, and I will set two pieces of data.
I want to be available to my template.
The first one is validator.
So first set and the key I'm going to use to find it in the template is validator and the value is validator.
So I'm passing that and also VARs Dot set.
And that's what I'll call user, and it will be an empty user model data dot user with, of course,
the two curly brackets so we can pass that.
Now, I just render my template, so I'll say error is a sign of the value of H Dot app Dot render.
And I'm going to render I have to pass it W and R and the name of the template.
In my case, it's called formed yet.
So I put forth the variables I want to pass and I'm not passing data in the fourth parameter for one
two three fifth parameter.
My counting is off today and I'll just check Verner.
So H Typekit render.
What is it saying here?
Cannot call non-functioning pitch right there, rendered up page.
Now a check for an error, if error is not equal to nil, then we'll just write it to the Error H Dot
app dot error log scribbling, whatever the error is.
OK, so that's enough to show the picture.
Let's make sure that works.
So let's go to our roots file.
And I'll just add a root say right before all these test routes right here, and we'll link to it on
our homepage as well.
So we'll say a dot app, dot routes, not routes, rendered routes, dot get and I'll make this one
signal and that will call a dot handler's platform.
OK, and I'm going to create the second one and comment it up because we'll need it in a minute.
We'll make that a post that goes to post form, and I will comment it out so we can compile this.
So now I have a route to that.
Let's open our homepage and my route is form.
So let's open our homepage, which is home dot job.
And we'll just add one right here form validation, I'll call it,
and it goes to slash four.
OK, let's reset our application.
Make restart just to make sure that form shows up.
And let's go back to our web browser and try reloading this page.
OK, so the link shut up.
Does it work?
There it is.
So we have a basic form right here.
Now you will also notice if we go back and look at that form page form on jet.
One of the things I put at the very top was no validate.
I turned off browser validation and I did not.
At the bottom of this file enable the standard bootstrap client side validation.
So I only want to use server side validation using the validation logic we implemented over the last
few lectures.
So we have the form up there.
In the next lecture, let's create that post form handler and do some actual server side validation.