So reformist displaying properly now let's implement the post handler and put some server side validation
in there, so we'll create a function A. My roots file, even though it's commented out, h handlers,
we called it submit form.
So let's call it submit form Whv Typekit, our response writer and ah, as a pointer to HTTP request.
So in the go world, anytime you post to form, you call from the request form and you check for an
error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll just log it and return each app.
The error log dot print line the error and we'll just return because this is just the test route anyway.
There are test functionality.
It's not a fully featured web app, so we don't really care about that sort of thing.
Now, as I did before, in my roots file this time in I'm in a handler, but we're going to do the same
thing.
We'll create a validator and it will be assigned a value of each app validator and we had it nil.
So now we have a validator and let's set up our validation rules.
So we have on the form, we have three fields first name, last name and email.
Let's make them all required, validator required.
And we just handed the request and all the fields we want to be required.
First name, last name and email.
So that's one rule.
Let's put some other ones in just to be safe validator.
That is email.
In this case, I just handed email and I'm going to hand it our form.
Don't get email whatever was typed into the form, if anything.
And we'll also put in two more just because we can check one say validate or not check.
And we need a Boolean condition.
So we'll say art form.
Don't get, and I'll say, the first name, first name.
Make sure you name these fields are Typekit these field names correctly.
You're going to have an arrow that's hard to track down will make the length of that.
I put a letter in front of it
green to the moon.
It's got to be at least two characters.
OK.
And that's for first name.
And my error messages must be at least two characters.
OK.
And we'll duplicate that and do the same thing for last name.
So those are validation rules.
So let's do a check here, if not validator dot valid.
Then what I want to do is take them back to that form and populate the form fields with the values that
were in there before they submitted and display error messages, if any.
So we're going to create a reverse variable and that will be just like a knee in the handle of the displays.
The form make jetport VAR map and we'll add the validator to it versus set, and it has to be called
the same thing validator and that's equal to validator.
Now, Validator has the errors map populated with information and will create a user very user of type
data dot user and we'll populate its fields with whatever they typed in user type.
First name is equal to art form dot.
Get the first name and no duplicate that I make this last name and make this last name and email.
Email is email all lowercase.
And then I set the user in my verse.
So verse, dot set and call it user just like it did in the first handler.
And the value is user and I render the page.
If error is assigned, the value is assigned the value of each dot app dot render Typekit page.
And that requires W and R and the view, which is form.
And our data, which is verse, you know, and if the error is not equal to nil, then we'll just log
the error again.
HK app dot error log dot print line the error and I'll return.
But if we get past that, all I'm going to do is just say valid, so format dot f print w valid data,
OK, at this point, I should be able to go back to my roots file uncomment this and hopefully that
will show up.
Apparently, I called it post form here.
So let's go back to my handlers.
We call it post form there.
OK.
Make restart.
Go to my Web browser.
Go back to the home page.
Go to form validation.
Then let's try submitting the form with nothing in it and there and I have valid data, which means
I have a return in the wrong place.
So let's go back here to Visual Studio code.
Find that handler and say, Return here.
Let's try that again.
Make restart.
That's better.
And go back to our form here and go to the homepage and go to form validation and try submitting the
form.
Perfect doesn't say valid down here like I did a moment ago.
Now let's give it one character submit form and change the error message to must be at least two characters
and did repopulate that form field.
Let's go B and C submit form.
All three fields are there.
See at sea, which is still not a valid email address because it has to have a dot something at the
end.
I still should get an invalid email address and I do, and if I make this dot com, that error message
should go away and it does.
And if I make these two characters that should go away and it does, and if I make these two characters,
I should just see the word valid printed up here validator.
There were error that worked exactly as expected.
OK, that's enough for form validation.
Let's move on.