So the next step in this project is to actually run a schedule that will perform checks on all of the
services for all of our hosts on a predetermined schedule.
So our default is to run the checks every three minutes and we'll probably make that shorter for development
just so we don't have to wait three minutes to see if things work.
But to make that happen while we there's a number of ways we could do this, we could.
And I'm going to go langue right now.
And looking at the package time, we could use the built in functionality.
That's part of the standard library called the timer.
So if I search for a timer on this page and go to type timer, we have all of the functions necessary
to do this built into the standard library.
But I'll tell you right now, this is a difficult package to work with.
And normally when I'm writing go code, I never reach for a third party package if the functionality
I need is already built into the standard library.
This is one of the exceptions.
I don't like working with the timer package.
I've done it before and we could do it.
But it's a lot simpler just to use a package like this one.
And this is called Chron and it's made by Rob Thig.
It's on this URL and I'll post a link to this on the course resources for this page.
This is the one I'm going to use because this makes working with schedules ever so much easier.
So I'm going to copy this part right here.
Actually, I'll copy the whole thing to make sure we have exactly the same
version imported into our code.
And I'm going to go back to my idea and stop my application and clear the screen and just go get that
package.
OK, so that will go and get it.
And now it's available to us, so it should be in my go mod file, let's make sure here and there it
is, it's been important.
So we have that available to us.
How are we going to use it?
Well, first of all, let's go to our main package and look at the main Digo file.
And in that I have a thing called set up app.
So let's look at that function.
And right at the bottom here, after we define our application configuration and all of these things,
let's let's make sure this is going to work.
Right.
APCLS a.
Then our preference map.
Good.
So right here, I'm going to do it just between Apte client equals W.S. client, and before I create
any new Helper's, I'm actually going to create a timer, something that I'm going to store in my app
config, and this will hold our schedule.
So the first thing I'm going to do is set a time zone.
I'm going to make it simple.
I'll create a new variable called Local Zone just so I know what my what time zone I'm working with.
And I'll ignore the error and I'm going to call from the time package load location and my location
is just going to be local.
So I'm going to use the local location.
OK, now I'm going to create a new scheduler and here's where we're using the Quran package.
So I'll create a scheduler which I will call scheduler, and it will be assigned the value of Chron,
which is our new package.
We just imported new and it requires some options and the options are just going to be Quraan with location.
And our location will be the location we just defined, local zone.
And I'm also going to give it a kronborg with chain.
Try that again with chain.
And on the next line, I'll make this a little more readable by having this over and coming up into
here.
And passing it Kronborg DeLay if still running, and I'll use Kronborg default longer and we'll go through
this in a minute.
And the last thing is Kronborg recover and we'll use Kronborg default longer.
OK, so this creates a new variable and that variable has some options.
So the first thing I'm telling it is I want to create a schedule and the schedule should use the location,
the time zone of our local time zone, which I defined right here.
And this Chron is being developed with a chain, things that will take place so it won't run a task
if the task is already still running.
So we don't have overlapping, overlapping tasks and I will log information if necessary.
And if one dies, just recover and keep the schedule going and log the error.
And that's all that that's doing.
I want to put this in my app config.
So let's look at our app config, which is right over in our.
Config, config, go, we already have a place in here to hold this, and I put it in as part of the
starter code and it's called Scheduler and Type Kronborg Chron.
So back in my setup app, I can come down here and simply say app dot scheduler equals scheduler.
OK, so that creates the scheduler and it stores it in the app config, but that's not enough.
We actually need to run this as well.
And what we want is something that runs all the time or at least runs where we want it to be running.
So I'm going I'm going to in my command web folder.
I'm going to create a new file.
Which I will call start monitoring, start dash monitoring, go, OK.
So there it is.
I will add that to my repository and this is going to have a few things in it.
First of all, I'm going to create a type which I'll call job, and that will be a stripped and that's
just going to have nothing more than the host service ID, which will be an ant.
And this is a unit of work we're in.
I store the host service ID now.
We only have one right now.
So this is going to have a lot of information to start with.
But if we have multiple hosts and multiple services, this can get quite large over time.
OK, now I'm also going to create a function here and I'll call this func J for job.
That's its receiver.
And I'm not using a pointer receiver, which is unusual, but in this case it's appropriate.
And this function is just called run and all it's going to do is run a schedule check.
Right now there's no scheduled checks, so I'll leave that empty for the moment.
We'll come back in here and we'll put in the unit of work to be performed or the task that performs
a given unit of work a little bit later on.
What I'm interested in right now is this function, which I'm going to call start monitoring, OK?
And it takes no arguments and it does something actually does quite a few things.
OK, so the first thing I'm going to check is should I actually be running my schedule now?
I'm going to look at the database for a moment.
And inside of the database, we have something called preferences and the contents of that.
And this is part of what you actually have from your default starter code is you have an entry called
Monitoring Underscore Live, and it's of Idy one.
And right now it has a value of zero.
OK, so just make a note of that and let's go back to our code and I'm going to check right away if
preference map.
And the key I'm looking for is monitoring live.
If that's equal to and it's a strong one, then start monitoring.
Otherwise don't, and we'll be able to turn that on or off in our application using this toggle right
here, which isn't hooked up yet, but we'll get to that eventually.
So that's how we're going to turn monitoring on and off.
And the reason we're setting that is because when this is running in the background, we don't want
to monitor things.
If that's set to zero, if it's set to one, we do.
And we actually want to do a number of things inside of this loop.
So to start with, I'm going to create a variable.
I'm calling data and I want to sign that and I'll make that of type map.
It'll be a map of string.
Strength.
OK, and that data is going to have lots of things in it.
Right now, I'm going to put one value in it data message.
Is equal to starting, not staring, starting.
OK, so I'm just sticking sticking that in there when this actually starts.
And then I want to at this point, we can read a few comments and we'll come in, write the code later
on at this point.
I want to actually trigger a message to broadcast to all clients, letting them know that the that the
app is starting to monitor.
OK, so that's what we're going to do once this started.
We're going to we're going to send a message and that will actually send a message to every page for
every client who's connected to our service, to our Web site.
And we're going to do something with that message.
Not right now, but we'll get to that eventually.
OK.
And then we want to get all of the services that we want to monitor.
So I'm going to put a to do here.
So I don't forget this, OK?
We want to get all of the services that we want to monitor and then we want to range through the services.
So we're going to go to the database.
We're going to go to our host services.
We're going to find all of the hosts services that are active, and we're going to monitor those according
to the values we find from that query to the database.
So once we arrange those services, as we're arranging through them, what do we want to do?
We want to I'll just have it in here, get these schedule.
Unit and number.
So we're going to get that information, then we're going to create a job.
That's a type job up here, then we're going to save the ID of the job so we can start or stop it.
This will allow us to add a task to our schedule and then start it or stop it without removing the entire
schedule, which is pretty, pretty helpful.
And for each of these tasks, we want to broadcast overheads over WebSocket.
So broadcast over WebSocket.
So, uh, the fact that the service
is scheduled.
And then we want to end our range.
So this is what we're going to do and let's just go through it again, so right away we're declaring
a type named job and that's a struct that just holds the whole service.
OK, then we're going to run the job and we're not going to do that right now, but we'll do it eventually.
Start monitoring, will actually make sure that we are monitoring by looking at the preference map.
If that value is equal to one, then we create a map, we put a message into it.
We trigger a message to broadcast to all of the clients that the app is starting to monitor its services
and that will give some feedback on whatever pages are appropriate to get that kind of feedback.
Then we'll go to the database and get all the services that we want to monitor will range through those
services.
We'll get the schedule unit and numbers so we know how frequently to run this in our schedule will create
a job and added to our schedule will save the idea of the job so we can start or stop it and we'll broadcast
the fact that the service is pending.
It's going to be monitored to all of the clients that need to get that information.
So that's the basic logic.
Now, first thing we're going to have to do, of course, is to write some code to get all of the services
that we do want to monitor from the database.
So we'll start working on this code, including the run function in the next few lectures, and it will
take a little while to get this going, but it's not that difficult.
All right.
So let's get started on that in the next lecture.