I just have a little aside here, as I was recording this course, the rudder were using GOCE.
If you go to that website or go to the GitHub repository and scroll down, you will see that we now
have semantic versioning.
So he's actually changed the way that we import this, which means that we probably should update our
dependency to use the new version.
So I'm going to copy the entire install thing here.
And not the only change from the last time we did this was slash V5 has been added to the install you
URL and I'll go back to my ID and I should caution you that my ID is going to try to be helpful and
it will make updating this just a little tricky, but not too bad.
So I'm going to go get that dependency and it adds it and then I'll go to everywhere that I'm using
this and I'm using it for sure in my file.
And all I really need to do is to come up here and change this, to slash V5 and hopefully it won't
do what it often does and try to import things for me.
OK, so it seemed to work that time.
Now let's find out where else we're using this.
I'm going to begin a search in here by saying find in files and I'm looking at my command web folder
and I'll look for cheap and it finds it only in my rootstock go.
Perfect.
OK, so now I know it's also being used in my handlers to get parameters, so I'll find in files, cheat
and I'll open this in the find window.
And the first place that's using it is my handlers don't go.
So let me go to that and scroll to the top and change the import to the five.
OK, that worked.
Where else do we have it?
So we had in our handler stock, we also have it and perform checks Dargo So let's open that up and
scroll to the top and change that to V5.
And if there are no errors and there are not, then that should work.
So the only other change here, if I look at my go mod file, I actually have two versions of CZI installed
right here and I don't need both of those now.
I could manually delete this, but the proper way to do it, of course, is to just make sure you're
in the level of your project and type go mod tidy.
And that should and it did it got rid of the old one, and that's all there is to it.
So now we've updated our dependency to use the correct new version that supports semantic versioning.
And that's just a little aside.
And I like to keep things up to date whenever possible, so I'll commit and push this to my repository.
And let's move on.