So we're working on getting our schedule to monitor specific services on specific hosts working, and
we left it off right.
Here's where we start monitoring only if monitoring live is equal to one.
So before we forget, let's go over to our database and look at the vigilante database, which is right
here, and just go to our preferences and we'll be doing this differently later on.
But right now, I'm just going to manually change that to a one.
And the reason I'm going to do that is when you look at this code, our start monitoring function doesn't
do anything unless monitoring live is set to one.
So I've made that change.
And I'm also going to make sure that I have IP running and I do.
Perfect.
OK, so let's continue getting things set up.
Now, you might notice right here at the very top of this start dash monitoring Digo file, which is
inside our command web folder.
I have this function run and it doesn't do anything at the moment.
It's just an empty function.
So just to get things moving along so we can actually get it started and start testing things, I'm
going to create a function.
I'm going to go over to my perform checks echo.
And inside of this I'm going to create a new function and I'll put it near the top just right about
here, just after I define my type JSON rasp.
And you can put it wherever you want, but I like it here.
I'll create a new function, which I'll call schedule check function and it'll have the receiver of
Repo DB repo and I'll just call it scheduled check and it will take one parameter and I'll call it host
service ID because that's what it is.
It's an end and it doesn't return anything and that will at some point actually perform our checks.
But right now I just have it empty and we'll come back and populated with some logic a bit later on.
So I'll give it a comment.
And this performs a scheduled check on a host service by idee.
OK, so I'll copy that.
That function name, go back to my start monitoring and inside of here I'll simply call that repo dot
and I'll pass in Jadot post service ID as the parameter.
So that's going to take a job using a receiver is how it gets it and it will actually perform that schedule
check.
And right now it doesn't do anything.
But at least I have the logic set up.
It's all wired together so I can call it now down here in these start monitoring bit.
I've created a map of type string string and I've called it data, and this is the payload that will
be sent to all connected clients over WebSocket using Pusha or IP in our case.
So that's what the data variable is.
And what I've done here is put in one thing, the message and I've just said started and I can actually
make this a little little easier monitoring.
Is starting OK, so that's just the message that's going to be pushed, all the clients now for the
very first time in quite a while, let's actually push something over WebSocket.
And since I'm in the main package, I actually have access to the app variable, which means I can use
the client, which is a member of the app variable.
So I'll check for an error.
There is a sign of the value of app client trigger and we did this once before and this has to be triggered
to a specific channel, which I'll call the public channel because I want everyone who's online right
now in our app to see this.
It has to have a label and I'll call this app Dash Starting, which nobody sees, but we're going to
using JavaScript on the client and I just pass at the data that I've created already and I'll check
for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And all I'm going to do here is log print line error.
OK, and then we'll take this comment from right here and put it where it belongs.
Right here and get rid of them to do, because that's done now, it's actually triggering it and pushing
it to all the connected clients.
Now, we're not listening for that in the JavaScript yet, but we'll get to that before too long.
So the next thing we want to do is actually to get a list of all the services that we want to monitor,
which means we need a database query.
So I'll write the code first, then I'll go add the database query right afterwards.
So I'll say services to monitor, which is just a variable I'm creating potentially an error are assigned
the value of.
And this, this function I'm about to call doesn't exist yet, but it will in a moment repo db dot get
services to monitor and it won't take any parameters.
And again, we're just going to be checking for an error and printing it out so this doesn't exist yet.
Let's go create it.
So I'll go over to my host, underscore postgrads file and I'll create a new function func and it will
take a receiver of M of type postgrads DB repo and I'm calling this get services to monitor.
It doesn't take any parameters, but it will return a slice of models that host service and potentially
their.
OK, now, because I always make mistakes when I type out the context logic, I'm going to copy that
and paste it in as I always do.
And then we're going to need a query which will write in a minute.
And after we have our query, we wrap it up with a sign operator improperly.
Will execute that by looking getting our rose and potentially an error, and that will come from Magdeburg
query context behind it, our context, will it our query and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil log print line error.
And we need a variable to hold all this information.
So we'll create a new variable where services is of type slice of models, dot host service will defer
our rose dot close and then four rows dot next and we'll create a variable to hold our individual host
service H which is of type so far H models dot host service and then we will check for an error while
we scan.
Our rose or try that again, rose Tascam.
And we'll have some entries in here in a minute.
OK, so let's go get a query written before we go any further.
Now, when we're looking for host services, and I'm pretty sure that here, this query will almost
we'll do almost exactly what we want.
So I'm going to copy that as my starting point.
I'm going to go over to my Idy or to my database client, and I'll just paste that query in there and
see what that's going to give us.
If I execute that, that gets me all of my host services and it's almost enough information.
So I'm going to get my host services.
I'll get the host service ID, the host side of the service.
Pretty perfect.
OK, I probably I might want the host name as well, so I'm going to put a left join hosts h on each
dot id equals HS host ID so that joins the host table and I'm also going to grab the hostname.
So the host name.
OK, now is there anything else I want to change here.
Do I want to monitor services or hosts that are not active.
No I do not.
So I'll just add where each active equals one and active equals one.
I don't care what order they come in because I'm just going to be adding this to a schedule.
So let's make sure this works.
It does.
Let's copy this entire query.
Go back to our code and paste that right in here.
OK, and I'll just format this a little bit better.
Just to make it more readable.
And tab this over, and that should get us all the information we need, which means we can now scan
this into our room.
So we're scanning this new A variable H and the first thing we're getting is the ID.
And then I'll duplicate this a few times and then we're getting the host ID.
Then we're getting the service idee.
Then we're getting the active, which will always be one, but I'm going to get it anyway.
Then the schedule No.
And I'll duplicate this again a few times, and we're just getting the schedule unit, then we're getting
the last check.
Then we're getting the status and duplicate that a few more times than the created at the updated at
the SCD, that's a service ID, so services.
So we service the ID, then the service name.
Then whether it's active, then it's Eikon.
Created an updated that and hostname icon has a capital R.
Created a.
Updated and finally on hostname.
OK, so we checked for an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll logged our print line, the
error and I'll return.
What did I call that?
Services return services and the error otherwise appended to the slice and so say services equals append
services.
And I called this variable H and then down here return services and no.
And I think I have a typo up here.
Yes I do seatbacks.
All right, so that all seems to be correct, so let's copy the signature for this, put it in our repository
so we have access to it, go back to our start monitoring and now we have services to monitor.
Now, at this point, I just want to print things out to make sure they're working.
So I will just range through services tomorrow.
So first of all, I'll say logged print line length of services to monitor just to make sure I have
some values in.
There is.
And I'll say Lynn.
Services to monitor.
OK, so let's just see if we can get all of this to run the way that it's supposed to.
So just as a reminder, before we run this, make sure you have your your IP running and now we'll we
need to actually call this before it's going to do anything.
So let's go back to our set up app and go.
And at this point right here, what do I want to do?
I've added it to my scheduler.
I'll start it by saying app dot scheduler dot start, which will actually start the scheduler.
Then I want to actually call that start monitoring function, so I'll just start monitoring.
OK, now let's go over there to start monitoring, make sure this is actually going to run.
So I'll just put a log in here logged print line and I'll put a bunch of stars in it so I can see it
starting.
Monitored.
So that actually should work if we unless we've made some type of somewhere, so let's make sure where
this is going to work, I'll run this.
So it says starting monitor length of services to monitor is one perfect, so it looks like it actually
worked for us, but let's make sure we've got the right service in there.
Let's put a few more things out just to make sure for underscore X is a sign the value of range services
to monitor and I'll just print some stuff out.
Logged up print line service to monitor on and I'll put in the hostname, which is X dot hostname is
X dot service dot service name.
OK, let's just make sure it's actually monitoring the ones that we want and I'll put a couple of stars
in front of it so I can see it stop my application.
Cleared the screen and run the application.
Service to monitor on localhost is TDP perfect, so we're getting closer.
OK, so we'll pick this up in the next lecture and actually start adding services to our monitoring
map and making sure that we have access to them after they've been added to the schedule.
Because one of the things we're going to want to be able to do is to start or stop a service without
stopping the entire schedule and starting it again.
And we'll start that in the next lecture.