So we know that we're getting all the host services we want to monitor, and that's good so I can get
rid of these log print lines here.
I don't need that one anymore and I don't need that one anymore.
I do need this range.
I'm going to move this comment up above this for Loop because that's we're arranging it through things.
And what we want to do inside of here is all this stuff.
So I'll get rid of this and replace this with that, OK, and format things.
So according to this, the next thing I want to do is to get the service, the schedule unit and number,
which is pretty straightforward.
Now, if we go back over to the GitHub repository for Quraan and we click on this, refer to the documentation
right here that will take me to this page.
And if you scroll down a little bit, you'll see the usage.
It's not far down and it shows how you actually add functions to the schedule to whatever you want to
run so you can use the same syntax you would if you're familiar with Chron on Linux or Unix or a Mac,
for that matter.
Or you can use the shorthand hourly or every one hour, 30 minutes, and you can add the manually to
a running Chron as well, which we're going to do at some point very soon.
And we can also look at entries in that list.
And finally, we know how to stop our schedule if we want to, and we know how to start it as well.
It's a start.
We did that already in the last lecture.
So let's go back here and see how we're going to do this.
Well, I want to get the schedule unit and.
No, but I actually want to use that as a string because again, everything here is added as a string.
So so let's create a string.
I'll just call it over for schedule, and that's a type string.
And then I will look at the schedule unit and build the string, the schedule unit and the schedule
number and build it as necessary.
Now, back in our database, just to remind us, if we look at the hosted services table, we have schedule
number, which is an entry and schedule unit, which is a string, and we put 3M to monitor every three
minutes.
But I might want to put days in there.
OK, so that would probably be D.
So what I'm going to do is just say if.
Extorts scheduled unit.
Is equal two days, D, four days and do something, otherwise do something else, and I'm going to
build my string here that we'll use to add a unit of work to our schedule, to add the service we want
to monitor to our schedule.
So I'll simply say is equal to formatters productive.
And I'm going to say, first of all, if it's days I'll just say at every percent D percent s, which
will be our placeholders and are placeholders, our exact schedule number times twenty four, because
there will be days.
And hours, OK, so if I put one day, this will change it to 24 hours, which is pretty straightforward,
otherwise even simpler.
C.H. is a sign, the value of format that is pretty rough.
And I'll say at every percent D percent s just like I did before.
But now I'll just put in the schedule number in the schedule unit Eckstut schedule no, not multiply
by anything and extorts schedule unit.
So now I have my strength.
OK, so I've got my string to add things in there correctly, so now I'm just going to create a job
and we already have that job to find right up here.
It just holds a hose service, Heidi.
So I'll say va jay job, jadot hose service.
It is equal to try that again.
I guess I missed the air.
There we go for our job and Jadot service, Heidi.
Is equal to X, don't hide because that's a whole service.
So now I've created my unit of work and I want to have the job.
So if you go back and look the documentation again, it's really straightforward to add a job.
You add it like this.
OK, so I can just call my scheduler, which is app dot scheduler, Dot Ajam and job, and I'm going
to add my unit of my schedule, which is a C.H. and my unit of work, which is my job right now.
That's great.
And that's great for scheduling something and a work.
But what if I want to remove this from the schedule or modify an entry in the schedule?
Well, it turns out that at job, if you look at the the.
Signature it it returns an entry ID and an error, so I'm going to get that entry because I'm going
to use it and I'll call that schedule ID potentially an error are assigned the value of get that and
I'll check for a log if error are for an error, if error is not equal to nil.
And I'll just log on the error.
So I just want to get this running.
Now, I've got that schedule.
What am I going to do with that schedule?
It's pretty straightforward.
If you go over to our config file, which is in our internal folder in config, I have an entry in here
called Monitor Map, and it's a map of it with a Chron entry ID as the contents of a two entries.
We look at it by an end and we get a current entry.
So let me go back to start monitoring and actually add that to our monitor map.
So I'll say app monitor map.
And the idea going to look it up for look it up by is our host service, it's extra ID and it will be
equal to schedule.
And because maps are immutable, any time I make an entry to that map, it's available everywhere.
So I've now added that ID to the schedule, to the monitor map.
So I'm going to put a comment here.
Actually, I have it right here.
I'll take that comment.
Cut it.
Paste it here and take this comment, cut and paste it here just so things are in the right order.
So I've now saved that.
To my monitor map, and that will allow me to start it or stop it as required, the next thing I want
to do is to broadcast the fact that this has been scheduled to all of our connected clients.
Now, you might at some point have been asking yourself, why are you sending this to WebSocket?
Because the only time this appears to run is when the application starts.
Presumably while the application is starting, there are no connected one Web clients.
And that's not entirely accurate.
I have my application running right now, so let me go to localhost four thousand.
We're going to have this toggle switch.
It's going to be possible to start and stop our entire schedule just by toggling this.
And when that happens, when I turn it off, if I'm looking at something like this, for example, our
problems or our settings in other settings, our schedule, I want this to update whenever I click this.
In other words, the only time we're not going to be just starting this, our monitor map, our monitoring
schedule at the application start, we may start it and stop it at any time.
That's why I'm putting this stuff in here.
So let's go back here and broadcast the fact that website broadcast over WebSocket is the fact that
the service is scheduled.
So we do that again by creating a data and this will be an internal data.
So maybe I'll call it payload.
Payload is assigned the value of make map, string, string.
And this is the same kind of variable that we have way up here.
This data.
I just don't want to reuse that one.
I don't like doing that.
I don't like variable shadowing or the possibility of running into a variable shadowing error.
So I'll give it a new name.
So I've created that and payload message, I'm putting an entry in there.
Is equal to scheduling, OK?
It doesn't matter what it is, I'm just putting some value in there and data.
I'm going to put in also the host service side.
So I'm going to be sending a message and I want to tell.
All connected clients, what this scheduling event is tied to.
So I'm putting in hosted service it and that will be assigned the value of or get the value of Sterkel
into a Eckstut ID.
So I'm converting an event to a string because my map only holds strings.
So I've put some more data in there.
And the other thing I'm going to do here now, and this is because if you recall when I was putting
date time or timestamp variables into the database, I don't like dealing with Nulls Engo, so I tend
to go with the whole if it has a value after the 1st of January at midnight the year one, then it's
a valid date.
Otherwise it doesn't was going to create a new variable here called year one.
Time to date and I'm going to set it to the year one and I'll put it any time after the year one, 11,
17, 20, 30 for 58.
And then some number say six five one three eight seven.
I'm just putting a date that's after my my start date and put it three seven at the end of it.
Why not timed out UTC?
So I've now created a year one variable, which I'm going to put a capital.
Oh there.
Just because that's how you're supposed to name variables and go.
So if created that, and I'll say if app dot scheduler.
Entry, single entry.
App monitoring map, because I might already have a monitoring map, I might have started and stopped
this at some point for the current host host service ID next.
Is after.
You're one.
The next time this event is going to run has already taken place, so it's been set, so it has a value
after year one, then data next run, which we may or may not use, but I'm going to put it in there.
When is this scheduled?
When is this event next scheduled to run its equal to abduct scheduler entry?
Singular.
Dot monitor map.
Extort idee.
Dot next dot format, and I'll put it in the standard go date formatting and syntax 2006 zero one zero
two three zero four zero five and then P.M., which will be A.M. If it's actually the ATM.
Otherwise, if that's the case data next run our data next run.
When is this next scheduled to run the sequel to just a string pending.
So all I'm doing there, when you start this at the first time we start the application, it will always
be pending, it will always be this case.
But if we've stopped the schedule and restarted it while the application is running, then there may
have there may be a next run date already set in our in our monitoring map.
So in that case, I'll actually grab what's in there and pass that as part of my payload.
Few other things I'm going to put in their data, say host for the hostname is assigned the value of
Eckstut hostname.
This is just information and passing, which I may or may not use, but passing a little bit too much
is going to hurt things at all.
Data service I'm definitely going to use is equal to escort service DOT service name.
So I'm passing this hostname and the service name.
And the other thing that I want to have in there as well is is it possible that this has run at some
point in the past?
Well, I know what that's going to be, so I can actually grab that from my last check.
So all I have to do is to make sure that if X last check, which is right in the database, if that's
after.
Year one, the variable I defined right up here, then it has run a schedule check at some point in
the past, so I'll say data and I'll call this last run because the other one is called Next Run is
equal to extort last check dot format.
And again, we use this same format strength.
So I'll just copy this.
And pasted in here.
Else, if there is no value after year one in there, then data last run is once again I'll just put
penning in there.
You put whatever you want, but I'm using it the same as what I have above spending.
So it's never run a schedule check.
OK, so that's their the last thing I want to do is to put in the actual schedule, which I don't know
if I'm going to use that or not, but I have that information now.
I may as well stick it in their data schedule is equal to and it's just a string.
So we use format as per of.
And it will be at every percent, D.
Percent s and in there will put extorts schedule number, the next on schedule unit.
So I've now populated my payload variable, which I see I started calling data again, so I better fix
that payload, payload, payload, payload, payload, payload.
That would have been a pain to find.
I had not noticed it right now, so I'm glad that I did.
So I have my payload variable up all populated with all the necessary information, so I just trigger
my web plan.
Account error equals Apte, W.S., WebSocket client trigger and I'm going to trigger again to the public
channel.
And I'm going to trigger the event, say, next run event amount of passive data and I'll check for
an error.
And again, I'll just copy this simple error check and then I'm going to copy this whole thing and send
another event.
So next one event is the first one.
And I will also send in another event that I'm just going to call schedule changed event.
Now, we're not doing anything with this right now, but right now, when I run this the very first
time it runs or any time it runs, it's going to trigger a trigger, a a data object.
It's going to pass a WebSocket event that says to the public channel the app is starting.
Then as I go through all the services here, I'll be sending to events.
And the first one I'm going to send is a next run event for a particular piece of data, hosted service
ID, and that has some information that I'll do something with in JavaScript on the client side.
And I'm also sending a schedule changed event to the public channel and I'll do something with that
on the client side.
So when this runs the very first time, every connected client should be pushed three WebSocket events.
The first one is the app is starting.
The second one is that there's a next run event for a particular hosted service ID.
And the last one is that there's a schedule changed event for a particular host ID and that should do
it.
That should get us up and running.
So let's make sure this compiles.
We'll stop this started.
And I have an error here means start monitoring what is this assignment to entry and no map.
So I made a mistake somewhere.
Where was that airline assignment?
Entry in MAP and it says line fifty six.
Let's have a look at that Apte up monitor map the Exide.
OK, back in our set up Apte go.
I better actually declare that map.
So let's create here after our app client.
Let's say monitor map.
Monitor map is a sign the value of make a map and what type is that?
A string and a an entry ID, so let's copy that and an intern there, so we'll copy that, paste that
in there and say ECG monitor map is equal to monitor map.
All right.
You can assign to a new map.
So let's try that again.
Run.
And it's running perfect.
OK, so everything seems to be working at this point, and we're not sure until we actually write some
JavaScript on the client side to see that we're receiving those events.
So we'll start that process in the next lecture.
But before we get to the next lecture, I'm sure you noticed this, but for some reason I seem determined
to use this variable data instead of the one I actually declared called payload.
So here in start monitoring, go on at the very end of the range, both times that I trigger my my WebSocket
client, change that third parameter from data to payload, make sure it compiles.
I'm sure it will.
All right.
Clearly, I need more coffee, so I believe I shall drink some coffee before we move on to the next
lecture.