So before we can actually make sure that we're pushing events to our clients and receiving them properly,
it will be really helpful if I could actually have this work, because then I can start my application
and have it display as on, because we've manually set it to on in the database already.
And then when you talk, it actually turns the monitoring off and then we can turn it back on and wait
for the events to be pushed to us.
So let's get started doing that.
And I'm going to go over to my I.D. and I'm going to open LAYO jet, which is in The View's folder,
in the layout layouts folder.
And it's called Layout Yet.
And right here, where is that?
Tarballs right here in front of me.
OK, so in this div where I have my class form, check form switch and the label is monitoring this,
these lines right here correspond to this button.
So I'm going to put an if statement in here if and I have available to me on every template, my preference
map and I pass that using my render function functionality when I pass a bunch of data to every template
and I'm going to look for in my preference map if the value of money touring live is equal to one.
And remember that everything stored in the preference map is a string, then I'm going to do something
otherwise else and then I'll have my end and I'll just copy this.
I tab it over first.
Tablet over, copy and paste it right here, and I guess I've got a tablet, too.
OK, so my ID is telling me that I have two things with the same ID and that doesn't matter because
only one of them will show up at a given time.
So if it's turned on, then I want this to be checked.
So I will say checked on the input and if I save that, so then my application is already running and
reload this page it should show has checked and it does.
OK, so now I want this toggle to actually call some JavaScript and it already has an ID and I'm calling
it monitoring dash life.
So in my JavaScript.
I'll just add another event listener, so I'll put it right in here, my dumb content loaded, I'll
just make sure that there's actually going to be here, I'll say document get element by ID.
And I called it monitoring Leive.
And I wanted to add an event listener, and the event I'm looking for is change, and I'm just going
to call a function and inside of that function.
Well, right now, let's just make sure it's actually going to work.
We'll say console dialogue changed toggle it'll work.
I like to verify these things just to make sure that I can trap any typographical errors early on.
OK, so now when I toggle this, I should get a message and I do.
OK, so that's working properly.
What do I actually want to do in here?
I don't want to just toggle right to the console.
I actually want to make sure that I do something based upon the state of that check.
So let's find out what the state of that check is, whether it's turned on or off.
So I will say let enabled.
In other words, monitoring is enabled equal to document.
Get element by ID, and again, I'm going to get it from monitoring, live monitor, touring, live
checked.
So that will be true if the doc if that Torvill is turned on.
So I'll say if it's not enabled, in other words, if it's turned off, do something, otherwise do
something else.
So if it's not enabled, what do I actually want it to do?
First of all, I want to get a confirmation.
I want to make sure that the user knows that he or she is turning monitoring off.
So someone make take advantage of that attention module that we used a little while ago.
And I'll call the method confirm and I'll pass it some parameters, so I'll put in some HTML.
This will be what's being displayed and say this will stop monitoring.
Of all hosts and services, are you sure?
So that'll be the what's the message is displayed and I'm going to give it a callback.
And the callback is nothing more than a function that gets the result of whatever action the user chooses.
So function result and I'll say if result.
In other words, if the result is actually true, then I'll just write a comment here.
Want to turn?
Try that again.
Want to turn.
Monitoring off and I right to the console console, that log would turn monitoring off.
OK, so that's if the result is true.
If it's false, else then we'll just say document dot, get out of it by ID.
And again, it's monitoring live.
And Will said it's checked to.
True.
So basically we'll give them a confirmation dialog box.
If they say yeah, turn it off then we'll actually turn it off.
Otherwise we'll set it back to turned on the toggle and take no other action that's purely cosmetic.
So let's go back here, reload.
This monitoring is now turned on.
This should give me a confirmation.
This will stop monitoring of all hosts and services.
Are you sure?
If I say cancel, it should turn this toggle back on.
And it does, but if I say, OK, it should leave, it turned off and I should get something in the
console log.
Would turn monitoring off, OK, so that seems to be working.
All right, so how are we going to actually toggle the monitoring on and off?
Well, the first thing we want to do logically is we want to in the database.
And let's look at the database again.
We're looking at the preferences table.
I want to change this to a zero.
So I'm going to have to write some code that updates a preference.
So rather than writing one specifically for monitoring alive, maybe I'll write a more generic one in
case I ever want to change the already more generic function that allows me to change the preferences
to whatever value I want them to be.
And the second thing I want to do is I actually want to stop monitoring.
So I need to stop the the current jobs that are running in the background.
They're not really cron jobs, but it's the Go Chron package and that's how I think of them.
So we want to do that.
And that's all we really need to do in this case.
So we'll get started on that.
In the next lecture, we'll write the necessary database function and we'll also figure out how to start
and stop our monitoring process in the background.