So what I want to do now is I want to have this toggle actually do more than just display a confirmation
dialogue and write to the console.
So I'm going to go back to my JavaScript and I'm going to create two new functions and I'm going to
do them outside of this document at event listener Dom Content loaded.
OK, so down here, just before my closing script tag, I'll write one function called function update
system pref and it will take two arguments.
The preference name, which preference do I want to update and the preference value, what do I want
to update it to?
And we'll do the logic for that in a bit.
The second function I want is going to be called toggle
monitoring.
And it will take one parameter, which will be a boolean enabled.
OK, so those are the two functions I'm going to use and I'm going to call them both right here.
So in this callback, if they actually are going to turn monitoring off, I will say update system pref
and I'll pass in the name of the value that's in my preferences table.
It's monitoring underscore Leive and I want it to be set to zero.
In other words, turn it off.
And then I'm also going to say toggle monitoring and I'll pass it false.
I want monitoring to be off.
OK, and down here, when monitoring is on again, I want to do the same thing.
I can copy both of these lines.
And paste them in here and I'll say monitoring live is such a one and Torgau monitoring true, I want
it to be set to true actually that's never my mind.
With booleans, this shows you zero and one which actually turns to the same actual value.
OK, so those will call the necessary functions.
Now let's get started with this one.
Update the system preferences.
So there's a bunch of ways I could do this.
I could use a fetch, I could use a form data with an Ajax response type.
Let's do that.
I haven't done one of those in a while.
So let's create a new form data variable that formed it equal new form data.
Try that again, form data and we'll spend some values to it.
So we'll say form data append.
And I'll append a name like this, and that will be prev name and I'll duplicate that and changes to
press value and pass a press value.
And because I'm using CSF protection, I also need to form data, append RF token, and the value of
that is
in parentheses.
Dots are RF token, not parentheses in quotes and double curly braces.
So those are the three values I want to pass and then I'll create a new XML HDP request.
So I'll say let Ajax equal.
New XML htp request and my response type, I'll assume I'm going to get Jason back from the server.
So Ajax response type.
Equals Jason, and I'm going to now post to a specific you are so I have to make the all up and then
add it to our roots file.
So Ajax door open and we are going to open a post request.
Two, and let's make it slash admin slash and let's look at our roots and see what we have in there.
So roots in the admin section, anytime I call Ajax, I'm putting Ajax as a second parameter.
So let's just add a new thing up here called preferences and we'll put in mux post and we'll put in
slash.
It'll be slash admin slash preference slash Ajax and.
Say, set system set a system.
Pref and that will go through Handler's repo set system, prev, which doesn't exist yet, but we'll
get to that in a minute.
So this is my URL and I have to put a slash admin before that.
So I'll go back to my layout or do my JavaScript slash admin slash, get rid of the extra slash.
So we're going to post to that.
You are up and we're going to send the form data.
So Ajax dot send form data.
Once that happens, we want to listen to the already state change of this HDP request, so Ajax's on
ready state change are a there are already state change is equal to a function.
And we want to say if Ajax Dot.
Ready, St..
Is equal to exactly for hour, our request is finish, we'll get a response, let resp equal to Ajax's
response.
And we'll say, if not resp.
OK, I'm going to assume we're going to be passing back in OK variable as part of our Jason will say
error alert.
Errors and we'll just pass whatever the error is, so resprout message.
So in my JSON response, I'm going to have two possible things.
There are two things in there.
At least I will have my OK value, which is set to true if everything went well and my message, which
will be populated with an error message if something went wrong.
OK, so there is our first one that will update the system.
Now let's go back to our roots file and see what we call that handler set system.
So we need to create a new handler set system.
So let's do that.
We'll go to our handlers, which are right up here and at the very bottom, I'll create a new function
thunk and it will have repo with the receiver of DB Repo this name, and because it's a handler and
has a W, which is an HTP response writer and R, which is a pointer to an update request.
OK, so that should make the error and the roots go away.
And it does.
Let's just log, let's just create some JSON and send it back and then we'll make sure everything is
wired up correctly.
So I already have I believe, JSON response.
Let me make sure Jason resp.
No I don't have one in there.
Maybe some perform checks.
Jason resp.
Yeah, I can use this type because that has everything.
I need it as an OK and a message.
So let's go back to our handlers and just create and send back an actual value.
So we'll say var resp is of type Jason Recip and we'll say RESPA.
OK,
try that again with the capital of OK equals true and respect message.
Is equal to nothing.
I don't have to do what I'm going to do it anyway.
Now, will marshall that to a variable called out and I'll ignore the error is assign the value of Jason
Marshall intent.
And I want to Marshall resp and I'm going to get no prefix and I'll invent it with the few spaces.
OK, then double header set will set it to application Jason
and we'll just write that to the what do we have here.
Not enough arguments set requires.
The key and the value content type, like any more coffee, and we'll just write that to the out so
w dot, right.
And we're going to right out and I should do it.
OK, so this should all be hooked up properly.
So let's stop the application.
Start the application.
And go look at our jails and see which ones actually making this call, so we're calling update system
on either turning it on or off.
OK, so let's just make sure it's all wired up correctly.
Reload the page here, the JavaScript console, look at the network and watch for XIKAR, for example,
or AJAX requests.
So should be able to toggle this off and say, OK, and it made a request and it gave me a status of
two hundred.
And the response is exactly what I want it true and a message.
And if I turn it back on so I'll clear this, turn it back on, I should get exactly the same thing.
And it looks like I did.
I did.
So that's wired up correctly.
Perfect.
So the next step is to actually go back to this handler and not just hard code a response, but to actually
change the value for the system, preference in the database and send back the correct response.
So, OK, with no message of everything worked or false.
OK, is that default with some error message if things failed and we'll take care of that in the next
lecture.