So now we want to actually update the system preference, any system preference, and this is going
to be a lot easier than I thought because apparently we already wrote this function, this database
function, set system pref, which does exactly what we want.
It'll delete it if it exists and then insert it if it doesn't.
Now we can write an update function, but this isn't going to change a great deal.
And I don't think we'll hit the billions of the the IDE limit of some billion records.
So I think we're OK so we can go back to our handlers.
And here, just after we declare and set default values for this message, we can say error is assigned
the value of.
Repo debe set system prev and the parents name is a name which will have to get in the second and the
preference value is value.
So let's grab those values from here so we can just say pref name is assign the value of our dot, our
post form dot yet.
And what we want is what do we call that in our JavaScript and make sure we get that right.
So update system pref name and value.
Underscore CREF name.
And prep value
is a sign the value of our post from target prep value, if there's an error, if error is not equal
to nil, then respawn OK equals false and respect message is equal to error.
I think a error on error that will get it for us.
OK, so that should take care of it.
So let's give this a try.
So I'll start my application and start my application.
And we'll go to the database and look and see what it's set to right now, so monitoring live is currently
set to one.
And if I go back to my Web browser and reload this.
And turn it off and say, yes, I want it off.
I got a two hundred, OK, which set back, sent back OK is true with no message.
And if I go to the database.
The preferences now set to three No.
There it is, monitoring lives down here, so desirable because it has a higher I.D., it appears lower
on the screen.
So that should take care of it for us.
Now, if you really don't like that incremented ID, it's not that difficult to do fix that.
We can actually go back to our preferences.
And I'm going to do that because this irritates me right now.
I can actually copy this entire function pasted here and just call this update system pref.
Which is actually nicer, so we can just get rid of this and say query is assigned, so we'll just fix
this query and it's pretty straightforward.
We just say update preferences set.
And what's the name of the column preference equal to dollar sign one.
And then we'll do the updated as well.
Updated and equal to or something to where.
And the name column is called name name equals Dollar Sign three and we'll pass in the update.
Preferences set preference equal to and that will be the value updated at equal to time Don.
Now.
And the last one is where the name is equal to name, and I should do it for us now if I copy this signature.
And go to my repository and add that into, say, preferences up here.
We could use that one as well, but this is just may as well put it in there, it's not going to hurt
anything.
Go back to preferences and make sure this is all correct.
It is.
And go to our handlers and change this to update system, pref, pref name, press value.
And what I'm calling is name and value.
So that should work.
OK, so let's go back to her handlers.
Make sure that's correct.
Will stop our application.
Start our application.
And go reload the browser page, look at the database.
So right now, Monitoring Live has the idea of five and that should go to one and it is five when I
do this.
So let's try that.
I think this is cleaner.
I'll turn it back on.
Come here.
Reload the database.
And it did stay to ninety five and it got a preference of one.
So that's exactly what I wanted.
Now there may be some cleanup required at the end because I'm not entirely sure we need all of these
database methods.
But for our purposes, we just want to get to the point where we can play with WebSocket a little bit
more.
So I'm satisfied with this for the moment.
All right.
The next step is to actually go and turn our monitoring schedule on and off, and we'll take care of
that in the next lecture or two.