So we're updating the system preferences that allow us to turn monitoring on and off, but we're not
actually turning monitoring on and off.
So I'm in my Jast jet file and I see I missed a tee and error alert.
So I'll add that in there.
What I'm going to do is we have this function already, toggle monitoring, and that's what we want
to use to actually start and stop the monitoring of hosts and host services in the background.
So just to make things faster, I will copy this entire function and paste it in here and I'll change
the URL where I'm instead of set system pref, I'll just change that to toggle monitoring.
OK, so that you, Earl, doesn't exist yet.
So I'm going to copy this part of it and I'll go to my roots file
and right here where I'm setting system preferences, that's the one we just put in recently.
I'll duplicate that and change this to the correct YORO.
And I don't need the slash admin because that's added by the shredder.
And we'll create a new handler, which I'll just call toggle monitoring, which doesn't exist yet.
But that's not a problem.
We can go create it.
So I'm over in my handlers file and I'll create a new function, which I'll call func.
It'll take the repo receiver
and I'll call it toggle monitoring.
And because it's a handler, requires a response writer and a pointer to a request.
OK, so I'll give this a comment.
Turn's.
Monitoring on and off.
Now let's go back to our JavaScript, because we need to do need to make a change there.
Here, I'm not going to post a name and a value.
I do need the CSS RF token, so I delete this one and I'll just pass enabled.
And of course we get that from the parameter pass to this function enabled and back in our handlers.
Let's go find those again right over here.
We'll grab that value enabled.
So enabled is sign the value of our post form dot get enabled just to make sure it all works.
I'll simply log that log print line enabled and I'll just send back a hardcoded JSON response like we
did last time just to make sure everything works.
So we'll say resp, we'll just do it this way via resp is of type JSON response and rasped OK equals
true and we don't need anything else.
So I just need to marshal this and send it out so I'll copy and paste from the previous function.
And this is just to make sure that everything is going to be communicating with each other the way that
it should.
So I'll start my application.
If it's running, I'll start my application.
The comp. I'll make sure IP is running, it's not so I'll start it and all I'll do is put a few blank
lines in there and go look at our localhost localhost 4000.
Apparently I have to log in admin at example, dot com password.
And I will open the JavaScript terminal and I'll turn monitoring on and we should get an 020 CASEVAC
and we got the first one and we got the second one.
Both are 200.
And if we look at the second one, that should be the Torgau monitoring.
And our response is everything's OK.
So they're talking to each other.
That's good.
Now we actually need to do something more than simply return a hardcoded value.
So let's go back here to our toggled monitoring on and off and think about how we're going to make this
work.
So obviously, we're going to be doing something in this handler based upon the value of enabled, if
enabled, is equal to the string value of zero, we're turning monitoring off.
And if it's equal to the string value of one, we're turning monitoring on.
Now, if you'll recall, we actually have back in our main package over here, start monitoring in command
web.
We have the file start monitoring Dudko and that turns monitoring on.
Now, one of the problems we're going to face right now is that we're going to have to do a little bit
of refactoring rather than because we're in a package handlers.
We can't call the function in the main package start monitoring.
So I'm probably going to have to refactor that to move this out of the main package and put it somewhere
else.
We'll put it in handlers because that will make things ever so simple.
So that's the first thing we're going to have to think about.
The second thing we're going to have to think about is exactly what do we want to do?
Well, let's just write some comments here to get things going.
So I'll say I'll do the statement first.
If the enabled is equal to one, then we want to start monitoring.
Otherwise, if it's equal to anything else, zero is the only other option we want to stop monitoring.
Let's do the stop monitoring first because we're already starting it in our main package.
So at least we can stop it without doing any refactoring at the moment.
So if we think about this, first of all, I'm going to say logged print line turning monitoring of.
And up here, I'll just copy this and pasted.
And turn it on, OK, when we actually have our monitoring system running, we have first of all, we
have all the values that are in the Crown package.
So we have something called entries, which will be looking at shortly that allow us to see all of the
entries that are in the monitoring package.
And we also have our monitor map, which is a map stored in our application wide config.
So what we could do I mean, we could do this and it might work is we could simply just do something
as simple as this, turning, monitoring on and off.
So turning it on would be nothing more than going to our repo, going to our app, going to our scheduler
and calling start.
And that would start it up, and here we could just say repo dot app, dot scheduler stop.
And once any existing service is running from our schedule, as soon as that's finished, it will stop
it and this will start it back up.
And that might work.
But I'm not an optimist.
And really what I want to have happen here is to ensure that when I stop the applications monitoring,
I actually empty the map, remove all the entries.
I do everything necessary to turn everything off.
So let's do it that way instead, because I'm just not an optimist.
And I want to make sure that when I stop the scheduling, there's not some leftover thing running in
the background.
And when I start it back up, I'm going to load all of the services I want to monitor.
And there's a reason for that, because when we have a problem service, we actually want to monitor
it more frequently.
But we'll get to that later on.
So let's have a look at the how we're going to do this.
First of all, let's remove everything from the schedule.
And that's really easy.
So I can say, first of all, for and I don't care about the index, but I do care about the value I'm
iterating through.
I'm going to range through four underscore comma X is a sign the value of range and will range through
our repo app.
The monitor map, so that will take me through every entry in our map and all we'll do is remove that
entry that's in the map from the scheduler.
So repo app DOT scheduler remove.
And this allows us to remove something by its ID.
And if you recall the value of X in this case, the contents, not the key, but the value that stored
in the map is the entry ID in the scheduler so that we'll get rid of it.
So that removes everything from our schedule.
So let's put a comment there.
Remove all items in map from schedule.
OK, so that's that's the first step.
The second thing I want to do is to empty the map, empty the map.
So I'm just going to do a similar thing for underscore and I'll call this one.
K is assigned the value of range.
Repo app, dot, monitor, map, and all I'll do is remove that from the map, delete.
Repo app, dot monitor map, and we're going to remove the value.
OK, so now our map is empty now because I'm not an optimist, because I always assume that something
is going to go wrong.
I'm going to do one more step here.
I'm going to say delete all entries from schedule.
To be sure, and I probably don't have to do this, but it's going to take no time to do it and it will
make me sleep better at night.
And again, for underscore and this time I call it I is range and this time around, not ranging through
the monitor map.
I'm going to go through all of the entries in the schedule.
Repo dot app, dot schedule.
Scheduler entries that are scheduled to write entries.
So now I'm ranging through any entries that still exist in our schedule.
All I do is call the method that's built in to my scheduler, repo dot app, dot scheduler, dot, remove,
and this time I'm removing idot ID.
So there's probably nothing in the in that schedule at this point.
No entries left.
But again, I just am not an optimist when it comes to this sort of thing.
So we'll actually remove the manual just to be sure.
So that should be everything.
I need to turn the monitoring off.
So when the toggle is turned off back in our JavaScript.
Right over here.
So this is going to stop all of the monitoring in this section.
The first thing I do is just write it to the console.
The second thing I'm doing is updating the system preferences to turn monitoring live to zero in the
database.
And then I call Torgau Monitoring and Torgau monitoring just passes the value, which is at this point
set to zero after this URL, which goes to this handler.
And at that point it goes through this part of the code.
So its rights to the console, to our log file, then it removes all the items from the monitor map,
from the schedule by going through the monitor map.
Then it empties the monitor map.
And what am I doing here?
Try that again.
I don't need an underscore here.
There, that's better.
Then I empty the monitor map and then I actually just make sure that the schedule has no entries in
it whatsoever and I stop the scheduler.
So this should work.
So let's compile a code.
Hit return a few times to make sure we have some blank lines, go back to our application, monitoring
is on.
So when I turn it off, I'll just go back and clear the log file here.
When I turn it off, it will give me my my my confirmation.
And I get to OK, so to 200 to just perfect and I get turned monitoring off, so that does exactly what
I want.
OK, so the next step is to actually turn it on and that's going to require some refactoring and it's
not difficult, but we'll take care of that in the next lecture.