OK, so we're at the point right now where we think if I look at my code, we have the monitoring being
turned off properly and that's actually true.
But we do have a problem that we that you may have noticed.
But I didn't notice it until after the last lecture and before this one.
So my application is running right now and monitoring appears to be turned off.
So let's turn monitoring on.
OK, and now let's go to another page.
And now let's turn monitoring off, OK, and let's go back to another page, so monitoring is off.
And when I go back to the overview page, it appears to be on and there's a reason for that because
when we toggle that switch.
So let's go back to our code here.
When we toggle that switch right in this JavaScript, OK, I'm calling set system, which is perfect.
And if we look at our roots file and we find that set system pref right here and I go to that.
So when I do this, I'm updating the system preference.
But what I'm not doing just before the point where I, I actually send back to Jason is I'm never updating
that value in our preference map that's being handed to all of our pages.
So I need to do that.
So I need to say something as simple as.
Repo dot app, dot preference map, and I'm looking for monitoring.
Monitoring Desh Live, I think it's called La Dash, let's make sure go to our preferences now it's
underscore life monitoring, underscore Leive that needs to be set to the actual value that we're passing
to our update system.
And that's value.
OK, so that we'll update it in our application wide config, so let's make sure that actually works
before we go any further.
OK, I'll stop my application and start it.
So it starts up reload the page to see what it actually looks like and it says the monitoring is turned
off.
And if I go to my database and reload, that monitoring is turned off.
Perfect.
Now let's turn it on, OK?
And let's reload the database to make sure it's turned on.
It is.
Let's go to another page.
Still on.
Let's turn it off, OK, and go back to our overview page, and it's still off.
So that takes care of that problem.
And that was an oversight I should have noticed long before now.
But we run into these things now and again.
OK, so let's go back to our code and look at our handlers.
And this is the part we want to do turning monitoring on.
So as I said before, we actually can't do it the way that it's set up right now because we have no
access to the code and start monitoring ago in our main package.
So what I'm going to do is copy all of this code except for the package statement.
Copy it and then I'll comment it out because I don't need it and I'll delete this file before too long.
And then back in my handlers package, I'll create a new go file called Start Dash Monitoring Dutko
and I will add that to my repository and I'll just paste this code in and then I'll need to clean a
few things up.
So to start with, we don't have access to the preference map here like we do in the main package,
but we still have access to it.
We just have to say app dot preference map and that fixes that problem.
And then if you go down here, we have lots of other things to look at.
So services to monitor is not equal to repo DB services to monitor unless we give this the receiver,
which is repo DB repo.
OK, so that should fix all of the problems down here, and it appears to the last problem we have is
that I can't call repo scheduled check because I don't have access to the repo variable here.
Actually, I do have access to the repo variable here because if you look at our.
Handler's file over here, handlers don't go at the very top, and this was in the default code that
you cloned when you started this course or this section of the course when I called new handlers, I'm
setting a package level variable called repo with the capital are equal to my database repo.
So back here in handlers start monitoring, all I have to do is change this to an upper kasar and that
will take care of it.
So now this actually works the way that it's supposed to.
So back in my handlers at the very bottom, when I'm turning monitoring on right here, all I have to
do is call start handlers.
So start hand or start monitoring.
I can call it by saying repo dots, start monitoring and that should take care of it.
So the last thing we need to do is to change our start up of our application, which is in setup Apgar.
So we can't call start monitoring anymore because that's that's just been commented out and I'm about
to delete that file.
But what we can do is call go handlers, dot start monitoring, which means I need to go rename start
monitoring to make it visible outside of the package.
No problem.
Let's do that.
So that's in handlers and now it's in start monitoring here.
Let's just rename this to make it visible outside of this package.
Start monitoring and we'll have to change it in our handlers to get that a capital S and our setup up.
Handlers, repo, don't start monitoring, and I put it go in front of it, just sort of run in the
background and the application will start a little faster.
So in theory, this should all work.
Now, I'll make sure that I have the code in the old start monitoring comment that out and I do.
And that means if this works, I can delete this file.
So let's stop our application.
Start our application.
And all compiled perfect, so that means I can stop this.
And simply delete from command web, the start monitoring go file.
And one last thing in set up aiport go, this is just a cleanup.
I actually don't need to start the schedule here at all because it's going to be handled by start monitoring
so I can delete this line entirely and I might as well do that and we should be good.
So now we have a means of actually turning the scheduler on and off.
And we're now at the point where we can actually start pushing events from our application to all the
connected clients and doing something with it.
And we'll get started on that in the next section.