So one of the things that makes using a package like Celebrity House or Laravel attractive to many developers
is the convenience of getting access to certain functions or methods or functionality.
And one of the things that we can say about our application as it exists right now is that it could
be a little more convenient.
And for example, I'm looking at rootstock go in the my app package and it's little things like this
in order to get a get request here and line 16.
I have to use the receiver, a and then app and then routes and then get, which doesn't bother me at
all because I can see at a glance exactly where that get functionality exists in the celebrity's functionality.
Now what we could do is make some convenience or helper methods, so let's try that.
So right at the root level of my project, because that's where rootstock go exists.
We're going to create a new file called Just Convenience.
Don't go.
OK.
And of course, that's in Package Me.
What I'm going to do is just make some helper functions, so for example, if I want to get a get route,
I can create a function with the receiver of a pointer to application and I can just call this route
get and I can give it the same parameters that aid our app routes don't get has, which is a string.
So I'll call it as string.
And then it has an FTP handler func.
So each of type http dot handler func and make sure you get the right one and it doesn't return anything.
And I then I just have that call a dot app, dot roots, dot get and hand it s and h my two parameters.
So what I do that that means I can go back to rootstock, go and do things like this instead of having
the home page, be a dot app, dot root start.
Yet I could just make it a dot.
Yeah, and that's a lot shorter, so that's really convenient.
So of course, we can do the same thing for post.
So let's go back to convenience store go and create another function.
I can just copy this whole thing and paste it here and change it to post, and this becomes a to start
post.
And of course, the other thing we do in Roots File is we use middleware.
So let me paste that again and change this to use.
And now it becomes a dot, and of course, it has different parameters.
It doesn't use all of these things.
It uses middleware.
So M and then we use the same kind of receiver or some kind of parameter signature that the use function
from the chip route uses.
And it uses very attic func HTP dot handler.
And the second parameter is HGTV dog handler, OK?
A weird signature, but that's how it actually appears in the cheap package.
So of course, we're going to now use them.
Dot dot dot.
Because it's very hot.
That's better.
But these aren't used anywhere, which is why I'm getting the warning.
I can go back now to routes and say, change the post one.
So this becomes.
Simply.
A post.
Now that's a small change, but it actually makes for very readable code, and a lot of people prefer
to have one helper function like that.
And really, it's nothing more than an alias to a dot app.
Don't read scanned or aid on app.
Don't read post.
But a lot of people like it.
So you might want to implement that functionality.
It's entirely up to you.
I'm going to make it available for my users so they can use them if they want to.