Now, just look, we made some convenience functions for the roots, we can do the same thing for handlers.
And actually, they're probably going to be used a lot more than the ones in the routes because you're
working with handlers a lot more than you're working with routes.
But we can use the same approach.
So let's go to the handlers folder in my app and create a new file.
And again, I'll call this one convenience.
Convenience, don't go.
And the package for this, of course, is handlers and will create one one that's really going to get
used a lot.
So in any handler, let's say I go to handlers, don't go any time I'm rendering a page, I wind up
calling H Typekit rendered up page.
And as you might have noticed, even I get that wrong once in a while, and I forget to put the render
before page or something like that, or I just put Dot render and I wrote that software to begin with.
So if I'm making those mistakes, chances are other people will, too.
So let's take care of that one first.
That was really easy.
We'll create a function with the receiver of H Pointer or two handlers, and we'll call this one just
render.
And it will take a response forever
and it will take a request
and it will take the template to render, which is a string.
And it will take variables and data variables and data, both of type interface.
And it returns potentially there.
And really, this is as simple as saying return stock app.
Don't try that again.
App Dot render.
The page and that takes W. an hour and template and variables in there.
And I don't know, I have quotation marks around that that looks better.
So we return that and that means I can go over to my say and I'll go and change this to nothing more
than h.
Not render.
And that's a lot cleaner.
OK, let me do the same thing for print line and everything else, but really, let's take care of some
other things that might be useful.
So back to our convenience, don't go in handlers and make sure you get the right one.
Because the way it is now, we're going to have to.
Every time we want to use the session, we have to start with a short app, not session, got put or
get or whatever it might be.
So let's make some convenience functions for that.
So Func H receiver of H handlers and we'll call this one session put put something into the session
and that requires the context of type, context, context right there.
And hopefully that the important for me, it did.
It also requires the key, which is a string, and it requires the data to put in there, which can
be anything.
So I'll just call it vowel of type interface, and it doesn't return anything.
So all we do is call HQ, app dot session put and we give it the context, the key and the value and
interface has an urn there.
And of course, we need to be able to check to see if something exists in the session.
Func, each receiver of handlers and we'll call this one session has and that takes the context of type,
context, context.
And it also requires the key, which is a string, and it returns Fallujah.
And again, we just return each app, not debug, but session dot exists and we give it our context,
but our key.
That was the same thing for getting values from a session.
Func H handlers one or two handlers session or session get like that, and that requires the context,
context, context.
It requires the key, which is a string, and it returns anything.
So interface interface like that with the two curly brackets.
And we just call each dot app dot session dot get and we give it the context and the key.
And of course, this has to return.
So we return that.
What else do you have to do with Sessions?
What you have to get things out of it?
So func h, I mean, remove something from it, not pull something from it.
H handlers session remove.
And that requires the context of type, context, context.
And it requires the key, and it doesn't return anything, and we just call HQ at the session that remove
and give it the context and the key.
Now what's wrong with this?
He should be a.
I'm very sloppy in my typing today, I apologize for that.
And there's two other things we need to do.
Sometimes you need to renew the token for a session and sometimes you need to destroy a session entirely.
So let's do those func h to handlers, and we'll call this session renew, which reduce the token.
And it just requires the context, ctcs context, context.
And it potentially returns an error.
And would you say, return H2 app
dot session for new token?
And here's the context.
And finally destroyed.
So we'll copy this one because it's very similar.
Taste it here and call it session destroyed.
Remove the session and destroy everything in it.
That just requires the context.
And we call a scrapped session.
Don't destroy.
OK.
So those become very useful and easy to type and easy to remember helper functions.
And that makes working with things much easier.
Now there's a few more.
We can put it in there and we'll add this as time goes on.
But we also had that random string functionality, so let's make that easy.
Func H handlers and if you recall, we created something that generates a random string and I'm going
to call my helper function random string that are split, right?
All it takes is one parameter.
How long should this string be?
And it returns a string.
And here I'll just say return app dot, random string and hand it in.
OK.
Very simple changes.
Very small changes.
But it will make working with this particular package much easier for end users.
Let's move on.