Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
how to create and implement interfaces.
And in this session, we want to talk about the ideas interface concept.
Into either face type, the tide interface, open and close, Kelly Races is known as the empty interface,
and it is used to accept the values of any type then teen or face doesn't have any mascots that are
required to satisfy it.
And so every time satisfies its.
Let's go to this school program to illustrate how to use empty interface.
First, go.
Main function and define two variables by different times and assign them for the example that I ain't
equals a hundred and that.
Yes, that's true equals.
Hello.
Now go out of main function and create the function that has parameter as an empty interface.
Fine.
Set a name for the example kind
and set the perimeter as an empty interface I interface.
In body of metal, we want to see the value and type of arguments that pass from main function, so
be right.
If Earth.
The type of person the U.S. person T after case, said Congressman Caddick's, that the opportunities
for the time served valuable.
I ah again, I reformat the code and save the project.
Now go to main function and invoke, define kindness and post to created variables, as are humans to
eat and see the result.
Go to main function first coined by IBD.
The sad irony of it.
And in the next line, you will find why this reform of the code save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output.
The time of 100 is ins and the type of halo is a swing.
Through the container phase.
We were able to send different values to our method.
For the example, even sent a type of integer and once a type of string to our metal, then viewed outputs.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.