Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
coffee one as nice items into another.
It's nice and golden in this session.
We want to talk about the others.
It's nice this concept.
Append its lines to an existing disguise and go language, the uses of triple dot or ellipses used to
append a slice.
Now go to this good program to illustrate how to append this line to an existing is nice and go line
first.
Create with slices.
In this case, we define variables, by the way, that she walked by this nice one.
He calls it square brackets, Typekit string and assign values.
Java Sea Shore and Google go to the next line and define an event that it's nice to equals.
The square brackets Typekit string and initialize value curve and pitch.
Now, append is nice one, too.
It's nice to buy ellipses in append function is slice two equals append slice two and slice one by there.
Let's now go to the next line and display two slices.
First off, the slice one column comma slice one and go to the next line.
If B, it's nice to call in and separately, well, it's nice to.
Reformat the crew, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output.
It's like one Java Sea Shark Go.
And it's nice to be Jawbone C-sharp Go.
We could copy as lies to existing as lies by append function and triple dot.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.