Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the pit of your station, we talked about
append this nice to an existing is nice English language and in decision we want to talk about the other.
It's nice concept.
Multi-dimensional a slice.
Multi-dimensional stories are just like the multi-dimensional array, except that it's nice, does not
contain this size.
Now go to the good program to illustrate how to implement multi-dimensional slides and go language.
First, create a multi-dimensional slice for the example, a slice one collar equals set twist core
brackets first and second and define tie for the example end and initialize the values first, 10,
comma 20 and set the comma end of the credit markets and goes to the next line and define another values.
For the example, 30, 40 and 50 set the comma end of the brackets and go to the next line and initialize
and other values, for the example.
60, 70, 80 and 90 and set the common end of the early brackets and go to the next line.
And we initialize the order values, for the example, at a hundred and a hundred and twenty and set
the common end of the curly brackets.
Now go to the next line and display.
This slice might even help to slice and dice, reformat the code, save the project and execute the
code.
Now we can see the output and we could define multidimensional slices.
We have reached the end of this session.
I hope you have taken full advantage of decision on the next decision.
Goodbye.