Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
at iTunes Twist Nice using app and function.
In this session, we want to talk about the authors.
It's nice concepts.
Modifying your slides and go like.
As we already know, that is a nice reference point.
It can refer an underlying era.
So if we change some elements in this noise, then the changes should also take place in the referenced
era or in other wars.
If you made any changes in this line, then it will also reflect in the array.
Now, go to the Scott program to illustrate how to modifying this slice.
First, create an area for the exemption, and a call in equals the square bracket and said six value
for land type is eight and initialize value 10, 20, 30, 40, 50 and 60.
Now create this list from this Eric.
Go to the next line and slice sovereign equals ray.
This global markets lower bond and offer bond for the example, zero, Colin, for now, we print elements
of area and this long as before modifying go to the next line.
And if the
first and only
certain area that I go to, the next one is the first slice.
And said the very idea the slice said the project, now we want to modify three elements of a slice
do the following.
For example, the Slice Index zero said the value the 100 go to the next line.
The Slice Index one set the value 200 and go to the next line and slice.
Index to initialize value by the 300, now go to the next line and display elements of Adi and his thoughts
after modifying the brackets list and second Ray and said How do you rate it and go to the next line?
If the second slice and certainly even a slice reformat the code, save the projects and execute the
code.
Now we can see the output first at a values are 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60.
And first the slice is 10, 20, 30 and 40.
After modifying second at A has the values 100, 200, 300 and 40 50 60.
And the second, this list has values 100, 200, 300 and 40.
Now we change the elements of this lies.
And so that the elements in the array also changed.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.