So in this section of the course, we're going to look at some other things that are important to be
familiar with.
When you're working with concurrent programming and in go where firing off a go routine into the background
is so easy, it's really important to be aware of race conditions.
So we're going to spend some time looking at those and we'll also look at a means of locking a particular
resource so that somebody has exclusive access to it until you're done working with it or some part
of your program has exclusive access to it until you're done working with it, and then you unlock it
and make it available for other things to access and change as necessary.
And that's called the sync mutex.
It's from the Sync package, it's called a mutex which stands for mutual exclusion.
And we'll also have a look at something, and it's just a brief introduction to it.
It'll take us a while to write the code, but it's important to be aware of channels and that is the
preferred way of dealing with concurrency in go.
So at the end of this section we'll have a look at channels.
Okay, so what are we going to do to start with?
We'll look at the sink, dot mutex package and race conditions.
And as I said, mutex is a shortened version of the phrase mutual exclusion.
It allows us to deal with and prevent race conditions from happening.
And I'll be talking about those momentarily.
Now, the great thing about Sync Top Mutex is it's really easy to use, not quite as easy as wait groups.
The other thing we've seen from the sync package but almost is easy and this allows us to deal with
shared resources like variables are some data structure, something that can be accessed by at least
two go routines at the same time.
And of course, if you have two things running in the background and they both try to hit the same bit
of data and things can happen, you may have unpredictable results and we deal with that by locking
and unlocking the resource as necessary.
Now we can test for race conditions and go either when we when we run a program just by adding a flag
to the go command or when we test a program, when we actually run a unit test or an integration test
or something like that.
And we'll have a look at that as well.
Now, a little bit more about race conditions.
Race conditions occur when multiple go routines.
At least two, you're never going to have one if you just have your main program and some other go routine.
But when you have at least two go routines running concurrently and they try to access the same thing,
say a variable like a string, and they can be extremely difficult to spot when you're reading code.
In fact, you can actually run a program that has a race condition.
It runs exactly as you expected and you move on thinking everything is fine.
But fortunately, as I suggested, go lets us check for these either when we run them or when we run
an actual test and we'll be doing both of these things in this section.
Now here's an illustration of how race conditions actually work.
On the left hand side of the screen.
I have my main function in my program and it spawns to go routines.
They don't have to be the same one, but both of these go routines actually access some kind of data
over there on the right hand side of the screen.
Now, since I have no idea which go routine is going to execute first or which one is going to end first
and both of these access and perform some operation on that data, bad things can happen.
So we'll have examples of how to create these will artificially create a couple and then how to deal
with them using new taxes in.
The last thing we're going to look at in this section is we'll have an introduction to channels.
And channels are nothing more than a means of having one go routine, share data or share information
with another go routine.
They're actually channels between those go routines which are running concurrently in the background.
So in effect, it lets one go routine, talk to another, and channels can go in both directions.
You can have uni directional channels or you can have bidirectional channels and in fact you can have
as many channels as you want.
So that information can be passed back and forth between go routines.
And this is an example of Go's philosophy of having things share memory by communicating rather than
communicating by sharing memory.
And the easiest way to see how channels work is to write a program that actually uses them.
So I'm going to introduce one of the classic computer science problems, and it's called the Producer
Consumer Problem, and that's how we'll finish this section.
And so let's get started.