So we've finished, we think our make pizza function.
And you might notice here that I added some comments and I had comments for pretty much everything and
we don't need to pay attention to them right now.
It's just to make it clear to you what's going on if you download the source code.
Okay.
Just to make things a little more useful.
So we have this make pizza function and as you recall, all it does is it receives an integer.
Okay?
And the first time this is executed, the first time we call this in our program, that integer will
be zero.
And then we add one to that integer and that's keeping track of what pizza order we're dealing with.
Then provided we're not on pizza number 11, we're comparing that to this constant, which is set to
ten.
If we're not finished to making pizzas, we try to make one.
So we delay a little bit right here.
We print out a message saying that we received the order.
This actually we don't delay yet, but that sets up our delay.
Then we generate a run in number between one and 12.
If that number is less than five, then we failed.
So we increment that package, little variable.
Otherwise it's true and we increment this package little variable.
And then finally we keep track of the total number of pizzas.
Then we printed a message saying We're making pizza number.
Whatever the pizza order is, it will take this many seconds.
Then we wait that many seconds, which is an artificial delay, just so that the screen doesn't zip
by really, really quickly.
Then we calculate the values for message and success based upon the value of this random number between
one and 12.
Then we create a pizza order.
Okay?
We populate that pizza order with the pizza number with a message we generated here and an indication
as to whether or not we made that pizza and we send that back as a pointer to the pizza order type.
So otherwise, if we're on pizza number 11, then we're done and we return basically an almost empty
pizza order.
We only have the pizza number calculated here.
Okay.
So now we want to turn our attention back to our producer here.
So we've called already in this for loop.
We've called make pizza and we handed it to the variable I, which initially is set to zero on the very
first time through this.
Okay.
The next thing we want to do is we actually want to listen to those channels that are part of our producer
type.
Remember that our producer type right here.
It has, as you can see, two channels data, which is a channel of the type pizza order.
That's the only thing that channel can receive and quit, which is a chain of channel error.
Okay, so how do we determine what we're going to do based upon the results of this call to make pizza?
So we're trying to make that decision here right now.
So I'll delete these comments just to give us a little bit more room.
And I'll say if current pizza is not equal to nil, okay, so we got something back and all I have to
do here is get the pizza number.
II is equal to current pizza dot pizza number.
So now I know what pizza number we're making.
Okay, now I know what it is when I read the code the very first time, but after that I have no idea
what pizza number might be.
So I get that from whatever I got back from calling make pizza.
And now finally we get to use this select statement and selects are only useful for channels.
Okay, you can't use them for anything else, but it's very, very similar to a switch statement which
you're probably familiar with from go and from other languages.
So it works pretty much the same way.
So our select has cases.
So we have a case which I have to spell correctly case, and our first case is going to be pizza maker
dot data.
And then this funny little thing here with current pizza and all this means is that when we get a current
pizza pointer, a pointer to a current pizza, we populate pizza Maker Data's value with whatever we
got from the channel and then a colon, as you often see with case statements.
Okay.
So what that means is we tried to make a paste, we tried to make a pizza something, put a comment
here.
We tried to make a pizza, not sure if it's successful or not.
But for example, you know, what we're doing here is we we sent data to the data channel.
We sent something to the data channel that's better.
We sent something
to the data channel.
Okay, so we're trying to make a pizza.
We send it off to the channel here.
That's what this case statement does.
Now, the only other case we need to worry about in this one is Case Kitchen, which is a variable I'm
making right now.
And that's going to receive a pizza maker.
Don't quit.
We're done.
We're quitting.
Okay.
Now, in this case, what do we want to do?
Well, we need to close our channels.
And this is a kind of golden rule.
Once you create channels, when you're done with them, you have to close.
Unfortunately, it's really easy.
I can close the data channel just by calling.
Close with a parameter.
Pizza maker dot data.
That channel is now closed.
And to close the quick chain.
Well, close.
And in this case, I'm closing kitchen, which I created right here.
Okay, so that's closed.
So this value is populated when I send something to pizza maker equipped and I can close it this way.
And that's done.
And at this point, I want to get out of this go routine, the go routine pizzeria.
I want to leave it entirely.
Now, how do I do that?
Because I'm inside for loop and then I'm inside.
And if statement and then I'm inside a select statement.
And of course, the way to get rid of this is just to call return.
I'm returning nothing.
And this go routine is done, and it will exit.
So here is our completed producer, and there are no errors in the program.
So what do you think will happen if I try to run this program right now?
Well, let's go down and look at the main function.
And this is where we always begin when we're trying to redo go program in the main func.
So in here I see my red numbers.
No problem.
I print something to the screen.
I create a producer as a pointer to type producer.
So pizza job is a pointer to the type producer.
I populate that with new channels that I create right here.
Then I call the producer in the background and I don't do anything else.
So if I try to run this program with all that work we've done in the last two lectures, what do you
think is going to happen?
Well, let's find out all over the turtle, clear the screen and I'll type.
Go run, dog.
All that work, and we have nothing else to look at when we run this program.
And of course, that's not surprising because although I've produced or created my pizzeria, which
is my producer and I've written the function make pizza just so it's not all lumped together into one
function here.
I haven't actually done anything to try to make a pizza.
I haven't actually created an order yet.
So when you think it through, the next step is to create and run the consumer, just like the comment
says here in line 136.
Okay.
And that's what we'll get started on in the next election.