So last time we got our consumer pretty much ready to go, we think and I just want to go over this
one more time because I know this can be a little confusing if it's the first time you've worked with
channels.
So in this function pizzeria, okay.
And that's called from the main function way down here on line 135.
In this one, the very first thing we do is keep track of which pizza we're making and we initialize
the variable AI to zero.
Okay.
Then we have a for loop and that will go forever or until the quick channel receives something.
So what do we do?
We populate the new variable pizza order by calling the function.
Make pizza with the current value of I and that gives back a current pizza, a pointer to a pizza order.
And if we're actually making or we tried to make a pizza, then we actually have some value from that,
something that has the pizza number and it also has a message and it also has a success variable.
Okay.
So we checked to make sure if pizza current pizza is not equal to nil, which will probably it's impossible
for that to happen.
But I'm a belt and suspenders kind of guy, so I always put this kind of checking.
Then once I get that value back current pizza, I populate I with whatever current pizza, pizza, pizza
number set to.
And of course that's our ordered number the first time through.
That'll be one, the second time it'll be two, so on and so forth.
Then we have this select statement.
Okay?
And that was really at the heart of what I wanted to get at in this particular exercise.
So what does this do?
This continues until certain cases are met.
Now, the first case, this one right here, we tried to make a pizza, so we send something to the
data channel, a chain pizza order.
So we get our current pizza, our pointer, and that's sent to this channel.
Okay.
If we want to quit.
Instead, we get a pizza maker equipped that populates this variable kitchen, which is of type chan
air and we close the channel, so we close pizza maker data and we close quick chan and then we want
to get out of this select statement and this if statement and this force statement.
In other words, we want to get out of the entire function pizzeria so we just return nothing and this
go routine then quietly goes away.
So that's where we are so far.
And of course, now we need to create and run the consumer.
So how do we do that?
Well, it's actually not that difficult.
We're going to use a four state a for loop.
But in this case, we're populating the variable I when we range through whatever is sent to pizza job
dot data, we just range through that channel and we have a couple of situations.
The first situation is, is the number of the current pizza, whatever we get on this channel, is it
less than or equal to the number of pizzas that constant?
If it is, then we had we had an attempt to make a pizza.
So we just wrote in a statement, if I drop pizza number, if that's less than or equal to the constant
number of pizzas, which in our case is ten, then we try to make a pizza.
Well, we don't know if we were successful or not.
So let's look at what we get from that channel.
And of course, that's if I don't success.
We were successful in this case.
So all we'll do is print out a message and we'll use that nice color package.
We'll set the text to Green because we're successful and I'll print out the message right off message.
Okay.
And then I can say colored out green.
Order number percent D is out for delivery.
Okay.
And my substitution is either pizza number.
Otherwise, we tried to make the pizza and something went wrong.
So this time all printed in red color dot red and we'll say I don't message once again and this time
we'll print out color dot red.
The customer is really mad.
Okay.
So that's our first situation.
If I got pizza, the number is less than or equal to the number of pizzas otherwise.
So else we're done for the day.
So we'll print out colored out sign and we'll just say, done making pizzas.
Now, what else do we want to do here?
We want to close that pizza job.
Channel error is a sign the value of pizza job don't close.
And of course, this function right here is actually defined by us right up here on the type producer.
We have the method close available to us.
Okay, so let's go back down here and we check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And of course, I don't think there's a situation where we can get an error here, but it's not going
to hurt to put in color dot red and then just error closing channel
and then whatever the error.
Okay.
So that should take care of everything we need to create and run the consumer.
So let's give this a try, see if we get everything right.
So I'll open the window up or upload a terminal up and I'll type go run dot.
So we got our message and right away received order number one.
And we can see that one is ready in it for delivery.
And we had an error making pizza number two.
And you notice if you watch very closely that the order, the pizzas are actually processed is not sequential.
So here we had let's look this finished running first.
See how we're making up to pizza number ten.
We're making that and we're finished done making pizzas.
So we started with order number one.
We received that and then we received order number two before order number one was done.
And we finished order number one.
We sent it out for delivery.
Then we got order number three and we're still working on pizza number two.
In other words, these are not in perfectly sequential order.
And of course, that's because our consumer is running as a go routine in the background.
It's running concurrently.
We're making more than one pizza at a time, or we're trying to make more than one pizza at a time.
And that, of course, is to be expected.
That's why when we closed the terminal here a while ago, a couple of lectures ago up here in this function,
make pizza, I said, I know the very first time that I come through, I'll be receiving a zero for
pizza number as the parameter to the call this function.
I know it's going to be set to one, but after that I'm not entirely sure what this value is going to
be because this is going to be called by a go routine which may have other produce or go routines running
in the background at the same time.
Okay, the last thing we have to do and we may as well do it just to be complete, is to print out the
ending message.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture.