So the last thing we want to do here is, as this comment says, is print out the ending message.
And of course, this has nothing to do with concurrency other than the fact that I am absolutely certain
this code will never execute until my producer is done producing and my consumer is done consuming.
But we may as well do it.
It'll just take a moment.
So I'll print out Color Dot Cyan and I'll put in, say done for the day.
Okay.
With that.
And then I'll duplicate that.
And just to make it a little more attractive, I'll replace the first line with a whole bunch of hyphens.
I started with hyphens.
I may as well close off with them as well.
So I have the done for the day message and let's print out our summary.
So color dot cyan and then a format string.
We made percent d pizzas but failed to make percent D with a total DA with percent d attempts in total.
And then my substitutions are pizzas made right there.
Pizzas failed right there.
And then, of course, total.
Okay.
So we have that and we may as well also put in a little message indicating just how the day went.
So we used a switch statement which looks suspiciously like a select statement, but is not.
Remember, select statements are only useful for channels.
So Case would just say, first of all, the case pizza's failed right there.
If it's greater than nine, then you had an awful day.
So we'll print out color dot red and we'll say it was an awful day.
And then we'll have another case.
Chase And this time pizza's failed is greater than or equal to six.
That's a good cutoff point, I think.
And we'll say color.
Don't read it again.
Cut it out, red.
It was not
a very good day.
Da da da.
And just a couple more case in this time will say pizza's failed is greater than or equal to four.
And we'll just say color dot yellow.
It was an okay day to do it, and case pizza's failed.
This time, we'll say, is greater than or equal to two.
These guys don't have very good standards.
Color yellow.
It was a pretty good day.
And then our default case.
And that is colored out green.
It was a great day.
Okay.
So with that little bit of change, let's run this again and make sure our message is print out as they
should.
One of the things I want to point out to you here is we just created a solution to the producer consumer
problem with concurrently running go routines.
And at no point did we even use a weight group or a sink mutex.
Now, to be clear, you could solve this problem using weight groups and sync up mutex as well.
There are many, many ways to solve this problem, but it's pretty important that you become familiar
with the use of channels, and I would encourage you to go through this code.
Just read it through, figure out how things are working, what's sending data to a channel?
Where do I get data from a channel?
Make sure you have that down cold and it will make the remainder of this course ever so much easier.
But here we are.
We're done making pizzas.
We're done for the day.
We made five pizzas but failed to make five with ten attempts in total.
And here this pizza shop thinks that a 50% success rate is an okay day.
So as I said, they don't have very good standards.
All right.
Let's move on and try looking at another classic problem from computer science.
And it's called the the dining philosophers problem.
And it's a lot of fun.
Now, to be clear, we're going to go through a couple of these classic examples, and they're going
to help you get used to the things you need to be familiar with in order to work with concurrent programming
the way that you should, and then will apply it to something that's closer to a real world situation.
And that's how we'll finish the course.
But we have a little ways to go yet.