So now that we have some idea as to what a race condition is, let's look at an example.
So I've started up Visual Studio code and I'm in a new folder.
So I'll initialize the project by starting a go on file, go mod in it, and I'll just call this example
too.
Okay, so we have a new government file and now I'll create a new go file called Mongo and it's in package
name and we'll just do a variation on what we did a couple of lectures ago.
Okay, so I'll create a variable MSG of type string and I'll create a main function.
And all that's going to do is set message to hello world, same as before.
Okay.
And now I want to actually change the value of update message a couple of times and then print it out.
So to do that, I'm going to do it in the background.
So create a new function and I'll just call this say update message and it takes one value s, which
is a type string and it doesn't return anything.
Okay.
And all this does is say MSG is equal to S.
Now, since I'm running that in the background, I probably need a weight group.
So let's put a weight group in here.
We'll just declare it right at the package level.
Var WG of type sync weight group.
And down here of course I'm going to defer WG, dot, dot and down here after my message weight group,
I'm going to spawn two instances of update message.
So of course I'm going to have to wait for them to finish.
So I'll say WG Dot and then I'm going to do it twice.
So I'll put two in there and then I'll call, go update message and I'll have that a string.
Hello Universe.
This should look familiar to you and then I'll duplicate that line.
I make this one Hello Cosmos.
And then I'll wait for those weight groups to finish.
WG Dot wait and then I'll print out the message format dot print line MSG.
Okay, dead simple program.
So let's go through this again.
We declare to package label variables one to hold our message and one for the weight group.
Then we have a function that we're going to call using the go keyword to run it as its own go routine
that calls defer weight group done so it'll decrement wait group by one when it finishes and all it
does is set the value of message to whatever it receives as a parameter.
Down here we give message an initial value, then we call weight group and two.
So we're going to wait for two decrements of the weight group and we call update message with Hello
Universe Call Update message with Hello Cosmos.
We wait for the weight group and then we print out the message.
So that all seems pretty straightforward.
So if I open up the terminal and type go run dot.
It said Hello Universe.
Well, that sort of makes sense.
You would think, since I'm waiting for these two weight groups, that it might be Hello, Cosmos.
So why is it Hello Universe.
Well, once again, this is an issue where we have a problem with concurrency.
Those two go routines.
The one on line 20 and the one on line 21 are both cold, and they're called in a particular order.
But I have no idea which one's going to finish first.
Now, in the instance we just ran, it's pretty clear that Hello Cosmos Line 21 actually finished before
line 20, even though it was called after line 20.
If I run this again, there's really no telling what kind of information I'm going to get back.
I've got a low universe again now three times in a row, but it might at some point be Hello Cosmos.
Now, if I run this program one more time, but this time I say Go run, dash, race and then dot watch
what happens.
It gives me a warning.
Data race and a data race takes place when you have concurrent go routines, as you know, that access
the same piece of data and because you're never sure which one's going to finish first, you actually
run into problems.
So how do I fix this?
You know, how do I actually make this problem go away?
Well, we can do that by using something called a mutex, mutual exclusivity.
And that's exactly what we're going to be looking at in the coming lectures.
So right now we have an example.
So right now we have a program that has a race condition.
And unless I put that flag dash race when I run the program, I probably have no idea that this is actually
a program that might cause me problems, that will cause me problems down the road.
So we're going to address that in the next lecture.
We'll have a look at Sync Mutex, and this is a very simple example.
So once we go through these two simple examples, one with the race condition and one addressing the
race condition, we'll look at a slightly more complex one.
Okay.
So let's move on.