So right now our program has a bit of a problem.
These two calls to update message on line 20 and 21 are both running at the same time.
They're concurrent and we have no idea which one is going to finish first.
And both of them, as you can see here, access the package level, variable MSG.
And because we're not sure which call to update message is going to finish first.
We have no idea what the value of MSG is going to be by the time our program terminates.
So we need to fix that and fortunately GO makes it remarkably easy to do so.
We're going to use something else from the sink package.
Right now we're using sink weight group and now we're going to use a mutex.
Now, I'm not going to make that a package level variable because I want to stress the importance of
not copying a mutex once it's been created.
So instead, I'll put it right here in the main function right after I populate Mzgee with Hello World.
Let's create a variable which I'll call mutex and it's of type synchro mutex.
Okay.
Now I'm going to modify update message to receive async mutex but is going to receive it and I'll just
call it M4 for mutex.
It's going to receive it as a pointer and this is important.
Sync Dot mutex.
Okay.
Now down here, I'll call both of these these update message lines, I'll add a reference to the attacks.
So I'll copy this and paste it here.
Okay.
So now we have the mutex being passed to update message and again we're passing it as a pointer because
you don't want to copy a mutex once it's been created or it just won't work in up here.
I'll just use it.
So how does it work now?
It's dead simple here.
Before I write to the variable MSG, that package level variable I just call import lock.
So now I have exclusive access to MSG.
Nobody else can change its value until I'm done with it.
And once I'm done with it, not surprisingly, I call import unlock.
Okay.
And that's all there is to a new text.
Well, there's actually a bit more to it, but we'll get to that later on.
But you can see how easy it is to use a new text.
So let's run our program one more time and I'll leave the dash race in there.
And again, I'm not sure what the result is going to be because I haven't actually waited for one particular
go routine to finish before the other one does.
So it might be university, it might be cosmos.
But the important thing here is that I'm accessing data safely.
This is what's called a thread safe operation.
Okay, so I run it and it says, Hello, Cosmos, I run it again.
It says, Hello Cosmos.
Third time this time it changed the universe.
But that's okay because I'm accessing the data safely.
There is no race condition.
Okay, now this is a really simple example.
Let's move on and try a slightly more complex example.
Okay?
And again, this is to illustrate how mutex is work it.
It's also to illustrate how important it is to test for race conditions when you're accessing data from
a go routine, running in the background, running concurrently with something else, you really have
to get in the habit of testing for race conditions.
Okay, let's move on.