Before we move on to a more complex example involving new taxes, let's write a test for our existing
code.
But before I do that, what I want to do is to restore this code to the way that it was before we added
our new taxes.
Okay, so I'm going to copy this and just to save it or paste it down here and then comment this out
so I can restore it back to the proper version later on.
Then I'm here.
I'll remove my reference to a mutex in the parameters to update message.
I'll remove both of my lock and unlock.
So there's a lock on, there's unlock on.
I'll get rid of my variable mutex here in the main function and remove these.
Okay, so we're going back to the way that it was before we put our mutex in there.
So there it is.
Now let's create a new file over here called Main Underscore Test.
Go.
Okay.
And again, this is in package main.
And I'll write one test func and I'll call this one test underscore update message.
And it has one parameter T, which is a pointer to testing dot t.
Okay, so let's write the test.
And the test will be pretty simple.
I'll set message equal to and that's a package level variable so I can use the equals operator.
Hello world.
Okay.
And then I'll create a weight group.
I'll use my weight group because it's a package level variable.
Add one and I'll call.
Go update message with Goodbye Cruel World just to change it to something else.
WG Dot, wait.
Okay, so I'm basically duplicating the functionality that I have in the main function, which I have
to in order to test this properly and then to write my test.
If message is not equal to goodbye cruel world with an exclamation mark, I have an error.
T dot error.
I'll just put incorrect value in MSG.
Okay.
Now that appears to be a good test, but remember we removed our mutex lock and unlock.
So let's open our terminal and type.
Go test dot.
And it all seemed to pass.
But just like I could go run dash race if I put go test dash race dot.
It passes again.
But what happens if I change this to A to duplicate this line and change this one to say X?
Okay.
Now, if I type, go test dash race.
Now I have to go routines running in the background, both accessing the same data in the form of message
that string.
Now when I run it.
Now I get warning data race.
Okay.
So there is a clear illustration once again of the danger of race conditions.
And remember, when you run the test by itself, if I just go go test, Don.
It seems fine.
But when I add that condition, check, dash, race that flag, then it lets me know there's a bit of
a problem.
Okay.
Just to let you know that you don't have to test for race condition conditions by running your program.
You actually write tests and add that flag dash race just to make sure that everything is going to behave
as expected.
Okay.
Now, let's move on to a slightly more complex example.