So let's try a slightly more complex example of a situation where syntactic mutex might be useful.
Now what I'm going to do is just delete everything that's in main dog.
Go here in the project.
I was working on the last lecture and then because this test doesn't make sense anymore, I'll just
delete that.
So we'll delete that.
Move it to the trash and back in mean don't go.
Okay.
We need some kind of situation, some kind of problem to solve where it makes sense to use.
And this is a totally arbitrary decision on my part, both weight groups and Sync Dump mutex.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to write a program that will project how much money someone's going
to make in the next year, the next 52 weeks.
Okay, so I'm going to have a main function, so -- me.
So let's just write some comments to figure what we're going to do.
I'm trying to figure out how much money somebody is going to make in, say, 52 weeks.
Right?
So I'll need some variables.
So a variable for bank balance, there's spell balance, right?
And once I'm done with that, I want to print out starting values.
How much do I have to start with?
Okay.
And we'll make that zero just to make it easy.
And then we want to define weekly revenue.
How much money do you make in a week and where does it come from?
And we'll have multiple sources of income just to give us something to work with.
Okay, then I want to loop through 52 weeks, which is one year, and print out how much is me.
And I'm also going to keep a running total.
So that that'll be a loop.
And inside the loop will do all that magic and at the very end will print out final balance.
Okay, so this seems pretty straightforward.
So we're going to have multiple sources of income.
We're going to loop through 52 weeks in a year and add up how much we're making from each of those sources
to get a final balance, a very simple and admittedly highly contrived problem.
But we're just trying to illustrate a concept here.
So the first thing I'll do is I'll define a weight group.
I'm going to need one of those, so I'll make that a package level variable silver.
WG, which is a type Cinque Dot weight group.
Okay.
So that imported sync form.
That's good.
I'm at uni, but I haven't.
And in go.
It's very common to group bits of data that are related into one struct.
So we'll define a type which I'll call income and it's a struct and it will have two fields.
First of all, what's the source?
Where are you getting this money from?
And that will just be descriptive.
It's just a string.
And then how much do you make from that source?
In any given week, I'll call that amount.
And just to make the math easy, I'll make it an integer.
Okay, so there is my type.
Now let's define some variables down here.
Start with inside the main function.
I'll have one variable called bank balance and it's going to be an integer.
And of course, because I'm defining that variable and not giving anything to it, it has a default
starting value of zero, which is exactly what I need it to be.
No, I'll printed some messages.
So under that comment where I say print out starting values, I'll just say format, print F and I want
to do the import format or print F, that's better.
Now it's important for me and I'll just print out, say initial account balance and then a colon, a
dollar sign, a percent D placeholder for integer and .00.
Okay.
And my substitution is bank balance.
And of course, that's going to be putting zero in there.
No problem.
So we've printed out a message now opened to blank line format of print one, and that gives me a blank
line.
I want to define my weekly revenue and of course that's going to use that type I just set up called
income and we'll just make up some values here.
So I'll say my incomes plural is a sign the value of a slice of income and I'll just give it some value.
So the first one will be in curly brackets, the source, and that will be say your mean job, whatever
this person job is.
Okay.
And the amount how much money does this person make in a week?
Well, $500.
Easy math.
Okay, now let's duplicate this a few times.
Say three more times.
One, two, three.
And we'll just put in three additional sources.
So the second source might be gifts.
Maybe this person's grandmother gives them $10 a week.
Okay.
And the third one.
Well, it's not can't have two main jobs.
Let's make this a part time job.
Lots of people have to work more than one job these days.
So this person's a dog walker and they make a pretty good one.
$50 a week for walking dogs.
And the final one is this person has some investments.
Investments and will make that they have really good investments.
They're making $100 a week.
Okay.
So now I have my income.
Now the next thing I want to do is just to loop through this.
So we'll say.
Four.
And indexes.
I income is what we're looping through.
And those are populated.
When I range through.
Not the 52 weeks.
Not yet.
That's range through income.
Okay.
We'll get to the 52 weeks in a minute.
So now I have those two variables I the current iteration and income, which is the current value of
the slices, strings, incomes.
Okay, so what do I want to do in here?
Well, actually, at this point, here's where I want to do the 52 week calculation.
But I want to do the 52 week calculation for each of the sources one at a time.
Now, I can go and write another function out there and just call that as a go routine by putting the
go keyword in front of it.
But this time I'll just inline the function go.
We're going to go a funk.
And that's going to take two parameters.
All right.
Which is an integer and income, which is a type income.
Okay.
So that's my function.
And I'll close it off right now, and I need to populate it with those two values I'm sending as parameters.
And those are called I in income.
Okay.
So this is going to run in the background.
And what do I want to do here?
Well, here's where I actually want to go through all 52 weeks.
So I'll put in a for loop for week is assigned the value of one.
My first week week is less than equal to 52 and again 52.
And will increment week one time each the each time through the loop.
Okay.
So what are we going to do here?
Well, to start with, I'll get the current bank balance.
Camp is a sign the value of bank balance, which the very first time through will be zero.
And then I add to that whatever the income for this current income source is for the current week plus
easy camp plus equals, I'm going to add to the current value of temp, which is bank balance income
date amount.
Okay.
And now I set bank balance to ten.
So in theory, I've added some value to my bank balance.
Okay.
And then we'll printed a message.
So we'll say format dot, print f and my format string is on week percent D you earned whatever the
value is.
Dollar sign percent d .00.
From a percent s whatever the sources and of course print out doesn't actually put a carriage returning.
So we have to put a slash in in like that.
And my substitutions for those are weak and income.
I'm out.
And the last one is income source.
Okay.
So that prints it out.
Now, of course, the one thing that you immediately spot here is that we need some weight groups.
Otherwise this program's never going to finish.
Okay, so let's go up here.
We've got our sync weight group already defined in a variable.
WG So what I need to do initially is to add the appropriate number of weight groups, and of course
that's going to be the length of my income.
So all I do here is say WG again WG and len of incomes.
So now I have defined my weight group.
Okay.
And down here when I'm going through this particular function, after this inline function is done,
I need to decrement that by one and we know how to do that.
Defer.
WG done.
Okay.
And of course, outside of this main loop, the, the big one that starts on line 35, we wait for all
our weight groups.
WG to wait.
Okay.
And the last step, apparently, or at least it appears to be, is to print out the results.
So format print F final bank balance column dollar sign percent D 0.0 0 a.m. i.
Substitution is just electrons.
Okay.
And then I'll print a blank format of print line.
Now, when I write this code, it all seems to make perfect sense.
I have my weight groups to find up here.
No problem.
I'm adding the appropriate number of entries to my weight group.
I have the defer weight group done and I'm pretty things that once everything is finished, I wait for
them down here and printed the balance.
But if we run this so I'll clear the screen in my terminal and type go run dot.
Everything seemed to work pretty well.
I have 3000 or 34,320 and everything appeared to work pretty well here.
Got lots of messages coming out.
Okay.
But if I clear the screen and type, go run dash race dot.
I get an error message up at the top here.
It says.
Warning data race.
And again, that data race is because I'm accessing this variable bank balance from multiple go routines
running at the same time, potentially at the same instant.
But certainly there's going to be an overlap of of of accesses to that particular shared resource.
So I need to fix that.
And of course, here's where we use center mutex.
So how do we do that?
Well, let's go back into our main function.
And right after I define bank balance, let's create a new tax.
And I'll call this one bar balance of type sync dot mutex.
Okay.
And I call it balance because that's what I'm locking in.
Unlocking is the bank balance.
So now where do I actually lock and unlock this particular resource?
Just pause the video and think about where the appropriate place to put that lock.
Command and that unlock command might be.
And I'm sure you're not going to have any difficulty figuring this out.
So give it a second.
I'm going to pause here for a moment, give you a chance to think about this.
You can pause the video and let's give it a try.
Hopefully you've figured out where that's supposed to go.
Okay.
I'm going to put it right here inside of the inner for loop, not the outer for a loop, but inside
of this inner for loop inside of the function itself.
Here's where I need to lock my access to the bank balance.
So the very first thing I do in this for loop is just call balance, dot lock.
And when I'm done working with balance, I go balance the unlock.
And now when I put my terminal and clear the screen and type go run dash race dot.
There should be no warning.
And in fact, there is not.
And of course, the other thing to note here and I just keep stressing this because it's important to
know how concurrency works.
I'm not getting all of the information in any sequential fashion.
Okay.
For a part time job.
Everything's coming in order.
But notice how a main job is interspersed here.
And then we switch to investments.
Then we go back to main job.
And that's because these these routines, these go routines are actually running concurrently.
And of course, that means that you can't depend upon getting these results in a particular order.
But in any case, we've actually successfully solved our race problem.
Here's a simple program that uses both weight groups and sync up mutex.
And now there is no potential race condition.
All right, let's move on.