So before we move on to an even more complex example, let's take a little bit of time and write a test
for this program for the one that calculates the earnings for a person for a year.
And of course, this one's really easy, so we'll just create it.
File main underscore test dock go in package main and we'll create one function func.
Now I'll just call this test underscore main.
Now you can't call it test main like this because that's actually something that's used by the testing
package itself.
But you're probably aware of that.
So I'll call a test main takes one parameter T pointer to testing dot T and we'll do the same sort of
thing we did last time around.
We're writing to the console, so we need to keep a copy of whatever OS standard standard out is.
So I'll call it standard out and that's equal to OS STD out right there.
And that does the import for me.
Now, once I've captured that, of course, I need to create my own versions.
So R and W and we don't care about a third parameter.
Come from over start pipe and now we need to set of STD out.
Make that equal to W from our pipe.
Okay, so now we have a means of capturing information.
And now we just run the main function.
Main, and it doesn't run as a go routine.
And by default, main is its own code routine.
When we're finished, we close the pipe.
So I'll ignore the error when I call w dot close, closed the w pipe and then we read the results into
a variable called result.
So result and ignore the second return parameter come from IO.
Don't read all and that does the import for me and I'm reading.
Ah, okay.
So I have that.
Let's convert it to a string output
and that's a sign the value of casting to a string result.
And I just check to see if the correct value is in there.
And if you recall, when this program runs properly, the result, the bank balance should always be
$34,320.
So all I have to do after I set post STD out back to its original value that's TD out is to write a
simple test if not strings dot contains and I'm looking at output and I'm expecting to find $34,320.
Then she'll take that right.
And if that's not there then I have an error te error and I'll just say wrong balance returned.
Okay, now let's run this test.
So I'll run it two ways.
The first way I look at my terminal, just type go test dot.
And I happened to get the right result that time.
But now let's check for race conditions.
Go.
Test dash.
Race start.
And it should pass.
And it does.
Okay.
So that was simple enough.
Let's move on to something a little more complex in this, actually considerably more complex than this.
And it's what's referred to in computer science circles as the producer slash consumer problem.
And it's a great opportunity to use what we've learned so far and apply it to a more complex problem,
one involving pizzas.
Let's move on.