This time around, I want to turn our attention to a considerably more sophisticated problem to solve.
And it's the sort of problem I would regularly give to students in first year computer science to figure
out on their own when we're dealing with concurrent or parallel programming.
Now, this is called the producer consumer problem, and this is the Wikipedia page entry for it.
And I'll put a link to this in the course resources and you can read about this at your leisure.
But as you can see here, it says, In computing, the producer consumer problem, also known as the
bounded buffer problem, is a family of problems just described by Dijkstra in 1965.
So it's been around for a long time.
And the great thing about this is that it gives us an opportunity to apply what we've learned so far
to a much more sophisticated problem.
So I'm going to go back to my I.D. and I've created a new window and opened a folder named Producer
Consumer, and now create a government file just to get started.
Okay, so in my terminal I'll say go mod in it and I'll just call it producer underscore consumer.
It doesn't matter what I call it here, I still want to spell it right.
Okay, so I created a government file.
Now I'll create a new go file called, not surprisingly, in Mango and it's in Package Main and it has
a main function.
So think of me and like I did last time.
What I'm going to do initially is just write some comments to figure out what we're going to do here.
The problem I'm presenting to you my version of the producer consumer problem is based upon a pizzeria.
So you have a pizzeria which has some people who make pizzas and that will be the producer in our producer
consumer problem.
Then we have a customer, one or more customers who at fairly regular intervals will place orders and
they're the consumers.
So they place the order.
The order goes to the pizzeria, they try to make the pizza.
Something might go wrong, somebody might quit, they might run out of an ingredient, whatever the
case may be, but they'll try to make the pizza.
And our goal here is to ensure that we write a solution to the producer consumer problem.
Now, that's a very general description, but as we go through, you'll see just how complex this problem
can be.
Okay.
So the first thing I'm going to do, I'll write some comments.
What I'm going to do initially is see the random number generator.
This will use pseudo random numbers.
And if we don't seed the random number generator, which is one line of code, we'll get the same result
every time.
So a generator, that's the first thing I'll do.
Then I'll print out a message saying the program is starting.
Okay, then I'll create a producer and I'll have to describe that using some kind of data structure.
But I'm going to have to create a producer, okay?
And then I'll have to run the producer in the background.
In other words, run the producer as its own go routine.
Okay.
And then I'll have to create and run consumer.
Now, this will be one or more customers.
One customer would be rather tedious, so obviously it'll be more than one customer.
But we're going to create that consumer and we're going to run it each time the consumer places.
In order for pizzas.
For a pizza, we'll have to send that request off to the consumer and then see what the result is.
Okay, so that's what's going to happen.
And then finally after that and that's one comment actually represents a fair bit of code will print
out the ending message.
Okay.
Now these comments give me an overall sense of what this main function is going to do.
But obviously we're going to have to have more than just the main function.
One of the things we're definitely going to need are a few types, okay, and a few constants.
So let's say when we're going to run this, let's define one constant up here const and I'll call this
one number of pizzas.
How many pizzas are we going to try to make?
And we'll make that equal to ten, just to keep things simple to start with.
Okay.
We'll also declare a couple of variables.
We're going to have pizzas made, which will give us the running total of how many pizzas we've made.
And pizzas failed because sometimes when we try to produce something, we're going to fail.
For whatever reason.
We've run out of some resource.
Whatever the case may be, we might not succeed and I might have total, which will just be pizzas made
and pizzas failed and added together.
And these are all going to be integers.
Okay, so we have that and we'll also have to have a type for a producer.
If we're going to create a producer, we'll have a type four and it'll just be a struct and it's only
going to have a couple of fields.
But these fields will be something you haven't seen yet.
And this is our first introduction to channels.
Okay.
And I'll be talking more about channels in more detail in the next section.
But this will get us started.
And channels are really far more powerful than new taxes and weight groups because they allow one go
routine to exchange data with another go routine.
They can talk to each other.
Remember, once we use that keyword, go to send a go routine off into the background.
We actually can't talk to it.
All we can do is wait to see if it's finished.
That's all we can do with the tools we have at our disposal right now.
So instead, let's put a couple of channels in here.
I'll make one called Data.
And to create a channel to describe the channel, you just use the keyword channel.
But then each channel has to have some kind of type, and I'm going to call this one something that
doesn't exist yet.
Pizza order.
The producer is going to receive an order for pizza.
And we'll make that pizza order in just a minute.
Okay, then we're going to have another channel, which I'll call quick.
When we're finished making pizzas, for whatever reason, we're going to send some information to the
quick channel and something else is going to receive it and do something with it.
But in this case, it's a channel of channels here.
Okay.
So we have one channel that holds a channel of errors.
So there.
Now, this this doesn't make sense.
Don't despair when we go through channels in more detail.
It will become clear.
But for right now, let's just follow along.
So we have our producer type.
Let's create another type called pizza order.
The one that I referred to there on line eight.
And again, it's just a struct and we need the information for a particular pizza.
Number one, what order is this?
So I'll call it pizza number, and that's just going to be an integer.
So the first one will be one, the next one will be two, so on and so forth.
Then we're going to have a message with respect to that order.
Either succeeded, it failed, whatever it was, but we need to give some kind of feedback to whatever
places this order.
So that'll just be a string.
And finally, we'll have a Boolean success.
Did we successfully make this pizza?
If true, we did.
If false, we did not.
Okay, so now we have a main function that just consists of some comments and we have a type producer
and we have a type pizza order and we have a couple of constants up here.
One constant number of pizzas and a few variables, all of type it.
So this is enough to get us started.
In the next lecture, we'll start actually implementing the code necessary to solve the producer consumer
problem.
Okay, so let's move on.