So at this point we have the absolute bare bones of our project kind of sketched out using comments
and leave to find one constant and a few variables and a couple of types.
Now let's get started making this functional, and it's going to take a little while because there's
a fair bit to do here, but none of it is terribly complicated.
So first thing here, the main function I say, see the random number generator, and that's pretty
simple from the rand package, which is built right into the standard library local seed.
And that did the import for me and we're going to see that using time dot now dot Unix nano.
And I need to import the time package time dot now.
That's better.
Dot dot Unix nano.
And that will ensure that we don't get the same results every time we run the program.
Okay.
And now I say print out a message.
Well, that's pretty easy.
We can do that.
But to make things a little more interesting, I'd like to add some color to our output for this program.
And there are lots of ways of doing that with a console application in go, but one that's used by a
lot of people, including myself.
And I'll take you to my web browser is this 140 slash color.
So this is nice because it works on Windows.
It works on Macs.
It works on Linux.
So let's go get that just to make things a little easier to read.
So I'll open my terminal and clear the screen and go and get.
And it's github dot com slash f 80 I h slash C hello.
And then we'll go and get it and adds it to my go mod.
Okay.
So now it's available.
So now that I can print out messages with color, let's do so.
So here, after this comment, I'll just use the color package I just imported.
And it's as simple as saying color dot and then the color you want.
And in my case, I'll go with Cyan to start with, see why.
And, and I'll just print out the pizza, which always the spelling of this word bothers me.
Pizzeria That way the pizzeria is open for business.
Then I'll duplicate this line and just change all of these to hyphens so it's underlined.
Okay.
And of course, this has absolutely nothing to do with functionality, but it will allow us to read
things more easily once we get going here.
So I've seeded the random number generator.
I've printed this out, and the next thing I need to do is to create a producer.
Well, if you recall, the type producer up here has two fields data, which is Chan Pizza Order.
And then quit, which is, oddly enough, Chan Chan error.
Okay, well, I can create that.
We'll see why we have a chain of Chan before too long.
So don't.
Don't worry about that.
I'm going to create a pizza job.
That's what I'm going to call it.
And it's going to be a reference to a producer.
Then I'll fill in its fields.
So data.
And here I need to make a channel.
Now, just like you make a map, you have to make a channel using the built in keyword make.
I want to make a chan and the type you can see up there in producer on line 15 is pizza order.
So it's a chan of pizza order.
Okay, so there's my first field and my second one is a quit.
And this is just make a chan of chan a channel of channels of type error.
Okay.
So now I have created my producer, and then I need to run it.
I need to run the producer in the background.
And that means I'm going to have to have some kind of function.
Now, this function, I'm going to call Pizzeria.
So I'll make the function here and just leave it empty.
So func and I'll call this one pizzeria and it's going to take one parameter, which I'll call pizza
maker.
It doesn't matter what I call it, but I'm going to call a pizza maker.
And it's a pointer to a producer.
Okay.
So I'll just leave that empty for right now.
Now, down here, when I say run the producer in the background, all I'm going to do is say, Go pizzeria.
With the pizza job I just created.
Okay.
Now, this doesn't do anything so far, but you can see the logic here is pretty straightforward.
We're going to generate our random numbers randomly, or at least pseudo randomly by seeding the ran
package.
Then we print out a message.
Then we create one producer, which is a pointer to the type of producer, and we populate its two required
fields with channels.
So we make a chain of pizza order.
Then we make a chain chain error.
And that's just so we'll have a convenient method of closing the channel when we're done with it.
Because once you create a channel, when you're finished with it, the golden rule is you must close
it.
Okay.
So this gives us a means of closing the channel and then we run that producer in the background.
Now let's go out and have a look at the actual producer.
The two things that we need to worry about.
The first one is, why am I using that chain of channels?
Well, it just gives me, as I said a moment ago, a means of closing the channel.
So what I'm going to do is go up here after pizza order and before my empty pizzeria function, I'm
going to create a thunk that has the receiver of P pointer to producer, not pizza order producer.
And that means any type of producer now has access to the function I'm about to write.
I'm going to call this close because that's what I'm using it for, is to close a channel and it potentially
return.
An error.
Okay.
And all I have to do is to create a channel, and I'll use that.
Make an error again.
Okay.
This is just a means of sending back an error if something goes wrong.
And then.
From the receiver.
P dot quit.
So it's channel that that type has the one called quit.
I had the channel to it to want to just create it and then I return on the next line.
I return an error, if any.
Now that will be nil if I close the channel successfully, but it won't be nil if I tried to close the
channel and something went wrong.
So this is now available to any variable of the type producer.
That's why I have that channel chat.
Okay.
Now what do I want to do in this function pizzeria?
The one that I'm calling from line 50 down here when I run the producer in the background.
What is this producer supposed to do?
Well, let's read some comments and figure it out.
Number one, let's keep track of which pizza we are making or at least trying to match.
And I'm going to do that just by having a variable, some integer, and then I'll just keep track of
it.
And after that, we want to run forever or until we receive a quick notification.
And we're going to get that from the quick channel that's part of the producer type.
And we want to run forever.
And what do we want to do?
We're running forever.
We want to try to make pizzas.
Okay.
So we're going to try to make pizzas.
And again, this is running in the background.
So that means that we're going to have to have a for loop in a for loop with some condition that lets
us get out of there.
Now, if you think it through, the only thing the pizzeria knows about or the producer knows about
is the channel data, which is going to receive orders for pizzas and the channel quit, which tells
us we're all done making pizzas.
So quit.
In other words, stop the go routine pizzeria that's running in the background.
So when we think about it, we're going to have a for loop.
So we'll just have a for loop like this.
And inside of that, for loop, we're going to try to make a pizza.
Okay.
And then when we try to make that pizza, we're going to get something back.
We're going to get some indication as to whether the pizza was made, whether something went wrong,
whatever it was.
So we're going to check to see if we got a pizza back.
Then we have to decide, did we actually make the pizza successfully or did something go wrong or did
we quit?
So we're going to have to have some kind of decision structure in here, and that's going to allow us
to have a look at a really important thing in the world of channels in Go.
And it's called the Select Statement.
It allows us to determine what action to take based upon what kind of information we're getting back
from a given channel.
Okay, so this gets us started.
I can actually run this program and nothing will happen.
It will just print out a message.
Let's give it a try.
So let's open the terminal.
Clear the screen and type.
Go run dot.
And it gave me that opening message.
And actually it did more than that.
All I can see is that it printed this out.
But if you look at the logic in the program, what actually happened was we seeded a random number generator.
We printed out the message.
We created a producer.
Then we ran this this go pizzeria runs the pizzeria function as its own go routine concurrently beside
the main go routine.
And we handed it a new pizza job.
And then, of course, there was nothing to stop the program from continuing on at that point.
So even though we have this infinite for loop up here in the pizzeria function, it just terminates
and this go routine just dies because the program stopped execution.
But let's make it a little more useful, or at least start making it a little more useful in the next
lecture.