All right.
Let's keep going with the pizzeria, our producer so far.
We just have some comments and an empty for loop.
And we want to do more than that, of course.
So first comment says keep track of which pizza we are making no problem of.
Create a variable called I and I'll make that equal to zero.
Okay.
So that will keep track of the current number of the current pizza that we're making.
And then down here inside the four loop, of course, what we want to do is to, as the comment says,
try to make a pizza.
But I'm not going to do that right in this for loop.
Instead, I'll call a function that doesn't exist yet, as I often do.
So I'll say current pizza, which is a variable name I'm declaring right now, current pizza that's
assigned and I'm going to call a function called make pizza.
I'm going to hand that by the variable that I'm keeping track of up here on line 33.
So which pizza are we making?
So I'm going to call this function make pizza.
Okay.
Now let's create a function called make pizza.
So I'll make that right here above this one.
Funk make pizza.
And that takes one parameter, which I'll call pizza number, and it's an integer and it returns a pointer
to a pizza order.
Okay.
And if you look at the types we have defined up here, pizza order gives us pizza number.
The message, whatever message we're sending back, indicating what happened with this order and whether
or not we were successful in making this pizza.
So let's start on this function.
The first thing I'm going to do is increment pizza number.
The parameter I received for this order I want.
Okay.
So the very first time we call make pizza, we're handing it the variable R, which has the value of
zero and we just increment one.
So now we're working on order number one.
And of course, we don't want to keep going indefinitely.
So we'll check to see if the pizza number is less than or equal to our constant number of pizzas, which
we have set to tell.
If it's less than or equal to ten, then we're going to make this.
Otherwise, we're going to do something else.
So we'll put in a statement there.
Leave it empty for the moment.
We'll come back to it already.
So in the first clause in this statement, we're going to try to make a pizza.
Now, I don't want things to happen at the speed of light.
And even though I'm on an old computer, this is a seven year old Mac and recording this lecture on,
it'll still go very, very quickly.
So let's create a variable called delay.
And that's going to be equal to from the random package, which we seeded in the main function.
We'll get an integer back into N right there.
Okay.
And that'll give us some value and I'll just choose five.
So that'll give me a neat random number back.
And as you can see, if you point at this, it says returns n as in a non-negative pseudo random number
in the half open interval from the default source it panics of and is less than or equal to zero.
I'm going to add one to that because it's possible to get the number zero back.
But I want to delay at least for 1/2.
Okay.
And I'll print out a message.
So I'll say format, print, ev
and I'll just say I received an order or received order number.
That's good enough order number.
And it will be an integer percent D.
And then I'll give it its carriage return because print out doesn't give me one.
Am I substitution for that percentage, of course, is pizza number.
So we'll say received order number one the very first time this is executed.
Okay.
Now, I'm going to try to make the pizza and I'm going to assume that in most cases, we make the pizza
successfully.
But if we hit some arbitrary number, then we failed.
Okay.
So I'll generate a random number and I'll have a one in three chance of something going wrong with your
order.
So I'll just say R&amp;D, which is a random number, is equal to Rand.
And again, and I'll give it the number 12 plus one, which will give me a random number between one
and 12 and I'll initialize MSG.
The message we're going to generate, we send this back as an empty string.
And I'll also set success, which is part of the pizza order we'll be sending back.
I'll assume it's false to begin with.
So now I have these things.
Now let's see if we were successful in making our pizza.
So we're going to do this by looking to see if the R and D that number we got back there, if it's less
than, say, five, if R&amp;D is less than five, then the piece failed.
So I'll increment that package.
Level variable.
Variable pizzas failed by one.
Otherwise else.
Pizzas made is incremented by one.
We successfully made this pizza.
And of course, the other variable I need to keep track of is total.
How many pizzas did we try to make?
So total plus.
Plus we increment that by one.
Now we'll print out a message again, format or print line or print f and my format string says making
pizza number percent D it will take percent the seconds and then a carriage return.
And my substitutions are pizza number and delay, which we calculated right up there on 135.
So this just gives us some feedback as to what's going on, and that will delay for a bit.
So we'll just say time dot sleep.
And again, this is just so it doesn't scroll by on the screen very, very quickly and it will be sleeping
for timed off duration delay times timed out second.
Now let's figure out what kind of message to send back.
We already know based upon what we have there on the lines 42 through 46.
We know whether or not we were successful.
But let's to make up a reason as to why we couldn't make a pizza or make the appropriate message if
we were successful in making it.
So we'll just do a simple if statement, if our R&amp;D is less than or equal to two.
This is one situation where it failed.
So I'll say message is now equal to format or as print as we're creating a string.
And my format string will be three stars because it's an error.
We ran out of ingredients
for pizza number, percent the integer and then an exclamation mark.
And my substitution of course is pizza number.
But else, if R&amp;D is less than or equal to say four, this is our conditions where we failed.
If it's one, two, three or four, we failed and we'll just copy this and change the message.
And this time, the error.
The error will be.
Say the cook quit while making pizza number D and D.
Of course, percent D is pizza number.
Otherwise, if none of those conditions are true, then we made the pizza.
So we'll paste this and we'll say success is now equal to true.
Remember a defaulted defaults then her messages just messages now equal to format or s print f pizza
quarter number percent d is ready.
We made the pizza and our substitution was against pizza number.
So we've now created our delay.
We printed out a message saying we got the order.
We initialized a random number variable between one and 12.
We initialize the message to be an empty string.
We initialize success to be false.
And then we decide whether or not we actually made the pizza successfully and update our three counters.
Then we print out another message saying We're trying to make it.
We delay a little bit some random number of seconds, and then we decide what message and success are
going to be based upon the value of R&amp;D.
So that's where we are so far.
So what we need to do now in this situation is to return a pizza order, a pointer to a pizza order,
as you can see right here in line 32.
Okay, so let's return it.
We can say P, which for pizza order is assigned the value of a type pizza order.
When we populate this fields.
So pizza number, that of course is the variable pizza number which we incremented by one when we started
this function.
The message which is the variable MSG and success, which is the variable success.
Okay.
So we have that p now we need to return it as a pointer, return a reference to P.
Now if you think it through the other situation where I have this else clause down here, I actually
don't need announce because if everything went according to plan, in other words, our condition,
our check up here, if pizza number is less than or equal to our constant number of pizzas, I don't
even need the else clause, but I do need to return something and I'm going to return.
Here is a pizza order, but the only thing I'll populate it with is the current value of pizza number.
The other things don't matter because we're done for the day.
So return a reference to and I'll just build it right here.
A pizza order.
And the only value I'll populate is pizza number, which would be set to pizza number.
And if pizza number is greater than ten, then it has to be 11.
So the only thing we're returning here is a reference to a pizza order with pizza number populated with
a value of 11 because our constant number of pizzas is at the ten.
So there is our make pizza function.
In the next lecture, we'll actually do something with what we're what we have here on lines 83 through
87 this for loop.
Okay.
So we're getting closer to being able to use that select statement I talked about in the last lecture.