So we're finally at the point where we can start work on the celebrity make and then some project name
functionality, in other words, someone wants to build an application using celebrities so they have
the celebrities binary installed on their system and they just type celebrities new and then the name
of whatever it is they want to build.
So of course, to do that, we have to work on the Seelye on our command line application.
And I'm looking right now at the file mango in the celebrities project in the CMT slash seelye folder.
And of course, in the main function here, this is after we call set up where we get started.
So we're switching here and we have help and version of migrating make, and I'm just going to add a
new so I'll put it right after help case new.
And of course, we actually require argument to in this case, because we need something to name whatever
the project is going to be.
So if our two is equal to an empty string, then we'll exit gracefully with the error.
Error New New requires an application name like that.
Otherwise, we're going to call a function, and we'll put all of the functionality for building a new
application in its own file with its own function.
So we'll just call this function that doesn't exist yet.
Do new with our two, and that's it for that file.
So now let's go over here to our Command Seelye folder and create a new file, which I'll call NewCo.
And of course, it's in package men, and we'll create a function funk do to try that again.
New and it takes one argument apt name, which is a strength and of course, that's actually our two
that's part of this function.
But it's actually the name of the new application.
So that's what we'll call it for our parameter.
Now I'm going to convert whatever they pass me as a name to lowercase.
OK.
So I'll say apt name is now equal to from the strings package right in the standard library to lower
that name.
And I have it in lowercase.
So let's think about the things we're going to do here.
When someone types celebrities knew the third thing that they type, the first one being celebrities,
the second one being new.
The third thing that the Typekit might be a single word like my app or it might be a complete URL like
GitHub dot com slash t solr slash my app.
And of course, we can't name a folder, something that has slashes in it.
So we'll have to say sanitize the application name.
Convert you, Earl, to single word.
OK, so that's the first thing we're going to have to do, then we want to get the application kind
of an empty celebrity application with everything set up for them so they can start working really quickly.
And of course, the easiest way to do that is to take my app or a stripped down version of my app and
put that on and get repository and then we'll just clone it.
So we'll say, get clone the skeleton application, and we're going to do that right in go code.
So a clone, an application.
And after we've done that, we want to remove the don't get directory because we don't want to have
them start an application that has a git folder that says, Hey, the code that you see right here belongs
in this repository over there.
So we'll get rid of that.
And that way it becomes an empty application.
They can make their own git commit and push it to their own repository.
Then we need to create a ready to go on file, and we can't put that in the git repository.
Of course, that's just not a good idea because it would have the wrong application name and all sorts
of things, so we need to create one for them.
Then we should create a make file.
And of course, that'll be different if they're on Windows or Unix or Linux or a Mac, so we'll put
the appropriate make file in place for them.
Then we'll need to update the Goda Mod file because what they're going to get from the repository won't
be appropriate for their purposes.
That's a really simple fix, but we do need to make a couple of changes in that document.
Then we'll need to update the existing Dongo files with correct name and imports.
And when we get to that part of this section, you'll understand what I mean.
But we're of course, when we do a clone, it's going to have imports that refer to the incorrect repository,
so we'll have to update that for them as well.
And finally, we have to run.
Go mod tidy in the project directory just to make sure that everything is cleaned up.
Now this looks like a lot of work, but it's actually a pretty simplistic process at this point, and
we'll get started on implementing some of this in the next lecture.
But this is an overall roadmap of where we're going to go in this section.
So let's move on to the next lecture and get started with sanitizing the application name.