So this time around, we need to update our our Dongo files and make some changes, and I'll give you
an example.
Let's go over to the GitHub repository that we created.
And if we look at main, don't go, for example, the code that we're cloning has things like you see
here in the import statement, my app slash data, my app slash handlers, my app slash middleware.
And of course, this isn't correct if someone typed celebrity's new GitHub dot com John Smith slash
my cool application.
We need to change my app to the correct URL so we can do that pretty easily.
And let's get started.
Let's go back over to our code.
And what I'm going to do is create a couple of functions in the Helpers Dot Go file, and I'm going
to create them there because I might need to reuse this kind of search and replace of go code at some
point in the future.
So I'll go to the helper stock, go file and make sure you open the one that's inside the CMD Seelye
folder, not the one at the root level of the celebrities project.
Let's open that up, and let's scroll to the bottom of this file and let's create a couple of functions,
so I'll create a stub function first.
Func, I'm going to call this one update source files plural, and it will take a path which is of type
string, and it will take something called f.i, which is filing of type of sport file info right there.
And finally, it will take an E R of type error e r or and it will return potentially an error.
OK.
And at the very bottom, this I'm going to say return nil, and we'll fill in the source code for this
in a minute.
Now this function update source files will be called by another function called folk update source.
And it doesn't take any parameters right now.
And all it's going to do is say walk the entire project, including folders.
So let's put a comment in here in here walk.
Entire project folder, including some folders.
So a kind of recursive walk through the entire project structure.
And we do that by calling for setting a variable error and calling from the standard library file path
right there.
Don't walk and walk actually requires a directory which will be Dot just dot the current directory in
our case, and we're going to update source files.
We're just handing it that function name.
OK.
And of course, we have to check for an error.
If error is not equal to no.
Then we'll exit gracefully.
We just can't go any further with the error.
OK.
Now, all the magic obviously happens here, an update source, Fox.
So the first thing we're going to do is to check for an error
before doing anything else.
So we'll say if error is not equal to nil and we got error as a parameter passed at this function,
then we'll just return the error.
But if we get past that, then we need to say, Is this a directory?
Check if current file is directory because we're watching the entire directory structure.
So if if I, which were received as a call to this function, that is dear, if it is a directory,
then return null, OK, and it will just go on to the next pop.
Now we want to make sure that we only check go files so matched and error are assigned the value of
from the file Pathmark package file path dot match and we're matching Stardust Go.
OK.
And we're looking for fikeni file info name.
And if error is not equal to nil, then we'll just say return the error.
But if we get past that, we have a matching file.
So let's read its contents.
We'll just make sure it matched.
We'll read its contents, read file contents, and we'll say read, which is just a variable.
I'm creating an error are assign the value of I owe you still don't read file.
Right there.
And we're using path, which we received as a call to this function.
And again, we'll check for an error, so we'll see if error is not equal to nil at this point.
If I can't read a file that I found, I'm not going to just return the error, I'll exit gracefully
with the error.
It's something is really gone wrong here.
Your file system is full.
You've got a bad hard disk.
Whatever it may be.
I don't want to go any further.
Now we'll do the search and replace.
So I'll create a variable called new contents is assign the value of strings to replace, and I'm going
to replace string casting read to a string.
I'm looking for my app.
That's all I have to look for.
I'm going to replace it with app URL, which is why I made that a package local variable in the first
place and replace every occurrence.
OK.
And right, the changed file.
And that's as simple as saying error is equal to I.O.U. till
the right file path, and I cast new contents to a slice of bytes.
New contents.
And I'll just pass zero as the final parameter.
OK.
Don't change anything.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then again, I'm going to exit gracefully because you should be able to write a file.
Otherwise, your file system is full or whatever.
And at that point, this should be pretty much ready to go, so let's say this.
And you can read more about the walk function if you just roll over.
It gives you a nice summary of how the package works.
It's pretty straightforward.
And if you've ever searched and replace multiple files in GO, you've undoubtedly used this before.
But in any case, now I can go back to New Dot Go and down here where I'm saying update existing dgo
files.
I can just say color yellow just to let the users know what's going on and again and invent it with
a tab dating source files.
Make a call to that.
And all I do is say update source.
And that should be pretty much ready to go.
So the last step in this process before we try actually running celebrities, tossing new and making
sure everything works as expected.
The last thing we do is run go more tidy and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.