So it's almost time to run commentary, but I have a couple of things I need to clean up first.
I'm looking at the file newco in the CMD Seelye folder of the celebrities project and right here where
I call update source.
Before I do that, I really should change directories, and it wouldn't be a huge deal if there were
no go files beside the place where I run this command.
But I really don't want to affect anything except what's in the directory that this function creates.
So I'll call OS.
HDR changed here and I want to change to dot slash plus app name and then run that update source.
OK.
And the other thing I want to change and this is just because I've been working with Go for so long.
Back in Helpers Dot Go.
Where I call, read, file and write file.
I used what it used to be prior to go one point one six and that's I.O.U. tell and it really should
be OS that was updated in Go 16.
Go one point one six.
So let's make that OS, and let's save our file and make sure that everything works the way that it
should.
We imported OS and we don't have our utility more perfect.
OK, so that was just a little bit of housekeeping.
Now back to our running go my tidy.
So by the time I get to line 123 in this function in this file, new don't go, I've already changed
to the app directory, the one that we created at the very beginning of this file.
So now I want to run go on tidy.
So again, color yellow just to let them know what's going on.
Indent it one tab running go lord tidy dot dot dot.
And now let's run it.
And this is really simple.
We'll create a command CMD, which is assigned the value of from the exact package in the standard library
dot command.
And we give it the command go and then mod and then tidy.
And this might not work, but we'll try it in.
In a moment we might have to put a compatibility flag in there and on the next line, we'll run it.
Error equals seemed to start and we checked for an error, so I'll just copy all of this and paste it
in here.
And now put a little bit of message out for the user.
Similarly, a pass that we can print colored green done building plus app name.
Actually, they typed up you URLs, put that you are out there and colored green.
Whatever else you want to say, go build something awesome.
OK.
So at this point, I should be able to build my seelye.
Let's open our terminal window and type, make, build and actually create a file called celebrities
in the dist directory.
Let's go to the disk directory.
And let's try running it now, it might fail because it might try to go and fetch GitHub dot com slash
tea seller slash hilarious, and I haven't pushed that up there yet, but we should get something anywhere.
So let's type.
Dot slash celebrity's new and I'll call it GitHub dotcom slash TESOL Solr new project.
So clumsy and everything seemed to run the way that it was supposed to.
OK, so let's try opening that folder or create a new window.
And I will open the file open.
And I'll find where I have that thing actually stored, which would be in here under celerity, us under
dist right here in open new project.
And that's what I want to open.
And let's make sure everything worked as it supposed to.
So I'll zoom the window and I'll open.
Mean, don't go.
So it has GitHub dot com slash Tesla slash new project slash data perfect, and it's importing that
perfect.
And there is no don't get directory that looks promising.
Let's see what the errors are in here.
OK?
The only error it has is that it can't find GitHub dot com slash TESOL or slash alerts.
And that makes sense because I haven't pushed that there yet.
But that's exactly what we're going to do in the next lecture.