So in order to make the celebrity horse new, whatever your project name is functional, we of course,
have to push our celebrity project to a public git repository.
So I'm looking at the celebrities project right now, and the first thing I'll do is create a don't
get ignored file
just to make sure things I don't want committed to my repository are not committed.
So as I did last time, I put that idea, and of course, that's for jet brains projects.
If you ever worked with jet brain software, you'll know that it creates a idea folder.
And I don't want coverage dot out to go up there, and I don't want my guest directory to go in there
as either.
Not shabby enough.
And I'll also create a read me file.
I'll just leave it empty.
Just put a title in.
Read me to me and in here I'll put celebrities.
And of course, you put actual read me information there, but I'm just going to put it in there.
So we have a read me file on the repository.
Now I'll open my terminal window, make sure I'm in the right directory.
I'm in the root level of my celebrity celebrity house project.
So type, get in it and get ad dot and get commit m initial entry.
OK, so everything's been committed to get.
Now I'll switch over to my web browser and create a new repository, and I'll make the name match exactly
what I used everywhere.
My source code, which is just pea, solar slash, solara toss and I'll make sure it's public and create
it.
And then copy this code or these commands, push an existing repository from the command line, so I
copy those, switch back to my terminal, paste them in and hit return.
And that should do it.
So now we'll go back and make sure it's there.
Celebrities, it's all there, perfect, so now that I've committed this to a committed and pushed it
to a remote repository, I should be able to try it out and see if we got everything right and we'll
take care of that in the next election.