So it's time to try our celebrity's new functionality and see what we got wrong, and I'm pretty sure
we got something wrong.
But anyway, let's run it and try it.
So am I still a toss up and I am going to run make built and that should build a Seelye version, my
C-list celebrity application into the disc directory.
So if I change into the Disc Directory, I'm doing less unless there is.
So that's the latest version.
Now I've already opened up my bare application from way back when and when I opened it up.
I noticed that I, in fact did forget to delete all of the middleware in here because we don't need
any of this.
All of this is actually except for the middleware go file.
So those should be gone.
And they are.
And now I'll go to my OK version control and committees.
Delete unused files.
So commit those.
And I'll push them.
And I go back to my Web browser, and I'll refresh this page to make sure it's the current version,
I'm looking at my Celerity app project in middleware that should just be one file in there.
That's better.
So now when I run celerity, this new everything should work as expected.
So I have my bare application here and let me switch back over to celebrities and I will copy my celebrity's
executable.
And yours might be called Celebrity X.
But I'm going to copy it to the location where I want to run it, which is my desktop, so I'll copy
it to my desktop.
And if you want to just click and drag.
Get it on your desktop somehow.
OK, so it's on my desktop now, so I'll open another terminal window by clicking the plus sign and
go to my desktop.
Or wherever you put the file and I'll try running dot slash house new and I'll just call it cool app.
OK, so Klum's, it puts it all down there and it's finished.
Let's open a new window.
And zoom in and open the folder on your desktop.
So I'll open from my desktop.
I'm looking for cool app right there and I'll open this up.
And in theory, I should be able to open my terminal window.
And type make start is probably not going to work the first try.
Nothing ever does.
And there is the first problem.
It tries to download two solar celerity version zero zero zero.
And of course, that's something we'll have to change in the go.
Don't modifier.
Let's see what we have to change it to.
So I'll simply delete this line entirely.
The one that says the refers to alertness and close this file and clear the screen and type.
Go get GitHub dot com, slash Tesla slash celebrities and see what it does.
OK.
So I downloaded it.
That's good.
Now let's type make start and see if it all compiles and runs.
Imported and not used, so there's something else we have to clear it that some handlers don't go.
So let's open up handlers.
We left a reference to Jet in there.
So should you be able to save this might goes away.
Good.
We'll close that.
So that's a second thing we're going to have to fix.
Let's do that right now.
Let's go over to bear your bear application and open your handlers right there.
And delete that one.
Save that.
OK.
And let's go back now and try running that again.
So back to cool app three are for the screen.
See if the third time is the charm.
Make sure.
OK.
Add up middle, weird check, remember undefined and that is in roots.
There's something else we have to change.
OK to recap and go back to our beer application.
Right here and find roots.
And doing that right now, let's commit all of these changes.
So remove unused code commit.
And push.
OK, and now let's go back and try running it again.
So I'm back to cool air and clear the terminal.
Start.
Perfect.
It's running.
So let's try running this or see what this does.
We'll go over to our browser and type local host four thousand.
And it works perfect.
OK, so we need to make a change now to our celebrities project, so let's find that celebrities and
what we wanted to change was.
In our CMT folder, templates go dark mode.
We want to get rid of this part.
What I'm going to do is put in V one point zero point zero because I want to make sure that I'm downloading
exactly the version that I want to download.
OK.
So I am referring to a tag version one point zero point zero, and I don't think I've tagged it over
here.
So go back to my celebrity's project.
Go to the root level and there are no releases, so let's create a new release.
I will tag this.
Has the one point zero point zero.
OK.
And I will because I missed that.
There it is.
OK.
Publish the release and I'll call this initial release, publish the release.
There it is.
So now when I go back to my celebrity's project, let's try this one last time.
So I'm going to, first of all, find the cool app.
So I'm going to, first of all, close my cool art project altogether.
There's beer celebrities cooler, so I'll close this.
I'll stop it first.
Make stop and I'll close this.
And then I'll remove the folder cool app, or I'm or RF Cool app, and you can just drag yours to the
folder or to the trash if you're using windows or use whatever the equivalent command is in your favorite
show.
And now we'll go back to my other terminal.
Here and I will go up one level, rebuild my seal, I make build.
Go to the dust folder and copy celebrities back to the desktop folder.
And now will switch to my other terminal window and Typekit slash celebrity's new cool app to.
OK.
Now open a new window in visual studio code Zoom to
open the cool app to folder.
From the desktop cool app to open.
Let's see if we missed anything else.
So open my terminal window and type make start.
So it's building it, that's a good sign.
The delay is that it's downloading celebrities and all the associated packages, of course.
And it started it.
And can I see it in my Web browser?
Let's just reload this page.
Perfect.
So there you go.
We have a fully functional application that allows us to specify a database easily, a cache, easily.
It has management for sessions, for user authentication.
It has all of the things I need to get started building an application.
Well, that was fun.
OK, let's move on to the final section of this course, and that's just where to go next section.