So let's get started, and we'll do the easy part first, sanitizing the application name.
The second step cloning the skeleton application.
Of course, that means we're going to have to backup our existing Maya project and strip it down to
just the bare essentials, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.
Right now, let's do the easy one.
So what we need to do here is to check to see if what they've given us is like a you are l to say,
a GitHub repository, and if it's not that we can just move on.
But if it is, then we need to clean it up a little bit.
So what we can do here is just check to see for the existence of a slash if strings dart contains.
And we're looking for app name.
We're looking in app name or we're looking for that character, an unscripted question mark, the slash.
If that's the case, then we have to get rid of this.
We have to basically get the last part of the URL.
So if what they typed in was GitHub dot com slash TESOL or slash my app, then I just want the my part.
So we'll just split it on the character.
It's all we have to do is create a variable, and I'll call mine exploded because I'm exploding a string.
And we call strings dot split after.
All right.
And what that does, it has the help message says here it slices whatever string you pass it into all
sub strings after each instance of some separator and then it gives us a slice back.
So we're going to split after aptamer and the slash, and then we just grab the last element of this
slice that was given to us.
So now app name is now equal to exploded, and we want the length of exploded minus one because computers
start counting from zero, of course, and that's all we have to do.
So let's try it out and we'll just print out to the look.
We'll say Logcat print line
app name is and then the app name.
OK, so let's give this a try.
So I'm going to just do it the easy way.
I mean, my Celebrity Juice project, I'll say make build, underscore Seelye.
It's built it now that copy the binary over to my my art project, which is not a problem.
We'll just switch there, open a terminal window and Typekit slash celebrity's new and I'll say my app
and I should print out my app.
App name is my app now.
Celebrities new.
And I'll call it GitHub dot com slash TESOL or slash my other app and my app name is now my other app.
And that's all we need.
OK, because we're going to use that when we clone something from a repository.
So in the next lesson, we'll actually write the code to clone a non-existent repository because we'll
create a new repository after we get the git code written and then tried it all right to get code first
in the next lesson.