So this time around, what we want to do is to write the code that will go and clone a remote git repository
and copy that into a folder, the contents of that repository into a folder that is named app name,
that thing we sanitized the last time around.
Now, just as a reminder, we're going to write code that tries to clone a non-existent git repository
and you can use a real git repository if you want to, but make sure it's a public repository, not
a private one.
There are some hoops you have to jump through if you're trying to clone a private repository, and we're
not going to cover that in this course.
That's beyond the scope of the things I want to do.
So let's get started.
So what I'll do is right here, I will, first of all, let the user know what's going on.
So I'll use my color package color dot green and I'll just say, and I'll prefix it with a tab.
So it's inserted a bit.
So Backslash T cloning
repository.
Now, as far as I know, there is nothing in the standard library in Go that will actually do what I
want to do next.
But fortunately, there's a very good public repository that we can use to go and clone things.
So let me switch to my web browser and this is the repository right here.
It's called Go Dash, get go to it.
And if you've never used it before and you Google around, you'll see there was a bit of a kerfuffle,
as we say in Canada, some kind of dispute about naming and so forth.
But that's all resolved, and the project is now being used.
As you can see, it's got a lots of stars and it works really well.
So we're going to use this because it's dead simple.
So let's go back to our idea and let's go get the necessary code.
So my terminal, I'll go get GitHub dot com slash go dash, get slash, go dash and get not yet get
slash v five.
And as I've said before, if version six is out, stick with version five for this course and upgrade
after the fact.
So that goes and gets it for us.
Perfect.
So now it's available now I can use it, assuming that Visual Studio code catches up to me relatively
quickly.
So I'm going to take this comment or this this command and put it below this comment where it belongs
and move it over and backspace a little bit just to make things a little clearer.
OK.
So how do we get cloning?
Well, it's actually pretty straightforward.
So what I'm going to call the function, I'm going to call plain clone from the get package.
It gives two things back, but I only care about the first one.
So I'll check for an error when I call from the Git package, which hopefully is this one right here?
No, it hasn't found it yet.
Well, I'll import it myself at a moment.
Get Dot Plane, Clone Capitol, see?
There it is found it could get dot plane clone and I'm going to clone into dot slash the current directory,
plus whatever the app name is, but that variable we sanitize last time around.
And the second parameter I'm going to hand is false.
And the third one is of type a reference to Typekit dot clone options right there.
And we're going to populate some fields in there.
OK.
So it didn't find it for me.
Of course it didn't.
That's what happened.
It did import it, but it didn't put the V5 at the end.
All right.
So that should fix it for me eventually.
And it did.
So the options for a clone options are simple.
What's the URL?
Where are we going to go?
And I'm going to go to a non-existent URL git at GitHub dot com slash TESOL or slash celebrities Dash
app Typekit, which is the full name to the non-existent git repository that will exist in a little
while.
And I'm going to read its progress.
I'm going to write it to OCR stdout so the user can see what's going on while the Get Clone is taking
place.
And I'm also going to put in depth one because over time the size of that repository might get very
large.
And if we don't put depth one, it will pull down to get repository and a whole lot of other things
from previous commits and so forth.
And I just want depth.
One Make it as small as I possibly can to make the download as fast as I possibly can and then check
for an error.
So if error is not equal to nil, then thinks it gracefully with an error, whatever the error is.
OK.
And that's it.
That really should take care of cloning it for us.
Now, if you want to try this out, you can put the URL to a correct or an existing public repository
here and just run it and see what happens.
But I'm not going to do that right now.
I use this package many, many times.
I'm pretty sure this is going to work.
So in the next lecture, I'll create a skeleton application and I will push that up to GitHub.
And then this will actually work and we can see what we got from that point.
So we'll take care of that in the next election.