So the next step in this process is to create a version of my app that will be basically an empty skeleton,
and the easiest way to do that is to do what I've already done.
First of all, backup your existing My App project, create a zip file from it, do whatever you need
to to make sure you don't lose the work you've done so far and then create a copy of this application
in a different folder.
I called mine bare BRT because it's a bare application.
I just stuck it on my desktop.
So once you've done that and please do, make sure you backup your existing code first.
Open it up in Visual Studio Code and you'll see that there's a bunch of errors and we don't care about
those because we're going to be deleting things.
And for example, if I open up the image, celebrities don't go file.
It says, I can't find that project.
I know because that project doesn't exist yet, and that's just fine by me.
So don't worry about that, but let's look at the things we want to get rid of, for example.
In my data folder, I have coverage out well, that doesn't need to be put there, so let's delete that.
So I'll move that to the trash.
I don't want the integration test, I don't want the models test, I don't want the remember token or
set up test or test go or token go or user ID go because in a bare application, none of those would
exist.
So let's delete those.
So those are gone.
Now let's open up models and see if yes, it's referring to things that don't belong there.
So let's delete those.
And down here, we'll delete these because we don't have it users or tokens, so those will be gone.
And I think that's all we have to worry about for that one so we can delete that.
And now let's open up handlers, so I don't want the off handlers.
Those can go for sure.
Convenience, don't go.
Let's look at that.
So, yeah, I'll leave all of those there because they're not going to hurt anything.
Get rid of the form veil handlers and the test handler.
Those can go.
And let's look in Handler's stock, go, do I want cash handlers?
No, I don't want those at all.
OK.
So those can be gone because we were just providing our users with the ability to use the cash.
We're not going to implement the cash for them.
We're going to give them the easy method of just using it if they want to.
Now let's look up Handler's dog, go and see what's in there.
So.
I do want a home page.
OK, so I'm going to leave that one alone, but I'll get rid of this comment that I did, and I don't
want anything else.
I can delete all of these because these were just things for us to work with as we were testing functionality.
So we're going to leave one handler home, OK, and we will make sure there's a home page for them to
look at.
So that takes care of the handlers folder and we can close that actually go back to the handlers folder.
I think I saw an error there.
Yeah, get rid of format because we're not using it there.
So let's close that.
Logs is fine.
It's empty mail.
What's inside of that?
Well, we want that to be completely empty.
We don't want a single template in there, so we'll delete all of those.
Migrations had better be empty, so I still eat that.
The temp is empty views.
I'm going to leave the layouts and I'll get rid of everything that's not home so that and that I'll
leave the home Typekit will delete all of those.
And let's open a home and get rid of this entire thing down here that says things to try so that can
go away.
And we'll get rid of this if it is authenticated, but so that can go away and the rest, that should
be fine.
So we'll close that.
The dot on the file aisle to lead entirely, because we're going to create that from our command line
application.
Let's make sure there's nothing inconvenience go that looks fine.
Coverage can go
and Docker compose picture anything in there that I need to change.
No, I think that's fine.
There's no password, you know, that we care about, except.
These ones and those are fine for development.
We can close that.
What about go dot Dontnod?
Well, let's open that up.
We definitely want to get rid of this bit.
Replace GitHub dot com whatever your URL is with a reference to a local folder named Celebrity.
So let's delete that, OK, and close that code to some that's going to be actually created when we
run, Goldman Tidies.
So I'll delete that as well.
And rootstock up, something's going to have to change there, so we don't need the mailer.
We'll leave that one alone and we'll just leave the route to the home page, and that's pretty much
it so we can go all the way down here and leave the static route and delete the rest of those.
And this should be a nice, clean file right now.
OK, so we can get rid of this and we can get rid of this because it is reused by roots.
I just deleted and that will show up properly when we're ready to work with this.
OK, so I think that clears this out pretty well.
Let's just make sure there's nothing in the in the public folder I images.
OK, that should be fine.
This is a good starting point.
OK, so the next step is to push this up to GitHub or your favorite git repository system.
I'm going to use GitHub because it's very easy to use free and extremely common in the go world.
So let's move on.