All right.
So the next step is to push our bear application, and that's what I have opened right now in visual
studio code.
We're going to push that up to GitHub.
But before I do that, we're going to create one more file in here, just called Read Me, M.D. and
inside of that, I'm just going to put a hash mark and I'll just put a celebrity's skeleton application.
It's always nice to have a read me up on GitHub, and I'm just going to put that in there.
You can put whatever you want in there.
Ultimately, of course, you would put some language about how to download the binary and how to run
it in the fact that you don't need to clone this application, but it's entirely up to you, and this
is sufficient for my purposes right now.
So now I'm going to open a terminal in visual studio code, and I'll give myself a little more room
here.
And I'll initialize a jet repository, so get not fit, get in it.
OK.
And you might see different messages than I do here, but don't worry about it typing get in.
It will actually create an empty git repository.
Now I need to add everything into it.
So before I do that, why don't I create also a get ignore file?
So I'll create a new file.
And this will just tell Git what not to put in there.
So Git ignored its dot git i.g.
A.R.T. all lowercase, and I'm sure you've used it before.
Inside of that?
Sometimes I work with actually most of the time when I'm not recording lectures, I work with jet brains,
products and forego.
I use go land, so I'm going to ignore the idea folder.
And that's not created by Visual Studio.
Code is created by jet brains, but lots of people use it.
And I'm also going to ignore discovery or coverage out.
OK, that's enough.
You can put whatever else you want to ignore into that folder.
And now I'll say get ad done.
That adds everything.
Yet commit dashcam and I'll just type initial entry.
And that's the message.
OK, so now I've created my git repository.
I've created the necessary don't get ignore to ignore certain files and I've added everything to it.
Now I'm going to go to my web browser where I'm already logged into GitHub and I'll create a new repository
and I'm going to name it exactly the same thing that I named it in my Seelye when we wrote those few
lines of code that will actually clone a remote kit repository and I called mind Solara toss up.
OK.
And I'm going to make sure it's set to public and I'll create the repository.
And I don't need to create a new repository on the command line, I just did that.
I want to push an existing one, so I'm just going to copy all of this by clicking a little button here,
and it should be copied at that point.
I'll go back to my I.D. Make sure I'm in the terminal.
Clear the screen and paste that text in turn.
There it should all be set up.
So now if I switch back to my web browser and just click on the name of the repository in the top left
hand corner, I should see my read me file down here and all of my files showing up here.
Perfect.
So now that we have this repository and it's a public repository and I know the URL to it, I can go
back and compile my application, my command line application, and just see if the cloning logic works
the way that we think it's going to, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.