So we have our code pushed to a GitHub repository, and now we can try our command line application.
So I'm in my silver toast project and just to make things easier, I'm going to open my make file and
I'm going to add a new command here.
I'm going to copy this build Seelye bit and paste of below that, and I'm going to change it just to
build.
OK.
So I don't want to keep switching back and forth to my between this project in my My App project.
So builds the command line tool to temp directory to disk directly dist directory.
OK, so I'm going to say go build and my output will be to the current folder slash dist ancillary tasks.
And of course, if you're a windows, put a Dot X either.
Now let's go created this directory just to make sure we have one.
So I'll come in here and say new folder just and I should be able to build this now.
So I open my command line, prompt my terminal and type, make built.
And now I'll switch into my dis directory seduced.
Clear the screen.
I will give this a try.
Dot slash celebrity's new and I'll just call it test.
And it says open Dan's no such file or directory.
Now, fortunately, that's pretty easy to fix.
What's happened, of course, is we have a check in there that says if you're running celebrities and
the directory you're in when you run, it doesn't have a dot on file, just dot because we need to get
values from there.
And of course, that's not true in the case where we're doing things like celebrities new.
So I'll close the make file or go to the Command Seelye folder and find out where that check exists.
So we've got a main go.
So the first thing it checks is validate input, and I know it's not checking it there.
It's probably in setup.
Let's go have a look at that.
And of course, here's where the problem is right at the beginning of the setup function.
And in order to fix that, I just have to see if the command the person is executing happens to be new.
Well, in order to do that, I have to receive a couple of arguments here or at least one I need to
get heard.
One.
And I'm going to take our two two just to be safe, both of type string.
And then I'll check here to see if one is not equal to new and one is not equal to new like that.
OK.
And there may be some others as well.
Version, for example, and our one is not equal to version and health is another one and one is not
equal to help.
All of these don't require a dance that's enough for now.
We'll check the rest of them later.
OK.
And all Dukas come down here in my statement.
And say this now, of course, I need to go where I call set up and pass it earned one an hour two and
of course, that's back in top of mean.
Don't go right over here.
Heard one or two?
OK, so let's go back up one level clear the screen recompile are up our command line application.
Make build.
Change back into the dis directory and run celebrities.
New cast.
And it's cloning the repository.
And it says repository not found, so I have something wrong in my view or else go fix that, then.
So that was in new Doggo Am I repository is get at GitHub dot com slash T slash slash alert has dash
apt.
Get, let's go see what it actually is.
So I'll copy that.
Go back to here and I have a and of a column, I should have noticed that.
OK, let's compile it in third time.
Is the term
make built?
And changing to the Disc Directory cleared the screen and we'll say dot slash celebrity's new test.
And there it is, it finished.
So let's see what's inside the test directory.
The test and do analysis.
And there are all the files.
Perfect.
So a couple of typos, but nothing to overly difficult.
All right.
Let's move on.