So when we clone the remote repository and put it in our new folder, of course, there's going to be
a market directory that tells everyone, Hey, all the code in this folder belongs to this remote repository,
and of course, it's pointing to the wrong ones.
We want to delete that.
And that's very simple.
We just call error.
And this is right in the new Dot Go file in the celebrities package.
Error is equal to from the standard library of sought removal, and that will remove everything in a
particular directory.
And of course, we want that to be in, and I'll use the format package dot sprint f and my format string
is dot slash percent s slash Typekit.
And the substitution for that percent, of course, is apt name and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll oh, we'll exit gracefully with the error.
OK, so that was really simple.
So we may as well do the dot on file in this lecture as well.
So what we're going to do is get our existing dot on file that we know works, remove everything that
doesn't belong in it and then do a little search and replace.
So let's switch over to our other application, my app, and let's open the dot on file right here.
Then we'll select all and copy and switch back to this latest project.
And what I'll do is put an empty file, which I'll call Omkar text right in our Read-Only Templates
file system.
So new file and I'll call it on text and I'll paste the contents in there and then I'll start deleting
things.
So at the very top, we meals will start here, app name.
It's not going to be my app necessarily.
It will be dollar sign, app name and of course, we'll search and replace for that.
When we do the installation of the data on file, I'll leave the app URL alone.
I'll leave debug to true and I'll leave it on Port 4000 and I'll leave localhost, which is appropriate
for development, and I'll leave this false as well, because we're not going to use secure connections
on a local development machine.
But I'll leave the database empty
because we don't know if they're even going to use a database when they start a new Scylaticus application.
And for Redis, I'll leave that empty as well.
But I will leave the red is prefixed to dollar sign apt name.
Is that a reasonable starting point?
For cash, I'll leave that empty and for cookie settings, which is not cooking settings, it's cookie
settings.
Ali, the cookie name again, I'll use dollar sign apt name like that in curly brackets, and the rest
of those settings should be fine for our purposes.
Session type all default the cookie because we can do that with nothing else mail settings.
I'll take those out entirely.
And let the end user fill that stuff in.
Mailer, AP Settings, I'll delete that.
Leave it empty and I'll leave the renderer to Jet and then of course, I don't want to have everyone
with the same default encryption key, so I'll put another placeholder in there dollar sign and then
in curly braces key.
OK, so that is a reasonable starting point for a dot on file.
Basically, we're just going to put the bare minimum in and allow users to fill this in as necessary.
Now let's go back to New Dot go and let's start creating a ready to go dot on file.
So I'll just put a little message here.
Color dot yellow and I'll prefix it with a tab and say creating dot on file.
Dot dot dot.
Just a little feedback.
And then I'll read the data for my template file system into a variable data an error or assign the
value of template fs.
Read File.
And I'm going to read templates and has to be in quotes templates on Typekit.
Then again, I'll check for an error.
So a copy and paste this.
Right to hear.
But assuming you get past that, I can convert data into a string, so I'll create a new variable called
on.
And that's a sign the value of string data will convert a slice of bytes into a string and then we'll
do a search and replace on equals.
Strings don't replace all.
And we're going to be searching on and we're looking for, first of all, dollar sign.
And then in all caps app name in curly brackets.
And we want to replace that with without name.
And then I'll duplicate that line.
But this time I'm looking for there's got to be a curly closing curly bracket there or this won't work
key again with the closing curly bracket.
And this time, I want to generate a 32 character long random string.
So I'll call seld on random string and make it exactly 32 characters long.
And now we have ready to go on file.
All we have to do is to write it to a file.
So we'll say error is equal to copy data to file, and we want to use a slice of bytes.
So we'll convert on into a slice of bytes and we'll copy it to format as f with a format string of dot
slash percent s slash icons.
And our substitution for that %s is just app name.
And again, I should be able to paste in my error check.
And at that point, this part should be done.
So let's give it a try.
I'll open my terminal window.
See what's in my district.
There's nothing.
So I'll go up one level and say, Make build.
And that should create the binary right in my dust folder, so let's go into the dust folder.
Just tell us.
There it is.
And we'll say dot slash celebrity's new test and see if we got it right.
So it says it created a dot on file.
Let's go into test and do analysis.
The last statue and there's my daughter on, so I'm going to open up my desk directory right here.
I'll close the command folder.
Look inside of Dist, there's test.
Let's see what's in the front.
And the acronym is test, and this should be a key at the bottom.
Everything looks good.
Perfect.
All right.
Let's move on.