So the next step is to create the correct Makefile.
Now, some users might not use a Makefile, but many do, myself included.
And if you recall, if you look at the repository for our remote application, which I called skeleton
application at GitHub dot com slash Tesla slash celebrities slash app, we have two versions of the
Makefile one for Mac and Linux and one for Windows.
And of course, we want to make the appropriate one for the users operating system.
The actual Makefile.
So let's go back to our code and here in New Dot Go right at Line fifty seven in my code, I need to
create a make file.
So obviously the first thing I have to do is to determine what operating system you want.
And the only thing I really care about is, are you on windows or not?
And that's really simple.
We can use something ready to the standard library if runtime right there dont go OS right there, if
that's equal to in lower case windows and I'll do something, otherwise I'll do something else.
So if it is windows, then I'm going to be using that file make filed out windows.
So what I'll do is create a file called source or a variable called source, and then I'll check for
an error and those come from OST open.
I got rid of the standard library.
We're just going to open the file and the file we want to open is formatted as per death.
So we need this in the form of a string and a format string is dot slash percent s and then capital
Makefile Typekit windows.
And my substitution as usual is happening, so I open that file.
OK.
And we'll check for an error, so I'll just copy this and paste it in here.
And if we get past that, then I need to make sure that file gets closed.
So I'll defer source close.
OK?
And now I want a destination.
So I'll create a variable called destination.
And of course, this is where we're going to copy the final version of the file and I'll check for an
error.
And those come from O's script.
We're going to create a file this time and again.
Its format is print off with the format string of dots percent s and now I want to call it make file
with no extension or my substitution is name and I'll paste in my error check and I'll defer destination
destination dot close and our copy it.
So I don't care about the return value, but I do care about an error and that's equal to Io dot copy
from to destination from source.
And I'll paste in my air, Chuck.
And that should be that.
Now I'll copy all of this logic because very little changes and pasted in here.
And this time on line 78 of my code right after the L statement, it's make Dot Mac and nothing else
really changes.
Now, obviously, you could make this one statement and just change the file name, make fold up Mac
or make fold up Windows appropriately.
But I want to make this as readable as possible for you, so I'll leave it like this.
And if you want to simplify this code, you feel free to do so.
And the last thing I need to do after this whole, if else statement is to delete, make file dot mac
and make folder up windows.
So I don't care about the return value, but I'm going to call the West Doc Remove and I'm going to
remove and I'll just put Dot Slash Plus app name plus slash make file Mac and I'll duplicate that and
put Windows there.
OK.
Now, the next step is to update the Goedert mod file, and what we'll do is actually delete the Dot
Mod file that's there and put it in one that we can create by hand.
And that's a pretty simple process, almost identical to what we did with the dot on file, and we'll
take care of that in the next lecture.