So the next step in this process is to create a go document file, and as I said last time around,
I'm going to delete the one we pulled down from the remote repository and just create one by hand.
So to make that happen, I'm going to switch over to the My App project and I'll open the goddamned
mod file and select all and copy and switch back to the celebrity's project and write inside the Templates
folder in the CMD Seelye folder.
I'll create a new file, which I'll call Go Dark Mode Text, and I'll paste in what I just copy and
then I'll scroll to the very top.
And there's really only two changes.
Obviously, we don't want to use this replace line anymore because the user won't have this letter to
this folder, so we'll delete that.
And the only other change is to replace the name of the module, my app with something I can search
and replace for.
So a dollar sign up underscore name.
And that should be the only changes we need to make to that file, so I'll close it and go back to new.
So down here in line 98 in new, don't go in my code, I'm going to, first of all, let the user know
what's happening.
So colored yellow and I'll prefix everything with a tab just to move it in and say creating go dot mod
file.
Dot dot dot.
And now I'll delete the existing file so I don't care about the return value.
It's equal to OAC.
Don't remove and I want to remove dot slash plus app name plus slash go model that gets rid of it.
And now I can create a new one.
But if you think it through, there are two possible situations we need to take care of here.
In the first case, if someone just types celebrities new my app, for example, that I can use app
name that variable I've been using right along.
But if they typed celebrity's new GitHub dot com slash, some user name slash some module name that
I need to use that instead at the very top of the Go Mod file.
So let's go to the very top of this file new dot go.
And right here in line 16, the very first thing I do in the do new function is get whatever they typed
and then online 18 through twenty two.
I actually exploded.
Look for a slash.
And if a slash exists, I take the last thing in that string after the final slash.
But I need what they typed here.
So what I'm going to do is create a package level variable, which I'll just call the app the URL of
type string.
I don't have to put its package level, but I'm going to.
And now before I sanitize it, I'll say after the URL is equal to app name and now I have whatever they
typed in lowercase exactly as I want it to be.
So I'll scrolled it back down to the do the bottom of the do new function.
And at this point I can read in the go to my text file that I just created, so I'll save data and error
are equal to template for file, and I want to read templates, slash go dark mode, support text and
I'll check for an error.
So I'll copy this code and paste it here.
And now I'll create a new variable called Mod.
And that's a sign the value of casting data to a string.
And I will search and replace Mod equals strings.
Don't replace all, and I'm looking for Mod looking inside of Mod and I want to search for dollar sign,
brace app, underscore name and close the curly brackets and replace it with after you URL, which might
be the same as apt name, but it might not run.
In any case, this will take care of whatever situation we happen to be in.
And now I just create my new Go Dot Mod file.
Error equals copy data to file, and I take mod and cast it to a slice of byte and I put it in dot slash
plus app name, not AP URL plus slash.
Go on and paste in my error check.
And at that point, I should be pretty much ready to go.
So the next step is to take care of the situation where the imports in some of the dark go files in
the repository that we cloned.
They don't have the correct name for whatever application the user is working with, and we need to
do a search and replace for every single dot go file check for the existence of, in our case, my app
all lowercase and replace it with the correct import, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.