So this course is all about implementing a very popular Web application framework written in PHP called
Laravel.
We're going to implement a similar thing, but we're going to write it in Go.
Now Laravel, as I'm sure you're aware, is arguably the most popular framework in the world today,
and it is extremely popular for good reason.
When you start a project in Laravel, you have easy access to the database with the eloquent Aughrim.
You have support for my skill and Postgres and other databases.
In other words, you get a lot of functionality right out of the box, and it is dead simple to install
with one command in your terminal.
You can create a ready to go framework that has user authentication.
It is templating, it has caching, it has sessions in its database.
It has all the things you need to get started writing the next great web app.
Now, there are some disadvantages to writing things in Laravel.
It's relatively slow.
It's certainly gotten faster over the years.
VP8 is much faster than five, for example, but compared to compiled languages, anything written in
PHP is relatively slow.
Laravel applications also have in general a lot of external dependencies.
So you're using composer, you're adding things and sometimes the things you're adding using composer.
Either they disappear or they just don't keep up with the times.
And a new version of Laravel comes out and you can't upgrade because the thing you're depending upon
that you installed using composer?
Well, it's not updated for the latest version of Laravel, and I run into that in the past as well.
Perhaps the most terrible disadvantage, and this is neither the fault of Laravel nor of PPP is the
incredible quantity of bad resources you have online.
So someone's working along in Laravel, they run into a problem, they go to their favorite search engine
and they type in a search term and they get a lot of responses, and a lot of them were written by people.
Who really shouldn't be allowed to be that close to a keyboard in the first place, they're just badly
written.
But again, that's not the fault of Laravel or a few.
Also, suppose you're right, this application and it's successful and you start getting massive amounts
of traffic.
You can in fact scale your application, but you have to scale it horizontally, meaning you add servers,
and that introduces a level of complexity that can be a bit daunting for some people.
Even if you have a single server compared to something that's written in Go, Laravel takes an awful
lot of system resources, meaning you need a bigger server to serve the same amount of traffic you would
with a much smaller server if your application was written and go.
But the biggest advantage, in my opinion, and it's just my opinion, the biggest advantage to working
in Laravel is I can open my terminal type one command and I have at the end of the day, a ready to
go framework.
I have user authentication, I have database access, I have caching, I have sessions, I have everything.
I need to write my application and that is a real advantage.
And what we're going to do in this course is we're going to build a go module that will duplicate much
of the core functionality that we find in Laravel.
Not all of it, but we're going to get the high points and I'll go through them in a moment, and I'm
calling this module celebrities, which is Latin for speed, which seemed appropriate.
Now we're going to build the framework, and we're also going to build a command line application,
which makes it really easy to install a project.
So in other words, I'll put my favorite terminal window and I'll type celebrity's new and some project
name and we'll have out of the box with that one step the following features we'll have access to multiple
databases.
Now, in this course, I'm going to include Postgres in my school, but we'll also have support for
Mongo Cockroach B and Super Out very easily, and you'll see how to do that as you go through the course.
I'm only going to deal with Postgres in my school.
But if you want to add Mongo or Cockroach or sequel right, you'll have absolutely everything at your
disposal to implement that.
And it's dead simple.
We'll also have complete user authentication for both the web and API, so you log on with the username
and password.
And if you're doing so on a webpage, it just sets a sessional variable and away you go.
But if you're logging on, using an API, we generate a token and you're ready to go and you can do
that with one command.
We'll also have support for database migrations, and we'll have support for multiple templating engines
now Laravel uses Blade and Blade is a great templating engine.
We're going to implement go templates and spend very little attention to it once we've implemented that
because GO templates are not remarkably popular.
Instead, we'll focus most of our attention on the jet template engine, which is much more user friendly
and much faster and go templates.
So there's no reason not to use that.
We'll have complete support for sessions.
We'll also be able to generate handlers, which are kind of like Laravel controllers.
And database models with a single command from the terminal will have support for easy to write middleware.
We'll have complete form validation and we'll have cross-site request forgery protection for those forms.
We'll support encryption, which is incredibly useful when you're writing a web application.
We'll also have response utilities.
So you write a handler, which is like a controller in the Laravel world and say, I want to send this
response back as X Amount or Jason or to download a file or obviously to render a web page.
We'll also have support for multiple caching back ends.
Now I'm going to implement two Redis and Badger DB.
But again, just as is the case with databases, if you want to use a different one, you'll have all
the knowledge necessary to do that on your own.
I'm implementing just reticent Badger DB and people who have worked with Laravel might say to themselves,
Why aren't you implementing a file system cache?
We use that in development all the time.
Well, the short answer is there's no need to.
File systems are relatively slow.
Badger DB will actually be a database that's embedded right into our application, and there's no real
sense then to implement a file based caching system because we have Badger DB.
We'll also have support for sending email, using SMTP servers or third party apps like SendGrid or
Mail Gun or Spark Post, and we'll have remember me and password reset functionality built right into
our user authentication system.
Now, the best way to show you what we're going to build is as follows.
Open a terminal window, so I have one open in front of me and I'm on my desktop and I'm just going
to type.
Celebrities knew my project and my sister project.
And once I do that in a remote repository is cloned, we create a dot on file.
Just like Laravel, we create a go mod file, which we need to manage our dependencies.
We update the source files.
We run Typekit to make sure everything's ready to go.
And I am finished.
And then if I go to my favorite edy, which is not Visual Studio code, but it's the one I'm using in
this course, and I open the folder and I look for the desktop and find my project right here and open
it up.
I have all the code ready to go.
So by default, I have access to whatever database I want, I just go to my dot on file and I specified
what kind of database am I going to use?
So I asked you earlier, Postgres, all the connection information.
Am I going to use Redis?
What are my cookie settings?
All the things you would expect to find.
OK.
And then I can open a terminal and type make start.
And that compiles my application to a single binary.
It starts it up, and I can go to my favorite web browser and go to local host four thousand.
And there it is.
All ready to go now with very little effort, I can generate a user authentication system, I can connect
to a database, I can implement a caching system.
I can do all the things I need to do in order to build the next awesome web application.
So this will be fun.
Let's get started.