Chances are, if you've worked with go much in the past, you probably already have it installed.
But let's make sure we have the latest version.
So as I record this, the current first result if you search for go or probably go long on your favorite
search engine, is this page golang dot org?
And there's a link to this in the course of resources for this lecture.
And in order to download Go.
Not surprisingly, you click this big button and you choose the distribution appropriate for your operating
system Windows, Mac, Linux.
You can compile from source if you want, but I don't recommend it.
It's a lot of work for no real benefit.
Now, if you're on a Mac, this version, the one that you see right here, that's the one for Intel
based processors.
But if you're on a newer Mac that has the M1 chip Apple Silicon, the one you want is actually this
one ARM 64, Darwin ARM 64.
So just download that and install it now as I record this.
Go is in the process of making this go dot dev the home page instead.
And when you take this course, this might be what you get when you search for it.
And again, it is pretty much the same thing.
Click the download button and that will actually download it for your operating system.
But the thing is, if you're on a Mac right now, you're going to get the AMD64 and not the ARM64.
So instead, you might want to click on this more link right here, and then you can.
You're taken back to the same page where we were just looking at.
And again, if you're on an Intel chip, you download this one.
And if you're on Apple Silicon, you download the ARM64 down here.
So install that, make sure you have the latest version and let's move on.