So we're also going to need an editor of some sort when we're writing go code and there are lots to
choose from, and chances are you probably have one.
But just to be safe, if you're looking one, this will do the job.
Visual Studio Code You just code a code visual studio dot com, which is found in the course resources
for this lecture.
Choose your operating system so you can have Mac, Windows or Linux.
Download it and install it.
And once you have it installed, start it up and I'll just switch to it right now and you're going to
want to go to the extensions and you go to want to search for go, obviously.
So when you find it, this is the one right here.
Rich go language support, install that.
So click on that, install it.
And once you've installed it, open the command palette, which is shipped Cloverleaf P on a Mac and
shipped command p on Windows by default.
This will pop up and look for go install update tools just to make sure that they're all there.
So select that and click this checkbox to check all of these and click OK.
And when you do that, that little terminal will open down here or the output, and it will show you
that they're all installing.
Wait for that to finish.
And when you're done, I always just restart my I.D. just to be safe and then you're good to go.