In this course, I'll be using Make, which is a really good and very commonly used build tool.
And of course, this is optional.
If you don't want to do this, you can just run the software the way that you normally do.
But I highly recommend you install, make and I'll be providing build scripts or make scripts, make
recipes as they're called as we go on in this course.
So this is the documentation for make itself, and I've put a link to this in the course resources for
this.
And there's a couple of different ways to install it.
But if you were on a Mac far and away, the easiest is to use homebrew and you install homebrew by copying
this link, pasting it into a terminal window.
And when you've done so, you can install make just by opening your favorite terminal and typing brew
install make and that will install it for you.
And when you're done, you'll be able to run make right from the command line.
But if you're on windows, it's a little bit different.
And since most people these days are on Windows 10 and some have made it to Windows 11, the equivalent
of Homebrew for Windows is called chocolatey.
And you can install that and there's a link to this in the course resources right here.
The instructions for doing so are pretty straightforward.
And once you've done that, you'll open windows and I'm on a Mac, so I'm going to pretend I'm on windows
right now and you would type choko install Mac and that will install a version of make that is suitable
for this course.
So go ahead and install make and let's move on.