So in this final section of the course, we'll just write some tests for the code we wrote in the previous
sections.
And testing is really important.
And normally when I'm writing code for myself and not for a course, I write tests as I write code.
But what we'll do in this section, we're not going to write tests for every single aspect of the code
we've written.
Instead, we'll write a number of tests that are representative and that will give you enough tools
that you should be able to write your own tests as required.
So to start with, we'll update our data, package those models to make sure that they're more testable,
because right now it's really difficult to test things with the way they're written.
And that's pretty straightforward.
We'll also test registering routes and we'll test rendering pages and we'll write tests for our handlers.
And in particular, we'll write tests for the handler that uses concurrency the most.
All right.
Let's get started.