So before we start writing actual tests, let's make our lives easier and set up a testing environment.
Now, when we wrote tests much earlier in the course for the various classic computer science problems,
we didn't have to do that.
But this is a web application.
And when we're testing a web application, one of the things we have to do is to duplicate the environment
that the various parts of our application run in.
And that's particularly true for handlers, but it's true for most parts of our application.
So over in the CMD Web folder, I'm going to create a new file which must be named.
Set up, underscore test, dot, go.
And this will run before our actual tests run.
It sets up our environment.
So it's in package main and we'll create a variable test app.
And it's a type config will create a test config for our for our tests, obviously.
And now we'll write a function named Test Main.
And this is a special function used by go.
Messed up my import there.
That's better.
Okay.
Used by God.
This will actually run before our actual test run action.
In fact, this will run our tests for us.
So what do we have to do?
Well, let's open up our main doggo.
Okay.
And let's split the window here.
So we have in one window we'll have main dog go.
And in the other one, we'll have our tests.
Now, something didn't quite work here.
Testing.
Not him, not me.
I don't know where that came from.
Okay, so what do we need to do?
Well, one of the things we're going to have to do is we're going to be using the session in our tests.
So let's gob dot register, grabbed out register.
We'll register the same as we do at our actual main function actually in our init session function data
dot user because that's the one non primitive type we're putting in our sessions.
So that's registered or it will be when we run this, then let's create a session.
So over here in this window we'll find in this session and I'll copy all of this, okay?
And then delete one thing.
This is a unit test and we need to import X, so let's just do that this way.
X dot new and that does the import for me.
Okay.
I don't want to use redis for a unit test.
No need to do that at all.
Redis has been fully tested and I don't have to worry about that at all.
And let's fix up our imports, find our okay and let's import HTP.
HTP the same site.
Mode.
That's better.
Okay, so now we have a session.
Now let's set up this test, that config variable that we declared on line 14.
And this is what we use as the app for our test.
So test app is equal to the type config and I'll fill out its fields.
So we have session, we can put session in there.
And remember, this is not the same session that we have in mind.
Go.
This one is specific to test me that function.
For DV.
I'm going to set that to nil.
We're not going to use the database at all for our tests, at least not for a while.
And for info log.
Well, I'll go over here and find info log wherever I create that this one.
So I'll copy that.
And paste that here and we'll have to import log, of course.
So I'll just put it in here.
Log.
And we need to import OS to do that import.
Whereas.
Okay.
And we also have an error log.
Error log, you know, populate that with the same thing.
I mean, don't go.
Okay.
So we have our info log.
We have our error log.
What's next?
Well, we're going to have to do models, but I'll leave that one alone for right now because we're
likely to use them for a little while.
And we need to make some changes to our data package to make it more testable, to make our handlers
more testable.
But I can put in weight and that will be a reference to sync dot linker and an error channel.
Well, I can just make the channel right here, just like I do with me, and I'll go make an error.
An error dungeon is just make chin look.
Okay, so now I have a test app all set up, mostly set up.
There's more things we need to do with it.
For example, when we get to testing our handlers, we'll be sending mail.
So let's create the dummy mailer.
Create a dummy mailer.
And that's as simple as setting out three channels.
Baratunde is assigned the value of make scan error.
Mailer Chan is assigned the value of make Chan message.
And again, I'll make that a 100 a buffer for 100.
And mailer done charm.
And that will be a sign the value of make a change.
Okay.
Now let's create the mailer.
So test app dot mailer is equal to mail that type.
And we'll put in weight, which is test app don't wait and we'll put in an error chain which is error
chain, the one I just made.
And we'll put it in a Mailer channel, which is the Mailer chan I just made, and we'll put it in the
mailer doesn't chan, which is the mailer done in China?
Just made it there.
Okay.
So I set up the mailer.
And what's wrong with that?
It's done, Chan.
That's better.
Sometimes autocomplete doesn't make my life easier.
Now, to make it really simple, we'll make our dummy mailer right here.
So go func.
We'll just create a function that runs in the background and we'll close it off with this closing parentheses.
So our dummy mailer is pretty simple.
Would you type of select statement and case?
We'll just consume whatever comes in from test app, dot mailer, dot mailer chan and we'll do anything
with it.
And the same thing for getting something from test out dot mailer.
Urchin.
And the final one is case gets something from test app again.
Test app dot mailer dot done.
In that case, we could actually just return, okay?
And we'll just make this a little more nicely formatted.
So there's our dummy mailer.
Next, we need to listen for errors.
And again, I can just single func and close that off of this parenthesis and have a for loop that runs
forever and inside have a select statement.
And our first case when we get an error which is populated by something coming in from test at error
chain.
Operators test app error, log error, log dot, print line and the error.
And our other case we need to worry about just this one gets something from test app, not error chain
done.
In that case, we return.
Okay.
So the last thing to do for now in test main is to run our tests.
And you do that by calling OST on exit and we call Ingram.
Okay.
And that will run all of our tests after it sets up the environment.
So we have our environment set up in the next lecture.
Let's write our first test for this project.