Okay.
So let's read our first actual test.
And what I want to test right now is just this rootstock goat, which has, as you can see, two functions,
roots and R3 here.
Now, rather than testing those functions, the only thing I really care about is that we actually do,
in fact, have these roots registered.
So let's write a test to make sure that all of the roots, I think, need to be in the project are actually
in the project.
So let's go over to our CMT Web folder and we'll create a new file and you have to name it like this
or it's conventional to name it roots.
And then we're going to be testing roots ago.
So I start with roots.
Then underscore test, dot, go.
And if it doesn't end in underscore test, don't go.
The test will never actually get executed.
So there's my new file.
And of course this is in package name, not Mailer Dun Chan Package Main.
There we go.
And what I'm going to do is create a variable root, which is equal to a slice of strings.
Okay.
And I'll just have one entry for each of the roots in my project.
I know I have a home root, and I have a log in root and I have a log out root.
And these are, of course, exactly the roots that are in that file.
Root, start, go.
I have a register root.
I have an activate root which has to start with a slash activate.
I have a plans slash members member member's slash plan, but I'm only calling it slash plans.
That will actually work.
We're just looking for this string and we have a slash.
Subscribe is.
I think it'll work.
We'll find out before too long.
Okay.
Now we'll create one function and I'll call this one test.
Underscore roots, underscore exist because that's what I'm testing is do these roots exist?
And it's has a variable T as a parameter and it's always a type testing T for this sort of test.
And I did the import for me.
So let's get the roots.
So we'll create a variable test roots.
And that's assigned when I call not from apt roots.
Like that.
Okay.
That comes from test app dot roots.
Oh, okay.
So I have these now these are actually coming back.
If you look over at roots dot go, it's being returned as the type H-2B handler.
But what's actually being produced if I roll over, this is the type A pointer to cheat on marks.
And of course the reason I can return that is that checkmarks satisfies the interface for a beta handler.
Okay.
So over here in roots test, don't go.
I'm going to cast that to key roots.
Key roots that's assigned the value of test roots dot cast to cheat out render.
Okay.
That's the type I want to use to run some tests and then I'll actually verify that the roots exist.
So I'm going to do that by ranging through I don't care about the index, but I do care about the root,
the current entry.
I'm going to arrange the roots, that slice of strings I declared above.
And I got to put the keyword range in there or this isn't going to work.
That's better.
Okay.
Now, I have an area here is I'm not using this.
I am an error here because I'm not using this.
But what I want to do inside of this is actually call a function called root roots exists.
So what I'm going to do is call a function that doesn't exist.
So root exists, which is a function I'm going to write in a minute.
I'm going to hand that T, which is the parameter T up at the very in line 19.
It's a parameter to this function call because I'm going to do my tests in the function that I call
and I'll hand it key roots.
Okay.
And I'll also hand the current root, the one I want to check for.
Now, let's go down here and create a function and we'll call this root exists.
Okay.
And it takes it takes as parameters T, which is a pointer to testing T.
It takes root, which is a type she dot router and it takes root, which is a string.
Okay.
And inside of this, I'm going to start by initializing a variable found to be equal to false.
So if I can't find it, it will be false when I'm finished checking.
Otherwise it'll be true.
Okay.
Now, how do I actually go through all of the roots?
Well, this is why I cast our our roots.
Our test roots online toe into she roots online, too.
What I'm going to do is ignore the return value when I call.
She doesn't walk.
And that's a function that's built right into the cheap package.
And I'm going to hand it roots and I'm going to hand it a function which is a method.
Method is the first parameter of type string.
Okay.
Found root is of type string.
Handler is a type UDP dog handler.
These are just required by this actual function.
And then middleware is, which we don't care about right now, but we're going to go dot, dot, dot
bunk.
This is very attic handling an HD dot handler and returning an HD brought handler.
Can't see you.
Don't take them there, Handler.
Okay.
And then outside of that parentheses, this potentially returns an error and I give it its opening and
closing curly brackets hit return and in between.
All we eat, we say as if root is equal to found.
Root then found is equal to true
and to satisfy the Arab, it will say return nil.
And that should be correct.
Now, once we've walked all the routes and checked for the existence of the route we're looking for
with the current route from the list of all routes.
If found, this is still set to false.
We didn't find it.
So we have to do a test and of course we have to do that outside of this.
Just before the closing parentheses and assist is now just simply if not found, if not found.
T Which we received as a parameter to this function air f and we'll give it a format string did not
find percent s in registered routes and my substitution for that is just a route.
So with that, I should be able to check to make sure that all of the routes that I specify up here
in this slice of strings that they actually exist.
So let's open a terminal and clear the screen and we'll CD in the CMD slash web and run go test dash
v dot to run all the tests in this directory and there's only one.
And did not find slash planes in registered routes.
Okay.
So I was wrong.
We do need to put members in there and we do need to put members in here.
Let's run it again.
There it passed.
Well, that was easy enough.
And if we put a route that doesn't exist up here like fish, it should fail.
And it failed.
So that test does exactly what it should.
Okay.
All right.
That was easy enough.
Let's move on and write our next test for this project.