So the next thing I want to test is the file render doggo.
And if you scroll down in this, when you get to the part where we add default data, you'll see that
we're actually using the session right here in line 66.
We're testing to see if there's a value user somewhere in the session and if there is, we get it.
And if we don't, then we just populate the user with an empty user object.
Okay.
Now, the interesting thing about this is if I try to write a test for ad default data right now, I
can write it easily enough.
It's a very simple test, right?
The problem is it won't work and it won't work because we're accessing the session.
So what we need to do is to go back to setup, underscore Tesco and go to the very bottom of this file
and write a little function that will actually add session information to our request.
So it's a really easy function to write func and I'll just call it get ctcs forget context and it takes
Ari.
Q Is the variable I'm passing as a parameter and it's a type of pointer to HGTV dot request.
Okay.
And it returns the type context, dot context right there.
And hopefully they did the import for me.
It did.
And all we do is declare a variable KCTCS while checking for an error when we call test app, dot session
dot load and we hand it ari cue dot context.
The context from the requests we received as a parameter to this function and then we say are a hue
dot header dot yet and we're looking for a header named x x dash session with a capital S and a capital
x.
Okay.
And we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And I just going to log it logged on.
Print line.
Print line here.
Okay.
And then we returns UTX.
Now, this gives us a means of getting session information into and out of any request we pass it.
And that's all we have to do here.
Now, let's go back over here to CMT Web and create a new test file and I'll call it render underscore,
test go.
And that's in package main and it keeps doing mailer dumb charm for me.
I wish it wouldn't do that there.
And the first thing I'll test is that add default data function so func test and I'm going to call my
test config because it has a config as a receiver and it's add default data.
Okay.
And it didn't import testing for me, but that's no problem.
I'll simply do it myself.
Testing t there.
So it's import of that for me and I'll get rid of my extra parentheses and let's start writing the test.
Now to test this, if you go back over to Rendered Echo and you look at what this thing requires, it
requires a request.
Okay.
So we need to build a request for this.
So back to render underscore test.
Okay.
Let's build a request.
Murray queue and I'll ignore the second return parameter come from HTP.
And we just called new request.
And that requires some method to get it.
And it requires some path.
Doesn't matter what it is because we're not using it or we're not passing anything, anything else to
it.
So nil.
And now we need to add the session data to that request.
And now we say KCTCS is assigned the value of and we just call that function, get KCTCS and hand it
our issue.
So now we have a context.
Let's make our current request, our HQ now equal to our HQ with context in hand at KCTCS.
Now that request can accept session information.
I can put things into it.
I can take things out of it.
I can check it, check to see if they exist.
Okay, so let's test our add default data by putting a few things in the session.
And now I can just call test out dot session dot put in.
What should I look for.
Well over here in rendered ago you can see that I'm looking for slash warning error, that sort of thing.
So we'll test some of those.
Back over to render test.
We'll put in using the context and we'll just use Ctcs and we'll put in flash and we'll put in Flash
as the value or the value of that, and then I'll duplicate it twice.
I'll change this to warning in this two error.
In this two error,
then there's two warning.
Now let's make the value to assigned whatever comes back from test out.
That and default data.
And that requires two things.
It requires a template data or an empty one.
So I'll give it an empty pointer to template data, and that will satisfy the first parameter requirement.
And the second one is a request, a pointer to request.
I have one of those.
I just build it are a Q and now we'll say if these are tests TD Flash is not equal to flash.
Then key to error failed to get flash data.
And I copy this, paste it twice
and make this one morning and make that one morning over here.
I guess
make this one error and make this one error and this becomes error and this becomes flash.
Okay, let's just spread things out a little bit.
Let's try running that test.
So clear the screen.
I'm still in the CMD Web folder so I can see my test files right there.
There's render test.
Don't go.
Go test dot.
And a failed failed to get warning, data warning, warning.
Warning and this would have to be warning.
Again.
Go.
Test dot.
And it passed.
Okay.
So that was an easy enough one to do.
So we've tested adding default data.
Now let's test the next function.
So over here and rendered our go.
We have another one here called is authenticated.
Let's test that one.
So back to render tesco func test config is then to cated authenticated that again t pointer to testing
dot t and same idea.
I need to build the request with the context so I'll put these closer together so they don't take up
quite so much screen real estate.
And I'll copy all of those and I'll build a request and add the session information to it.
Okay, now we say Earth is assigned, the value of Test app is authenticated and I give that my request.
Now, in this case, if both is true and the test failed, as there should be nothing in that session
that says the user is authenticated, so te error returns true for authenticated
when it should be false.
Okay, so there's my first case.
Now my second case is we put a user ID in the session.
So test out dot session, try again session the put and I'll put in ctcs with user ID, which is what
I'm looking for in that is authenticated function and I put the value of one in there.
Okay.
And now I'll copy this and modify it.
So copy paste, get rid of the assignment operator and change that to if not returns false when it should
be true.
Let's run that test.
So go test dot.
And it passes.
Perfect.
Now, the last thing to try from our rendered Argo file is, of course, the actual render function.
Okay.
So the render function, if you recall, takes advantage of this variable path to templates and it specifies
it when we're in production.
When this is running, look at the root level of the application CMT Web templates.
We're going to change that value because when we when we run a test, we're not running it from the
root level of our project.
We're running it wherever that test happens to live.
So let's get started over here in render underscore Tesco.
Let's create a new function and we'll call this one.
Test config underscore render.
And again with T pointer to testing T and the first thing I'll do is say.
Path to templates is assign the value of the current directory slash template.
Okay.
Now we're going to be this time be needing both a request and a response.
I don't want to.
We use a real response.
So instead of create a variable called R called HTP test, right of the testing package dot.
New recorder.
Okay, that gives me something that satisfies the requirements for a request for a response.
Now, I also need a request, so I'll copy these three lines to make those requests.
To make the request.
There it is.
Now I have a request and I have a response.
Now I will call test app the render and we'll try rendering with a response.
So we use a response recorder with the request which we built by hand, and we'll render home dock page
to go HTML.
Okay.
And we also have to give it some kind of template, too.
So we'll give it an empty reference to template that.
And now what are we going to test?
We will test to see if our encode the response code.
If it's not equal to 200, then something went wrong.
So t don't error
failed to render page.
And this should be an equals operator, not an assignment operator.
Let's try that out and see if it works.
So clear the screen.
Go.
Test done.
And it passed.
Okay.
Now, there's obviously more things you could put into these tests.
You could test to see if there's a nonexistent template, that sort of thing.
But this is sufficient to get you started, I think.
So let's move on.
And what we'll do next is we'll start working on the data package to make things more testable because
the way it is right now, we actually need to have a database running to run unit tests, and that's
not good.
And fortunately, it's an easy enough change to make.