So this time around, I want to make some changes to the data package just to make it easier to write
unit tests for things like our pages that were display.
Now the reason I'm doing this, if you open up Main, don't go.
And we go to the top where we have our config being set up.
What we do, we populate the field models in the variable app of type config.
We're actually calling this function data new and we're handing it a pool of database connections.
Now we do that for a very simple reason.
If we look at the new function in data, it actually allows us to give this DB variable a pool of connections
to the database and then the actual models, user and plan and so forth.
Well, user in plan, those are the only two they actually connect to the database.
And that's a bit of a problem.
That means if I want to run my unit tests, then what I have to do is to actually have a database running.
I might spin up a Docker image with a known version of the database.
I might just start a local database before I run the tests.
But that's actually not a good way to do things.
And fortunately, it's really easy to fix this.
Let's close models ago.
Go and over in the data folder.
What I'm going to do is create a new file and I'll call it interfaces.
Interfaces, dot go.
Okay.
And this is in packaged data which I have to spell.
Right.
I'm going to create two interfaces, one type, I'll call it user interface and it's an interface.
Okay.
And I'll create another one type, not surprisingly, plan interface, which is also an interface.
And of course, in go, in order to satisfy an interface, all you have to do is to implement all of
the functions that are attached to that interface.
And if we look at user, don't go here while we have all these functions we have get all which takes
no parameters and returns these things we have get my email and so on and so forth.
So let's go back to interfaces.
Don't go.
And I have in front of me a sheet of paper with a list of all these function names.
Get all is the first one.
It takes no parameters and returns a slice of pointer to the user and potentially an error.
That's the first one.
Then I have get by email and that requires email, which is a string and it returns a pointer to a user
that again, user and potentially an error.
And then I have get one, which is pretty much the same.
So I'll copy this and paste that here and change this to event.
Okay.
Then I have update which takes no parameters and potentially returns an error.
I have delete, which takes no parameters and potentially returns an error.
I have delete my ID, try again delete my ID, which takes ID and potentially returns an error.
I have insert which takes user of type of user and returns an interest in an error.
I have reset password which takes the password which is a string and potentially returns an error.
And the last one that I have is password matches right there and that takes plaintext, which is a string
and returns bool and error.
And those are all the functions which I have to spell interface.
Right.
Those are all the functions that are used by the type user.
Now I've got an interface and by default the user type now satisfies this interface because it has all
these methods exactly the same.
Unless I have a typo, which is always a distinct possibility.
Let's do the same thing for a plan that has get all that text nothing as parameters but returns a slice
of pointers to plan and potentially an error.
We have get one which takes an idea of type integer and returns a pointer to a plan and potentially
an error.
We have subscribe user to plan.
Subscribe user to plan which takes user of type user and plan of type plan and it returns an error.
And we also have a mount for display which takes nothing in return to store.
Okay.
Now, unless I have a typographical error, these interfaces are now acceptable.
They're complete.
So let's find out by going to models ago and will change what's here.
The type user in models to be instead.
User interface.
Okay.
And we'll change this one plan to be plan interface.
Now I immediately have two errors and the error is because probably tells me here might at the end.
Cannot use user literal value of type user as the interface user does not implement user interface user
method delete has pointer receiver.
Well, that's just because we have a pointer receiver.
So who changes to a reference error goes away and hopefully we get everything right with plan.
We change this to a reference and that goes away.
And now with that one change, it becomes possible to modify the data package.
So we can have something, have things that satisfy the user interface and the plan interface.
They don't actually talk to the database.
Okay.
And that will make things ever so much easier.
So to make that happen, what we're going to have to do is I'll just do it this way in the data folder.
I'll create a new file, which I'll call test dash models that go.
Okay.
And again, it's still in package.
And we'll give this one new function instead of using the new function, which is part of the data package.
We'll create a new function called testing.
Okay.
There's many ways to do this, but this will do the trick and it will have to accept a DV cool, which
is a pointer to SQL DB because it's a pointer we can pass that nil and it returns models.
Okay.
So DV pool will still be equal to DV pool.
And that's the package level variable.
It's actually db.
It's not DV pool.
DB is equal to DB pool.
It makes no sense to have one variable equal to itself.
But if you recall over in models star go, we have this variable DV, which is a pointer to SQL DB.
So back in test models, we're just setting that to whatever this receives and we'll pass it nil.
So it'll make DV equals or nil.
We're not going to use it for the tests anyway, but there you go.
Now we return.
In this case, we're still going to return models.
Okay.
But we're not going to return user type and plan type.
Instead, we'll create two new types.
So let's go back over two models.
Don't go not model stock.
Let's go to say user doc.
Go and let's go to the very top and get this user type and copy it and go back over to test model stock.
Go and paste this here and rename it to user test.
Okay.
And we have to import time, so let's do that time, dot time right there.
That does it.
Okay.
So now we have this tape.
And what we're going to have to do, of course, is to create one function for each of the ones in this
list.
The interfaces will have to create functions, all of these, but none of them will touch the database.
Okay.
So let's get started with that.
We'll do user and then we'll do plan in the next lecture.
So simplest thing to do is I'm going to open up user Darko and I'm going to copy every one of the user
functions right here.
All the way down to password matches.
Copy.
Then I'll go to test dash models and after my type user test, I'll paste.
Okay.
Now we have lots and lots of errors and that's easy enough to fix the errors.
By and large, apart from imports, most of which will go away when I make these functions very, very
stupid by removing most of their functionality, it's the receiver.
Okay.
We already have a get all on the type user.
So let's see how we get search and replace.
I believe it's over here.
So we're going to search in this file for you pointer to user and we're going to replace it with you
pointer to user test.
Like that.
Okay.
And I should be able to replace all somehow here.
What does I do?
Replace.
Perfect.
Well, it looks like it replaced them in both test dash models.
And in user accounts.
Apparently I didn't do what I thought it did.
So.
Let's try replacing here in user go will do the opposite so will replace you pointer to user test with
you pointer to user and what does this do that does that one this should do all of the.
Perfect.
So that fixes that one and it fixes this one.
Okay.
You can tell I don't use Visual Studio code as frequently as I use Go Land.
In any case, we managed to recover from that disaster.
So the next step is to make this as simple as I possibly can.
So what I'm going to do is just get everything out of this like that.
Okay.
And I'll create a simple user so I'll create an empty or a variable var users, which is a type slice
of a pointer to user, which is what we have to return.
And then I'll populate that with one user.
So I'll make a user assigned the value of the type user, and I'll put it and say ID one and I'll put
in email admin example dot com and I'll put in firstname
admin and then lastname admin.
It doesn't really matter what it is as long as I have something in there and then I'll have password.
I'll make that ABC.
Not a very good password, but this is test data and then active one is admin one.
Get rid of the extra comma and created a is time dot now and updated app is time now and down here I'll
just append that to my slice.
So right after I define this type, I'll say users equals append users.
In a reference to a user there.
Now this function get all doesn't touch the database at all.
And of course we have to do the same thing for every other function.
Now the next couple use a user, so I'll copy this one and I'll go to get my email.
I'll remove all of this information way down to here.
Scroll up so I can see what's going on.
Create a new variable called user where it's done and I'll do the same thing for this one.
Delete everything out of this except for the return statement and paste in user.
No, I'm not actually using the parameters here, but it doesn't matter.
I just want to create a function that returns the correct types.
Update.
Update just has to return nil.
Just don't report an error.
That's it.
The same thing for delete and the same thing for delete by id,
insert returns and into an error list.
No problem.
I'll just delete everything except for the return statements and I'll return say the number two and
no.
Reset password that's just returning nil for an error.
So that one's done.
And the last one returns a bullet in error.
So I'll delete everything and just return.
True and nil.
Now.
Now I have a version of the user that has no problems whatsoever except that I need to save so it gets
rid of all these imports that it's not using anymore.
Okay.
Then I can actually simplified even a bit more.
Get by email.
Returns a pointer to a user id nil and get one.
Does exactly the same thing.
So all I have to do in this one to get rid of that is just say return, get by email and it pass it
into string.
Okay, that does the trick.
So now in get one is called, it'll call, get by email with an empty string and that returns dummy
data.
Okay.
So now we have a version of our users that doesn't touch the database.
And the next thing to do is to do exactly the same thing with the plan, and we'll do that in the next
lecture.