Okay.
So we have the user test type all set up and let's do exactly the same thing for a plan.
So I go over to plan.
Don't go and go to the very top and I'll copy it's type and then I'll go back to test dash models Tokyo
and go to the very bottom of this file.
You can put it in its own file if you want to.
It doesn't really matter.
Paste that in there and name it.
Plan, test.
And of course we need to do exactly the same thing we did last time.
But this time I'll do the searching, the replace properly.
We copy all of the functions associated with plan.
We go back to test models, we paste this in here, okay?
And then we go to the edit menu, choose five or choose replace and we're going to look for P plan and
replace that with p pointer to plan, test, make sure you spell it right and we click this little button
to replace all.
And that does it.
All right.
So now we do exactly the same thing we did before.
We'll get rid of all of everything and get all except for the return statement.
Okay.
Then we'll create a variable plans of type.
A slice of pointer to the type plan will create one plan
of type plan and populate some information.
So say ID will make one plan name.
We'll make, say, bronze plan.
Plan.
Amount.
We'll make, say, 1000.
I see.
I'm missing a colon here.
That's why my autocomplete not cooperating.
And created a will make time out now and updated.
I will make time on now.
Okay then we append this to our slice.
So plans equals append plans and plan.
And it has to be a reference because it's a pointer there.
So there's the first one.
The second one does almost the same thing.
So I'll copy this plan and I'll get rid of everything in here and paste in my plan and done the next
one.
Subscribe user to plan.
It just returns an error or nil.
So let's return nil.
That's easy.
And the last one we just need to import format and everything else should stay the same.
So if I wanted to print f six.
And it didn't do the import for me.
Why not go up to the top here and put it in myself?
Okay.
All the errors are gone.
So now the next step is to actually return something here instead of returning an empty models.
Now we can return user and we'll return a reference to user test and plan becomes, not surprisingly,
a reference to plan test.
And unless we missed something, this should now be functional.
So let's add this to our setup underscore test.
Don't go to all the trouble of creating this new function test new and all the the database models and
types that actually are database free.
So let's use them in our tests or we'll set it up so we can use them in our tests over to to set up,
underscore, test, go at the very top where we're creating this config in here anywhere I can put now
models and instead of calling data dot new, I call data dot test new and hand it nil for the database.
And that gives me a bunch of models that I can call when I'm running handler tests or running my handlers
as tests without requiring a database at all.
Okay.
In the next lecture, we'll get started testing our handlers and eventually we'll get to the point where
we're testing concurrency as well, which is, after all, the entire point of this course.
So let's move on.