So now that we seem to have our models completely divorced from the database, let's start writing some
test for handlers and see if we get everything right.
And I'll give you a warning right now.
We didn't get absolutely everything right, but it's an easy fix.
So let's get started in our CMT Web folder or create a new file, which I'll call handlers, underscore
test scope.
Okay.
And it's in package main and we'll write right now one test.
We'll just test the home page to Handler for that.
So write a function and I'll call it test config.
Underscore home.
Okay?
And it takes one parameter t a pointer to testing T.
So the very first thing we're going to have to take into account, if you go over to the handlers file
and we find that handler for home right here, okay, it's expecting to find home dot paged HTML.
And of course, that calls the render function and that one has this variable at the top, the path
to templates.
So we're going to have to override that variable.
Otherwise it won't find the template and it can't render it and that's easy.
So back in handlers underscore Tesco, we'll just say path to templates, which is a package label variable
that's now equal to DOT slash templates because the templates folder is right beside this test.
Okay.
So that's the first thing we have to do.
Then we create a response recorder and we know how to do that HDP test and we'll create a new recorder
and that's substitutes or takes the place of the response.
Writer So we have that now.
We'll create a request, same as usual request and I'll ignore the error is assigned the value of HTTP
new request and we'll give it a get because that's what the home handler expects and it's the home page
and we're not passing any data or anything else to it.
Okay.
And then of course, we need to get the request with the session data.
So KCTCS is assigned the value of that function gets ctcs.
We wrote a while ago and we handed the request and then request is now equal to request with context
syntax.
Okay, now we're ready to call the handler.
We want the test, so I'll declare a variable handler.
And that's a sign the value of each HTTP dot handler func right there and we hand it from our test app
variable we're calling homepage
and now we call that handler.
So handler don't serve HTP with our, which is our response recorder and the request we just built and
now we perform our test.
And what kind of tests should we look for.
Well, this should return htp dot status.
Okay.
Or status code 200.
So if our encode is not equal to htp dot status, okay, then we have an error.
So we'll say t dot error and we give it some error message failed expected 200 but got and we'll just
put our encode there.
Okay.
So let's see if that test works
inside the cmd slash web folder.
Go test dash reader.
And it passed.
Now, that's not surprising because the home page actually doesn't hit the database, but that's a pretty
easy test.
Now we have other functions.
If we look at our routes file, other handlers like log in and log out and register.
These just, you know, they're very simple pages and they're all going to follow exactly the same format
as the one we just wrote for our homepage.
So maybe it makes sense to go back to handlers or underscore test, don't go.
And instead of just doing one test per page, we'll just write a simple table test.
In other words, we'll set up some data like this will come up here and create a variable.
We'll call it page test, and that's equal to a slice of structs.
And we populate the fields for this simple have name, which is a string, that's a name for our test,
whatever we want to call it, what you are already calling and that's a string and we'll have an expected
status code which will be an integer.
Then we're going to have to specify which handler we want to call, and we can do that by making a field
called handler of type issue report handler func like that.
And then we can specify the actual handlers we want to call for that individual test.
There might be session data.
Some of them require session data.
So we'll just make a map of string any so we can put anything in that map and then pass it into the
session.
And we also might check for things like expected h html.
Once you render the page, we can actually look at the stimulus generated and search for a particular
string.
So we'll make that a string.
Okay, so that defines it.
Now we populate it and we'll put in to start with just the homepage, just to make sure it works.
So.
The first test will have the name of home.
We're testing the home page and we'll have a URL of slash, which we're not using, but it's nice to
have it.
It makes it easy to see which route this matches with, and we'll look for the expected status code.
And of course, that's going to be HTTP dot status.
Okay.
And what if we wanted to check for HTML?
Well, we won't do that right now.
We'll worry about it later on.
Okay.
So for the moment, this gives us one variable.
Let's just save that.
That should not be an error.
That's better.
Okay.
So at the moment this gives us a variable with one test to run.
So let's just make them make a simple table test here and it's going to follow the same format as this.
So let's just rename this test to test underscore pages like that.
Okay?
We're still going to have our path, the templates that'll be set this way.
But now we do a for loop four and we don't care about the index, but we do care about the current entry,
which I'll call E that comes from ranging through page tests.
And inside of this will create a response recorder.
Interception like this will make copy editor here.
Paste it into here.
The.
And then we'll make the path name instead of a slash like this.
We'll go to either the URL.
Okay.
And then we want to call our handler and perform a test.
So let's get all of this out of here.
Cut it.
Paste it up inside of here.
Save this to format it and we'll modify it as necessary.
So instead of calling handler this way, let's delete that and just change this to e dot handler dot
serve htp.
Okay.
So that takes care of everything except for the session data and we may as well write that logic right
now after we set up our context and get our request with the context.
We'll check to see if that map which is in page test called session data if that's empty.
So we'll say if len of e dot session data if that's greater than zero.
And there's at least one thing in that map and all we have to do is arrange through that map for key
and value our assigned values by calling range e dot session data.
Okay.
If they exist, then we just put that value in the session test at that session, not put using our
context ctcs we put in key and value.
Okay.
Now we only have one thing in our table test.
Well, let's run it to make sure it works.
So let's clear the screen and run.
Go.
Test dash v dot.
And we have a fail.
And he says we're failing.
Handlers are scored.
Test.
Don't go 40.
Let's see what's on line 40.
And of course, we actually have to put the handler in there naturally.
So handler.
That's equal to test out.
Our homepage.
First lecture of the day.
Let's run that test again.
Much better.
Okay, so now that we know that it works with one page, let's add a second page.
Okay.
But before we do that down here, we may as well put in that check for expected HTML.
And that's pretty simple.
So we'll say if len of e dot expected h html this is email expect to find in the rendered page.
If that's greater than zero, then we're looking for html and all we have to do is say HTML, which
is a variable I'm declaring right now that comes from our response recorder, dot body, dot, string.
We get the response body as a string and then we check to make sure that our expected HTML is in there
and we can do that using the strings package.
If not strings dot contains and we're checking in html and we're looking for e dot expected html.
Then we have an area keyboard area with a format string of percent s field expected to find percent
s but did not.
And my substitutions are the name of the test heat opening and the expected h html e dot h2.
You expect that each html.
Okay.
And here we may as well put this as an error f as well just to put the name of the test in there.
Percent s failed colon expected percent d but got percent d.
This makes it work for any test in the first substitution is the name of the test e not name.
Second substitution is e dot expected status code and the final one is the code we actually got.
Okay, let's run that test one more time to make sure there's no typos.
Perfect.
Now, let's add a test for a second page.
Well, what's another page that we can test pretty easily?
Probably a login page.
Let's try that one.
So I'll copy all of this just to save some typing or paste it.
Here is my second table test and I'll call this one log in page
and the URL will be slash log in.
Our status.
Okay is correct.
That's what we expect to see.
But the handler is actually test out that locked out login page.
And let's save this to format it.
Now, let's go look at that template for the login page and find some HTML that we we expect to see
in that page.
So login page type HTML, I expect to see this title.
So let's copy that and go back to our handlers test.
And this time we'll make sure that text actually exists.
Expected HTML and I'll use the back ticks so I can paste this in without those double quotes causing
me problem.
Okay.
So I'll say that.
Open the terminal, clear the screen and run the test again.
And it passed.
Okay.
Now, obviously, we can do this for every one of the pages we expect to find.
But let's do one that's a little bit different.
Let's copy this and paste it here and we'll do the log out.
Now, log out doesn't actually render a page.
It doesn't redirect.
But the URL is log out.
And we're expecting to find status see other.
If you look at the handlers and you find log outs all search for log out
it sets the status here to see other and then redirects us to the long log in page.
And the other thing we should have for log out of course is we should actually have some session data.
We should be able to log out only when we're logged in.
So let's just add a field here in the log out page.
We'll add some session data, and all I have to do is build a map, a map of type string that takes
any and then curly braces and I'll put some values in here.
So we'll put in, say, user ID, which has to be there if you're logged in and I'll just put one in,
you're supposed to have a user variable.
I'll just put an empty user in there user.
And that's a type data dot user, just an empty one and curly brackets and a comma and save this.
And now I should be able to run this test and get the correct response.
We're not expecting to see any HTML on a redirect so I can delete that.
Okay.
So let's run the test and this should pass.
So I'll clear the screen.
Go test.
Dash V dot.
So far so good.
Now, this is all really encouraging and obviously you can go and add any other page right here.
But the minute you add one or certain ones that actually interact with the database, there are certain
situations where you're going to run into problems.
Even though we set up that test dash models file and duplicated all the necessary functions or methods
tied to user and tied to plan.
There's still a couple of situations where we're going to run into problems when we try to execute a
certain test, and that has absolutely nothing to do with the test models we set up.
It has to do with the way we access those models in our handler, and we'll see an example of that and
how to address it in the next lecture.