So this time around, I want to test this function over here and handler stock go and the function is
called post login page.
And of course this is the function that is called when someone actually fills in their username and
password and log in screen.
So this is handling a post request, so let's get started doing that.
Okay.
So over and handlers dot test or handlers underscore test, don't go.
I'm actually going to put this in its own function.
So I'm going to do a little bit of work on this one just to demonstrate something.
So we'll declare a function and I'll call it test config, underscore post, log in page and it takes
one parameter t pointer team testing dot t
now.
First thing we'll have to do, of course, is set the path to the templates so the render function can
find the appropriate page if necessary.
Path to templates.
And this is equal to DOT slash templates because it's right beside this test.
Now we're posting some data to this and to post data in our in our test will declare a variable called
posted data.
And it's a sign the type of an it has to be from the URL package values.
Okay.
And we'll put two in here.
And the first one is email, which is what's the username filled in on the form?
And that's going to be equal to and it has to be in curly brackets, admin app, example dot com.
And then we'll put in some password.
Okay.
So we'll put in password and it doesn't really matter what it is at this point.
So I'll put in, in curly brackets, ABC one, two, three.
And then just to make it a little longer, I'll copy this and paste it a couple of times there.
So we have a password now or we have posted data that consists of an email address and a password.
So far, so good.
Now we declare a response record HIV test.
Don't try that again.
Test dot response.
Reporter
And we'll declare request.
Ignoring the error when we call from the HTTP package.
New request.
And it has to be a post request and it's going to go to slash and login, which we're not using, but
it's nice to have it match what it's actually going to.
And then we need to encode our posted data into the correct format.
And we do that by calling strings dot new reader and then we call posted data dot encode.
Okay.
And now we need our request with the context.
So KCTCS is assigned a value by calling that function get context handing at the request and our request
is equal to.
Request dot with context six.
Okay, now we need our handler.
Handler is assigned the value of HGV to hand lir func and we give it the appropriate handler test our
dot post login page right there.
Okay.
Now we serve the handler.
Handler dot serve HGV and we hand it our our response recorder and our request.
And this should be new recorder.
Now we perform a test.
Now let's go over and look at Handler Echo and see what we're supposed to get back at the very bottom
of this function.
At the very bottom of this function, we're supposed to get HTP status C other.
So let's perform that test.
If heard a code
is not equal to again achieve a status C other
than will say T to error wrong code returned, which is enough to get this going.
Okay, so let's run this test.
I'll open the terminal window.
I'm in the correct folder.
Go test.
Dash V dot.
And everything seemed to pass.
That seems really encouraging.
But what happens if we actually make this a little more accurate test?
Over in Hamburg, don't go.
If you look near the bottom of this function post login page, we should have, for example, a key
user ID with some value stored in the session.
Let's see if it's there.
So after this check for the response status code, let's say if not test ab.
Dot session dot exists using the context and we're looking for user ID like that.
If that doesn't exist in the session, then something went wrong.
So we'll say t the error did not find user id in session.
Our test passed last time.
Let's see what happens when we actually check the session.
So I'll clear the screen.
Run the test again.
And it failed.
It didn't find that in the session.
Why not now at this point?
This is where I start testing things like Let's find out what code is actually being covered in our
test.
And fortunately Go makes that really easy.
All I have to do is in the same folder where this test exists is run these two commands, go test again,
dash cover profile equals and then some file name and I always call mine coverage out.
Okay, so let's run that command.
Now this will run the test, which will fail, but it will also produce a file called coverage that
I can use to look at the code in more detail.
So the test failed.
It produced the coverage file.
Now I'll run go tool cover, dash html equals and then the name of the file.
I just specified coverage.
Okay.
And what this will do is fire up a web browser and show me what is actually happening in the tests.
Anything that's green is covered.
Anything that is red is not covered.
And here's the function I'm interested in post login page.
So what happens?
It does.
In fact, for new the session token, it does pass the form post.
There's no error, so this doesn't get executed and I'm fine with that.
We do get the email and the password.
We do get a user from our fake database and there's no database behind it, but there was no error.
So we have a user and then we check the password and here's where we have some grief.
Notice that it's getting the value for valid password and it's getting an error when it calls user DHCP
password matches.
And that's where the problem lies.
The problem is that when we said to ourselves, our test models are completely divorced from the database.
They are entirely divorced from the database.
If I call a variable user like I created this variable user up here when I called app top model start
user, I can't buy it by email.
That's calling my test function, but when I call it directly, user password matches.
The problem I run into is it's calling the actual production version of password matches.
And of course, it's never going to find a valid password because this variable user doesn't have any
of its fields populated.
It's populated up here with just empty values or dummy values.
So it's never going to be able to do that.
Password matches the way that I want it to.
And fortunately, that's pretty easy to fix.
Let's close this and go back to our code and go over to the handlers ego.
Go file and find that line, which is right here.
Line 44, my code where I'm checking the password.
We change that to app dot models, dot user dot password matches.
So let's run that test again and see if everything works as expected.
So go test dashboard.
And this time it should pass.
And it does.
Okay.
So that means that anywhere in this handler's file that I'm calling a method on the user variable directly.
In other words, I'm not calling app dot models, dot, user dot, whatever the method is.
Instead, I'm calling some variable that is that the user type dot the method.
I have to change that.
So let's find those really quickly.
So act up, models.
That one's fine.
This one's fine.
This all looks okay.
So that was all right here.
We're calling out of session.
Destroyed.
No problem.
Register pages.
Fine.
Post, register page.
So we get a variable you and we call you, insert you.
So here we should be calling at dot models, dot user,
dot insert.
So we found one there and that is in the function post register page.
Let's keep going.
We generate a token from a string.
So far so good.
Let's try to activate account.
So we're calling here verify token, which is fine.
So we get the variable you and we call get by email here we call you update.
Now we're gonna have to make a change to the actual update function.
Instead, this will be app dot models, dot users update and we're going to have to hand that you.
Okay.
So that means now we have two changes to make.
The first one is going to be actually three changes over here in our data folder.
We're going to have to change the interface type.
So update will have to be user of type user.
Okay.
And delete.
We can just get rid that -- altogether because we're not even using it.
So I'll comment that one out then we're going to have to go.
Two models don't go.
That's okay.
But we'll have to go to user echo, find the update function, which is.
Here somewhere.
Update.
We'll have to make this.
Accept the type.
User of type.
User.
And.
This becomes user.
We'll copy that and paste it right here and here and here and here.
Okay, so that's it for the production version of the database models.
Now we'll have to go to test models and find the error here, which is going to be in the update.
Where are you?
Update So get all, get by email.
Get one update right there.
That's going to have to take the tape user or the model user of the user.
Okay.
So handlers, let's go back to handlers and make sure that worked.
So that takes care of this situation.
Subscribe to plan.
We had an idea and a plan I.D. and we're not calling anything directly there.
Here, we're getting a user from the session.
That looks okay.
We're calling this directly.
We're going to use are we calling any methods on that?
You know, we're fine.
Okay.
And here we generate the manual.
Good.
Get invoices simple and choose subscription is the last one.
That should be all the changes we have to make there.
Now let's run our tests one more time to see if we broke anything.
Go test stash v dot.
And we do have a fail.
So that's in handler's dog go line 151.
Handler stock go line 151.
So here the error is it says cannot use variable of type star data don't user as type data don't user.
All we should have to do here is to reference that.
All right, let's try that again.
Go.
Test dash v dot.
And everything passes.
Okay.
Now, you might be asking yourself, is there another way to do this?
To me, it's really convenient to be able to call methods on a variable of the type user, for example.
And a factor is the way they would normally do this is you would not separate your test database functionality
and your production database functionality.
The way that we did instead would use something called the repository pattern.
And it's pretty easy to implement, but this is of course in concurrency, not in repository patterns.
And if you're interested, I do that sort of thing in another one of my courses, the one that's entitled
something like building modern web applications in go.
And it's pretty straightforward, but this is sufficient for our purposes.
All right.
Let's move on and actually test something that uses concurrency and we'll discover we have another problem
or two when we do that, which is, after all, why we write tests in the first place.
Okay, let's move on.