So the last thing I want to test in this section is the handler that uses concurrency the most.
And of course, that's this one.
Subscribe to plan in the file handler scope.
And as you know, this handler fires off one go routine that generates an invoice, an eco routine,
fires off another go routine that sends an email.
And the first thing I notice when I look at this handler is that I have some hardcoded values that are
going to cause me some grief, like here on line 214 when I have slash temp here.
And a little bit further down, I have it here as well.
And of course, this go routine, the one that generates a manual, it calls generate manual.
And if I go down to generate manual, I have yet another hardcoded path name right here.
So let's take care of that.
Let's go to the very top of this file and let's create two new variables.
So the first one, I'll call our path to manual.
Okay?
And it's a string that's equal to in production, dot slash PDF.
And of course, that's where manual dot pdf is the file that we open and modify when we're generating
a manual.
And the second one, I'll just call temp path the path to the temp folder and in production, that's
dot slash TMP.
Now we'll go down to that handler, subscribe to plan which is right here and let's fix those hardcoded
path names.
So I'm looking for the part where I generate a manual right here.
So let's get rid of dot slash tmp and replace that with a percent s and over here our substitution will
be the temp path temp path comp and we do exactly the same thing here on line 228, my code percent
s replaces dot slash temp and our substitution is temp path.
Now we'll go down to the generate manual function and we'll change this to use format as Pranav to build
a string that's print F and I'll get rid of the dot slash PDF and replace that with percent s and we
declare substitution here and that is path to manual and closer parentheses.
Okay, so now that's a little more testable.
So now let's go over to setup underscore test ago and here right in the test main function, I can actually
set those two variables I declared right here.
It's a little simpler and in fact if you wanted to, you could move path to templates in here as well
and remove all references to it in our test.
It's up to you, but I'll just put in temp path and that's going to be equal to when I'm in testing.
It's the current directory, then up one level and up one more level and then the folder temp.
Okay.
And path to manual.
Same idea.
It's equal to the current folder which is CMT web, then up one level, then up one more level, which
is the root level of my project.
Then the folder called PDF.
Okay, so let's go over to handlers underscore test and write any test.
I'll go to the very bottom of this file and I'll create one test file function func and this one is
going to be called test config because there is a config receiver and this one is called subscribe to
plan with one parameter t pointer to testing dot t and here I'm going to need a response recorder and
I'm ready to context and requests and all that sort of thing.
So let's copy everything out of this previous function and paste it in here and we'll make modifications
as necessary.
First of all, this is a get request, not a post request.
And here every other function we've written that tests a handler, I said we don't care what the URL
is, but in this case we do because remember we're calling slash subscribe and it has to have one query
parameter named i.t.
So I'll put question mark.
It equals one here.
We're actually using it this time.
Okay.
And the last parameter can be nil because we're not posting anything.
So I have my response recorder, I have my request and I have my contact all set up.
So let's get started with the test.
Now, this particular handler requires that there be a user in the session, so I have to put a user
in the session and that's pretty easy.
Test a dot session dot put using Ctcs the context we built, it's going to be called user like that
and it has to be a data user.
So we'll put that in here and we'll give them an ID of, say one, an email of say admin at example
dot com and a first thing first name will be admin,
last name will be user, active will be one.
And that should be sufficient.
Okay.
So now we have a user in the session, so let's get our handler.
So we'll declare a variable handler and that is assigned the value of each UDP dot handler func right
there.
And the one I want to pass it is of course test app.
Not subscribe to plan.
And now we serve that handler.
Handler.
Dot serve htp with our response recorder and the request we built.
Okay.
Now, at this point, I can write a test if I want to, and I'm going to look for, say, status other
as being the response code.
If our code is equal to are not equal to HDP or status C other than my test is failed.
Right.
So T dot rf.
Expected status code of status c other but got percent d because it's an internal code and that will
actually work.
And if I run this test right now, I have no idea what's going to happen because I'm not going to bother
running this test right now.
If I do, nothing's going to have time to finish those two go routines.
I'm firing off the one that produces a PDF, for example.
It's not going to have time to finish because I need to take advantage of that wait group.
And that means that I need to come in here and wait for things to finish.
Now, you might think this would work.
Test out.
Don't wait, don't wait.
Okay.
Seems logical.
It should do the trick.
Let's try it out.
So I'll open the terminal and I mean the right folder.
So I'll run.
Go test dash v dot and it's not going to finish.
It might, it might pass.
I don't know, but it's definitely not going to finish.
Let's see what happens.
So it starts running the tests and it gets to test config, subscribe to plan and it stops and it will
stop forever or until the power goes out, whichever comes first.
So to start this test, I'll hit control C and then I'll close the terminal window.
Now let's figure out what's going on.
It seems pretty clear that it's waiting here where I'm telling it to wait.
And of course, what it's waiting for is for that variable test app dot wait to have the value of zero.
In other words, every time we added one to it, it has a positive value and every time we remove one
from it goes down by one.
And clearly we're adding more than we're removing.
And where is that happening?
Well, let's go back and look at that handler again.
So back over in, handlers.
Let's find that.
Subscribe user to plan right here.
So in this function I'm adding one to the weight group here and I'm removing it here.
On line 194.
And down here I'm adding one to the weight group online to 12 and a removing it here online to 14.
So why is it not zero?
One plus one is two minus one minus one is zero.
It seems that they should all be set to zero, but of course this app does not send mail.
Also adds one to the weight group and down here app dot send mail also adds one to the weight group.
Now, we didn't notice it up until this point because we never actually tried to wait for anything in
any of our tests.
It didn't seem appropriate to do so, since we weren't directly running any concurrent code or any code
that was concurrent in nature.
But now we see we have a bit of a problem.
Actually, we have two problems.
Let's go over to setup, underscore Tesco and let's find that bit where we create a mailer and start
it.
So we create the daily mailer here in this section and then we start listening here.
And the first thing I notice is everything inside that go func that should be wrapped in a for loop.
Otherwise it's going to send one email and then just the weight group will die.
And of course that's exactly what happened.
Every time we called any handler that generated email in our tests, if we did, it just sent the one
email that go routine died.
And we don't notice anything because as far as the problem is concerned, you don't need it anymore.
Now the second problem we run into is here.
When I check for the case, something comes in on the mailer chain.
That means somebody tried to send email or we tried to send email.
And we need to at this point actually add one thing to this test app.
Dot wait.
Dot done.
Okay.
Because we're never actually firing off the code that sends email in our tests because we're not testing
our email functionality.
So here we need to decrement our weight group by one.
Now when I open my terminal and clear the screen and run this test, it should pass.
And it does.
Now, that pause there for 5 seconds was because I told the routine that generates a manual to simulate
something that takes a lot of time by putting a pause in there.
But it passed.
But of course, I'm not done.
I want to make absolutely certain that there are no race conditions.
So I'll go back here and add a dash race to this and run it one more time and make sure we got everything
right.
So it'll start the tests.
They'll still be that 5/2 delay and running go test.
Race always takes longer.
There goes.
It's pausing while it subscribes to a plan and everything passed.
Okay, so there we've managed to write some basic tests for core web functionality and we've also written
some tests that test concurrency, and I think that is sufficient for our purposes.
Now obviously we didn't test every little bit of our application, and that wasn't my intention.
My intention was to give you the tools necessary for you to be able to write your own tests in whatever
your project may be.
So there we go.
And that is it for this section.