Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
installing, go learning and preparing this code idea in Windows operating system and indecision.
You want to talk about the installing Go Lang and repainting this good idea in Linux operating system.
How to install Golang in Linux system.
First, go to go blank dot org slash deal and download the latest version of Google Lang in an archive,
find using Debian you get comment as follows.
Now select Go Lang version based by operating system.
If our OS is 64 bit select Go Lang 64 bit version.
And if it is 32 bit, we select Go Lang version 32 bit.
Next, check the integrity of the tarpon by verifying the SHA 256 checks, some of the are qualified
using the South comment as below where the flag dash is used to specify the algorithm to be used.
Samson Dash, a 256 Go Lang Dart part Dart Cheez-It To show that the contents of the downloaded are
confie are the exact copy provided on the Go Lang website.
The 256 bit hash value generated from the comment about as seen in the output should be the same as
the provided lounge with the download link.
If that is the case, proceed to the next step.
Otherwise download the new tar ball and run the check again.
Then extract the tar archive, find into RSS, use the restless local directory using the comment below.
Sudo tar dash c uppercase SS user SS Local Dash IX visit f go lang dot tar dot gz where Dash C upper
is specifies the destination directory.
First set up your go watch space by creating a directory home, go on their projects, which is the
root of your workspace space.
The focus phase is made of three directors, namely being which will contain go executable binaries
S4C, which will store your source vine and pcgg, which will store package objects.
Therefore, create about directories as follows and call the Air Dash P home slash go on the project.
Slash open and close calibrations and between input been comma s or C and comma pcgg m code.
The air means make directory and second c.
The whole S lets go on their projects, see the means change directory and to else means least files
and directories.
Now it's time to execute, go like the rest of Linux programs without specifying its absolute patterns,
its installation directory must be installed as one of the Valley of Pad Environment variables.
Now at such user, it's local as Let's Go West has been to the path environment variable by inserting
the line below in your research ethics fine, fine for a system wide installation or home Slashdot profile
or home Slashdot bash online profile two user a specific installation.
Using your preferred ED weapon, the appropriated user profile fired as per your distribution and at
the line below.
So save the file and exit it.
Export pact equals pact columnists use it as such, local estimates go as this been.
And then set the values of go pat and go bingo environment variables in your user profile find to point
to your space directory.
Export go pack equals home IST, let's go on the line projects and export go being equals.
Go pack it slash beam.
If you install Golang in a custom directory other than the default path means it's less user, it's
less local.
You must specify that directory as the venue of the Go Route variable.
For example, if you have installed Go Lang in the home directory at the lines below to your home Slashdot
profile or home, a Slashdot bash underline profile file export go root equals home slash, go and export.
Pack equals pack column.
Go to the slash mean.
The final step on the decision is to effect the changes made to the user profile in the current Précision,
so right souls home don't bash online profile and execute or source home if Slashdot profile.
Very fine go blank installation around the comments below to view your go version and environment,
go version to see the version of Go Lag and Go Ms.
To see the go your environment.
Type the following command to display use age information for the GO tool, which many schools source
code go help.
To test if your go installation is water chaotically, right, is small, go.
Hanawalt program save the fine in-home go on the line project saucier slash hello directory on your
go lang source files must be and with the Don't Go extension, begin by creating the Hello Project directory
on their home.
Go on the line project as Slash CRC, so we right in the air dash p home go on the line projects r sirc
slash hello, then use your favorite editor to create the Hello Dot Go find in the Halo Directory in
this example we used from VM, so write the I Home must go on the line projects s less SIRC as such.
Hello s nash.
Hello dot goo.
Now go to create a sample.
Add the lines below in the fine, save it and exit it.
Now compiling the program evolve as using go in, install and run, it's so full compiled, we use go
in a town, come in and run the program we use Go Run.
If you see the message, hello, welcome to the Golang programming in Linux, so your installation is
working correctly.
Install visual studio code on Debian and open to.
The most preferred method of installing visual studio code on Debian based systems is by enabling the
voice code repository and installing the Visual Studio could package using the app package manager.
So we use the command, so the app update.
Once updated, proceed in install dependency required by executing the command sudo apt install software,
Dash Properties, Dash Common APT Dash Transport, Dash STPs.
Next, using the devil you get command.
Download the repository and import Microsoft's GPG key as shown.
Once you have enabled the repository, update the system and installed visual studio code by running
the comment, so do APT Update and sudo APT install code.
Due to its size, the installation takes approximately five minutes.
Once installed, use the application manager to search Visual Studio code and launch it as shown.
Install vs code extensions after the installation launch vehicle.
Then opened a St. John's marketplace by the council plus shift plus x chalky and search go and install
it.
Now it's time to install up the tools for do this.
Open the comment palette by the Control Plus Sheathed Plus piece key and around the Go column install
update tools common after ex-security.
You can see go extensions listed here, selling all and install them.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue to contend in
the next session.
Goodbye.