Hello and welcome to the Guoliang programming language course in this session, we want to talk about
install the go programming language practically inside the Linux operating system.
First in a stall, the Golan.
Go land dot org, slash the URL.
We entered the gold and software download page based on the desired operating system, selecting installation
file and download it because my system is leaning.
We select the Linux installation fine.
And go to Lenovo's tap.
And copy the name of the last version of Golang.
Now open a new terminal and downloaded by Debbie Lou, get command.
So be right, w get Dash C, H T T P s column s S-Class go lang dot org slash dl slash and paste the
name of the last version of Go Blank that we have copied it.
Now, download this starting.
The download completed in this time, check the integrity of the tar ball by verifying the SHA 256 checksum
of the archive file using the source and comment saw the right solution.
Dash, a 256 and paste name of the Go Lang last version that we have copied it.
Now we can get the SHA 256 checksum hashes of the fine and it's quiet now extracted are confined into
this user.
It's local directory.
So in terminal, go to destination of the archive file, download it and extract go lang.
File into Escort's use it.
If this local by this command sudo tar the ash see.
Escorts, user escorts, local.
That's exquisite Earth.
Name of the last version of Golden Boy, the title Dodd.
Geez, it.
For the check, we will go to the S-Class User Escorts Local Directory.
And now we see the gold and installed chronic.
Now configuring Golang environment in Linux, first set up your Go workspace by creating a directory
at home for the example named Go Online Projects, which is the root of your workspace, the workspace
is made of three directories, namely Bing, which will contain go executable binaries.
SRT will be restore your source files and pcgg, which will restore package objects.
Now let's go to write some commands for create workspace.
Sudo.
In the air DSP home S.A. go on the line, projects open, Credible says Bien como SIRC como pcgg and
close curly braces.
Now go to home and check the go on the line project, walk to space.
All the directory is created and see all things is okay now it's time to execute, go.
Like the rest of Linux programs without specifying its absolute path.
Its installation directory must be installed as one of the values of path environment variable.
So at its user, it's not local.
It's let's go if there's been to the path environment variable by inserting in your search ETSI as that's
profile file for a system wide installation or home Slashdot profile or home Slashdot bash on the line
profiling for user specific installation.
Now we set it for user a specific installation so open the user profile means that Slashdot profile
and add this line.
Export pact equals pact, Colin Less user, it's less local.
Let's let's go.
Slash bean then set the values of girl pat and go bingo environment variables in your user profile fine
to point your workspace directory.
So add these lines in profile.
Export, go, pat.
Equals.
Whole east, let's go on the line projects.
Export.
Go being.
Equals.
Girl power.
It's last been.
The final list that honors this section is to effect the changes made to the user profile in the current
position by source comment.
So we right source.
Home air slash.
Dot profile and execute this comment for verifying go link installation, run the go version and go
and in to view your gold version and environment.
So be right, go.
Well done.
Now we can see the gold version and go, and now we can see the environment of go.
So the installation is correctly and everything.
All right.
Now it's time to install Visual Studio code on Debian, or up until the most preferred method of in
a stunning visual studio code on Debian based systems is by enabling the VIOUS Code repository and installing
the Visual Studio Code package using the APT package manager.
So first, we try sudo apt.
Update.
The update is a starting and wait until update complete.
OK, the update has got completed once updated Prosit in install dependencies required by executing.
So we write.
Sudo apt in a song.
Software, the ICE properties that's common is space apt.
Dash Transport Dash has two tips and execute the program is being installed.
Press Y and continue.
Wait, Anthony, installation complete.
OK, installation complete next, using the W, you get comment, download the repository and import
Microsoft's GPG keys for convenience.
I have already saved them in the fine copy and put them in the terminal.
So go to our fine.
Well, Penny, copy these lines and move them to the terminal and execute them one by one.
Once you have enabled the repository, update the system and installed visual studio code by running
the command.
So do.
Opted.
The update is starting.
Wait until update complete.
And sudo apt get install.
Could.
Due to its size, the installation takes approximately five minutes.
Once in its thought, used application manager to search visual studio code and launch it.
OK.
This software installation process is complete.
Now it's time to go to configure device code.
So open the Vasco.
First opened Extension's marketplace by council plus shift plus short key and search go extension and
install it.
OK.
It's installed.
And now open common pilot by console plus shift plus Pete Shawki and select Go column in a stone slash
update tools.
And select all the check boxes for in a stunning all requires tools.
Now we are waiting for the installation of the required tools to be completed.
OK.
Download complete it now for Test, create a simple project, so go to Explorer Project and go to work
a space.
And create a folder like, hello.
And inside it, create a fight.
Like Maine that go.
And write some quotes.
In future, we will talk about these quotes here, just we want to tests.
All right, package main.
Forage Maine and write the message by the comment FMD, not print and set the message, for example.
Welcome to go programming.
Language.
Save the project, go to terminal and run the project first.
Go to hell of a lower.
Hello.
And run the project by the comment Go Run.
Plane that go.
Now we can see the message Welcome to go, programming language, all things are OK and you're ready
to write your codes.
OK, we have reached the end of decision.
I hope that you have take full advantage of decision until next session.
Goodbye.