So welcome to let's build a go version of Laravel Part two.
And before you enroll in this course, one thing you should be really clear about is that this course
should only be taken after the first course, which is oddly enough entitled Let's build a go version
of Laravel, because this course builds on the core functionality that we have in the first half of
this course.
So first time around, as you'll recall, if you took that course, we have an awful lot of functionality
built into a package called celebrities that makes building web applications really, really easy.
And of course, what we're trying to duplicate is much of the core functionality you find in the web
framework known as Laravel.
So we have support from multiple databases for sessions, for user authentication, for all sorts of
things.
And this time around, what we're going to do is extend that to include more core functionality.
For example, we're going to start with building remote file systems.
These days, very few sophisticated Web applications just serve everything from one place, they'll
have assets like graphics and videos stored on Amazon S3 buckets or FTB server or something like that.
So we're going to build in support for four different file systems Mineo, Secure FTP, WebDAV and Amazon
S3 buckets.
And once we have those up and running, we'll build a file system agnostic file uploader where you can
upload a file using standard web upload and have it automatically stored on whatever file system you
wish.
We'll also improve our database migrations.
Last time around, we built migrations that were pure sequel, and this time will also support features,
and we'll build that functionality right into the celebrity command line application.
We'll also add support for social authentication, and we'll support only two in the course GitHub and
Google.
But when you go through those lectures, you'll also learn how to implement that for pretty much any
social authentication that's available these days.
We'll also build in support for remote procedure calls, which is an alternative method of having your
web application listen for commands.
So rather than posting a JSON file or something like that.
Instead, we'll build remote procedure calls.
We'll also simplify testing, so we'll make it easy for people that are using celebrities to build web
applications to actually test their handlers without having to build support for sessions and everything
else read into their tests.
We'll do all that heavy lifting for them and let them test what they want to test.
We'll also add some browser functionality to our tests, much like Laravel Dusk Package, so you'll
run a test.
If something goes wrong, then you can actually capture a screenshot of what the browser shows at the
moment of failure.
And we'll also add some support for browser emulation in testing, for example, clicking buttons.
All right.
It'll be a lot of fun to go through all of this, so let's get started.