Panel and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
logical operators and in decision, we want to talk about the other operators concept.
Operators, presidents operate or presidents determines the grouping of turns in an expedition.
This affects how an expedition is evaluated.
Certain operators have higher precedence than others.
For example, the multiplication operator has a higher precedence than the Edicion operator here.
Operators with the highest precedence appear at the top of the table.
Those with the lowest appear at the bottom within an expertise in higher precedence.
Operators will be evaluated first.
Now let's go to the school curriculum to illustrate how to use operators precedence.
First, we define a variable and initialize it by an expedition.
For example, we define a variable like X calling equal and initialize it by seven plus three multiplication.
Two now display the output by the following comment.
So we write that if.
Resolve.
Paula, Person, D. and Sir, it's very, very.
Reformat the court, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output result is 13 here.
Each is assigned 13, not 20, because operator multiplication has hired a pittance that operator plus.
So it first gets multiplied with three multiplication too.
And the result is six and then six value adds into seven.
And final result is 13.
OK.
We were able to explain operators precedence and go language and give examples.
We have reached the end of decision session.
I hope you take full advantage of this session until next session.
Goodbye.