All right.
Welcome to class.
I'm super excited you're here.
And in just a moment I'm going to start getting you going with everything in the course I'm going to
give you the course resources I'm going give you access to an outline for this course I'm going to go
over my credentials because I think it's important when you take a course to understand a little bit
about the individual who's teaching you or the individuals who are teaching you and we're gonna have
two teachers in this class I'm going to tell you about that and but the first thing I want to do is
and if you've taken any of my other classes you know this is something I do at the beginning of all
of my classes including my classes at the college and the university is I'd just like to take a moment
and commend the students commend you for what you're doing because what you're doing is to me one of
the noblest of endeavors and so I just want to congratulate you for taking that first step to improve
your own life improve your own life.
Gandhi said Be the change.
And when I was young Be the change right Be the change don't wait for somebody else to be the change
don't wait for somebody else to make stuff happen and when I was young I kind of thought that that meant
that you know you had to go out there and start changing the world and changing how people do things
and changing other stuff.
But now that I've gotten older I've realized that be the change means like no manifest the change in
yourself first and then worry about everything else because as we each individually improve our own
lives the world is getting better by that amount.
And so I just commend you and that's why I think of education as the noblest of endeavors.
I commend you for improving your own life because if everybody in the world embarked on the journey
that you are embarking on right now the noblest of all endeavors that endeavor of educating yourself
of improving your life of building your skill set of becoming better and more knowledgeable so you can
contribute and help others and generate more income.
And with that extra income provide for yourself and provide for your family.
And if your wealth gets big enough you know influence and help others as you improve your own life as
you educate yourself as you come out of the darkness of ignorance the source of all suffering.
Right.
Because when people act on skillfully it's because they're ignorant they don't have the knowledge that
they need to act in a different way as you come out of the darkness of ignorance.
And that's the root of suffering as you come out of that and come into the light come into the light
of knowledge and knowing and awareness and better skills the doors the opportunities the the potential
of your life starts to fully open.
And so this can be a long process.
Life is both long and short.
It's both long and short.
And when you're young sometimes it can seem like man it's going to take forever to get where I want
to go I can't believe it.
This is such a big mountain to climb.
What else are you going to do with your time.
Right.
Like what else are you going to do with your time.
You to watch TV.
That's not a good use of your time a little bit.
OK.
Like you know have a little bit of fun relax a little bit.
But like there's stuff that you can know in life to live a better life.
I've created an entire course on that.
That course is called The Journey.
It's the things that I've learned in my life about how to live a better life.
For instance focusing on the four areas of health your physical health your financial health your social
family health your psychological emotional health the four areas of health keeping those all in balance.
So you're you know not out of balance right because who wants to be that rich person on their deathbed.
Would all they have is money and nobody likes.
Right.
You've got to have social family health.
You've got to have physical health.
You've got to have financial help.
Unfortunately our world is a caste system based upon how much money you have.
And if you don't have money you don't get as good of food.
You don't get as good of living conditions.
Yes you don't get to live in the safer neighborhoods.
You don't get to drive to safer cars.
You don't get better.
You don't get as good of health care so as you build your skill set as you come out of the darkness
of ignorance the source of all suffering and as you move into the light of knowledge and knowing and
better skills you're improving the world one person at a time.
And so that's the noblest of all endeavors.
And I just want to commend you.
Yes.
I get a man.
How little your brother.
Hallelujah sister I just want to commend you.
And by the way I come from my mom's side of the family a southern Pentecostal preacher.
So if I start preaching the good word a program and an education that's that's what you got coming for
you every now.
Every now and then I get up on the pulpit and I also believe in humanity in sharing one's humanity and
in building software for humans right.
Knowing the humanity knowing humans and and what the tools are that they need the better we know humans
the better we recognize our own humanity and the humanity of others the better we're gonna be able to
build software for people and the more successful working b not only you know with the the products
the software that we build but also in our relationships.
So humanity is really important and being authentic and being a man of my word or a woman of my word
and saying what you mean and wearing your heart on your sleeve and having integrity so all that stuff
super important and.
But the main point of this video is I commend you for the step you're taken to improve your own life.
To start out on this in this journey and to embark upon the noblest of all endeavors and to educate
yourself come out of the darkness of ignorance and move into the light of awareness and knowing and
skills better skills that's only going to make the world better.
So I'm going to speak to a little bit I said man when you're young it seemed like a huge hill to climb.
I'm going to speak to that coming up in a video.
I'm going to give you some skills to help you learn more effectively and to understand research backed
people right.
It's backed based on primarily the research you know or most most notably most notably the research
of Angela Duckworth on what makes students successful so as your teacher as your professor I'm in your
corner.
I want to see you succeed as a student so I'm going to I'm going to share with you what it takes to
succeed as a student so that you know that.
So you'll be like Okay that's what it takes to succeed.
I can do that if you don't know what you're doing right.
Education is kind of crazy or school systems crazy because you go there to learn but they never teach
you how to learn.
It's like you came there to learn but they never stop to show you how learn they just say start learning
this stuff.
There's a way you can learn better and if you know that you can apply and it's simple and it's easy
and I'm going to teach it to you and that's coming up.
So if you feel like me this is a big hill to climb I feel a little bit overwhelmed.
I don't know if I'm gonna be able to get to the top of that mountain.
Go to that mountaintop where you could see the other side.
I don't know if I'm going to be able to get there.
We're gonna speak to that and tell you how to get there and I'm going to give you a little bit of inspiration
a little bit of wisdom.
I believe in something I like to think of as the education hierarchy.
So not only teach in skills and knowledge right.
Which is pretty much what most education today does a mediocre job of doing.
Not only giving you skills and knowledge but also giving you wisdom motivation inspiration to me.
That's the full monty.
That's the full kit.
Right.
You got skills knowledge wisdom motivation inspiration because I believe fundamentally at the root my
job isn't to just give you skills and knowledge.
My job is to motivate you and inspire you and teach you how to be the champion of your own life how
to get in the driver's seat of your own life how to be proactive how to have an internal locus of control.
One of the number one things they try to teach United States Marines when you become a United States
Marine they try to teach you how to and how to have an internal locus of control how to get in the driver's
seat of your own life how to be proactive how to build the life you want.
It ain't always easy right.
So that's one of the primary things I want to convey to you.
Knowledge skills and knowledge but also wisdom motivation inspiration Plutarch Plutarch says that the
mind is not a vessel to be filled.
The mind is not a vessel to be filled but Kindle to be ignited.
So that's one of the things I want to convey in this course.
I want to ignite the Kindle within you ignite the passion within you ignite the potential within you
so that you could build your best life improve the world one person at times starting with you you're
being the change and then realized great success and then go on out into the world and and share that
wisdom that knowledge spread the light of knowledge and skills to others so that so that the world becomes
better because there's a lot of ignorance out there a lot of suffering.
And education is the antidote when we learn we become more skillful when we become more skillful we
can build better things take better actions have a better life.
So that's what's common in this course.
I'm going to leave you with one last thing which is this quote by Omar Bradley since we were just talking
about the importance of knowledge skills and knowledge but also wisdom motivation and inspiration.
Omar Bradley who is a four star general five star general and war two man saw some action saw some darkness
and and there's this quote he has let me find it.
Let me try this one I'm not seeing it.
This guy is this guy is what do you call it somebody you look up to.
Right.
He's one of those people for me.
The words eluded me I'm a little bit under slaps a short term memory is gone out the window.
But here's Omar Bradley.
He's not a mentor.
I don't know him but not an idol.
I don't know what the word is man.
Message me on Twitter if you know what word I'm trying to come up with.
The world has achieved brilliance without conscience.
Ours is a world of nuclear giants and ethical infants.
We know more about war than we know about peace more about killing than we know about live.
If we continue to develop our technology without wisdom or prudence our servant may prove to be our
executioner.
So we are the Jedi Knight.
We are the humans with superpowers being able to code.
We are building the future and understanding the myth of Prometheus and how tech is a tool like buyers
a tool and it can be used for good or for bad and bring some wisdom right.
Similarly skills knowledge but wisdom motivation inspiration bringing some wisdom to that.
So you know in some ethical awareness about how do we use our tools.
I think that's all really important.
So that's the introduction of the course.
The primary takeaway my dear friend my fellow colleague on this planet my fellow human we are all in
this together to get a little California hippie on you right.
Yes we have to like take care of yourself first you gotta take care of yourself first gotta make your
own bed first feed yourself first.
Right.
But once you get your own house in order you can step out and start helping other people were all in
it together.
And I just want to convey this at the beginning the course and the primary takeaway is I commend you
for embarking on this journey.
I commend you for embarking on this journey and that's a 100 percent heartfelt and I'm 100 percent in
your corner and I wish for you as strongly as I wish for anybody in the world including my own children.
Your your success.
I want to see you succeed.
I want to see you triumph.
I want to see you realize the life you want.
And so whatever that means for you a life of goodness where you're helping others.
That's that's what it's all about.
So I got a lot of good stuff to share in this course.
We're going to be focused primarily on technology but the human element is important as software engineers
we're going to talk about that in its own video coming out because the more we understand humans the
better the products and service we're going to be able to build the better the relationships we're gonna
be able to build the better life we're gonna be able to build.
So welcome to class.
I'm glad you're here.
Super glad you're here.
I commend you for taking this first step.
Let's get started and jump into the next videos.
See you in the next one's.