Now let's talk about my credentials so my credentials are that I'm a tenured professor in California.
I've taught at the University and the college level for over 20 years.
I started teaching as an adjunct professor in 1997 and I was one of the first university professors
to teach online.
I taught online in nineteen ninety seven.
It's hard to believe I haven't made a ton of money off the Internet.
I didn't create some dot.com startup and partly that's because my background is in economics an undergraduate
degree in economics and a master's in business after teaching adjunct faculty as an adjunct faculty
at the University for three years.
In 2000 a tenured position at the Community College opened up and I went to work at the college teaching
accounting in 2001.
In 2001 they needed somebody to teach programming because this was right after the dot.com boom Internet.
Well the Internet's been going since the 60s but the World Wide Web it just like kind of gone through
its dot.com boom and crash but is like they needed programming professors and they said Are you willing
to teach that I was good with computers so I started teaching web dev teaching myself and teaching students
web dev.
I've since taught web death to undergraduates and graduate students in computer science at both the
college and university only at the University of graduate students in computer science and then two
thousand and five.
I was continuing to do postgraduate work and online education at UC San Diego always improving myself
always bettering myself always looking to see like how can I learn and grow and become a better person.
Right.
So I was doing postgraduate work in online education at UC San Diego and then about 2005 I started with
a calling something called the online teacher training program where we taught all of the college faculty
in central California how to teach online.
In 2008 I was recognized as one of the top professors in the entire California system which is the largest
post secondary system in America with over 2 million students I was one of the top eight or 10 or 12.
I forget how many there were professors recognized in 2008 and 2013 I learned about the Go programming
language and I learned that Google looked at all the other languages and said none of them are meeting
our needs.
We've got to create a new one and then they tasked Rob Pike Ken Thompson Robert Grossman to build it.
And so those are those are three individuals who are luminaries in computer science heavy hitters.
They helped build the C programming language the Unix operating system and you TFA encoding coding scheme
and so they built to basically help build the bedrock of computer science.
They said We're gonna build a new language and they did it with Google.
I said I'm going to know that language.
So I started learning that language in 2013 that I was one of the first university professors in America
to teach go at the University level.
And and I've also created online go courses which is one of these courses right here.
So it's a little bit about my credentials and my background.
I have an ability to teach right.
I've learned that over two decades.
Malcolm Gladwell takes 10000 hours to get good at something I've been doing this right.
That's about 10 years.
I've been doing this twice that long.
So the ability to teach and create online classes and I understand computer science and programming
but I'm not the high end computer science professor I've done introductory classes because my training
hasn't been in computer science.
So that's a little bit about my background.
I'm just looking here to see if there's anything else that you know I wanted to include in here.
And I think it's good for you to know a little bit about your teachers background just so you can kind
of see how the life journey that I took and where I ended up.
And I love programming and to add this into I love programming because I love building and I love creating.
And for me building and creating and making something and bringing it into the world is one of the most
satisfying things ever.
And so all of the different endeavors I've been involved with in my life and I started out in high school
I loved making documentaries and I was nationally recognized as a high school student for making documentaries
and I went to UCLA before declaring my major in economics and I and I wanted to study film and television
and had some life struggles super socially challenged when I was young and I like almost like retarded.
So socially challenged.
And so anyhow that's my undergraduate degree.
I ended up getting it in economics.
I started out in film and television.
I've had a love of literature and the humanities in my life.
But this theme of building and creating whether it's documentaries or all those read books over there
those are all books I've written during a hard time in my life whereas that basically ground zero and
I don't think I could have gone any lower without dying.
I built myself back up from that and part of that was writing my way out and just had to experience
so much loss in my life and I had so much grief at one point in my life.
That is all I could do.
Like at one point I was walking on the campus of college campus and a colleague said Hey Todd how are
you doing.
I just stark.
You know and because I'd just gone through a huge loss and I had so much grief and so that's how I got
out of it.
So those books I like them you know and I'll just share a little bit.
You could publish some of my wrote about 50 novels so I teach during the day and I just go home at night
and I'd write and I'd write and I'd write I wrote about a book a month for a couple of years.
I wrote 50 books and I published about 20 of them.
And so one of them here this is about Hitler if he had been reincarnated.
That's the surprise ending.
But once and then again.
So the ideal vice which the German shoulders soldiers would climb up the mountain to get pinned into
their lapel.
So this theme of humanity.
And if you look at TAC in the history of tech and if you look at like the wars right.
Steve was me AK and if you look at like Steve Jobs Steve Wozniak Steve Jobs dude I can't believe I'm.
Yes he was an actor both named Steve.
And if you look at likes Steve Jobs and like they were all people who are really interested in art and
humanity and like was the Woz ended up sponsoring the ballet with some of his riches and and Steve Jobs
was like you know really into different cultures and different religions and went over to India and
studied meditation for a while and was really into calligraphy which is why early computers had all
these different beautiful fonts that you could use.
And so this idea of like creation and you know like you know software engineering is very much engineering.
But there's also this idea of building things for humans and and having that be a part of it.
And so I share all that so you have a little bit of information about my credentials and where I'm coming
from and what I know and what my experience has been and my perspective and also yeah.
So you just know a little bit about me.
So I think it's good for you to know a little bit about your teacher before you get into the class because
actually a lot of research on learning theory says that the more that you feel some pot to go with your
teacher the more you have a connection with your teacher the better you do in the class.
And we all know this from personal experience right like if you hate your teacher you don't even want
to go to the class.
And if you like your teacher you like I'm you can go to that class and start remember when I was an
undergraduate I had a calculus professor and I only had to take one calculus class but I liked this
guy so much I called him the Monk of mathematics.
I liked him so much I took two more calculus classes I guess maybe two more calculus classes.
And so I took three classes when I only needed one because I just when this guy would go to the whiteboard
and do math is like watching Michelangelo like paint and you know like maybe I speculate what that might
is just like you got this peaceful for you they just stand back and look at what he wrote on the board
and admire it.
And it's like I just loved seeing his love for his craft and that kept me in the class.
So we we don't go to classes where we don't like the professor and you know we we do better in classes
where we do like the professors.
That's why I share a little bit this humanity.
And and I also just really want to convey that concept of you know we're building things for humans
we've got to know humans we've got to understand humanity and I love building stuff whether it's writing
a novel or creating a documentary or building a website or creating a course like all of that's joy
joy for me.
So those those that's a little bit about my credentials.
Yeah.