So now I want to give you the course resources and so we've got a course outline here.
And this folder here this link will bring you to the folder where anything that you see is used in the
course aside from GitHub will be in this folder.
And then I'm going to add a link to get hub here as we start creating a code base that you could go
get the code.
So you know that link will be there.
And then here's a link to some of my favorite things people sometimes ask me for book recommendations
and so I have my coding books that I recommend for go.
I have books that I've read about wisdom like Franz Kafka NO NOT THAT ONE LIKE A Man's Search for Meaning
by Viktor Frankl.
Right.
So Viktor Frankl man search meetings an amazing book.
You know Michael Paul and how to change your minds really been one of my favorites recently smarter
faster better.
So all those books are listed there along with I think I have some of my favorite movies and things
like that so you could check that out and then the course outline to get to those link.
You see you need to come to the course outline and to do that.
I'm going to because I realize right now that I didn't do this.
I'm going to go to bitterly which is that link creator and and I'm going to click Create and you can
see I had an alias there James.
And so I'm pacing in that link and then it gave me a funny name so I'm going to customize the back half
and we're going to call this awesome coding.
Why not.
And and and then I'm going to see if that clicks up.
Come on give me awesome coding.
Hey where'd it go.
Let's see if that worked.
Let's try going to bit Lee forward slash awesome coding.
I don't know if it took you to copy that in case it worked.
Nope it didn't take.
Let's try this again.
So I'm gonna get that you are L Sorry for the delay.
Maybe this is a little interesting if you've never seen it before I now it's a little bit basic.
We're in kind of a more of a dance class and or intermediate class and add a tile course outline.
Maybe I need to have a title and working at an awesome awesome coding and there.
Come on man Click Give me up here and customize back half protip create bit links from any Web page
one click get bent like extension I don't know why that's not clicking in up here usually you know let
me just copy that and save it and see if it kicks in.
OK so I have to hit save.
All right.
There's awesome coding so if i paste in awesome coding bitterly awesome coding that's gonna take me
to the course outline.
So I'm just gonna drop that end right here that you could go to that you URL each TTP colon forward
slash forward slash B T dot l y forward slash awesome dash coding and you can get to this course outline.
All right.
So those are the course resources.