OK so now we have a video dedicated specifically to this concept of being built for humans.
I think this is an important concept to remember and it's a concept that I'm remembering we've already
spoken to a couple of times already.
But it's also a concept.
So not only for me building this class is something that's important for me to remember but also as
you're building any software.
Generally speaking all software eventually is being built for humans.
Right.
So thinking about that just thinking about how can I more effectively build this for humans.
I think that's an important perspective to bring to this creative process of software engineering where
we build better tools for humans.
And so I just wanted to speak to that in its own video.
And I'm going to share with you something.
It's a acronym and that acronym is CSI computer science right.
Normally we think of CSI as computer science CSI and you could see that right here in the course outline
CSI.
But for me I was thinking about this the other day and and I realized in the phrase that came to me
as an alternate meaning for CSI is collectively stupid collectively intelligent right collectively stupid
collectively intelligent because there is this thing called multiple intelligences and so multiple intelligences
means that you know I might know some stuff about X but not Y and you might know a lot about y but not
much about X. And so we all have multiple intelligences so collectively you know each of us individually
right has areas that we don't know stuff and together we individually we have areas where we do know
stuff.
So together we're more intelligent and then collectively stupid doesn't quite fit as much.
But there is group think where a bunch of humans can make bad decisions together and history is littered
with examples of that.
Right.
So you don't have to look very hard maybe even at the place where you work to see a group of people
making bad decisions.
And so just remembering that you are a representative of this great profession and this great domain
called Computer Science CSI and not only does CSI stand for computer science but also collectively stupid
and collectively intelligence and sometimes groups of people can make really bad decisions.
So it behooves us and it's part it's it's bestowed upon us it's part of our responsibility to speak
up when we think a group of people are making a bad decision and then also to recognize that collectively
we are also more intelligent that we can all work together both sides of the same coin.
All right.
Because we all know certain things and don't know other things.
And so I wanted to speak to this at the beginning this course because this course is going to have two
instructors and I will be one of the instructors and then my friend my colleague a former student of
mine Daniel is going to be the other instructor and we're going to teach this course together.
And the reason we're teaching it together is because there's things I do not know I am a great I'm a
great introductory introductory Comp Sci professor I'm very good at teaching introductory classes that's
what I've done for a large part of my career but I've been on kind of like a loop cycle since my academic
training was in economics and business I've been on it kind of recursive for loop where I just teach
the intro classes and so you know if you don't have industry experience if you aren't using it in the
trenches every day there's a lot that's lost.
Can I teach the intro classes great.
Yes.
Right.
I have that down but all of the nuances that you get when you're a professional developer that from
using it six seven eight hours a day you don't get that when you're professor is a professor teaching
intro classes going to committees grading stuff meeting with students and helping them.
And so we're gonna have Daniel in here and I'm going to model for you what it means to collaborate to
work with other people to be humble and to say man I don't know anything about that and to ask questions
because we're going to go into stuff in which into which I do not have knowledge.
And so you know I have some cursory understanding but Daniel will have the expertise in that area and
so we're gonna be exploring that territory together.
I'll be able to ask astute questions I'll be able to slow things down if they start going too fast.
If like Daniel's like firing way I could like wait a minute wait a minute let's break that down let's
pull that apart and look at all that in one video and really get that concept.
And so that's what we're gonna be doing and there'll be two teachers and I'll be one of them and there's
things I know and there's things I don't know.
So part of this course will be going into territory or things I don't know which is great because I'm
excited to do this course so that I can learn but somebody who's a professional dad and who's working
and using it every day in the trenches because I want to broaden my skill set and so that's a really
important human trait to bring into your life to be humble to be willing to learn.
I don't understand why any how anybody could be a teacher if they aren't also willing to learn which
means being willing to say I don't know.
Which means being willing to be humble.
And so many teachers feel like they have to be the expert and have all the answers.
My goal as a teacher is to get it clear and to get it clearly conveyed to you right.
So I can understand it and I could convey that understanding to you and we could do that together.
That's my goal and I have to learn to do that.
And so we're going to be going through this course together in that way.
And one of my previous courses I shared this phrase that came to me when I started thinking about making
this video and this phrase is that the more I admit I do not know the higher I go the higher I go the
harder it becomes to admit I do not know.
I know it's a little bit like some kind of Zen paradox or something but here it is right there so you
can read it.
The more I admit I do not know the higher I go the higher I go the harder it becomes to admit I do not
know.
So holding on to that that that reality right that not everybody knows everything that we all have areas
where we know stuff we have areas where we don't know stuff holding onto that reality and being willing
to own it and embrace it because everybody tries to like put up a front and you know a few skate and
you know present themselves more powerful or knowledgeable or better than they are it's like just be
who you are.
And so you know being willing to admit like oh I don't know anything about that please tell me more.
So when I was a graduate student I remember being in a class and asking a question and the professors
like would and answered it and then he's like do you get it.
And I'm like I still don't get it.
Professor tried to explain it again.
He said Do you get ice.
I still don't get it.
And you said come see me during office hours.
I said OK right.
And and then after class one of the students came out to me is like and was like I'm so glad you're
asking questions because I didn't get it either I'm like Why didn't you speak up you know.
But you know it's like people are afraid to admit like it's a sign of weakness that they don't know
something.
So anyhow it's important to meet you don't know it's him.
That's the first step in learning.
And through this course it'll be taught by myself and my colleague and friend Daniel and former student
and a professional working Deb and so I'll be learning here alongside with him.
So that's how the course is going to be structured.
All right.
So that's that's a built for humans this course is built for humans it's built for humans.
Built for you it's built for me and part of our humanity is you know that idea of multiple intelligences
we all know stuff we all also don't know stuff and being willing to be humble and collaborate with others
and work with others and to learn.