So in this section of the course, we're going to focus on channels a great deal more, and channels
are the preferred method of sharing memory.
So if you recall back in the introduction, I said that goes approach to concurrency is share memory
by communicating, don't communicate by sharing memory.
And this is achieved primarily through the use of channels.
So we're going to have a look at both channels and at another classic problem from the field of computer
science called the sleeping Berber.
So channels channels are nothing more than a means of allowing communication to and from a go routine.
Once you fire off a go routine into the background, as it were, you really have no way of directly
communicating with it, apart from the use of channels.
And channels can be both buffered where they can accept more than one thing in the channel.
In other words, if you have a buffer channel of size ten, you can put ten things in a channel or they
can be a buffer, which only takes one thing at a time.
We'll have an example of that shortly.
Now, one of the golden rules of channels.
Once you open a channel, you must close it.
If you don't close the channel, you're going to wind up with a resource leak and bad things will happen
as time goes on.
And one other thing about channels, typically they only accept a given type or interface.
So you can have a channel of booleans or a channel of iNts or a channel of a custom struct type that
you've defined yourself.
But typically they only accept one kind of data.
So we're going to spend some time looking at channels initially in this section, and then we'll move
on to this problem, the sleeping Berber and this is a classic problem introduced by Dijkstra in 1965.
It's been around for a long time and it's a highly contrived example, but it's a classic for a reason,
like the other classic problems we've looked at so far in this course.
This really forces someone to look at the problem of concurrency in detail and figure out how to achieve
what you want to achieve with the most efficient solution possible.
So what is the problem?
A Berber goes to work in a barbershop with a waiting room, and that waiting room has a fixed number
of seats, so it can only hold so many people.
Now, when the barber shows up, he looks in the waiting room.
If there's nobody there, then he takes a nap.
But when a client shows up, if there are no seats available, he or she leaves.
But if there is a seat available, then the.
And the barber happens to be sleeping.
Then the client wakes the barber up and gets a haircut.
If the barber is busy, the client takes a seat and waits his or her turn.
And once the shop closes, no more clients are allowed in.
But the barber has to stay until everyone who's waiting gets a haircut.
So let's have a little illustration here.
And no, I did not draw these images.
Someone with actual skill did.
So here's our barbershop.
So the barber shows up to work and has a look in the waiting room.
Here we have four seats.
There's nobody waiting in the waiting room.
So the barber takes a nap.
And there he is, taking a nap.
Then a client shows up and the client wakes the barber up and goes and gets his haircut.
Okay.
Now, as the day goes on, there might be more and more people showing up in the waiting room.
If someone shows up and there's a seat available, then that person takes it.
And if somebody else shows up and there's no seats available, then that person goes away.
Somewhat unhappy because apparently he needs a haircut.
Okay.
And at the end of the day, the barber goes home.
Now, this might seem like a pretty simple problem, but we're going to try to achieve this using foreign
currency.
And to complicate things a little bit, as we go a little bit further into the section, we'll actually
add more than one barber.
So it's an excellent exercise in the use of channels.
And if you work through this and you pay close attention to what's going on and you understand exactly
what's going on at the end of this section, you will have a solid grasp of what channels are, how
they work, and when to use them.
So let's get started.