So if everything went according to plan, I should be able to run this program now and see the expected
output.
So let's give this a try.
So I'll open my terminal and I'll make it a little bit bigger.
Okay.
And we'll type.
Go run, dot, go, run, dot.
Now, remember, we have one burger.
We have ten places in the waiting room, and people are arriving at a fairly steady clip.
There's a lot of people arriving fairly quickly.
So what should happen at the end of the day?
There should have been a lot of customers who left because they were waiting.
Room was full.
And are poor barbers going to have to stay way past closing time if everything went according to plan?
Let's find out.
Go.
Run.
Don't return.
So lots of people came in and look at all the people being turned away.
They leave because there's no room in the waiting room.
And here's our poor barber, Frank.
After the shop closes, he starts a client 11.
He goes through a whole bunch of different clients, finishing these poor people who are waiting in
the waiting room.
So I hope Frank was paid by the haircut and not by the hour.
Or maybe by both.
The poor guy had to stay really late.
So how do we make this a little more efficient so we don't have so many people leaving?
Of course that's not difficult.
Go to the top of Main Don.
Go.
And we can make the waiting room smaller.
So we could say seating capacity, too, with no other changes.
If I clear the screen and run this, we should still see lots of people leaving.
But Frank won't have to stay as long.
Let's find out if that works.
People are leaving.
Lots of people leaving, but at the end of the day, there should be far fewer people for Frank to do
after the shop closes.
And he only has to do one, two, three, one, two, 65, 76 and 84.
So those are the ones that he finished.
Okay.
Now let's go back and change this to a seating capacity of ten again and let's add a few more barbers
and see if we can make this more efficient.
Clearly, this shop gets a lot of business.
So let's add some barbers.
So I'll duplicate this.
Say, one, two, three, four, five.
So now we have one, two, three, four, five, six.
They can all be named Frank.
So we'll make this one.
Girard, Girard.
And we'll make this one, Milton.
And this one is Susan.
And this one is.
So, Kelly.
And finally, Pat.
Okay, so now we have far more barbers.
Let's see what happens this time.
Here, the screen.
We shouldn't see as many red lines because we have more resources available to take advantage of the
people in the waiting room.
Okay, here we go.
No red lines at all.
There's two red lines, three red lines for five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, 11.
Well, there's still some red lines there.
But it should finish a lot faster, too.
And everybody went home.
And the very last line says the barber shop is now closed for the day and everyone has gone home.
So as you can see, you can add barbers.
You can make the waiting room smaller or bigger.
You could change the arrival rate so people don't show up quite as quickly.
But clearly, we seem to have solved this.
But just to make sure and again, this is something you need to get the habit of doing go run dash race
dot to make sure there are no race conditions and there shouldn't be.
But let's make sure no warning and everything is going according to plan.
Okay.
Well, that was a lot of work.
But as you can see here, we have a really complex problem.
And all we used to solve it was the buffer channel.
The buffer channel, and that's pretty much it.
We have no new taxes and we have no wait groups and everything worked really, really quickly.
So this is a clear example of taking advantage of Go's philosophy.
Don't communicate by sharing memory.
Share memory by communicating.
Okay, let's move on to a slightly more realistic problem, one that you might run into in the real
world.
And we'll finish out the course with that.
See you in the next section.