So some time ago we had a brief introduction to channels.
And at that point I ask you just to follow along, because we'll be talking about channels in more detail
later on.
And now we're going to talk about channels in more detail.
So I've opened a new window in Visual Studio code, and I just opened a folder called Simple Dash Channels,
and right now it's empty.
So let's open our terminal in Visual Studio code and just type go mod in a call line.
Simple dash channels.
It doesn't matter what you call.
So that creates my go monster.
And now I'll create a new mango file.
Mango.
And of course, that's in package, man.
And I'll create a main function.
Thank me.
And what we're going to do this time, it's just a really simple program that demonstrates how channels
work in go.
And as I said quite some time ago now, channels are just a means of allowing one go routine to communicate
with another.
And I'll give you an example as to why that's important.
So right now in this program, I just have an empty main function and I'm going to create another function
up here, funk and I'll just call it shout and you'll see why later on.
And at the moment it doesn't take any parameters at all and it doesn't return anything.
And all it has inside this function is a for loop that just goes forever.
And for now, I'll just have it print something to the console format or print line
and I'll just say executing loop.
Okay.
So there's this function isn't called yet, it doesn't do anything.
And if I come down here and call this the way it normally would without with a concurrency, I just
say shout, okay, no problem.
You know exactly what's going to happen here if I put my terminal and type go wrong.
Dot It's going to print that executing loop endlessly and it never exits and that makes perfect sense.
That's exactly what it's supposed to do.
Okay, but if I put the keyword, go in front of this and then I want to keep the program going.
So I'll say time dot sleep and I'll sleep for say ten times timed out second again.
You know exactly what's going to happen here.
The program starts, we go to the main function.
It says, Start the function, shout in its own go routine and this runs in the background.
Okay.
And then we sleep for 10 seconds.
So if I run this right now, we'll have exactly the same as what we did last time.
But if I was to wait for 10 seconds, the program would terminate.
The problem is that the main function now has absolutely no way of communicating with that one that's
running in the background.
And as you can see, the program terminated because 10 seconds went by.
Channels allow us to communicate between go routines.
And as you recall, the main function in any go program is, in fact, its own go routine.
So channels are nothing more than pipes.
You might think of them like that.
There are ways of pushing data to a go routine or getting data from another go routine.
So how do we make that work?
Well, to start with, I'm going to create two channels and I'll call them ping and Pong, so I'll create
two channels.
The first one is called Ping and I make a channel with the keyword make and I just say it's channel
and every channel has to take some kind of type.
So in this case, I'll make this a channel of type string.
That's the only thing this channel can take.
Then I'll duplicate this line and call the second one.
Pong.
Okay.
So now I have two channels.
I have an error because I'm not using them yet.
But I do have two channels, one called Ping and one called Pong.
And now I'm going to pass those channels.
Ping and pong to that go routine show.
Okay.
So up here, of course, I have to accept those types.
So I'll say Ping, I'll call them the same thing, which is a type chain string and pong, which is
also a type channel string.
Okay.
So now I've passed these two channels that I created here on the lines 15 and 16 to that function shout,
which is running as a go routine.
So now we have these channels.
Let's do something with them.
Okay.
So instead of printing out executing loop, let's do it.
But let's get a value from a channel.
In other words, inside this endless for loop, the one that never exits.
I'm going to accept a value from the channel called Ping.
Ping will be the channel we get data on in the shut function and pong will be the data we send channel
to inside the ship function.
So how do I get a value from a channel?
It's simple.
I declare a variable.
I'll call it SW because it's a string.
That's a sign the value of.
And there's my operator.
Okay.
And I put the channel after it.
This means when you get something from the channel ping put it in the variable sw.
Okay.
So once I have that, what I'm going to do here is write it to the channel PO and how do I write information
to a channel?
These are almost exactly the same syntax, but to the channel pong, I'm going to send whatever I get
from the channel ping, but I'll do a little operation just so I know that the date is being changed.
So this function is called shout and we'll just shout by converting everything to uppercase and putting
some exclamation marks after it.
And I'll just use the format as part of its function and I'll give it a format string percent s and
then say three exclamation marks and my substitution will be from the strings package, which is part
of the standard library.
I'll convert everything to uppercase.
And when am I converting?
I'm converting.
Yes, that string I got a moment ago.
Okay.
So this is now waiting to receive something from the channel pane and it's sending it back on the channel
pong.
But of course, I have to send something to that channel.
So let's make this a little more interesting.
We're going to start it in the back.
We're going to create our two channels, and we're going to start this go routine in the background.
And then instead of time, dot sleep, let's just put a four statement here for actually let's put some
instructions first.
So format dot, print line and I'll print out some instructions for the end user.
So I'll say type something and press enter and then I'll put enter Q to quit.
We'll make this a little simple little program that allows people to type things in.
Okay.
So there's my instructions printed on the line.
Now I'll put an analyst for loop here and I'll print a prompt
just to let people know they should type something in.
And that's as simple as saying format or print.
Not print line, but print.
And I'll print out this symbol with the space.
So there's my prompt.
Now I want to get user input and I'll just use the scanner for that.
So I'll create a variable per user input of type string and then I'll read whatever the user typed into
that.
So I'll ignore the two return parameters because I don't care about those.
That's equal to from the format package scan.
Okay.
And we're going to scan it into user input.
That variable it just declared.
So it allows me to type something in.
Now.
We'll check to see if the user typed a Q to quit.
And that's easy enough.
If user input
is equal to and to convert everything to lowercase just to make it simple.
So it doesn't matter if the type an uppercase Q or a lowercase Q string start to lower.
Q Then they want to quit.
So user wants to quit, so I just break out of the loop.
Otherwise here's where I'm going to send something to that channel, and we'll do it exactly the same
as we did up here in line 13.
But I'm not sending it to the Pong Channel.
I'm sending it to the ping channel.
So ping gets user input, whatever the user typed.
Okay.
And then I wait for a response.
So what I'm doing is sending something to the ping channel.
I'm sending user input, whatever the user typed to the ping channel and then I wait on the Pong channel.
And that's as simple as saying whatever the response is, that's just a variable name I'm choosing.
It's assigned whatever comes in from pool.
Okay.
Now I have to do something with that variable.
So I'll set format the print line
response column and then a comma and then whatever the responses.
And once I get outside of this loop, when someone's typed a queue to get out to quit, in other words,
here's a golden rule.
And I've said it before, and I'll be saying it repeatedly as time goes on.
When you're done with channels, close them.
Otherwise, you're going to have a resource leak.
So I'll print out a message format or print line.
I'll just say all the closing channels.
And how do you close the channel?
It's as simple as saying Close the channel, ning ping and close the channel name path.
So I'm all done with those channels.
So let's go through this again.
When the program begins execution, the first thing that executes, as always, is the main function.
The very first thing I do is create two channels.
I'll put in a comment.
Create two channels.
Both of these channels, one is named Ping.
One is named Pong.
They only accept strings.
Okay.
Then I take those two channels and pass them to the function.
Shout with the keyword go which sends start this function up here running in the background and just
run forever.
And it will because it is a for loop with no exit condition.
So that will run forever.
So that's running in the background.
Then I just print out a message.
Then I have my for loop starting on line 26 when I print out a prompt.
Okay.
And I've printed on one line.
So the carriage return or the entry point will stay right beside this prompt symbol.
Then I use format dot scan line to read whatever the user types into this string user input.
I check to see if the user typed the queue if they did jump out of this loop.
If they didn't, then take whatever they typed, send it to ping.
Ping receives it or send it to the ping channel.
And the show function listens to the ping channel, gets whatever it receives, stores it in variable
s, converts it to uppercase, adds three exclamation marks and sends that string back on the Pong Channel.
And down here, once I've sent it to the ping channel, I wait for a response from the Pong channel
I printed out.
That's all there is to it.
So when I run the program now, I'll open the terminal and clear the screen and type go run dock.
And I have imported not used time, so I have to save this first.
And that will get rid of it.
There we are.
There the screen.
Try it one more time.
Go.
Run, Dot.
So it prints out the prompt the little instructions type something at press enter.
So if I type Trevor and hit return it should send it to the ping channel, get received in the show
function, get converted to uppercase and sent back with three exclamation points.
And it did it sent it back.
Then if I type hello.
Which I spelled wrong but like that that should get converted to uppercase and sent back.
And it does it.
When I type a q it should quit and say all done and it closes the channels.
So that, I think, is a pretty simple explanation for how channels work.
Here we have two channels and we use them, and when we're done with them, we close them down here
in line 44 and 45.
Okay.
Now, there's one more thing that will make your life easier in some cases.
It's also possible when you're declaring parameters in a function like this.
To specify a channel is being send only or is being receive only.
So when you think it through, we're only ever receiving on the ping channel and we're all only ever
sending on the Pong Channel.
So how do I make this a receive only channel?
Well, you just put a little arrow here like this.
Now, that's a receive only channel, and this one is a send only channel, and that's all you have
to do.
Now, that's absolutely not necessary, but it does prevent you from accidentally trying to send to
a channel that you're intending to receive upon.
Okay.
So if I run this again, it should still work.
So let's go the screen.
Go around forever.
It worked in queue and it quits.
Okay.
So that's the simplest scenario of using channels you can send on channels or you can receive on channels
and make sure that once you declare them and use them and are done with them, that you close them.
Okay.
All right.
Let's move on to a slightly more complex example using channels and then eventually, before too long
will be using channels in the sleeping barber problem.