So before we move on to our next problem or example, there's a couple of things I want to draw to your
attention, things I should have mentioned in the last lecture, but did not.
And the first one should be manifestly self-evident, but just to be safe.
So back here in our simple channels, example, in the main function, if I comment out this go shout
bit here.
So this go routine never get started.
Okay.
I got a warning from Visual Studio Code telling me I'm not using this.
I know that.
I just comment, commented the set.
So if I open my terminal now and try and run the program, everything will look good at the start.
Go run de no problem.
I get my prompt and I try to type something in.
So I type in Trevor and here return.
And what happens next?
If you look at the code, what happens next is it tries to send this to the ping channel.
Whatever I type goes to the ping channel.
But of course, even though I created it up here on line 25, there's nothing listening to it.
So when I press return, I get a fatal error.
All go routines are asleep.
Deadlock.
And that's go's rather helpful way of telling you you're sending something to a channel, but nothing
is ever going to receive it.
There's no good routines out there.
There's no listening to that channel.
Okay, so I can fix that, of course, just by uncomment this line.
So that's easy enough.
Now, the second thing I wanted to draw your attention is when I receive something from a channel like
this where I'm receiving into the variable se whatever is sent to channel ping, I actually have an
optional second parameter I can get from that channel and I'll just call it.
Okay like this.
Okay.
And what that does that.
Doesn't actually say anything right now, but I can check to see if okay is false.
If not, okay.
Because it's a boolean.
Okay.
If not okay then I can do something here and that second return parameter.
It just tells me whether the receive value was sent on the channel.
True.
Or it's a zero value return because the channel is closed and empty.
False.
This is an easy way to make sure that the channel is in fact not closed, and we'll be using that later
on in the course.
Just a couple of lectures actually when we start working on the Sleeping Barbara program.
So that's just to draw it to your attention.
Okay.
Now let's go on to our next challenge and this is using the Select Statement.
So I have a new window open in Visual Studio code and as usual, I'll do get a go modifiable taping,
go mod in it and I'll just call this channel Dash Select because we're going to be looking at the select
statement which we saw briefly a while ago, what we're going to look at in more detail right now.
Okay, so let's create a new empty file mango and put it in package main and create a main func.
Now what I want to do here is show you how the Select Statement works in the Select Statements.
As I said some time ago, they're only useful for channels and there are a lot like the switch statement
or what's called a case statement in other languages, but there are only four channels and you can
only use channels with the select statement.
Okay.
So to start things off, I'm going to create a couple of things that will become the routines.
I'll create a function here and I'll call it server one.
It doesn't matter what I call it, but I'm going to call it server one.
That will take one parameter which is called C-H, and it's a type channel string.
Okay, so that's what it's going to receive.
And then I'll create another one below that phone server to coach and string once again.
Okay.
So it also takes a channel.
Now up in this first one, this server one.
What I'm going to do is create a four loop that runs forever and I'll sleep for 6 seconds.
So the very first time it comes into this this for loop, it's going to pause for 6 seconds.
I'm not sleep and I'll put it six times time the second.
Okay.
And after that, after 6 seconds have gone by, I'll send to the Channel C H, which I received as a
parameter to this particular function.
Just some text.
This is from server one.
Okay, I'll do a similar thing down here in the other function server two.
But this time I'll sleep for 3 seconds inside of my for loop time does sleep a little less three times
time dot second and then again, not surprisingly, I'm going to send to the channel.
This is from server two.
Okay, so we're not doing anything with this function, so let's do something with that.
What I'm going to do down here is I'll printed a little, you know, introductory message, so format
or print line and we'll call this select with channels.
Just so we know, the program is starting out and then I'll do format or print line, underline it.
So I'll make it exactly the same length as the title just to get things started.
Okay.
So we've printed it our, our little welcome message.
Now we'll declare two channels.
So I'll call one channel one and we make a channel again with the main keyword and we're going to make
this a channel type stream, and then I'll duplicate this and I'll create a second channel channel to
same type channel string.
Then I'll start my go routines, go server one and that requires a channel and I'll get server one channel
and I'll duplicate that.
To make this server to make this channel to.
Okay.
So we've started our program, printed a message, created two channels, started to go routines.
And if I run right now, of course, it'll just exit instantly because there's nothing to keep the program
going.
So let's put in some code here that will keep the program going for a loop, will do it.
Now, if I run this right now, I'll get my welcome message and nothing will happen and nothing will
happen forever because I'm not doing anything.
So what I'm going to do in here is use the select statement.
So select.
That's how I define it.
And as I said before, the Select Statement is a lot like a switch statement, but we only use it with
channels, so we have cases.
So in the first case, I'll say S1, which is just a variable I'm declaring that is populated by getting
something from Channel one.
Okay, so that's my first case.
And what am I going to do if I get that?
I'll just say format the print line.
And so I know which case is being executed.
I'll say case one and I'll print it, whatever I get back as well.
Okay.
So there's my first case.
No surprises there.
Let's have a second case.
Okay.
Case as to and this is populated again by listening to a channel.
And in this case, I'll listen to, strangely enough, channel one again, which seems redundant.
But let's put it our format up, print one, print one.
We'll say case two and whatever we get from that channel, which is S one, that's TiVo or two, and
that's the value that we just got in this case statement.
Now let's put in a case three.
Case S three is populated by listening to.
Channel two this time, and not surprisingly, format or print one and will say case three and whatever
s three is, and you can probably guess what's coming next.
Chase s four which is populated by listening to Channel two again and format of print line.
Chase four and S four.
Okay.
Now, what do you think is going to happen when we actually start this?
So if you think about what's happening here, we execute a program, main gets executed, we print out
a little title.
We create two channels.
I start to go routines, one that's listening to Channel one and one that's listening to Channel two.
And these will not exit until the program terminates because there's absolutely no reason for them to
exit.
There's no condition where those will actually stop executing the four loops.
And then I have this endless for loop here where I listen to, you know, channel one, no problem.
But then I listen to Channel one again and I'm printing out different messages.
So I'll know if either of these gets executed.
And then I do the same thing listening to the same channel in two different cases.
Now you might say to yourself, how come he's not closing the channels?
Well, this is a highly contrived example.
There's no situation where we ever get inside of this for loop.
I could put a condition in here that says, after this select statement, after 30 seconds, you jump
out of the loop and then close the channels.
But this is just to demonstrate how the select statement works.
So let's not worry about that right now.
Instead, let's think about what's going to going to happen here.
Now, you would think, because this first check on line 34 one.
It actually matches the situation where we received something on Channel one.
So this one will never get executed.
That's what you might think.
Let's try this.
Let's open the channel and type.
Go run dot and hit return.
So there's a pause and then I get case three and let's throw these up so we can see them.
Well, that makes sense.
Case three.
And then I have a case for now.
Why would Case four ever get executed?
My whole point here, the whole purpose behind this highly contrived example, is to demonstrate that
when this select statement executes it, there are multiple cases that match the same condition.
For example, here we get responses back on.
Case three and case four.
Well, these are functionally identical.
The only difference is that I'm printing a slightly different message out here.
If there's more than one case that the select can match, it just chooses one at random.
And there are lots of situations where that's useful.
So that's the first thing I want to tell you about this selecting.
And this will run endlessly.
So let's stop it.
Control, see and close this and tell you the one other thing I want you to be aware of when it comes
to the Select Statement, it is also possible to have, just as you would in a switch statement, a
default case.
Okay.
And this default case is useful for avoiding deadlock.
If there's a situation where none of these channels are listening, then the default case will stop
your program from crashing.
And this is a great situation where you might want to say, well, there should be a go routine running,
but there's not any.
Print yourself a little message here.
There's lots of situations where the default is helpful.
Okay.
And I'm getting warning for my ITV telling me you shouldn't have an empty default case.
That's true, because the loop will spin forever, but the default case can be extremely useful.
Okay, now in this situation, it's not.
So I simply comment this line out and that will that will get rid of the warning.
But select statements are really useful.
They're very helpful and the relatively simple to use.
I will be using these later on in the course later on in this section actually.
But this is sufficient for our purposes at the moment.
So let's move on and look at buffered channels.