So the last thing I want to look at with respect to channels before we start using them in the sleeping
barber problem is the concept of buffered channels.
And as usual, I've started a new window in Visual Studio code and I opened a folder named Buffered
Dash Channels and I'll as usual, create a go month file, go mod in it buffered channel.
That'll work.
Okay.
And now I'll create my main doggo file.
And this is pretty simple.
Okay, so package me
and I'll create one function called main and above.
That will create a function that will run as a go routine.
So func and this will just be called Listen to Chan and it takes one parameter which is a chan.
And this time I'm making a chain of events, okay?
And inside of that I'll have an endless for loop and I'll say Here, print a got data message.
Any time I get data in this channel, first of all, I'll get the data or as a sign the value of listening
to see H.
Okay, I'll print out a message format dot print line
got try that again.
Got I from channel.
Okay.
And then I'm going to simulate doing a lot of work.
And in that case, I'll say, time, don't sleep.
One time's timed out second.
So we're doing something in this function and we're pretending we're doing something in this function
that will take 1/2 to complete, which is a long time for a program.
Okay.
Then on my main function, the first thing I'll do is create a channel and I'll call this one C-H.
And it's a sign the value of that again, a sign the value of will just make a chain of events like
we did before.
And we'll change this line in a minute.
Then I'll start my go routine, go listen to channel and give that the channel.
And down here I'll send a lot of data to the channel.
For I is a sign the value of zero.
IE is less than or equal to 100 I plus plus and will send data to the channel 100 times.
Okay, so inside that loop, let's say format dot print line, just to print out a message, should
we know what's going on?
And I'll say sending I to channel dot, dot, dot, and then I'll send out a channel.
So C-H gets all right and then I'll say format dot print line because this is going to block until that
go routine finish is what it's supposed to be doing sent I to channel and then once an outside of this
I'll say format of print line done and close the channel as you should.
Closed C-H.
Okay, no surprises here.
This is dead simple.
We create a channel.
We start a go routine that listens for information from that channel.
When it gets it, it prints and message out.
Then it goes to sleep for 1/2 and the for loop continues endlessly.
Okay, so the first time it gets some information, it'll receive that.
Print out the message, go to sleep for a second.
Then it goes back up here and it blocks until it gets something from that channel again.
So it pauses here.
Now we're sending a hundred things.
So this should go pretty fast, you would think, right?
Let's open the terminal window, clear the screen and type.
Go run dark.
And you can see there's a 1/2 pause between sending and things actually being sent.
That's because that go routine is actually blocking in the background.
Okay.
So we can wait until a hundred things are gone, but it seems kind of pointless because you know exactly
what's going to happen.
So I'll stop this and I will make one little change to the program.
So I'll close the terminal window and up here in line 20 where I say make chin int, let's put a comma
there and put it ten.
Okay.
So now we have a buffered channel one with a fixed size and let's run the program again and see what
happens.
Okay, so go run Dot.
Now watch what happens this time.
Ken, things went really, really quickly.
That's because this channel now is buffered.
It's allowed to have more than one thing in it and buffer channels.
Just take one.
And if you're waiting to receive something, everything grinds to a halt.
But in this case, we actually put ten things in the channel, and now it's going 1/2 at a time because
every time it pulls something off the channel here on the line, 11 in my code, we have one free space
in the buffer.
So it takes one more.
So the first ten went really, really quickly.
Now, you might be asking yourself of what possible value is a buffer channel?
And the answer is pretty simple.
They're useful when you know how many go routines you've launched.
In our case, we've launched one.
Or we want to limit the number of go routines we launch, or we want to limit the amount of work that's
queued up.
And in our case, it's the last one.
We're limiting the amount of word that work it that is queued up and everything else just pauses.
It stays in the buffer until there's a resource available to work on it.
Okay.
Now, these are very useful.
The vast majority of times you're probably going to use on buffer channels, but there are lots of situations
where buffer channels just make sense.
All right.
So with this brief introduction to channels, let's move on and start using them.
Because I'm a firm believer in the philosophy that you learn to code by actually writing code.
And in this case, we're going to learn how to use channels by writing code that uses channels.
So let's begin our consideration of the sleeping Barbara problem.