So now that we've looked at channels in a bit more detail, let's get started working with them.
And we'll do so by tackling the classic computer science problem of the sleeping barber.
So I've opened up a new folder in Visual Studio code and I'll initialize a go file by typing go mod
in it and I'll just call my Berber.
Okay, so let's create our main go file.
And typically when I'm working with a project like this, I like to put some comments at the top of
the mango file just to state the problem.
And I've written some out and I've copied to clipboard and I'll place them in here.
And if you want these, just download the source for this project from this lecture and you'll have
the comments.
So let's get started.
So we're in Package Main
and we're going to have obviously some variables.
What I'm going to do right now is just type out a few comments.
Okay?
So we'll have some variables here and we'll have our main function, of course, of Main.
I can put that in there and let's write some comments just to break this problem down into some parts.
So what do I want to do in here?
And that's all I'm going to do.
This lecture is just write some comment and then we'll start tackling them in subsequent lectures.
So if we look at the statement of the problem, there's a textual description of it right here.
But the rules are basically what I have here in these these bullet points.
So we have a barber shop and if there are no customers in the waiting room, the barber falls asleep
in a chair.
So the barber takes a nap.
Well, that's easy enough.
A customer.
If a customer shows up and the barber is asleep.
The customer has to wake the barber up to get a haircut.
Now, if a customer arrives while the barber is working, the customer leaves.
If all the chairs in the waiting room are occupied but sits in an empty chair if one is available.
Okay, that makes sense.
When the barber finishes cutting someone's hair, he or she inspects the waiting room to see if there's
any waiting customers and goes to go to sleep.
If there's nobody there otherwise.
Takes the person.
Cuts their hair.
The barber shop can stop accepting new clients at closing time, but the barbers are not allowed to
leave.
If there's anybody in the waiting room, so they have to cut everyone's hair if they're waiting, even
if the shop is closed and after the shop is closed and there's no clients left in the waiting room,
the barber goes home.
So those are the rules.
Now, this problem, like the ones we've dealt with so far in this course, it was originally proposed
in 1965 by the computer science pioneer Dijkstra.
Okay.
And the point of this problem and it's perfect for our purposes right now.
The point of this problem and it's solution is to make it clear that in many cases you don't have to
use semaphores or as we call them, we go mutex in order to solve the problem.
So let's read some comments to think things out.
So the first thing I'm going to do is there's going to be an element of randomness in this program.
So we're going to want to seed our random number generator.
Okay, that's easy enough.
That's one line of code.
Then we'll want to print a welcome message of some sort.
Again, pretty simple format.
Print line will do the trick.
We'll probably install a color package just to make things a little more attractive.
Then if we need channels, let's create channels
if we need any.
And as you know, we are, in fact, going to need at least one channel probably to.
And then we're going to want to create some data structure that represents the barbershop.
Okay.
So that will describe the kinds of things that that make this barbershop what it is.
How big is the waiting area?
How long does it take to cut hair?
How many barbers do we have?
Any channels we might need?
Things like that.
So we'll have to create some data structure.
Then we're going to want to add barbers.
We'll start with one, but we'll add more than one as time goes on just to see how things work.
Then we're going to want to start the barber shop.
Barber shop.
So that data structure we had up there.
We're going to want to make that run probably in the background, probably as a go routine.
So I'll put it as a go routine.
And that's going to run until the shop closes.
Okay.
So everyone's hair is cut.
There's nobody left in the waiting room.
We've passed the maximum time.
The barbershop can be open, that sort of thing.
And then finally, finally.
But next, we're going to want to add clients.
So we're going to have to have clients show up somehow.
Okay.
And then we're going to block it until the barbershop is closed.
And by block, I just mean keep the application going until things are finished.
Okay.
Now, this is a very high level description of the kinds of things we're going to be doing, but it's
a good starting point.
We might move some things around or or add something or delete something as time goes on.
But this at least breaks this rather complex problem down into manageable bits.
So we're taking a top down approach to this.
Okay.
So in the next lecture, we'll get started writing some code and replacing some of these comments or
adding code after these comments just to get things going.
And it's going to take a while.
This problem is considerably more sophisticated than the ones we've looked at so far, but it's an excellent
introduction to the actual use of channels.
All right.
Let's move on.