So let's get started populating these comments with some actual code and we'll just get started this
time around.
It's going to take a while to finish this, but right away here on line 25 and my code, I'm going to
need some variables, some package level variables.
Well, we know we have a waiting room, so let's declare a variable, which I'll call our seating capacity.
How many seats in the waiting room that's going to be equal to ten?
Ten is a good start.
Okay.
And then we're going to have customers arriving.
And it says up here in my comment at the top, clients arriving at roughly regular intervals.
So let's just define something here.
I'll say var arrival rate, arrival rate, and I'll make that equal to say 100.
And that will be milliseconds because I don't want to wait forever to watch this program execute.
We also have to determine how long it takes to cut someone's hair.
So var will call this cut duration and that's going to be equal to 1000 times timed millisecond.
Okay, I'm using a thousand milliseconds because I might speed this up as we're working on it or slow
it down and it's easier to work with milliseconds than hold numbers.
4 seconds.
Okay.
And finally, how how long is the barbershop open?
Well, we'll make it time open.
We'll just make that equal to, say, 10 seconds, ten times time dot second.
Okay, so there are some variables and we might need some more, but this is a good starting point.
All right.
Next seed, our random number generator.
And we're going to use that random number generator in conjunction with the arrival rate so that clients
don't always arrive at exactly the same interval.
So we can see that we know how to do that random seed and we're going to seed it using time dot now
dot Unix nano right there okay so that seeds our random number generator so far this is pretty easy.
Now we're going to print out some some messages, a welcome message here.
I'm going to use color.
So I'm going to do the same thing I did a while ago.
Open my terminal window and I will go and get from GitHub dot com slash f8 are h slash color cross-platform
compatible so it should work on Linux, Windows and Mac.
So now I send my go mine file, which means I can come back to my code and after this print welcome
message I'll just say color yellow will printed it in yellow.
I will print out some text the sleeping server problem and then I'll duplicate that line and change
these to hyphens just to make things a little more attractive.
Okay.
So we've defined some variables.
We've seeded a random number generator and now we've printed out a title.
Now create channels, if any.
Well, I know I'm going to be using channels in this, but let's think about the kinds of channels we
might have.
We're probably going to have a channel that we send clients to.
Okay, so let's create a channel called Client Channel, and that will be assigned the value of make.
A channel that's a string, it accepts strings.
And I'm going to make this one a buffered channel.
And I'm only only going to allow the client channel to be the same size as seating capacity.
That way I can have more than one client in the channel, but I can't have more than whatever seating
capacity is set to.
And right now that's ten.
So maximum ten people in this channel.
Okay, so that's one channel I'm going to have to have for sure.
And I'm also going to have to have one that says everything's done and we can go home.
So I'll call this done channel.
Okay.
And we'll make that a channel of type bool.
So when everything's done, will send a boolean to that channel, and the next one is to create the
barbershop.
Well.
To do that, I'm going to need a type.
And what I'm going to do, because this problem was a little more sophisticated than the last ones.
So I'm going to create a new go file called Barbershop.
And I'll put Barbershop related things over here.
So in this one package main
all define a type, which I'll call barbershop that seems appropriate barbershop.
And it's just a struct and it has a few fields.
So the first thing we need to know is what's the shock capacity?
How many seats in the waiting room shop capacity?
And of course, that's an integer.
We're also going to need to know how long it takes to cut hair.
I'll call this one hair cut duration.
Okay.
And that will be of timed duration.
And we're also going to need to know how many barbers do we have?
Number of barbers.
And as I said, we're going to start with one, but it's going to be an integer.
And we're also going to have our channels.
So we're going to have to have a chan, which is barbers done.
Chan That's what I'll call it.
Barbers done.
CHAN And that will be a chan of type ball.
Okay.
And we're also going to want the clients.
CHAN Clients.
CHAN which is a chan of type string.
All I'm going to do is pass a clients and name to that.
That's all.
I really, really do know that there is a client and that client has some unique identifier, a name
of some sort.
And finally, we'll have one here that says Open, and this is just a boolean.
Okay.
So when the shop is open.
That's true.
When the shop is closed, that's false.
So let's save this just to format it.
Now we have our barber shop type.
So let's go back over to Mango and let's define a shop.
So I'll create a variable.
I'll just call it shop.
And that's a sign, the value of the type barbershop.
We'll just populate its fields.
So shop capacity.
Well, we know that one.
That's seating capacity.
The variable that I just defined up there in line 33.
So we have that one.
We're also going to want haircut, duration, and that will be cut duration.
Another variable that I just defined, and we're also going to need the number of barbers.
And initially, I'll set that to zero.
We'll add them down at the comment here that says Add barbers.
Okay.
And we want our clients.
Chan When we have that, we just find it in called a client.
Chan.
And then we want our barbers done.
CHAN And we just to find that that's called done chan.
Done, Chen.
That's better.
And finally, is the shop open?
Well, I'll set that true.
Just hard code that because the shop will be open when this program starts.
Okay.
Now, I'll just print out another message here.
I'll say colored out green.
This time the shop is open for the day.
Okay, so that's been printed out.
Now, the next thing I want to do is to add barbers.
Now, what I think this problem through, I'm going to have one thing called the shop that's running
in the background, somehow doing its thing.
Whatever it's going to do, I don't know.
And then I'm going to have at least one barber.
But as time goes on, I'm going to add two or three or ten barbers to this.
So maybe I'll have each barber running as its own go routine.
Okay, now, how am I going to do that?
Well, it's actually not that hard.
What I'm going to do and we'll do this in the next lecture, I don't want to make these too long.
It's not a fine.
A method on the type.
Barber shop called something like and barber.
And I'll just add barbers to the shop to that variable we created right there in line 52.
So I'll create a function called Ed Barber with the receiver of Type Shop, and that gives us a function
where we can add as many barbers as we want.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.
Actually before we go, I see that we have an error here.
For some reason my id imported both github dot com fatty color and something else.
So let's just get rid of this one.
That's from go get which we're not using in this lecture.
Okay, so that problem goes away.
All right, let's move on.