So this time around, what I want to do is to add one barber to our program and we'll add more later
on.
But right now, let's just get it working with one.
And as I said last time, what I'm going to do is take this type barbershop over here and barbershop
doggo.
I'll add a method to it called Save and Berber.
Okay.
But before I do that, I mean, I'm going to add the Berber.
The Berber will run as its go routine, as its own go routine.
So if I add one Berber, I'll have one go routine for the Berber.
If I had five, I'll have five go routines for the Berber.
And of course, what does that Berber need to have access to?
Well, obviously everything in the shop, but most importantly, a barbers job is to cut hair.
That barber has to be able to look for clients.
So we'll be using this client's chin field in the barber shop, type one that holds client chin that
we created up here on line 47.
Now, let's figure out what other things a barber has to do.
So that's why I put these comments here.
So the barber falls asleep.
That's one thing the barber has to do.
The barber has to be woken up by a client, but that's the client's job.
So we'll ignore that for right now.
The barber cuts hair checks, the waiting room goes to sleep and ultimately goes home.
That's all that the barber does.
Okay, so let's go back down over here to barber shop.
Don't go.
And underneath this type.
Barber shop will create a new function with the receiver.
And I'll call it sharp.
And it's a pointer to the tape barber shop.
And I'll call this ad barber.
And what is that going to take for parameters?
Well, the only thing I really want is a string to describe this barber's name.
So it's called barber type string.
Every barber will have his or her own name, and this doesn't return anything because it's a go routine.
So the first thing I'll do every time I add a barber, I'm going to increment this value here.
Number of barbers in the tight barber shop by one and that's easy.
I have access to that in the receiver shop dot number of barber's plus plus.
Okay.
So I've now added one barber to this every time.
One barber to the shop every time I call this function.
And then I need to run a go routine.
Well, I can do that this way.
Go func and declare a an inline function that runs in the background because of that go keyword.
Okay.
And it's not going to take any particular values so I can leave these parentheses empty.
But what do I want to do in here?
Well, the very first thing I'm going to do inside of this go -- is to set a variable is sleeping
is a sign the value of false.
Initially the barbour's awake.
He or she arrives at work.
Presumably they're awake when they arrive at work.
That's always a good thing.
And then they have to go and check for clients.
So we'll say color yellow and then my format string is percent s, which is the barber's name.
Goes to the waiting room to check for clients.
My substitution is just a barber's name.
Okay.
And then we check to see, is there anyone in the waiting room?
And that's what we're going to do endlessly until the day is over.
So just have a for loop.
And the first thing we'll do in this for loop, if there are no clients, the barber goes to sleep and
this is just textual feedback.
So we'll check to see if there's anybody in the client's chair and we do that using the built in operator.
Len if the length of from the receiver shop dot clients charm if that's equal to zero and there's nobody
in the channel and remember this is a buffer channel the same size as the number of seats in the waiting
room.
And if there's nothing in that channel, that means that the waiting room is empty and any existing
clients might be getting their haircut or that might be already finished and the shop is just empty.
There's nobody else that needs a haircut.
So what do we do if there's nobody in the waiting room?
The barber goes to sleep, color yellow and my format string is there is nothing to do.
So percent s takes them out.
Am I substitution for that?
Percent S is just barber the current barber's name and of course we want to set now is sleeping is equal
to true this barber is now sleep.
And once we get past this, we actually keep listening to that channel, to the channel, chopped up
clients channel.
So we get a client from the channel.
In other words, we get a client from the waiting room.
Somebody has arrived.
So the line is easy.
It's client is a sign the value of whatever comes in from sharp declension clients channel.
Now there's one other thing we need to do here, and we need to make sure that the shop is still open
because the rules say back in the mango file, they say that once the shop is closed, we don't accept
any new clients.
So you might think at this point that I could use this field open on the type barbershop.
I could use that because that's a boolean.
That's true.
When the shop is open and that's false when the shop is closed.
I could do that right now with one barber, but the minute I have more than one barber, we have a potential
race situation a to race because we might have one more than one go routine time trying to read that
open field on the tape barber shop or trying to write to it.
So instead, here's a situation where we can take advantage of that second parameter you can get from
reading a channel, and I'll call this shop open.
And this is not the same data that's stored here in the field open on the type barbershop.
This is a value that's either true or false.
And remember that second return parameter we get when reading a channel.
It indicates whether the value received from that channel was actually sent to the channel.
In other words, it's a client that's true, or it's false, which means the channel is closed and empty.
So that's what we're going to use.
So now I potentially have a client and I have a Boolean, true or false, that tells me whether or not
the shop is open so we decide what to do.
If shop open.
If the shop is still open, then we actually got a real client from the channel.
And what do we do next?
Well, let's go back and look at the main logo and it says over here at the top, if a customer arrives
while the barber is working, the customer leaves.
If all chairs are occupied.
I don't care about that.
And we have it here.
A customer must wait the barber up if he is asleep.
Let's go back to the barber shop to go and handle that situation.
That's pretty easy.
If he's sleeping, if the barber is sleeping, we'll just print a message out.
Color dot yellow.
Percent s weeks.
Percent s up again.
Percent s up.
Period.
And my substitutions are clients, which is just a string.
The name of the client and barber, which is the name of the barber.
And then we set these sleeping equal to false because the barbers.
Now, wait.
And the next thing we have to do if the shop is open right here is cut hair.
We're going to cut the client's hair.
Now, I could put all that logic right in here, but I like to keep things as clean as possible.
So let's declare another function with the receiver of Shop Shawl pointed to barber shop and we'll call
this cut hair.
And this will take the barber's name.
Barber and the client's name?
Plant, both of which are strings.
It doesn't return anything.
So we'll leave that one alone for a minute.
But we'll call it here.
So we'll say sharp cut hair.
And we want barber and barber.
Barber and clerk.
Okay.
So that will cut the person's hair.
But the other condition on this, if shop open logic isn't else and it's simply shop is closed.
So send the barber home
and closed this go routine because we're done with it.
Okay, so we'll need another function.
I could again do it right here, but I'll shred another function down here.
Say Funk Shop pointed to Barber Shop and we'll call this one Send Barber Home.
Okay.
And it'll take the barber's name.
So we can print that information to this screen, which is a string.
And yeah, we'll populate this one in a little bit, but for right now, we can call it up here, we'll
say.
Shop.
Don't send Barbara home with the barber's name, and we need to exit this go routine.
And we know how to do that.
We need to get outside of this for a loop outside of this go funk.
What we do here is you say return and we're done.
And that clothes that go routine will actually close.
Now, while we're at it, since it's really simple to do this, let's fill out these two functions.
The first one is cut here and we have the receiver shop and we have the barber's name.
So we have everything we need to know.
All we're going to say is color dot green or whatever color you want.
And my format string is percent s is cutting percent s apostrophe s's hair period.
And my substitutions are barber and client.
And then we wait for the time necessary to cut that person's hair.
And that's just time out sleep when we have the time, the duration right in the shop receiver it's
shop dot haircut duration.
Okay and then we'll print out color dot green percent as is finished cutting percent se is hair and
my substitutions again are barber and client.
That's easy.
And then down here, send barber home.
That's pretty simple as well.
Color dot not put it cyan this time just to make it stand out.
Percent se is going home and it's just a barber sitting and then we're not quite finished because we
need to do one more thing.
If this barber is done for the day, that means the go routine associated with that barber is either
gone or just about to disappear.
So that person can't take any more clients that's no longer available.
So we need to send a boolean to that shop.
Dot Barbers Dunkin so shop got barbers done.
That channel receives crew to send a boolean to it.
Now we know that Barber has gone home.
Okay, we've sent a value there.
All right.
That's quite a bit of code for this time around.
But we now have everything we need to add a Berber.
So let's go back to Mongo and let's add a Berber.
So down here, after we've printed the shop is open for the day, we're going to end burgers.
So all we need to do now is to say.
Shop and Berber.
And we choose a name.
So, Frank, we add Frank to the.
To the shop.
Okay.
Now we have all this other stuff to do.
But right now, as I come down here and say, time to sleep, just to make it pause for a while, say
five times timed out second.
Okay.
And I run the program.
What do you think you're going to get as feedback, if anything?
Now just pause the video for a moment, review the code we've written so far.
And in a couple of seconds I'll run it and let's see if what you think comes out is actually what we
get.
Or we might have made mistakes, but we'll find out in a minute.
So go run Dot.
And I'm going to give you a couple of seconds to pause this and think about it.
That should be long enough.
Let's run it and see what happens.
And I think that's exactly what should have happened.
So there's no question he's going to print out the title.
There was no surprise there at all because if you look up here, all we do is random, see?
Then we print the title.
So that's going to happen no matter what.
But it also created these channels.
It also created the shop.
It also printed out this message again.
And then it added the barber.
Frank and Frank did exactly what he was supposed to.
Frank went to the waiting room to check for clients.
There's nothing to do.
So Frank takes a nap.
Okay.
Easy start to his work day.
That clearly there's some more things we have to do.
So right here, the next one would be start the barber shop as a go routine.
And then we're going to send clients to the barber shop so we can start on this part, starting the
barber shop as a go routine in the next lecture.