So we're getting pretty close right now.
We have successfully seeded a random number generator.
We haven't used it yet, but we will very shortly.
We've printed out a welcome message.
We've created two channels that deal with the barbers, one for clients that the barber is waiting for,
and one when a barber is done for the day.
We created a type for barber shop and populated its various fields.
We've printed out this message and we can add barbers, and the barbers successfully go and check to
see if there's a client in the waiting room.
And if there's not, we know at least that they take a nap.
Now, we need to do this part.
Start the barber shop as a go routine.
And this is good.
Simple.
So what we're going to do, of course, you start a go routine, we'll just start start a routine with
a go funk like this.
And of course, we have to determine what are we going to do in this barber shop go routine?
And really, what we need to do is we need to make sure that the go routine stays open, at least this
amount up here on line 36 time open, which in our case right now is 10 seconds.
Well, that's easy.
We can do it like this.
And it's really simple for this part.
We simply do this time after and we look for time open.
So what we're doing is waiting for that to happen.
But we also, at this point, once the 10 seconds go by, we need to close the shop and we need at least
two channels to make that happen.
Okay.
So we're going to do fine tuning channels here.
We'll make a channel called Shop Closing, because remember, it's possible for people to show up before
the shop closes.
Find an available seat in the waiting room and wait in the rules.
Say that the barber can't go as long as there's somebody still in the waiting room.
So we need this channel and we'll make that equal to.
I don't need parentheses here.
I need an assignment.
Operator will make a channel of time book and then we'll have another one closed.
And that's a sign the value of again make channel book.
And what we'll do here is will block for the the length of time that this is supposed to be open.
And then we'll send to the shop closing channel we'll send true and then finally we can say closed is
assigned or is pushed the value of true as well.
Now, in between those two, there's one more thing I want to do.
I want to take care of closing the shop for the day.
So what I will do is call a function that doesn't exist yet on the shop type.
That shop variable we defined right up on line 51 a call a function called close shop for day.
And it doesn't take any parameters.
Now, let's go write that over in Barber Shop Echo.
At the very bottom of the file, we'll create a function with the receiver of sharp pointer to Barbershop
and we'll call this close shop for day.
It doesn't take any parameters at all.
That's going to do is prints and messages out and things like that.
So we'll say color dot cyan just to make it stand out.
Closing shop for the day we print that message.
Okay.
And after that, we close the clients channel shopped up clients chain.
So we can't accept any more clients because that is now closed.
Okay.
And here is where we set shop dot open equal to false.
So that field open on the type barbershop stored in the variable shop.
We're setting that defaults now.
And now the next thing we have to do is we have to wait until all the barbers are done.
And that's pretty easy, actually.
Okay.
Because when a Berber is done for the day, if you'll recall right here, we're sending the Sharpe Dot
Berbers done scanned the value of true.
So all we have to do, say four and I'll call this one a it's a sign the value of one.
It's a simple for loop.
We're going to go through this.
A is less than or equal to.
Shop.
Number of barbers.
We know how many barbers we have and we increment one every time through the loop a plus plus.
And inside of this, we just call.
We wait for shop dot barbers dungeon to get something.
So that will block until every one of the barbers has sent the dumb value.
The value of true to the barbers done channel field of the type barber shop steward in the variable
shop.
Okay, so this will block until every single barber is done.
And once every single barber is done, what do we do?
We close.
The barber is done.
Chain, close, shop.
Got barbers done, champ.
We don't want to leave that open.
And now we can print out a message color dot green.
And I'll just say the barber shop is now closed for the day and everyone has gone home.
Then I'll duplicate that and I'll change this all to hyphens just so it's easy to see in the output.
Okay.
Just cosmetic.
Absolutely not important for concurrency.
There.
Okay.
So at this point, if we go back to Main, don't go.
Let's run it again.
Go!
Run, Dot.
I should wait for 5 seconds.
And everything looks exactly the same as it did before.
Now, that seems a little odd, doesn't it?
Because if you look at this go funk here on the line 69, we have this line time after time open.
Why did that not wait for 10 seconds?
Well, it's because we haven't actually sent any clients to this yet.
Okay.
We actually need to start sending some clients and then here block until the barber shop is closed.
So in the next lecture, we'll start adding clients.