So we're getting much closer to having this problem solved.
The next step, of course, is to add clients.
But I thought I'd just go over this little bit of code here.
Inside what line?
73.
73 in my case.
Okay.
You might have been asking yourself, what exactly does this time after time open do?
And all that does is block until.
Time open passes, so time after, which is 10 seconds, in our case, a duration set in our variable
right up here.
Time open is 10/2, but I still need to keep this time sleep because, well, when the main program
exits, when the main function exits any existing go routines, they just die.
So we actually do need to add clients before we can see anything.
And fortunately, adding clients is pretty easy.
Now our clients can just takes a string.
If you recall this, right here are clients chan in the tight barber shop.
It takes client chan, which is a channel of strings and all we're sending that is the name of the client
and we're going to name our clients with the singularly unimpressive names of client one, client two,
client three.
So I'll just create a variable clients assigned the value of one.
Okay?
And now we need to start adding clients and we're going to do this as a go routine as well.
So go func which I have to spell.
Right.
Go func doesn't take any parameters and I need my closing parentheses so it actually is an inline function.
This will be fired off as its own go routine and we'll have a for loop with no exit clause specified
in the for statement self.
And now we're finally going to use that random number.
Remember, we seeded a random number generator right at the beginning of the main function.
We're finally going to do it and all we're going to do is to get a random number with average arrival
rate just to make things a little more realistic.
So I'll declare a variable random milliseconds and that's a sign the value of from the ran package using
the INT function and then we'll use the modulus operator and go to times arrival rate.
And that just gives us a slightly staggered arrival rate.
Nothing important there.
And now inside this go routine is a select statement which we haven't seen for a while, but here we
are select.
So our first case will be we received something from shop closing and of course the only place we can
get that is right here on line 71.
In my code after time open passes we send the value of true to shop closing and here we're waiting for
it.
Okay, so that's our first case.
And what do we do when that happens?
We just return.
We're all done for the day.
Okay.
And our second case is time after and it's going to be timed out millisecond, not microsecond millisecond.
Time's time, duration, and now we use random milliseconds.
Okay, so this is the point when a client arrives and they're arriving at slightly random intervals.
Okay.
And the shop is still open because we haven't matched the shop closing case just above this.
So now we need to add a client.
Now, how do I do that?
Well, I'm going to, as usual, go back over to Barbershop.
Go.
Go to the very bottom.
And I'll add a function with the receiver of shop owner to barber shop.
And I'll call this one and client.
And it will take one parameter, and that will be a string.
The client's name.
So I'll call that client of type store and it doesn't return anything.
So let's print out a message just so we know what's going on.
And I'll say color dog green.
And it will be star star star so I can see it.
Percent s arrives and my substitution is client.
So client whatever has arrived.
So we print that out.
Then we need to decide.
This client is arrived.
But the shop might be closed so we can say it shopped our open.
If that's true, then we can handle the situation where we need to send this client to a barber.
Otherwise, it's closed.
So these this one, these people are still getting haircuts, but the shop is closed.
That's this situation.
So we'll just point out print out color dot red.
So it's very visible.
The shop is already closed.
So percent s leaves and the substitution against client.
Okay, that's an easy case.
We don't need to do anything else there.
But in this case, of course, we need to send the client to the client channel, which has a fixed
size of shop dot shop capacity.
In our case, right now, it's ten.
So the way to handle this, of course, is with a select statement.
So we'll say select.
In our first case, the shop is open and there's room in the client's channel.
So case shopped dot clients Chin receives client and we'll just print out color dot blue just to make
it different.
SE takes a seat in the waiting room.
And the substitution is client.
Okay, so we print that out.
The other situation, the only other possible situation at this point, I want to make that so yellow.
Blue on dark screen is hard to see.
Okay.
The only other possible situation is we couldn't send to shop DHCP clients chain because the the buffer
channel is full.
So the default case handles the other case default.
And in this case we'll just print out color.
Don't read.
The waiting room is full, so percent se leaves.
And the substitution is quite.
And as far as I can tell right now, this is all I need to do to add a client.
So let's go back to Mango.
And in this case, we'll say shopped Ed Klein right there.
And we'll put the client's name and I'll just choose format s, print F and give it a format string
of client number percent D for integer I put in there.
Okay.
And I guess I need to import the format package.
I guess I'm not using it for t dot s print f that should do the import for me.
And it did.
And of course once I've added the client increment R by one.
Okay.
And I don't think I need to do anything else after this.
I mean, at this point, I can remove time to sleep down here and all I have to do is block until I
receive something from the closed channel.
And the only place that closed channel get sent anything is from the go routine that starts the Bob
Barbershop right here on line 74.
So if we did everything right, we should be able to run this and see some kind of meaningful output
that matches the rules that are specified for the sleeping barber problem.
So give this a try in the next lecture.