So in this section of the course, we're focusing upon adding and activating users and displaying the
list of available subscriptions to our users.
Now, although this course is entitled Working with concurrency and go, there's not going to be a lot
of concurrency in this section, but we need to get this out of the way.
So we get to the point where we can actually write some code where concurrency is appropriate.
So what are we going to do?
To start with, we're going to worry about adding users to the system and validating user accounts.
And the way we'll do that is when a user registers, we'll send them an email with a link in it that
they have to click on in order to activate their account.
And of course, for security purposes, that URL, the one that's included in the email, it needs to
be signed so that it can't be tampered with.
And we'll take care of that.
And it's really straightforward.
And the last thing we'll do in this section is just modify your application so that there's a page that
displays all of the available subscriptions, things that users can buy.
So let's get started.