So what we want to get started with this time around is registering the user.
So someone comes to this site, they click on the register button, they enter their email, choose
a password and give us their name.
And when they click register, what we want to have happen next is we get that information.
We generate a URL with a link in it that says Activate your account.
So we add the user after they fill out this form, but we leave that user inactive and then we send
them an email, they click on a link and that user becomes active.
So let's get started.
So back over in our I.D., we're going to be sending an email.
So let's just create an email template.
So in the templates folder inside cmd slash web, let's create a new file and I'll call the first one.
Confirmation dash, email, dot, HTML, dot and go HTML and then I'll create another one named confirmation
calling for nation dash email dot plain dot go each came out and just to speed things along, I'll copy
the existing male dot html go each HTML, copy that and I'll paste it in the appropriate new file.
The HTML version, I'll just change it.
So in here I'll put a paragraph at the beginning that says Thank you for registering.
Click the link below
to activate your account and close my paragraph tag and then I'll change this to the link.
A trip equals and then whatever data is passed to this template and then I'll just put activate your
account
and close the attack.
Okay, so that's that version.
And now the plain text version.
Same thing.
I shall just copy the text, copy this and modify it as necessary.
Remove the HTML tags.
So in here we'll put in a defined body and then paste in that stuff and then and we'll just remove the
tags here.
Okay.
Because this is plain text and HTML will not work.
So there and remove this and this.
Okay.
So now we have some email templates.
Now when we send this email, the link is going to be something like FTP, Collins, slash, slash,
whatever the site is, slash, activate and then question mark.
Email equals whatever the email is, we're going to pass the email as part of the URL.
But of course, that's a security loophole.
It means that anyone can just start guessing emails.
Not that they would, but you never know.
There are lots of people out there who want to cause you grief.
They can just start firing random emails and they're trying to activate as many as they want to.
So what we need to do is we need to make the URL tamper proof.
Now, if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file called.
Signer dot go, dot zip.
Download that and extract it and then copy the contents into the cmd slash web folder.
And I have the contents of that currently on my clipboard.
So I'll create a new file called Signer.
Don Go and I'll just paste them in there.
Now, this is something I've used in in many of my courses.
It uses a package called GitHub dot com slash, BW Marin slash and go dash along, which I have to go
get.
So I'll copy this and open my terminal.
Clear the screen and type.
Go get and then paste that in.
This is a very simple package, although it allows you to do is to generate signed text of any sort.
So we're going to sign our URL that we put in the email that we send off with a link to activate the
account.
Okay.
Now, this is very simple.
The thing to pay attention to here is that I have a constant a secret right here, and I just chose
ABC one, two, three, three times.
And of course you'll have a much longer and more secure secret in your code, and you're probably not
going to store it in your code.
You'll read it from an environment variable or something like that.
Well, this has a couple of simple methods, actually.
Three.
One that will generate a token from a string.
So if I pass this a, u, r, l, for example, it will hand back a euro with a hash appended to the
end.
Verify allows me to pass some signed text, a signed link in our case, and verify that it actually
matches the signature that we would generate from our code.
And the last one is to check to see if something has expired so you can have links that expire after
60 Minutes or whatever you want.
So we have this available to us now.
And what we'll do in the next lecture is we'll go back to our handlers file right here.
And we'll start on this function post register page.
And it's very straightforward.
So let's move on.