So this time around we want to get started on this function post register page and of course this is
a handler and it's called When someone fills out that registration form and hits the register button.
So we have some comments in here and these will change or get moved around.
This was just to get us started, but we know we're handling a forum post and of course in go, any
time you get a forum post, the first thing you want to do is to pass form data.
So from our the request variable, that's a parameter to this function we just call personal.
Okay?
And we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then what are we going to do here?
We'll just print it out.
Dot error log dot print line error.
Rarely does that error ever take place.
Okay.
So the next step would actually be and I'm not going to do it in this course because this is not a course.
I'm building web applications, but I'll put it to do comment in here, validate data.
So we want to make sure that this user is not already registered.
We want to make sure that they filled out all the necessary stuff and we handled some of that with client
side JavaScript validation.
But typically you're going to validate the data and I'm going to skip that in this course.
So the next thing I want to do is to create a user.
I know how to do that, and that's easy.
At this point.
I'll create a variable view and it's a type data point user and I'll just fill in all the fields that
I know about.
So I know about email and that comes from our dot form dot get.
We have access to that because we pass the form data and we're going to get email because that's what
it's called in the form.
Okay.
And we also have the first name, first name our top form get and in the form that's called first hyphen
name.
Okay.
And then I'll duplicate that and make this last name.
I make this last dash name, I'll duplicate it again and change this to password and change this to
password because that's what it's called in the form.
Okay.
And then even though I don't need to do this, I'm going to make sure that this is readable by specifying
active to be zero.
I'm creating a user who is inactive and I'm also going to set is admin two zero even though those are
the defaults both active and these admin would default to zero.
This just makes it clear that I'm creating a user who is not an admin and who is not active.
Now I insert this user into the database and that's just a simple method.
Now I'll ignore the returned ID and check for an error when I call from you the variable I just created
insert you.
Okay.
So I'm asserting that user and I'll check for an error.
So we'll say if error is not equal to nil this time around, I'll say after session don't put with are
not context and the key of error.
So it'll show up as a message on the page.
I'm able to create a user and then of course you put whatever else you want in there.
Okay, then I'll redirect the user issue.
Repeat on redirect with W and ah, they take them back to the register page which seems to make sense
with status C other.
Okay.
And then return.
We can't go any further now if we get past that at this point we want to send an activation email and
that's why we made those email templates and installed that sign or dog go code last time around.
So the first thing I'll do is create a URL, you URL just a string variable and it will be equal to
format print s.
And my format string is and I'm going to hard code the URL.
Normally, of course you'd read that from an environment variable or a dot on file or something like
that.
But we'll just hardcoded HDP Collins slash slash local host.
And if you're going on a different port, make sure you add the port there.
Local host and I'm going to take them to the URL activate.
That doesn't exist yet, but it will before too long.
And I'm going to give it a query parameter email equals percent s and my substitution for that is UDOT
email users email.
Okay.
So that's my euro and apparently it didn't import format for me.
So let's go put that in there.
Thank you.
Okay.
Go back down to find our handler again.
That's better.
So now I have this URL, but of course, that's not what I'm going to use for a link.
I'm actually going to use a signed that singed signed URL and I'll make that that we assign the value
of generate token from string and I'll have that URL.
Okay.
So this calls that function over here and sign or don't go and it actually appends something to it,
a hash.
And we can look at that hash and determine whether or not we actually generated this.
Okay.
So this prevents URL tampering and just to make it readable, let's put it in here.
Laptop info, log dot, print line deadline and I'll print out the signed URL so we can see it in the
console.
And of course now we actually just create an email message.
So MSG is assigned the value of the type message and I'll fill in the necessary fields.
And all I really care about here is two and that will be your email.
That's who the e mails going to the subject.
I'll just make that activate your account.
The template, we specify a custom template and that's confirmation email, the one we made in the last
lecture of the lecture before that.
And the data were passed into this template.
And in this case, I want to make sure that the what I'm passing actually renders properly.
And if you recall the type four message, the field data in the type message, that's any I can put
anything I want in there.
And I know this is going to be HTML in at least one case, so I'll make that template template HTML,
I'll just cast my assigned URL to template dot HTML and I know that will work properly in the go template.
And now I send the email and that's going to take place in the background.
So app dot, send mail, send email in messaging and I redirect the user.
So I'll put in a success message app dot session, dot put with not pop put with our dot context.
And it be a flash message and I'll just say confirmation email sent.
Check your email for whatever you want to say there.
Okay.
And now we do a redirect, HTP redirect and with W and our I will take them to the login page and I'll
just say issue to status of it.
Okay.
Now, this this comment here where I misspelled subscribe.
That's not going to happen here.
That's obviously I don't want to bother subscribing them to an account or a particular subscription
package in the registration.
So I'll stick it down here for now.
It's probably going to get moved out of there as well, but this is enough to get us started.
So at this point, I should be able to restart my application, make restart my Docker images are running.
I hope we're about to find out.
Yep.
There.
So let's go back and try this out.
Let's go back to our web browser and I'll reload this page and I'll register as me here dot com with
a password.
Test.
And me.
And here.
And when I click register.
What should happen, of course, is I should get the success message and I should get an email sent
to my mail hog.
Let's find out if it works.
So we've got the confirmation email message.
And if we go over and look at our console in Visual Studio code, there is the signed URL.
So there's the part I specified from CDP right up to me at here dot com.
And this was appended by my signer package.
Now what's to see if we get that email?
Okay.
So in May, a hug.
I'll refresh everything.
And there it is.
Activate your account.
Now I can click on this link if I want to, but there's actually no route or handler set up to handle
that.
So in the next lecture, we'll take care of the route in the handler for activating an account.
All right, let's move on.