All right.
So we've managed to register a user and make them inactive and send that activation email.
And of course, now we want to write the handler and set up a route that allows them to click on the
link in their email and validate their account and set them to active.
And of course, the handler is the stub handler activate account in the file handler scope.
So the first thing we're going to do and remember this is going to come in as a get request.
It's not a form post, they're just clicking a link.
And the first thing I want to do is to validate the URL.
Okay, so I validate the URL by first of all, getting this part of the request or I'll call it URL.
URL is assigned the value of from the request.
Get the request you are okay.
And then I want to build a test string, something I can use to actually validate the url.
So I'll say test url.
It's a sign the value of from the format package s print f and I'll give it a s print f and I'll give
it a format string.
So again, I'm hardcoded in the URL, but normally you'd get that from the environment or a dot on file
or something like that.
So I'll put an HDP code slash slash local host like that and then a percent s with nothing between local
host and the percent s and I'll substitute URL what I just grabbed from the request that gives me the
test url.
Okay.
And I'll declare a variable.
And that is assigned a value when I call verify token and I hand that test the URL.
So that will be the URL with the hash appended to it.
Okay.
So that's what we're passing to verify token.
And if I get OC back as true, this is a valid token, but if I get not OC other words OC is false,
then we have an invalid URL signature, so we'll just throw an error at them.
So we'll set in the session after session, dot put and I'll put using icon text and I'll put an error
and I'll just put invalid token which is sufficient for our purposes.
You can put whatever you want in there naturally and do a redirect, exploit redirect using W and R
and we'll take them say just to the homepage, try that again, just to the home page with an error
dot status, the other or whatever status you want to use.
Then we return.
No point in going any further.
Okay.
So now I'm going to ignore these comments because they're probably going to go somewhere else.
My next step is to activate the account.
And how do I do that?
Well, I get the user from the database.
I set active to one and I save the user.
I know how to get the user because I have their email address.
So I'll say you an error come from and I'm going to call app dot models dot user doesn't get my email
and I can get the email right from the query parameters are the URL query that again
not get and I'm looking for email.
Okay and I'll check for an error.
So I'll copy this.
This right here.
And do would check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And I'll just paste that in and change this.
No user found
otherwise activate the account account you don't active user I just got from the database that's equal
to one and I update the user and that's easy and is equal to.
You don't update.
And all the information stored in the receiver for that method.
So all I have to do now is check for an error.
So I'll copy this and paste this here and say.
Unable to update user.
But if I get past that, I'm just going to redirect.
So I'll copy these two lines to save some typing.
Put it in here and get this back where it belongs.
And I'll make this a flash message.
And I'll change this to.
Account activated,
you can now log in and will take them to the log in page.
Okay.
Now, I'm going to leave these comments from here here for right now, but will be moving them to handlers,
to the appropriate handlers when we make those handlers in a bit.
And the last step is to go over to roots and set up the appropriate route.
So we'll open route, stock up.
And we'll change this just to activate.
Okay.
And that goes to activate account because that's what's in the email and that's the easiest step.
So now I should be able to make restart.
Go back to my web browser.
I still have this account activation email open.
I'll just click on activate your account and see what happens.
The account is activated you can now log in and I think I used me and here dot com with password test.
Let's see if that works.
Everything worked according to plan.
Perfect.
So the next step is to create another menu item or a button here or something that allows and authenticated
user to subscribe to an account.
And of course, that'll require a couple of more handlers and it'll allow us to write some concurrent
code as well over here.
So these comments that show up back in handlers not go, these are going to get moved into the appropriate
handlers and we'll write all of these or as much of that as we can concurrently.
Okay, so let's move on.