So now that we can actually register user, activate that user and that sort of thing, the next step
is to allow that user to select one of the three plans that we're offering in our fictitious website,
our fictitious company, the Bronze, Silver or Gold Plan.
But if you recall some time ago when we were working on this function, add default data in the rendered
go file, I left this comment to do get more user information.
And what I want to do is once that user is authenticated, we've actually put their user information
in the session and we want to get it out.
Now I want to make that available to the template, but only if the user is authenticated.
And fortunately, that's pretty easy.
So I'll delete this comment and I'll put a simple check in here.
So I'll look for the user variable to be populated and I'll also put an okay there, which will be true
if I can get this and false if I can't and I'll call apt session knocked out load i want does it get
from the context for using the context I'm looking for user.
Okay.
And I'm going to get that and then I'm going to cast it to a data dot user type.
So that's what I'm calling now.
This will be false if I can't get that information and this will be true if I can.
And remember, I'm casting it to a data dot user, not a pointer to a data dot user.
Okay.
So we'll say if not, okay and I'll just write to the info logger there, log after error log dot print
line and I'll just put can't get the user from session.
And that's purely from my my information.
Nobody's ever going to see that on the website.
Otherwise I want to add the user to all the information that's available to me in the template.
Okay.
So let's scroll up to the top and uncomment this line where I'm adding the user to the all the data
that's going to every single template.
And I'll say this to format it.
And now I'll go back down to where I'm putting this in here and I'll say TV user is equal to and it
has to be a pointer, right?
I can't just put the user in there as an object.
It needs to be a pointer.
So I'll put a reference to user and that will give me access to everything stored in that user data
type on every single page that an authenticated user visits.
Okay, so let's move on and get started displaying the plans that our users can subscribe to once they're
registered for our site.