So now that we can create an account and log in after activating the account, the next step, of course,
is to display the list of plans, subscriptions that a user can purchase.
And we have three in our database bronze, silver and gold.
So let's go over to handlers ago and we'll start working on the handler.
And of course, we'll have to put a template and a routine.
We'll get started right here.
So down at the bottom of this file, handlers, dot, go.
I'm going to create a new handler func with the receiver of app pointer to config as usual and I'll
call this one choose subscription which is as good a name as any and it takes a response writer and
a pointer to a request.
Okay, so the very first thing, no one should be able to see this page unless they've already created
an account and logged in.
Now we could write some middleware that does that for us, but this is a very simple example.
So I'll just put the logic right in here.
Okay.
So I'll check to see if not after session.
Session.
Dot exists and I'm looking for using the context.
I'm looking for user ID and that tells me whether or not the user is logged in.
Okay.
So if they're not logged in, we'll just generate a message at dot session.
Not put using are not context and I'll put in a warning message and just say you must log in to see
this page and then I'll redirect the user HD Peacock redirect using W an R and we'll take them to say
the login page, which seems appropriate.
And we'll put in an HDP DOT status temporary redirect right there and we'll return.
Okay.
But if we get past that, then we know the user is logged in.
So let's show the page.
Now, in order to show the page, we need to show all the various plants and over here in the plan and
go in the data folder.
We actually have a means of getting all the plants right here get all.
So let's use that socrata variable plans while checking for an error when I call after model start plan
don't get all.
Okay then we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then something went wrong with our connection to the database or whatever.
So we'll just print it out.
An error log dot print line
the error and we'll return.
Okay.
Which is sufficient for our purposes today.
And of course, you might want to display an error page or something else, but I'll leave that as an
exercise for you.
Now I want to pass the variable plans to the template that doesn't exist yet, but it's going to need
it because we have to draw those.
We have to draw a table or something, at least those plants.
So I'll create a data map variable and that's assigned sign the value of make map string is the key
and it will take anything at all.
Any.
Okay.
And then we'll add plans to that data map.
Data map with a key of plans is equal to plants.
And then we just render the template using app render and we render using W and R and this will be the
template we'll make in the minute plans dot page dot, go HTML and we'll hand that a reference to template
data which is what it expects to find that or nil and in there will make data equal to data map and
render has a lowercase r.
That's better.
Okay, so that's the handler.
Now let's go create the plans dot page.
Doug switched him up.
So in templates, CMC Web templates, we'll create a new file called Plans dot page and go to your map
and save a bit of time or copy the contents of the home page.
So home page go to tomorrow.
I'll just select all and copy and close that and paste that right in here.
Okay.
And then we'll modify it as necessary.
So we'll change the title to plans and we'll get rid of all of this.
Okay.
Now let's just create a table with the class of from straight from bootstrap table.
Table.
Compact table stripped.
And we'll close that table tag.
So I don't forget.
And then we'll put it in a t head and close that
and a TR and close that
and we'll put in the headings.
So I'll just put in a couple of simple headings, t h for that again t h plan slash th0 duplicate that
twice and I'll center these once class equals text dash center
and I'll copy this and paste it here.
And change these labels to say price
and select.
Okay, so that's my t hat.
Now we'll have the t body and close that.
And inside of this T body we want to range through index dot data.
And the key we used was plant.
So we have this map data available to us and we're going to arrange through that whatever we find in
the key plant.
And we just put that in there so we know that's going to be there and we'll end this.
And in between, of course, we're just going to draw some tears and a t, t and inside of that we'll
put in a dot plant name, which we got from the database and close this and then we'll have a t d class
equals text dash center.
And inside of that, I'll put the key and this is dot plan amount formatted and we get that from the
database.
We can look at that in a minute.
So how much does it cost per month?
And that takes the value.
So for bronze, it's 1000 sense that converts it to dollar sign 10.00.
Just because that's what people expect to see.
Let me close the tree and then we'll duplicate this and change this pen.
To a button.
Okay.
I'm going to put this on a couple of lines so it's more readable.
So what I'm going to say is a class equals beaten.
So bootstrap button and I'll make it a button save primary.
So it's blue.
Easy to see.
Then I'll make it small feat and dash, Sam.
Okay.
And when we make the trip equal to nothing, so just hash a bang and we'll add an on click handler.
And that will cause some JavaScript that doesn't exist yet.
And we'll call that, say, select plan and will hand it the plan ID, which we get from ID like that.
Okay.
And closer quotes and we'll just put in here, select and close the egg.
So that will list all of the plants.
So we've got our TVs.
We need to close our tr t bodies already closed.
Table's already closed.
Let's go down the JavaScript section.
What I want to have happen is when someone clicks on this select button, I want some kind of dialog
to pop up just to confirm that they want to choose that plant.
So it'll have some message and then two buttons select and cancel.
And if they click select, we subscribed the user to the plant.
Now, to make this really easy, let's install a JavaScript library.
I want to go to my web browser and I will search for Sweet Alert two right there.
So it will be a link to this in the course resources for this lecture and it's called Sweet Alert.
Okay, now I'm not going to bother downloading and install this.
I'll just go over here to just deliver and there'll be a link to this in the course.
Resources as well.
Just delivered icon with an E missing and I'll search for sweet alert two right there.
That's the one that I want.
Okay.
And I'll delete the one that I had selected from the last time I visited here.
This is the one I want sweet alert to all messengers, and I'll have a list added to the collection.
Then I'll click show and configure all links and the one I want is to output some.
I'll just copy this to the clipboard, okay.
And go back to my I.D. And just before the opening script tag will install that library by pasting in
the link to the queue.
Okay.
Now I'll define a function called so I'll call it function.
And we called our select plan and it took one argument.
Actually, I'm going to give it to arguments.
So back up here.
I'll put in the ID and then in single quotes I'll put in a dot plan name like that just so I can put
the name in the pop up menu as a pop up dialog as well.
So this will take two things, X and the plan.
Okay.
Now, what about what do I want to do inside of this function?
Well, it's really simple.
I'll just take advantage of sweet alert.
And Sweet Alert will fire a dialog with my attributes by calling small dot fire lower case.
Okay.
So in opening parentheses and opening curly bracket and a closing curly bracket and closing parentheses.
And inside of this I'll give it a title and the title will be subscribe
and then I'll give it some HTML textual message and I'll just say, Are you sure you want to subscribe
to the space?
And then a plus plan like that.
Okay.
And then a plus and a question mark and a comma to end that off.
And then another attribute to specify is show cancel button.
Give them a cancelled button.
True.
And then I want the confirm button text override that to to have it say instead subscribe.
Okay.
And then after the closing curly bracket and the closing parentheses, then we put a then clause in
and then result whatever we're getting back and then the arrow function, we'll close that up.
So I don't forget.
And inside of here we'll have a simple if statement, if result DOT is confirmed, which is supplied
by sweet alert, then we'll take them somewhere.
Okay.
And what I'm going to do is type this in that I'll comment it out because it's going to try to take
them somewhere that doesn't exist yet.
Window dot.
Location the ref.
Equals and we'll take them to slash subscribe with the idea that they just chose which is X which we
received as a call to this function.
Now a comment that it right now because we're not able to use that at the moment but now we have a handler
and we have a template.
So in the next lecture, we'll set up a route and we'll make sure that this renders the way that we
think it's going to.
Okay, let's move on.