All right.
We're almost ready to try things out.
But I did have a couple of typos in the last lecture.
The first one is down here in the comment that I part of the then clause in our sworn call.
And then it's just the missing equals sign right here.
Otherwise, we're not going to be able to get that query parameter and up here in the range statement.
For some reason I said range through index dot data plan, but it's actually plans plural.
As you can see over here in the handler, we added plans as the key on line 178 micro.
Okay.
So now we need to add a route to this handler.
So let's go back to our routes file right here and let's add a route right here.
I'll put it like this.
Mac, start.
Get that again.
Mac start.
Get slash plans and that's going to go to app dot choose subscription.
Okay, so let's restart our application or start it in my case, make start, my Docker images are running
so we have access to the database and it started.
Now go to my web browser and go to local host.
Okay.
So the pages are working now.
We don't have a link to it yet, so let's just put Slash plans here.
And I'm logged in and I can see it now.
I'll copy this.
First of all, let's try the button.
Make sure this fire is as expected.
I'm going to choose the bronze plan and it gives me my nice little dialogue and I cancel and it takes
me back to this page.
Now let's log out.
And try going to local host slash plants and I should get a warning and get redirected.
And I do.
Okay.
So that all works really well.
Now, let's add a link up here.
First of all, let me log in and then at example dot com with the password.
Very secret.
So I've loved it.
Now I want a plans thing to show up here.
Now, obviously, in a real Web site, you're going to have one that's available to the public.
But we just want to get to the part where we can write some concurrent logic.
So let's go back over to our I.D. and let's open up and have Bardot partial don't go each HTML.
And that's the navigation bar at the top of the screen.
And all I have to do is to duplicate this line and change it to plans and plans.
And I will only show up for authenticated users.
So let's go back over here now and reload this page.
And there's my plans link.
And it works as expected.
Okay.
Now, when I'm logged in and after I've bought a plan, I shouldn't see select next to the plan that
I'm currently looking at.
It should say something like currently select it.
Let's put that logic in place because that's pretty easy.
Remember, we added all of the user information to every rendered template.
So back here in the plans dot page, don't go each time out.
Let's go to the content block.
Define content.
And right after the opening line for that block, I'll create a variable called user and that will be
assigned the value of DOT user.
The only reason I'm doing that is it gives me easier access to it inside this range statement and this
is where I need to do things.
So really the only place I'm making a decision about whether or not a user has a plan is in this.
This block right here where I'm displaying the button.
So what I can do is put an if statement here.
So if I want to put the end condition, if two things are true.
And the first one is that the user has a plan because a user might not have a plan if they just register,
they certainly don't.
So dollar sign user.
So if that's true and we have an equality check here, user dot plan dot ID is equal to ID.
If that's true, then I'm going to display something.
Okay.
And then I'll put an else here.
And close my if statement.
And and what I'm going to put in this first block, this first check, get over to the right spot.
The simply strong.
Current plan.
Strong.
Okay.
So we'll save that.
And then I'm going to go to Beekeeper Studio and give my user a plan.
So I start a beekeeper studio and I'll manually add an entry.
So I'll go to concurrency and connect.
And I look at my users to see what my ideas.
So I'd one for immediate example dot com and I'll go to user plans.
And I'll add a row, so I'll outro.
Let the IDB generate generated.
One is my user ID.
I'll subscribe to plan one.
I'll just put a date in here.
2022 zero 517 2022 zero 517 and I'll apply this.
Okay.
Now that user is now subscribed with the plan.
But if I go back to my website and I reload this page.
We have an error, so there's a typo in there somewhere.
Neil Poynter Evaluating Direct planned ID.
Okay, so got a mistake there somewhere.
Let's go find that back over to my I.D. dot plan.
That's better.
Okay.
So the user was set, but plan was set to nil.
So I'm checking to see if plan is actually not nil.
In other words, that pointer points to some location in memory that has data.
So let's go reload that page and see if that works again.
Reload.
Okay.
Even though it reloaded the page successfully, it still doesn't show that I'm subscribed to the bronze
plan.
And that's because the user data that I'm getting for this page comes from the session.
And when I logged in, I didn't have that plan.
But if I'm longer and long back in admin example dot com very secret this time it should work.
And now I want to go to plans.
It shows me that's my current plan.
Perfect.
Okay, let's move on and we'll write a stub handler for choosing and subscribing to a plan and we'll
get started on that in the next lecture.