So the next step in this process is to get started on the route in the handler that allows us to subscribe
to a plan.
So over here in plans, dot page go HTML, the URL we're going to is slash subscribe.
So let's uncomment this now because we'll have it active in a few minutes and let's go back over to
Rootstock, go and set up a handler for subscribe.
So we'll set up a muscat and it's going to go to slash subscribe and it's going to go to a handler that
doesn't exist yet called say subscribe to plan.
Okay, now let's go over to our handlers and create a stub handler for that.
So right after I'll put a right before this one because I want to be using some of these comments funk
app pointer to config and we'll call this subscribe to plan and it takes a response writer and a pointer
to a request.
Okay.
Now let's put some comments in here just so we have something to work with.
So what do we want to do in here?
Well, first of all, we want to say get the idea of the plan that is chosen and that comes as a query
parameter named on DH.
That'll be easier.
And the next thing we want to do is to get the plan from the database.
We need to know some information about it.
Okay.
And then we're willing and we want to get the user from the session.
So this means that I now know the user.
I know the I know the plan the user has chosen.
And of course, there's a few things I need to do here.
Number one is generate an invoice.
So let's get that comment at here and put that down here.
Okay.
So we're going to want to generate an invoice.
Then we're going to want to send an email with the invoice attached.
So let's put that comment down here.
Then we're going to want to say generate a manual.
So I'm going to assume that when you buy a gold plan, you get a manual that's customized for you as
a PDF and that sent to you.
So we'll say generate a manual and will generate a very simple one because it's not critical to have
an actual fully formatted manual for a non-existent service.
We just want to generate a PDF with some custom information in it and send that.
Then we want to send an email
with the manual attached.
Okay.
And after that, we're going to want to subscribe.
These are to an account.
Let's put this over where it belongs.
And then finally, we're going to want to redirect.
Okay.
So that's at a high level the sorts of things we want to do in this subscribe to plan handler.
So obviously, some of this can be done in real time or sequentially.
So getting the ID, getting the plan, getting the user.
But this stuff generating an invoice, sending an email, generate a manual, sending an email.
All of that should take place in the background or concurrently, and that's what we're going to work
on next.
So this is enough to get us started.
Let's move on.