All right so we're done with the hands on exercises now we're moving into G.P.S. and the first thing
we're gonna do is learn a little bit about P C and Daniel's been doing some research on this I'm going
to be learning about it right alongside with you.
What did you find out about JROTC here.
DANIEL So GOPAC ended up being kind of almost a replacement for communication protocol that Google developed
and a G or P C is actually a recursive name GOP C stands for GOPAC wrote procedure call it yeah it's
the annual hey is our piece GOPAC Stanford Google GAAP seems like I don't know.
And then under that fake you you found GAAP C stands for a GAAP so.
OK.
GAAP C kind of like you know what Jason stands for G javascript object notation but here GAAP stands
for GOPAC remote procedure call of course.
That's fine.
So yeah.
So GAAP C was developed at Google and and there's a couple of things to it but one of the things is
it's an alternative to Jason and starting to become used more more widely.
Right.
Yeah it's it's it's become something that's used.
Yes.
So it's it's an alternative to HBP and GOPAC most often like ninety nine point ninety nine percent of
the time it uses Protocol Buffers first communicate for how you pass data around.
So this is similar to ATP you're using Jason so GOP sees Protocol Buffers so GOP sees CBC or B.C. to
call methods on your server or remote as opposed to ACP you're sending in requests with a method and
a path and then instead of a body to an HP request in GOPAC you've got protocol but for message.
OK.
So old way HDP make a request an endpoint and then I get a response back some Jason.
Right.
That's one you knew a G.P.S. and make a request to get back a prototype off and the prototype is binary
information but it's data right.
Yes yes it's a replacement for Jason it's smaller and more efficient to encode and decode into it.
All right.
So so that's what GOPAC is.
It's a little hard to use the HP Jason HP libraries are everywhere because it's used so often.
So it's in the standard library for most period languages.
And same thing for Jason.
It's so common that it's insanely everything GOPAC.
Not so much.
So the GOP see part of it the the transport is simple enough.
That's just a library for every language but in the protocol buffer is actually where it gets a little
more complicated to use G.P.S..
And so in so in the next video we'll get how to install G.P.S. and the protocol buffer compiler Yeah.
And so the best way to understand something is often just to see it in action and says we work through
kind of seeing in an actual game and greater understanding what you see as the good starting point of
understanding G.P.S. is it's HBP Jason GOPAC protocol.
It's a new way that we could exchange information between machines.
All right sounds good.