All right so so to install G.P.S. their instructions for installation are actually a little bit dated.
They're actually from the go path era of stuff but a lot of times when you see a go path era item it
is possible to do it with go modules too There gets to be a little bit of complexity here however because
there is a binary involved there is the proton see the protocol buffer compiler which needs to be installed
as well.
So I will be walking through this kind of with a mouse.
So to install this you need to find the the the occupation for how to get started.
So I'm going to go to quick start Doc quick start and I want to go quick start.
And this is actually where the installation for go instructions for go Is this the quick start.
They don't actually have their tutorials or reference so so the install G.P.S. so the main GOP library
is just a plain go library so you can just import this and use it go modules just by itself.
So you don't even need to go get it.
So you can ignore this step.
This is just go.
This is go module compatible.
If I actually copy and paste that into it into a new tab my browser and then click the link to go through
into the get hub.
I will find there is a scroll down there is a go dot mod so there are already modules module ready.
Nice.
So you don't have to go get it go getting is the old way to go path and now it's modules happens automatically.
Yeah.
Don't need to even do anything.
So the more tricky part comes from the Protocol Buffers part.
So to make Protocol Buffers you need the pro C program.
And so the proto C program you can find it there's a link right here to get hub dot com Google proto
above releases.
So if I go through two that go through that link this brings me to the Protocol Buffers proto above
the releases thing and so need to install the protest program from here.
So I don't think I want the prerelease version so 3 10 release candidate 1.
It's probably OK but I think it's just safer just to go back to the latest release.
It's not a one and they've got a lot of possible downloads but the ones you want are these ones down
here at the bottom.
The ones that are a proto C a version number a platform and possibly a C you type.
So I'm on windows I'm a 64 bit Windows machine.
So this is the one I want to download and if you're Linux 64 bit that's here.
Here's Mac 64 bit OK so x 86 64 is for 64 bit OK so we great to click that to download it and why that's
downloading a nice function I was working with last night is and go dark.
I think it's in their package OS thing its package OS impact Joe has and then is it art.
How do you where's the OS are not that architecture runtime runtime runtime it's in runtime and runtime
you have architecture
go arc right here will tell you that you know where it is want a stack overflow link somewhere it will
tell you the architecture of your receipt machine if you want to see that so that's kind of an interesting
thing to take a look at and see what that will show you is go ask
go out go ask go path career environment variables police go environment variables I think they're in
the constants
in the and we have go asking D6 four there you go it's just an interesting take a look at it so you
could see there under us so they're using the x eighty six thirty two and six or so so the generally
speaking you'll want your platform x six sixty for most machines are 64 bit right so now it's downloaded
I will open this up and updated here.
So this puts in a bunch of stuff here would I actually need is in the bin folder I just need this executable
and I need to be somewhere that's on my path.
So one location that's on my path that I have setup is a I have a bin folder in my in my home folder.
I've got that setup on my path so anything that's in here is on my path.
So I'm just gonna put the proto C probe in there.
So now if I do pro C C A Dash V for version it most program support does not support at dash dash version.
You like Potosi 3 9 1 so that's courtesy.
So the next step is where we actually get to the more confusing part.
So beyond Potosi go is not a part of the base Potosi stuff.
So you need the proto C in for go.
And so here's the tricky bit to get working with.
Go modules is to install something that's a binary with go path.
You just go get it and the executable is in your bin folder when you go path go module doesn't have
a go path so that's not a thing anymore so you could just do this make make sure you're not in a folder
with the go dot mod and you could do this and all go into go path way of doing things.
And the only way to do it the old way.
So but the new way of doing things if you go to the go the get hub Weeki for go laying the modules page
there is a how can a track tool dependencies for a module.
That explains kind of how to use modules for executable is like that.
And basically what it says is you want to create a tool stop go file so if I go here I'm going to just
create a new folder 0 5 G or C and in here I'm just gonna create a file was gonna call it tools go and
it's going to be package doesn't really matter.
So I'll just call it package main just cause that seems likely to be thing.
And I want to put this comment here near the top of the page so this is 0 0 actually to warning the
build com it must be before the package declaration.
So this is how you restrict a Go file from a permit from building so you could do a plus build windows
in this go file will only build on Windows or Linux or Darwin but you can also put in kind of whatever
you want.
So tools is a tag that's never actually used.
So it'll never actually build this Go file but the go file exists.
And so any imports you make will go into your go mod file.
And so now I can add in my go to GOPAC.
And this is the go proto C plugin so I can import that.
And so now if I go if I'm in the right folder I need to be up over year
mod tidy they look at my go mod I should now have that proto buff pattern going put above in my modules
list at 1 3 the version 1 3 1.
The other thing to note is you need to make sure your go in environment variable is set.
So if you do go in the Go bin mine is set to that bin folder in my home.
So if I pull that back open again
go back in to that bin folder.
It should put the go proto C extension in there.
It doesn't look like it did because I didn't actually download it.
I go modded tidied it but then it's never actually downloading the package because it's never actually
using it.
So to actually force it to download despite never actually using it you can use go mod download to download
all dependencies that are in your go mod whether they're in use or not.
So hopefully that worked doesn't look like it did.
B is this import needs to be underscored because I'm not actually using it.
Maybe my tidy go mod download.
Give me a sec.
Okay so I need to go install that path now it looks like just looking at the dock station maybe.
There you go.
Now I've got Potosi Django so at once in your module go modules list.
You have to go install that particular binary file manually so it won't be downloaded.
Go my download this just say you need to install it manually but this will respect your go mod for files
version no.
So now I've got Potosi Gen go.
You see along with Potosi and so now Potosi now supports and go on my system and that is actually it
Potosi is working on my system GOPAC will be automatic as soon as they start using it.
So that is it it is now installed with go modules.
Nice.
Well done.
I'm going to off line.
This video is gone a little bit long.
Off line I'm going to go through that with Daniel once more and get some steps in the next video we'll
do a quick review.