Okay so now when Daniel was doing all of that I noticed I started to glaze over.
And that's why at the end of that video I was like wait I got to go through that again with you and
I wanted to get some notes and so I put together some notes here and then we're gonna get my system
set up just so you could see that installation and so will I will call this installation.
Just keep Mac and so you saw a window on the last one.
And now you're going to see it on the windows.
It's called Windows and you're going to see it on Mac.
And so the steps there if you take a look at those steps the first step was to go to the Web site and
then go to a quick start go and and then install the pro CE program and the Potosi compiler is used
to generate the G.P.S. service code and then we take the executable from Proto.
So I did all of that open it up came down zip file and I got this here and then inside this bin folder
we got proto see into this proto C has to be found by my computer when my computer looks for executable
and the environment variable upon which to which my computer looks for executable is the path environment
variable and so I just want to make sure that this proto C is discoverable somewhere on my path.
And so if I go to my terminal and I echo dolor path it will show me my path very long so I can look
through here at all the places set and I could put it in some location and add that location here if
I wanted to my path variable or I could just use a location that is already existing and so I think
I'll take my privacy and put it in user local bands I'm just going to copy that and and then I need
to move it from this location to there.
And so right now I am actually in No not that location singing chat change documents change direct directory
to documents and then inside documents it is proto C and and then inside proto C it has been and then
now inside of there I'm going to move that and I'm going to move proto C and I'm going to move it to
this location.
Is that all look right to you.
Yes.
And I'm gonna hit enter and if I see to that location and then doing allows I could see I've got proto
C in there.
So that's good.
And that was the next step on the processes to take the executable from proto C stored in some location
at that location on your path environment variable.
And that was all that.
After that we need to import this this package right here.
Get icon going above proto see Django and using go modules create a file like this in your project and
Daniel's already created that file.
But before I pull that code down I'm going to go here and take a look some below.
And beneath that I don't have that in here yet.
There's nothing in there about GitHub dot.com going proto above GitHub dot com going above.
I don't have anything in there.
I don't have that in there yet.
So next thing I'm in do is just on my terminal and get myself current with Daniel.
So I need to see these back to documents and then inside see documents go into the go project and do
get status and and I'm your branch is behind or G.M. by one committee can be fast forwarded get pulled
update.
So do I get full and then do I get status again and get add Dash 8 add my homework and get commit dash
and and I'm gonna change it this time I'm doing great.
Often I tell students You're doing great as encouragement I'm giving myself a little encouragement after
my homework and then I'm gonna push that up and and so that should all be good.
Now get status and and now when I take a look here I should have Daniel's code down here and then there's
five GOPAC and in G.P.S. we have tools and then we have this right there.
And now if I look at my go mod that is still not shown going proto but for it there genius I love it.
And so now that we have that file right here.
So it's bringing that n confirm this is in go mod and now I want to run go and stall is that's correct
at this step.
So go install is the next step.
And this is going to actually bring the code down so that it's on my computer right now it just says
go get it if it's used or we're not using it anywhere so it hasn't gone and gotten that right.
Yes.
So but first thing takes you go being set.
Oh that has to be done first.
All right.
So I want to set my my go been to environment variable to something and go Benz one word.
Right.
Yes two.
There you go.
So we'll go take a look at.
Back to my nano.
Well we could do first of all go in B and so might go Ben is currently not set to anything and now I'm
going to nano dot bash.
And by the way I'm in kind of my user folder and then inside there on a Mac.
I've got my bash profile and that's where I set environment variables and so I'm going to now nano my
dot bash profile and and then and here I can just copy this basically export go.
Ben is equal to forward slash users.
And we had a little discussion about where should I set my Go Ben to with go modules and just to kind
of document that so you could hear a little bit of that discussion modules is kind of a new way to do
things.
And that's giving you your name spacing and that's giving you your package management and versioning.
But then we have the go work in the go path right to go past set your go workspace.
That's the old way and in the go workspace.
You had your Ben package source folders.
So my head those are kind of two separate things like oh I don't want to do anything in that area anymore.
That's the old way where I have my go path and then we talked about it in your account.
No it's fine it's there use it's your go folder you've got a pen folder in it.
Right.
Set your go Ben to that.
And so it could still use that folder is no big deal.
Would that have any complications if I had legacy code and I did want to like suddenly use my go path
workspace to that place should be not your bin folder it should be fine.
Have been folder files get overwritten fairly often and whenever you whenever you grab something new
that inexcusable.
So a pair programming does that all look good to you.
Yes.
And I think the only other thing that I would check is to actually confirm will confirm that afterwards.
So now I'm just going to exit and hit yes and hit enter and now I need to restart my terminal for that
to take effect.
That's the easiest way that I've found to do it and I could do go in V.
And now my go Ben is set to that location.
I just want to make sure that that location exists calm fairly confident does.
But to do that I'll copy this
and then just CV there yeah we're all good if I go up a level and allies.
That's my workspace.
And that is.
Yeah.
Good.
All right.
And so that's just a convenient location that's on your path that go right to yeah.
So it will install binaries there.
Yep.
So so now you're go install knows a little notes where she put that executable that it builds.
So if we actually take a look at what's in there right now
we've got those and when I do my go install and get that proto buff proto see Django which is this code
which is all proto see Django Reinhardt see Django process Django.
We're just getting this proto see Django.
And yeah.
So now and I do this install I should see that set into my then folder count load package cannot find
I don't need my H TTP.
You need to make sure your part.
You need to make sure you're in your go module folder.
So just because you want to make sure that you install it at the version that go mod is low key it has
pinned checks on you to go see CV documents and then googling project.
Yeah.
And then now and they should just get a job right.
Yeah just get a now let's look at the and now we could switch back to here and we can to save a keystroke.
Do that.
Now we have privacy jingo in the bin folder there.
Yep.
And.
And now just go mod tidy.
That's just to make sure that that that go on tidy is to make sure that your that privacy chain goes
in your co mod before before you install.
So so confirm this.
If it's not there do come on.
Tidy.
See that all again.
So so so use the wrong location should be a dot must be moved to.
So it should be moved up to right here.
Yes.
So.
So if it's if.
You need to make sure that privacy chain goes and you go mod that go my title is how you make how you
put it into that good mod if it has not yet been put there.
Because the two mines just automatically show that like you know modify it or put it in Yeah if it's
not there.
All right.
And a seedy CV documents going go project and go mod Heidi unnecessary at this point but hey did a little
bit of stuff.
All right.
So that's that's good that's getting it installed on a Mac.
I hope that was helpful to you and I hope those notes were helpful.
And we will see you tomorrow I'm going to go home and do some serious G.P.S. reading tonight.
So I have some things to add to the conversation tomorrow.
Daniel thank you.
It's a pleasure.
I appreciate doing this with you and learning with you and pair programming and teaching it's totally
it's it's really beneficial process you know.
Appreciate it.
See you all in the next video which for us will be to morrow anything you want add Sia.