So let's turn our attention to the final project for this course.
And the final project is a slightly more real world use of concurrency.
What we're going to do is we're going to build a subset of some imaginary service that allows people
to buy one of three possible subscriptions.
It doesn't matter what those subscriptions are for.
Let's assume that you register for an account on this system, and then you choose to buy a bronze,
silver or gold subscription package.
And when you buy it, you get generated an invoice that is sent to you and you also get generated a
user manual of some sort.
Say this is a service that requires that you get some documentation for an API and this service wants
to generate a very customized version of a user manual that has examples that are specific to your API
key and that sort of thing.
It doesn't matter what it is.
The point is that we're building something that's going to use concurrency.
Now, this first section in the final project is all about setting up the web application, getting
some routes in place, and some handlers and some database logic and things like that.
Managing sessions, rendering pages.
So basically it's some boiler plate code.
We have to get out of the way before we can actually start writing some concurrent code.
So let's get Start.