As I suggested last time, we can't actually use our application until we set up a little bit of middleware
that loads and saves the session on every request.
And there are instructions how to do this right on the Alex Edwards assist GitHub repository.
But it's pretty simple.
So inside the CMB Web folder, we'll create a new file, which we'll call middleware Dot Go, and it's
in Package Main and we'll just write some simple middleware.
So I'll declare a function with the receiver app pointer to config as usual, and we'll call this session
load, which seems to make sense.
And like most middleware, it takes one parameter next of type HTTP dot handler.
Okay, and it returns an HGTV dot handler.
So what this does is modify the request and this is dead simple.
We just return app dot session right there, dot and load and save.
Okay.
And we give it next and that's all that's required to make this happen.
So we've made the actual middleware now we need to use it.
So let's go over to Roofstock.
Go and right here in the middleware section, after we recover from panic, we'll say, Max, don't
use and it will be from the app session live.
And with that middleware in place, I should be able to start the application and hit the web page,
the homepage.
So let's give it a try over my terminal and I'll type make start.
The application is building.
And it's running.
And I should be able to now to switch to my web browser and just go to local host and let's see what
happens.
See if we got it right.
And there it is.
Okay.
So we're displaying one page now, obviously the links here for registering log in and so forth.
They're not going to work because we haven't set up the actual routes or handlers for those.
But at least I know that I can now render a web page and send it to the end user.
All right.
Let's move on.