Now that we know we can actually display a web page to the end user, let's take some time and set up
a few more stub handlers for the rest of the pages in our site.
And we're not going to have a lot of pages.
We're just trying to demonstrate how to use concurrency in a real world application.
And of course, we're just doing a subset of what is some fictitious larger site.
But that's okay.
Let's go over to our handlers.
Dot go first.
It will set a few up so we already have a handler for the home page.
Let's do one for the log in page func app pointer to config as usual and we'll call this one logging
page, which seems to make sense and it will take a response writer right there and a pointer to a request.
And all we're going to do here is actually render a page.
So it's pretty much the same thing as what we did before.
And let's copy this and pasted in here and let's get the name of the template.
It's log in page to go HTML.
So I just put logging dot page to go each time out.
And then of course we'll have to have a handler that actually does the logging.
We'll just do a stub for that right now config and we'll call this one say post logging page because
a post request will call this handler and again need a response writer and our pointer to our request
and we'll leave that empty for now.
Okay.
And then we're going to have to have a log out function and that's pretty simple func that pointer to
config and we'll just call this one log out and it will be W.A.S.P. dot response writer and our pointer
to HTP to request.
And again, I'll leave this empty for now to some stub handlers.
The other thing we're going to want to let people do is register to register and possibly buy something.
So funk app pointer to config and we'll call this one register page with w h heartbeat of response rater
and our pointer to HTTP request.
Now this one is just, just displaying a page.
It's the registered on page token which html.
So I can copy this, paste it here and make this register.
Dot page dot go html.
And again we'll have a post handler.
So to handle that after somebody actually fills out the registration form, we'll call this one, say
post, register page and we'll leave it empty for now as well.
So after they register, what we'll do is send them an activation email to verify that we have the valid
email address and we'll actually have them activate their account and that will be a get request, but
it'll be very similar to this.
So I'll copy this, paste it into here and just call this activate account.
Okay, so there are some actual stub handlers.
Now let's go set up some routes to them over at our routes file.
So we have the home page.
Let's do one for actually logging in, so forth so much.
And yet when you go to slash log in, we'll take you to the handler after log in page and then we'll
duplicate that and make this a post.
And when you post to the from the log in page, you're going to go to the slash log in route again.
But this time it's a post request and we'll change this to post log in page and we'll duplicate that
again and make this log out.
But the log request will be a get request and we'll take them to the log error handler right there.
Okay.
And the next one would be, say, max dot yet and you're going to go to slash register to register for
an account and that will take you to app dot register page and we duplicate this, make this a post
request and that takes you to post register page
and the last one is activate.
So we'll make this a get request and it takes say activate, maybe activate dash account.
You can always change it later and that takes you to activate account.
Okay.
Now with those changes, I should be able to restart my application, make restart.
So everything compiled a restart of the application.
Let's go back to our web browser and see if these work.
So I should be able now to go to the Register page and there it is, and I should be able to go to the
login page and there it is.
Okay, now nothing else works, but this is a good start.
All right, let's move on and take care of implementing graceful shut down, which will be the first
time in this section we've actually done anything with concurrency, and it's not very complex, but
we'll get started on it right away.