So our final application is going to have a number of go routines running in the background.
Some of those go routines are just going to be listening to channels and some are actually going to
be doing something like sending an email or generating invoice or something like that.
And when you decide to stop this application, for whatever reason, maybe you need to do some work
on the server, maybe you need to implement a hotfix or something like that.
Whatever the case may be, you need to stop the application.
And if you just stop it, like if we type, make it stop.
Right now, everything just stops.
Any running go routines just die without finishing.
And that's not good because you might not send an email that needs to go out or generate an invoice
or whatever the case may be.
So it is good practice to implement graceful shutdown, and that's what we're going to do this time
around.
So back here in the file, I mean, don't go inside the CMT Web folder.
Let's scroll to the very bottom of this file and let's create a go routine like this or a function that's
going to be a go routine function with the receiver app pointer to config as usual.
And I'll call this one listen for shutdown.
Okay.
And it takes no parameters.
This is going to run in the background and just listen for something.
So what I'm going to do, first of all, is I'll make a channel called Click.
Okay?
So I'll make a channel.
And it's going to take OS dot signal right from the OS package and it has a length of one which is unnecessary,
but I'm going to put it in there anyway.
And then we'll say signal, which again is right from the standard library dot notify and we're going
to pass it a quick channel and we're going to pass it.
Just call sig int the interrupt sig int try that again.
See it.
And there it is.
Okay.
When you get the interrupt signal to stop the application or Cisco dot second term to terminate the
application, which is there is a sink term.
Okay.
That's what we're listening for and we'll block on the quick channel.
So this just pauses until we actually get the request to terminate or interrupt the running application.
Okay.
Once that happens, once we get past that line, line 151 in my code, we'll call another function that
doesn't exist yet called app dot shut down.
Okay.
And after that runs.
OS exit with the status code, not executable exit with the status code of zero.
Okay.
Now I'm calling a function that doesn't exist yet, so let's go.
Right that and that's a pretty simple function.
So func the receiver pointer to config, we're going to call this one shutdown.
And what are we going to do inside this function?
Well, we're going to perform any cleanup tasks, whatever those might be.
And for right now, I'll just put after info, log, dot, print line and we'll just say would run cleanup
tasks, dot, dot, dot.
Okay, that's the first thing we're going to do and then we're going to wait for everything to finish.
Now, remember, back up here.
We go to the very top of this file.
We added a weight group, a reefer plunger to a weight group in the field, weight in our application
config.
So we have a weight available to our entire application.
Let's go back down here.
After we run any cleanup tasks, what we're going to do next is just block.
Until weight group is empty and we know how to do that at on weight, which is our weight group, not
weight.
And once that's all the semaphore count in that weight group hits zero, then we move on.
And what will we do here?
Well, we'll print out a napkin for log and just put a comment because we have nothing to do right now,
print line and we'll say closing channels, because that's one thing we'll do.
And shutting down application.
Dot, dot, dot.
Okay.
And that's all that we do.
We have no channels to close at the moment, so we'll just put these messages out.
Now I've got this listen for shutdown, which calls for shutdown, but of course, I'm not starting
this application yet.
I'll go back up to our main function.
Wherever that is.
Right here.
And just before we fire up the Web server, we'll listen for signals.
And of course, that's sink term in cement.
And to start that go routine, we just go go app dot listen for shutdown and now that's running in the
background.
So with those few changes if I open my terminal now and say make stop in case my application is running
and it wasn't and so it makes start, it rebuilds it.
Okay, it started the web server.
So I'll just clear the screen and say, make it stop.
Now this what you're going to see next will definitely show up on Linux and Macs.
It may not show up on Windows for some reason.
Some people using whatever shell they happen to be using on Windows they don't get output from in the
terminal when they're running make commands.
But many do, and I've never figured out what the actual combination is that doesn't allow it to show
up.
But trust me, this is what's happening.
If you follow it along.
Exactly.
Here's what's going to happen when I start the application it says would run cleanup tasks and closing
channels and shutting down application.
And that is a graceful shutdown.
So, of course, what we're going to do down here.
The very bottom of our file when we block until the weight group is empty.
Every time I want to send an email in the background, I'll simply increase weight.
That weight group, the field weight in the application config, I'll increase that by one by adding
one of the weight group.
Or if I'm printing, generating an invoice or something that's going to be running in the background,
I just keep incrementing that.
And of course I'll also have a deferred weight group done in the functions that are actually increasing
the weight group count by one.
So when they're finished, they reduce it down to zero.
So this allows us to ensure that any background tests that are running will actually finish gracefully
before the application terminates.
Okay, let's move on.