So before we can work with the database, we probably should add some tables and at least one user because
we need someone to log in with.
And if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file you can download called DB
Dot SQL.
Does it download that file, unzip it and open it up in your favorite text editor I have right here,
select all and copy and this is just basic sequel to create some tables and populates a couple of them.
So copy that and go over to Beekeeper Studio, which I have running and I'll connect to my database
concurrency and I'm going to paste what I just copied here in the query window, which shows up by default.
Then I'll say select all and run the selection.
And that, as you can see, creates a table called plans.
And if you look inside of that, we have three plans.
These are the various things that people can subscribe to.
So we have a bronze plan.
The plan amount is the price of the plan in sense.
Whenever I'm working with currency, I tend to store the information in the database as a whole, number
as an integer, and then I just divide by 100 to get the actual dollars and cents value.
So we have bronze, silver and gold, which cost ten, 20 and $30 respectively.
We have a users table and that has one user and the username is the email admin at example icon.
The first name is admin, the last name is user.
The password is actually a hash of a password and the password for this user is very secret, all one
word and all lowercase.
And if we scroll over here a bit, we have a user active field.
One means the user is active, zero means the user is not is in an is underscore.
Admin tells me whether or not this user is an administrator and then created out and updated out and
the actual user plans is just a joined table.
It only has a few columns, so it has the ID column, which is the primary key.
Then we have the user ID, which is a foreign key to the user's table and the plan ID, which is a foreign
key to the plans table.
So if user one buys the bronze plan, this would be whatever the primary key is, one would be the user
ID column, one would be the plan ID column and created out and updated are just timestamps.
Okay, so we have some content in our database.
In the next lecture will install the data package.
Okay.
That'll be the necessary SQL commands and the models that allow us to interact with the database.
Let's move on.