So now we have a means of displaying Web pages to end users.
We have a database that has some content in it.
And of course, we need some means of interacting with that database.
Now, this is a course on concurrency and not database programming.
So just to speed things along.
If you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file called Data dot the zip download
that extract it and you'll find a folder from that zip file called Data.
And I put it at the root level of your project, just like you see right here.
I have a folder called Data right beside the CND folder and it has three files in it models, plan and
user.
Now let's go through these.
This is really simple stuff.
If you've ever worked with a database before.
You'll be familiar with this.
So I'll look at the user dango file first.
And this is in packaged data and it just imports things from the standard library.
Nothing sophisticated here at all.
And we have at the very top a type user.
And of course, this matches exactly what's in the database.
So there's a column called ID in the database and I call it I.B. here.
That's an integer.
So we have ID, email, first name, last name, password, whether the user is active or an admin.
The standard created out and updated at fields.
And then we have plan.
And this of course corresponds to the plans table in the database and we'll look at that in a minute.
So this just maps a a struct, a type to the database fields, simple enough.
And then we have with the receiver user, which points to this type of course a whole bunch of functions.
One lets me get a slice of all the users and it returns a slice of pointers to the user type and potentially
an error.
Very simple stuff.
We write the simple query.
We get our rows from the database with a DB query context and DB of course.
We'll have a look at that in a minute.
Okay.
And down here, we just loop through the rows that we get from the database, populate one user, type
in a variable user, and then we append that to the slice.
Okay, so that's simple enough.
And we do the same thing for getting a user by email and we'll use this in a bit when we log the user
in.
And then down here we get one user by ID and of course, this gets the necessary user and this one also
gets the plan.
Okay, so we'll get all the user information and then we'll find out if that user has already purchased
or subscribed to one of the plants we're offering in our application.
And if they do, we set up a plan variable and add that to the user.
And if we don't, it's just nil.
There's nothing in there.
Okay, an empty plan type update.
It allows me to update user delete allows me to delete a user by user ID.
Delete my ID is the same thing, but instead of getting user id from the receiver I pass, the ideas
in aren't exactly the same, otherwise just delete from users where id equals whatever.
Insert allows me to add a new user and we'll be using this one.
When we register users, we can reset a user's password and we can verify whether or not a supplied
password matches the hash we have stored in the database.
Very simple stuff.
So that's the user one.
Now let's look at planned on go.
This is shorter because we're not doing as much with the actual plans, but the same idea.
I have a struct that matches the structure of my database table here.
I can get all the plans.
I can get one plan by ID and I can subscribe a user to a plan.
And what this does is it inserts into that table user plans, the user ID, the plan ID, and then the
timestamps, and that's it.
And the last one is just a little utility function that allows me to get a price from the database and
format it as though it's currency and return a string.
So if we have a thousand in the database, this will return dollar sign 10.00 or $10.
Okay.
Now, the last one to look at is models dot go.
And this is what we're going to use to make our database functions available to our entire application.
So we set a constant here.
DB Timeout.
If you can't do your database operation in 3 seconds, something has gone wrong.
Very standard and this is DB and this is our connection pool, our pointer to a sequel DB type and this
is what we use to connect Postgres.
Okay, now we have this function called New that we're going to call before too long from our main dot
go file.
This creates a new type of models and models.
It's just this type down here right now it has one field user user.
Any time I add something to this return statement in the new new function, one of my database models
and I add it to the type models, it's immediately available to my entire application.
So let's add plan in here.
Okay.
So I'll put in plan of type plan and then it's an empty instance of that.
And then down here I just add plan and plan and with no other changes, once I actually call this new
function from Mean Don't Go, which I'm going to do in just a moment.
All of the database models and their associated methods are available to my entire application.
So let's do that right now.
Let's go over to Mango right here.
Okay.
And let's also open up config.
Don't go.
So in config, don't go.
I'm going to add a field to this called models.
And it's a type data package.
We just installed dot models.
All right.
And it did the import for me, and I'll save this to format it and I'll go back to Main Dog, go and
find the main func right near the top right here.
And where I populate this applet application config right after the weight I'll put in models and that's
now equal to a call to data dot new and I hand it TV, which I already have.
I got that right up there in line 27 and I put a comma after this and save it to format it.
And if I try compiling my application, make restart or actually make a start cause I see I just stopped
it.
Everything should compile.
And it did.
It compiled just perfectly.
Now we have access to the database, but we're not actually using anything in that database.
So in the next lecture will implement the logic for logging user in and logging you user out.
And of course, that will interact with the database.
It'll interact with Sessions, which interact with Redis.
It just gets us closer to having a functional application.
So we can finally get around to implementing some concurrent logic.
All right, let's move on.