Okay.
Now that we can interact with the database, let's go back to handlers.
Okay?
Go in the CMD slash web folder and let's implement the logic to log something in, or at least most
of it.
Okay.
So this function is actually called when someone goes to this page, log in.
And we're passing email, address and password and that's it.
So back over here.
What's going to happen is will attempt to log the user in, if we can, will put some information in
the session and redirect the user to a different page.
And if we can't, we'll take them back to this page with an error.
Okay.
So any time you're logging someone in or logging someone out, it's always a good idea to renew the
token that's stored in the session.
And fortunately, Alex Edwards X package makes that trivial.
So I'm going to ignore the response when I call from the app.
The variable that we go is part of the receiver dot session, dot renew token, and that just requires
the context context.
Okay, now the session token is renewed and we're going to try to log the user in.
So we're getting a post request to this.
So of course the standard thing you do is pass form post, and we do that by saying error is a sign
the value of from the request will pass the form.
If there's an error, it's not equal to nil, then we'll just abort error log dot, print line dot error.
And of course you'll do something more sophisticated in a production application.
Maybe take them back to that screen with an error message, whatever the case may be.
But we're just focused on getting this working so we can learn about concurrency, so we get past that,
which we always do.
Now we'll get the email and password from forum post, and that's easy email, which is the variable
I'm declaring right now.
A string is equal to our dot form dot get and if you look at the form the HTML, I need that particular
input email and we'll duplicate this and we'll call this one password are not from not get I called
that one password on the form.
So now I have the user credentials.
Now I try to get the user from the database by email address.
And now that we have those database functions implemented, it's simple.
I'll declare a available user while checking for an error when I call.
And here I will go to app dot models, dot user dot, get my email and that did the import for me.
So we're good to go.
And of course I pass email as a parameter to that function and I'll check for an error.
So I'll say if error is not equal to nil this time, I'll say after session I'm going to put something
in the session dot put.
And that requires the context are not context.
And I'm going to put it in with the key error and the value will be just invalid credentials or whatever
you want.
Okay, so I put that in there.
So that's stored in the session now and I'll redirect the user, take them back to the log in, page
htp, dot redirect and we'll go here to the homepage.
No, we're not going to go to the home page.
We're going to go to the login page.
That's better.
And we give them a status.
ACB dot status.
See other is fine, that'll get us going.
Okay.
And actually I missed two parameters.
I don't know why I've written this a million times.
The response writer, the request, where are we going?
And the status.
That's better and we just return.
We don't want to go any further.
Okay, so we return, which I eventually will spell, right?
Once we get past that, I found the user.
But let's validate the password.
So we'll check the password.
And that's as simple as calling valid password, which is just a variable name I'm choosing right now
valid password.
And again, an error comes from calling and now I call the method on that user type for the variable
I just got on line 26.
So user dot password matches right there.
And that requires one password, the user supplied password.
So that will take the password the user gives us.
Compare the hash that we have in the database with the password that supplied.
If they match valid password is true.
If they do not, then the user entered the wrong password.
Okay.
So we'll check for error here.
If error is not equal to nil that I'll do pretty much the same thing I did last time.
I'll just copy all of this, put it in here and that's sufficient.
I'm not going to give them any more information than invalid credentials because I don't want to give
too much information away.
Now we check to say if it's not a valid password, then they supplied the wrong password.
Okay.
And all we're going to say here is pretty much the same thing pasted in there.
And that will take care of it once again.
Don't give away too much information and log into screens.
Just let people know you can't log in.
But if I get past all of this, we've actually logged this user in.
So.
Okay.
So logged user.
Yep.
And how do we log a user in?
We just put something in the session.
What I'm going to put in is app dot session.
Try that again.
Session dot put.
And I'm going to put in using the context aka context.
And if you recall, user ID is what I'm going to put in when someone is actually logged in user ID,
that's what we're putting in there.
Okay.
So now that exists and now I can check to see if someone is authenticated in that render default data
bit or add default data function in the render page, render echo.
And I'm also going to put in app dot session because I might need it put.
And again with irked context, I'm going to put in the user, the whole user model that I got back that's
just user.
Now in order to make that happen, what I need to do is to go back to Domain DONGO And I have to register
that type when I start the session.
So let's find the bit where we make the session right here.
You can't just put something in the session willy nilly, as one says.
Instead, you actually have to add, you have to register it.
And fortunately, that's a one liner.
We just say garb, which is part of the standard library register, and we're going to register data
dot user and we have to put the empty or the curly brackets in like that.
Now I can store that in the session.
If I don't do that, the application will still compile and it'll still run.
But the moment someone tries to log in and does so successfully, you'll get an error saying I can't
store this in the session, don't know about the type.
And that's one of the features, if you will, of a strongly typed language.
Now back to handlers.
Docker, redirect the user.
Anytime you have a successful forum post, you want to redirect somewhere else so they don't accidentally
submit the form twice.
Okay.
So htp on redirect.
And this time I'll remember to put in w an hour, but I'll just take them to the home page and I'll
say export dot status C other and the only other thing I'll do.
You may also try out the session here.
Okay.
What I'm going to put in here is after session.
Try that again.
It's not a comment.
I'll put something in the session.
Just a welcome message or a successful log in message after session.
Dot put and I'll use my flash once so aka context and remember that flash and warning an error that
we have an ad default data.
We're going to try that.
It will put it in a flash message and I'll just put successful log in.
Okay, so let's try this out.
Let's reset our application, make restart.
And we'll go back to our Web browser and just make sure we get it.
All right.
Okay.
So I reload the page to make sure this is current and we have one user in the database and that is admin
at example dot com.
Okay.
And the password for that user is v e r y s e c r e t very secret.
All one word, all lowercase.
And I'll try logging in.
And it worked.
So we say we see the message successful.
Log in.
But if I reload this page, that should be gone because that's pulled out of the session using session
dot pop.
So it takes it out of the session, stores it in a variable that I can use and then immediately removes
it from the session.
So it's gone.
Perfect.
Now we have this logout button and if I click on that, we're going to get an empty screen because that's
a stub handler.
So let's go implement log out.
That one's really easy.
So I'll close my terminal and find the log out handler, wherever that is.
So home page, log in, page post log in, page.
There's log in.
Okay.
Logging out is as simple as once again destroying the session.
So clean up session.
So the first thing I'll do is just delete the session entirely.
So I'll ignore the error when I call app dot session dot destroy.
And this destroys the user session, but it needs the context.
So there's the contact and once they've logged out again, it's always good practice to renew the session
token app dot session dot renew token again with the context art context.
And now I just redirect.
So each endpoint redirect and we'll redirect using W and R to the homepage.
Now to the logging screen.
That's a good place to take them once they've logged out and achieved a status C other.
Okay, so let's restart the application make restart.
And because my session was stored in Redis, when I go back to my web browser, I should still be able
to go to any page like a home page and reload this.
And I'm still logged in.
And now you can see log out.
So let's click on log out and see if it works.
And we're do.
Now you notice that the log in link reappears here and the log out link disappeared there.
And I'm sure you're aware of this.
But if you go over here and look in CMT Web templates and find the nav bar right here, I'm just making
a little decision.
Remember, we added toward the default data that's passed to every single template this authenticated
and it's a boolean.
It's true when the user is logged in and false when the user is logged out.
So I just if you're not logged in, you see the register page, the link to it.
If you're if you are logged in, you see the log out link.
If you are not logged in, you see the log in link.
And the same idea happens with those alerts that appear at the top of the screen that comes from alert
stop partial logo each time out.
So we check to see if the data called flash dot flash, which is passed to every single page.
If that's not an equal string.
I just use bootstrap and display this with the class of alerts access.
So it's green.
If there's an error, I do the same thing, but I make it red and show what's ever in the error variable.
And then warning is just an alert warning with whatever's in the dot warning variable that every single
template gets.
Okay.
All right.
So now we can log in and we can log out.
Let's think about what we're going to do in these other handlers, because here's where we're finally
going to get to some concurrency.
Now, the Register page, it can stay pretty much the same, but once someone registers, let's just
wait some comments to see what we're going to do.
The first thing we're going to do is create a user.
Okay.
And that doesn't take long.
Then we want to send an activation email and that's what we'll start on next, is sending email concurrently
in the background because sending email can be expensive, not in terms of money or not just in terms
of money, depending how much you send, but in terms of processing time and a delay, I don't want
to sit there waiting.
After I've created the user while I connect to a slow mail server and maybe four or five or 10 seconds
go by before the email sent, I just wanted to fire off in the background.
Okay.
So send an activation email and then we want to subscribe the user to an account.
And that's just inserting one row in the database.
And I don't want to do anything else with this function until I actually get this function called.
So we'll send them an email with a link in it.
They're going to click that link and it will call this handler.
And here's where I want to do some more things.
So I'm going to want to say validate the URL to make sure that it's not just randomly generated by somebody
else.
I want to have some kind of secure link in the email.
Then I want to generate an invoice which might go it as an email.
Then I'm going to want to send an email with attachments.
I want to assume that whatever service this person is subscribing to, that they need some kind of documentation.
So if they get the bronze plan, I'll send the bronze documentation and the gold they'll get the gold
gold documentation and probably go as a customized PDF and we'll get to that later on and finally send
an email with a with the invoice attached.
Now we're going to do these things and these things using concurrency.
And of course it'll take a while before we get there, but we'll get started in the next section.