So let's get started working on the code for our final project and what we're going to be doing for
the next few lectures is actually just setting up the base code for a web application, and it'll be
a while before we get to concurrency.
Well, let's get started.
So I've opened a new folder in Visual Studio code called Final Dash Project.
And as usual, we need to go mod in it here, go on in it and I'll call this one final dash project.
It doesn't matter what I call it.
Okay, so there's my go on file, and now I'll create a new folder at the root level of my project called
CMT, which is pretty conventional.
And this is a web application.
So inside of CMT, I'll create one called Web, and inside of the web folder, I'll create a new file
called Main Dot Go, and it's in Package Main and I'll give it a main function func main.
Okay.
Now, this is a web application and in my case, I'm going to be listening on Port eight.
So I'll set up a constant web port.
I'll make that equal to the string 80.
Okay.
And we'll be using that in a little while.
Now inside of this function.
Let's write some comments from the things we're going to want to do.
We're going to have a database at some point.
So I'm going to want to connect to the database.
And we're also going to have to have some channels.
We won't get to those for a while, but let's create some channels.
Just a comment so we know what we're going to be working with here and we're going to want to wait group.
So we're going to create at least one weight group, weight group, and you'll see why.
But it'll take four or five lectures before we get there.
Finally, Will want to set up the application and think, okay, and then we're going to want to listen
for web connections.
Now, what else do we need to do here?
We definitely need to connect to the database.
But this what we're going to be building is a subscription service, and that's going to allow people
to create accounts, which means they're going to be able to log in.
So let's add another comment here as well.
Since people are going to be logging in and since this is a web application and we're going to be serving
templates right from here, we're not doing client side page rendering like React or view.
We'll just do a simple web app where all of the rendering of pages is done on the server side.
And that means we're going to have to manage sessions.
So let's say create sessions, whatever is required to make that happen.
So we're definitely going to have that.
And down here, after I create the application config, one of the things we're going to do whenever
somebody buys a subscription for a website or creates an account, you're going to be sending email.
And that's an ideal situation to take advantage of, goes concurrency functionality.
So let's add another comment here.
We're going to set up mail, mail, however that works.
Okay.
And we'll get to that before too long.
So they're at a very high level are the kinds of things this main function is going to take care of,
will initialize a database, will create some sessions, will create some channels.
We're going to need a weight group and we're going to be using that right away.
I can see that if I'm going to be sending email in this application and I'm going to be sending email
concurrently, if someone decides to restart the application for whatever reason, maybe you're going
to do some maintenance or whatever it is.
You don't want to just say, stop the application.
You actually want to wait until any mail that is waiting to be sent gets delivered and then you quit.
And of course, that's an ideal situation for a wait group.
So they're at a very high level are the kinds of things we're going to want to do.
Now, let's think about sessions to start with and some things we're going to have to import into this
project.
Let's just take care of our go gets right now.
So I'll open my terminal and clear the screen.
First thing for the database I'm going to use Postgres and there's a couple of different drivers out
there for Postgres.
One is called I think PCU.
It's been a while since I've used it, but if you actually read the documentation for that right in
the front page of the GitHub repository, it says, and don't use this one, use Jack CS instead.
So let's go get the necessary things for Jack CS Postgres driver so I'll go get from GitHub dot com
slash jack C slash PG con and that will get the first thing I need.
Okay.
So that gets that.
Now I'll clear the screen and go and get from again GitHub dot com slash and jack C slash PG X slash
v4 and if V5 happens to be out when you take this course, please install V4.
If we increase the major version for a particular project, that usually means there are breaking changes.
So install v4 for this course and a V5 is out and it shouldn't be for some time yet.
But if it is, just use this version and then upgrade after the fact.
It will make your life ever so much easier.
So we'll go get that.
So that's a driver for our database.
Now for sessions, you could use guerrilla sessions.
There's all kinds of them out there, but one that I really like and one that he's never let me down
is done by Alex Edwards, and that's the one I'm going to get.
So I will go and get from GitHub dot com.
Try that again.
GitHub dot com slash Alex Edwards slash s c.
S slash v2.
And the same logic applies here.
If there's a V3 stick with V2 for this course.
Okay.
So we'll go and get that.
And one of the nice things about Alex Edwards session management management package is it allows different
stores for session data.
You can store it in the database in a cookie, but I want to use Redis.
And Redis is a really fast in-memory cache and it's super simple to use with this session manager.
So we'll get the necessary package for that.
Go and get from GitHub dot com slash Alex Edwards slash SC s slash Revis store like that.
Okay.
So we'll go and get that.
And the last thing I want to worry about right now is this is going to be a web application.
It's going to allow people to register for a service and to buy things and to log in and to log out.
And while we could do everything with the standard library, it's pretty customary for go developers
working on a web applications to use some third party router, and one that I really like is called
the Chey River.
So let's get that now because we're going to need it momentarily.
Okay.
So I will go and get from GitHub icon slash, go dash key slash V5.
And that should go and get it for me.
And I must have mistyped the address.
Yes, I did.
Goce slash g slash v5.
Try that again.
There.
That adds that.
And I don't know if I need to do this, but just to be safe, I'll put slash V5 slash middleware because
we'll be using the middleware for this package as well.
Looks like it already has it.
Okay.
So there are all of our go gets and that gives me I think right now at least most of the things I'm
going to need as I work on this web application.
The only thing that I'm not sure about and again, this is just I think it's already installed, but
let's just make sure I hit the up arrow a couple of times back to the Jack C bit.
So after Jack C v4, we might need to do this.
I can never remember, but it won't hurt to return here.
I just added std lib to that command.
So go get github dot com slash jack c slash pg x slash v4 slash s.t.d. lib.
Yeah, it was installed, so we didn't need to do that.
That was an unnecessary step, but it didn't hurt anything.
Okay, so when the next lecture we'll start populating these comments or underneath these comments with
some of the things we need to actually make this application start up.
So let's move on.