So in this project, we're going to be using Postgres as a database.
We're going to be using Redis as a store for our session information.
And we're also going to require some kind of mail server, a dummy mail server that will capture mail
for us.
And I want to use Docker for that and I really encourage you to do so as well.
I've had a number of people say to me, Don't Docker, slow my system down.
It never has.
As I said a couple of times, I'm running this on a seven year old Mac and Docker works just fine.
So I encourage you to do that.
Now.
If you want to install Redis locally and you want to install Postgres locally and so on and so forth,
you feel free to do so.
But I really encourage you to give Docker a try.
It works really well and it is not that resource intensive.
So to make that happen, what I'm going to do is have you go to the course resources for this lecture
and you see a file there called Docker Dash, composed with a small dot zip.
Download that file, unzip it and put it as I have at the root level of my project.
So right beside the cmd folder, right beside go to AdMob, go to mod, there's my file, docker compose,
let's give it a look.
And then just in case you don't have Docker installed, I'll show you where to go and get that.
So this is a very simple Docker compose and what this allows me to do is to start what you see here,
three services Postgres.
So Postgres 14.2 is the version I'm going to use for this course Redis And I'm just using the latest
version of Redis.
It doesn't really matter, but the latest one will do the trick.
And then Mail Hog, which is an unfortunate name, but this is a dummy mail server and it allows us
to send the email without actually sending email mail home, captures it, and it offers a web interface
where we can go and look at our email.
So we'll start this in a minute.
But if you don't have Docker installed, also one of the course resources for this lecture, you'll
see a link to this Web page right here.
And these are the instructions for a mac.
But as you can see on the left hand side, there's instructions for windows and there's also instructions
for Linux.
Okay.
So so it doesn't matter what operating system you're on.
The instructions are pretty simple.
Now, just a word of caution about the version for Mac.
If you're on an older Mac, like like I am with an intel chip, this is the one you want.
If you're on a mac with one of Apple's own chips, the M1 or the M1, ultra or one of those, then you
want this one.
Make sure you get the right one.
So install that.
So once you have that installed, let's go back to our I.D. and I'll bring it up.
Now, as you can see here on line 16 of my doctor compose y email, I'm saying have a volume stored
the data for Postgres in the current directory.
That's what the dot means then.
Then in a folder called DB Data, they're in a folder called Postgres.
Now, in a lot of cases, Docker will create that for you.
But I'm not an optimist, so I'm going to create a new folder at the root level of my project called
DV Dash Data, and inside of that I will create two folders.
The first one is for Postgres and it's just called Postgres.
And the second one is a new folder for Redis.
Okay.
Now, once I've done that, I can open my terminal and clear my screen and type docker dash, compose
up, dash de.
Okay, now the dash de will run this in the background and I'm going to do that.
So here, return.
And what'll happen is it creates and starts all of these.
Now they're starting right now and you can see it created all of these files for Postgres and there's
probably some for Redis as well.
Not yet, but it'll get there eventually.
Okay.
So I'm going to hide that and I'm going to go to on a mac.
I just go to the little Docker icon like this on Windows.
It's in your system tray and I'll bring up the dashboard.
And I click on containers and then I expand this final project and I'll click on, say, the Postgres.
And it takes a while the very first time it starts it because it has to initialize the database.
And what it's doing is not just initializing an empty database store and it seems to be finished here.
Back over in my Docker compose, it's actually creating a database called concurrency and you access
it using this username Postgres and this password, which is just password.
Okay.
So that creates all of that for us.
Now once that's up and running, you're going to want to get your favorite database client as well.
And I recommend you use this one and I'll put a link through this in the course resources as well.
It's called Beekeeper Studio, and there are versions for Mac and there are versions for Windows.
You can just click on the download button up here and it will take you to the one appropriate for your
operating system.
And as you can see, it supports Windows, Mac and Linux.
So if you don't have a Postgres client and this is one means of just connecting to the database and
looking at it so we don't have to use the command line.
And it's really easy to use and it's free and I think there's some paid version of it.
I'm not.
Yeah, the ultimate edition.
But you want the community edition right here because it's free and it will do the trick for us.
So get Docker installed, bring up Docker, compose, let it run for a while to make sure the database
is initialized and download Beekeeper studio if you need a client.
Okay, let's move on.