So at this point we should have Docker installed in, we should have our Docker images up and running.
So if you recall in the last lecture I ran Docker, compose up a dash D and bring it down.
And I'm not going to do it right now and I'm sure you know this, but to bring it down, it's just Docker
Dash compose down and that will bring it down.
But I want it up right now.
So the next step is to set up the database.
So back over and mainboard go.
We want to connect to the database.
But before I do that, let's make sure that we can actually connect to the database using Beekeeper.
So I'll bring a beekeeper and I'll select a connection type of Postgres and all the information I need
to fill out here is right here in Docker Compose.
There's my user, there's my password, there's my database, and I'm connecting to the local host on
this port.
Five, four, three, two.
So I'll leave it as Postgres.
Local host five four, three, two.
User is postgres password is password.
My default database is named concurrency and I'll test my connection.
Okay, so we can connect.
I got connection.
Looks good down here and that's all I need to worry about right now for that.
So now let's go back to mean don't go and start connecting to the database.
Now I could write all the code right in my main function, but I think it would be cleaner to put it
in its own function.
So I'll refer to a function that doesn't exist yet in it.
DB Okay, then I'll come down here outside of the main function and create a new func called DB.
It takes no parameters and it's going to return a pointer to sequel.
DB like that.
Okay.
So this is a pretty simple function, but I'm going to have this function actually call another function
just so I can try to connect to the database repeatedly if necessary.
Okay.
Not necessary to do this, but I think it's a little cleaner.
So I'll declare a variable con and that comes from calling yet another function that doesn't exist yet
connect to.
DB Okay, and I'll check to see if it's succeeded by checking to see if con is nil.
If con is equal to nil, then we have something that we really can't resolve right now.
So I'll just logged out panic and I'll just say can't connect to database.
Okay.
And the actual connection finally will take place in a function called connect to DB.
It takes no parameters and it returns a pointer to sequel dot db.
Okay, now what I'm going to do is try to connect to the database some fixed number of times, and if
I can't do it after that many tries, then will just die.
Okay, so we'll set a variable.
Account's assigned the value of zero.
And then we'll connect to the database and I'll assume that I'm going to get my connection string as
an environment variable.
So I'll get my DSN my connection string.
It comes from The O.C. What's The O.C. package?
Right in the standard library.
We'll get an environment variable and I'll call that environment variable.
DSN So now I have my count set to zero, I have my connection string and I'll just start falling inside
of that.
I'll say connection and error come from calling open DB which doesn't exist yet, but it will in a minute.
DSN Okay, so let's go down here and write that open DB function func open DB and that takes DSN, which
is a string.
And this will return two things.
Hopefully it'll return a pointer to a sequel.
DB Our connection pool and potentially it returns an error.
Now this might seem like a lot of functions, but this is just a way for me to keep things really clean
and make sure that I have multiple attempts to connect to the database.
And this one's really simple.
So we're going to declare a variable DB while checking for an error.
When I call from the cycle package, which is part of the standard library open and I'm going to open
the type PG X and then work until I import some things at the top.
And we'll do that in a moment and I can add my connection.
String DSN okay.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll return nil in the air.
And then just to be safe, we'll say error is now equal to if we get past that, we have a connection
connection pool.
But just to be safe, I'll say air equals v dot ping.
I'll try to ping the database.
And again, if we have an error, we'll return it.
So I'll copy this code.
And paste it here.
And if we get past that, we just return DB and nil.
And up here I see I misspelled DSN up here.
After I check for that connection will say if error is not equal to nil, then we don't have a connection
yet.
But I don't want to give up just yet.
So I'll just say logged off print line postgres not yet ready to die otherwise.
Else we didn't connect.
So we'll say logged out print line connected to database will return our connection.
Return connection.
Now if we have that error, we don't want to stop at this point.
We want to try a few more times.
So I'll say if counts is greater than ten, if count is bigger than ten, if we can't connect intense
tries, then something went wrong.
So we'll just return nil.
Otherwise we'll say logged out print line, backing off for 1/2,
timed out sleep and we're going to sleep one time timed out second.
10 seconds should be enough time to connect to the database and we'll just say continue.
So there there is the code that we can use to connect to the database.
Now, we still have some work to do because although if we look at the top of our file up here, it's
imported database sequel.
That's just the standard library cycle driver.
So we have to import a few more things and we'll use the blank identifier saying even though this package
isn't directly used in the code, we still need to have it.
So we'll put it in GitHub dot com slash jack c slash pkg com.
And again we'll use GitHub dot com slash check C slash pkg x slash v4.
Then we'll duplicate that line and we'll add slash STD Libbi at the end.
Okay.
So at this point, we can now try to connect to the database.
So we'll put a variable here like this.
DV is assigned a value of any DB and just to get it to compile are picking the database right here.
So db up ping.
Okay.
Now at this point, I should be able to open my terminal, my, my back end docker images are running
and I should be able to run this program.
But of course I need a DSN now.
We could, if we wanted to, actually just set an environment variable and run the program.
But I think this is the point where we should start using, make sure you install that way back in the
first section and it's going to make our lives a lot easier.
So in the next lecture we'll set up a Makefile and we'll try running this and see if we can actually
connect to the database.
All right, let's move on.