So this time around, we want to set up a make file just to make our lives a little bit easier.
And the process is a little bit different in on Windows than it is on Mac.
But to speed things along, if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see two files.
One is called Makefile dot zip, and that's for Mac or Linux, and the other one is called Makefile,
dot windows, dot zip.
And obviously that's for windows.
So download the one appropriate for your operating system, unzip it and put it at the root level of
your project and make sure it's called Makefile with a capital M and no extension.
Okay.
And before we actually look at that, I did have a couple of typos in the last lecture.
And you think I would have noticed that because, you know, the whole bright red color in the mango
file name here.
But apparently I wasn't that alert last time around and they're easy fixes.
The first one is here in mango in line for the line 34 function called in DB in my code I didn't return
anything.
And of course I just have to go return corn.
Okay.
And the second one is down here in this for loop.
Even though I have the variable counts, I never actually incremented count.
So I need to do that counts plus plus.
And I fixed both of those typos before I uploaded the source code for the last lecture.
Okay.
So in any case, now let's have a look at the Makefile and I'll go to the Mac version first Mac and
Linux and then I'll go through the windows.
So it's a really simple file at the very top.
I have three variables and these are substituted down here.
So for example, I have binary underscore name is equal to my app and down here each of these is a command
I can type after I type the keyword make.
So if I type make build of the command line in the same directory where this Makefile exists, it will
build the binary.
So here it runs the on c c go enabled is set the zero which is good good practice for building a binary.
If you're not using zygote now then I just build it and you can see that binary name in curly brackets
with a dollar sign in front of it that's substituted for.
Or we get a substitution there for my app.
Okay, so we can build it, we can run it, we can clean it, which is clean the binary and runs go
clean.
Start is just an alias for run stop stops everything and restart first run stop then run start and we
have test for running tests.
We'll get to that eventually.
Okay.
Now, one key thing you have to know about make files is here.
That has to be a tab.
You can't use spaces, it has to be a tab.
So if for some reason when you download this, those are converted to spaces which apparently has happened
at some point in the past.
I don't know why.
Just change them all to tabs and you'll be fine.
Okay, so that's the version for Mac and Linux.
Now the Windows version right here, unfortunately, you're not going to see any any coloration here
because Windows doesn't mean anything to my idea.
But the process is almost the same.
Just some of the commands are different.
So like line 12, for example, a little bit different.
So we have, as you can see here and DSN, that's our data source name, that's for connecting to Postgres
and that's the one we care about right now.
And I exist so obviously over the other other one as well.
And in this case for Windows, I just put a dot xy at the name of the binary name so Windows will know
it's an executable.
Okay, so I have the appropriate file name to make file and I'm in the final project folder right at
the root level.
So I'm in the correct directory.
And if I type else, you can see that the make file is right there.
And if I type make start, this should run my application and connect to the database.
If we get everything right, let's find out.
It's building it.
It connected to the database.
Life is good and at this point it's actually terminated in finished because it is not doing anything
else.
If you look in the main ego file over here, all we're doing is connecting to the database, pinging
it, and then the application terminates.
But at least I know I connected to the database without any problem.
Okay.
In the next lecture, we'll get started with sessions.
So let's move on.