So we've managed to connect to the database successfully, and the next step is to connect to Redis
and initiate our sessions.
And that's really simple.
So here in mean don't go under the comment, create sessions.
Let's call a function that doesn't exist yet, which seems to be really popular these days session,
which is just a local variable I'm declaring it's a sign the value of init session ticked up.
Okay, now let's scroll down to the very bottom of the file and let's initialize the session.
So we're going to have a function here which I'll call in its session.
It takes no parameters and it returns a pointer to from the SC US package.
That's Alex Edwards version two dot session manager right there.
Okay.
So it's a new sessions manager.
That's what we're going to be returning.
And we're also going to have another function here underneath it.
And this one will connect to it and I'll call it in it.
Revis Now we already have Redis running as part of our Docker compose file and this function will return
a pointer to a retasked pool right there.
Okay.
So let's connect to read it first.
Now, this is dead simple.
We'll create a variable, which I'll call read his pool, which is a pool of reddest connections.
And that comes from a reference to the type red is dark pool.
Right there.
And we fill in the necessary fields so we'll save maximum time for an idle connection.
Is ten, which is a good default.
I have to spell.
I'll write though.
That's ten.
Okay.
And then we just dial the read a server and we just use an inline function.
With reddish scone.
That's the first parameter and potentially there and we return reddest on dial.
And just like we did with the with the database with Postgres, I will assume that this TCP connection
that the string comes from over, don't get on credit.
Now the great thing about this is in our Makefile, we've already specified that environment variable.
Okay, so that's really simple.
And then down here we have this is a closing collar.
And outside of this, we return red as pool.
Okay, so that will get us a red us connection.
Now let's initialize the session.
So this is really simple.
We'll say set up session, and all we do is say session, which is the variable I'm declaring right
now.
It's assigned the value of from the X package new.
Okay.
And then we just set some attributes on it.
So what are we going to use for store session, dot store?
Well, we're using Redis.
That's going to be equal to read this store, which I have to spell.
Right.
Read a store dot new and then I call that function.
I just wrote in it.
Read us.
Okay.
So that tells the session store all of your information for every session in Redis.
Then we'll set some good default session.
Lifetime.
How long should it last?
Well, let's make it 24 times.
Time.
Got our.
Okay.
The last four one day session dot cookie right there.
And we'll set some cookie attributes to persist.
Do we want this to persist between visits to the website?
Sure.
We'll make that true.
Session dot cookie, dot.
Same site.
I'll make that equal to HD.
This is a consent from the HTTP package.
It should be dot.
Same site lacks mode.
Okay.
That's sufficient for purposes.
And session dot cookie dot secure will make that equal to true.
It won't actually be secure in a local host connection, but it will be when it goes live.
Okay.
So we have that.
Now we return the session and up here we still have an error in our code because we're not using the
session right now, but we'll be doing that in the next lecture when we actually set up the application
config.
We're going to skip these two for now and we'll set up the config.
Then we'll come back to these two.
Okay.
So at this point, our code will not run because we have an error, but that's because we're just in
the middle of things and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.