All right.
So we have a session now and we have a connection to the database.
And now it's time to, as I said, last lecture, start working on this bit.
We're going to skip the channels and the weight group for the moment, and we'll come back to those
later on.
But right now, let's set up the application configuration and I'm going to do that by going over here
to my Explorer and I'll create a new file and I'll put it in the CMT Web folder.
Okay, so new file and this will be called Configure.
Okay.
And it's in package me
and what we're going to do here is set up a type and the type will be config.
And this is the type we're going to use on the receiver for the various parts of our application to
share the application configuration.
And it's just a struct and it has a few fields and we'll be adding new fields as time goes on.
The first one is our session and it's a of type pointer to export session manager right there and that
does the import for me.
The second one is DB, which we might not use, but I'll put it in there for now.
It's a pointer to SQL DB.
The third one will be an info log, which we haven't done yet, but it's an information log and it's
a type pointer to log dot logger.
And this is just a convenient way of writing things to the console or to a log file.
We'll also have an error log, which would be a pointer to log logger.
And we're also going to have a weight group, which I'll just call.
Wait.
I think that's a good name.
And it's a type pointer to Sync Dog Waker, which you're already familiar with.
Okay, so let's save this.
That is a good starting point for our configuration.
So let's go back over to me and I'll go and use this.
Okay, so I'll get rid of this DB ping because we're not going to need that in a moment.
And down here, let's create a wake group which will be using momentarily or in a lecture or two, probably.
And it's just called WG and it's a of type sync don't wait group.
And of course, I have to put the curly brackets.
Now, let's set up the application config.
So we'll create a variable called app and it's assigned the value of the type config and we'll populate
its various fields.
So we have session and of course that's the variable session from line 26.
We have DB.
And of course that's the variable DV from line 23.
And we have weight, which is a weight group.
And that's a reference to the variable WG from line 31.
Okay.
So now let's take some time and set up some loggers as well.
We might as well.
So right here, I'll just say create loggers.
And this is simple stuff.
Info log is assigned the value of from the log package dot new and we're going to make this go to OS
straight.
And of course, in production, you'll probably have this writing to a file but we're not in production
will prefix it with the word info in all caps and then a tab character.
And what we're going to log is that log dot l date the date and then a pipe and then logged on l time.
And let's duplicate this whole thing and make this one error log
and we'll prefix it with error in a tab and we'll still have log l date analog l time.
But then we want to find out where there took place.
So we'll put log dot l short file.
Okay.
And then down here in our app config, we can now put in info log is info log and we can put an error
log is error.
Look.
Okay.
So now we have an application config.
And again, we'll be adding to this as time goes on.
But this is enough to get us started, at least now.
The next step, of course, we're going to be setting up mail.
Before too long, we're going to be creating channels probably at the same time we set up mail.
The next step is actually to listen for web connections, and that requires that we have something like
a roots file using that goce package we imported.
And also at least one handler.
And again, our application doesn't compile right now because we have that app variable we're not using,
but we're in the middle of things.
And by the end of the next lecture or the one after that, we'll be able to start this up.