So at the moment our application does not compile because here in the main dog go file, we have this
variable app and we're not using it and we'll be using that when we start listening for web connections.
But before we can do that, we need to set up a few things.
We need to set up some handlers.
So in the CMG web folder or create a new file called handlers, which I have to spell, write handlers
don't go.
We'll also need some routes and I'll put those in here as well.
See any web new file routes, docker.
And you might notice that I added a templates folder here.
Just ignore that you'll be adding that yourself in a few lectures for the moment.
Let's go back to our handlers and get that set up so handlers don't go.
And obviously this is in package, mate.
Okay.
And we need to create at least one handler.
And what I'll do is just create a handler for a home page that doesn't exist yet.
So I create a function and this will have the receiver app pointer to the type config.
Okay.
So we'll have access to everything we populated into that config variable named app in the main go file
before too long.
Okay.
So this is a very simple handler and I should put a stubborn here for now.
I'll call it home page.
And because it's a handler, it requires two arguments a response writer which I'll call w http dog
response writer right there.
And it also requires a pointer to a request, which I'll call error, and that's a pointer to HTTP request
and that's just going to stay empty for right now.
Okay.
So it's a stub handler.
Now let's go over to this roots dot go file and create some roots.
So again, this is in packaging which I have to spell, right?
And we're going to create a function with the receiver of app pointer to config.
Again, our application config.
And we'll just call this roots and it's going to return an HTTP dog handler.
And this is where we're going to use the mux rotor.
So the first thing we'll do is create a rudder and we'll call nine months for multiplexing, which is
pretty common.
And it's a type cheeked new rudder.
New rudder.
And I've got to make sure I get the right one because I have multiple versions installed.
That's the one I want, version five.
So it gives me a new rudder and we're going to set up some middleware and we'll use right now some of
the middleware that comes bundled with that rudder, which makes it such a great package.
So to use middleware with the key router has just maxed out use and then name the middleware you want.
And this one is going to be straight from the middleware package that comes as part of Cheat.
So I'll use middleware DOT and I'm looking for the recover right there.
And again, I need to make sure it's version five and it is.
So now I has a middleware and now let's create a root, a root to the home page.
So we'll say define application roots and we're going to have a MUX, get any get requests that goes
to this slash is going to use app dot homepage and then we just say return mux.
Okay?
And that's all we have to worry about for this for right now.
Obviously, we'll be adding things here as time goes on.
But now I can go back over to Mango.
And what I'm going to do is set up a new function here outside of the main function, which I'll call
surf.
Okay?
And it doesn't return anything.
But what it does is start a web server, so start HTP server and this is simple create a variable called
SRB for serve and it's of the type a reference to a checkpoint server server right there.
Okay.
And I just populate some fields for right now we can just put in the address EDR and I'm listening if
you remember, we have that constant web port at Port 80, so I'll use the format as print, f, package
or function.
And my format string is just a colon which this particular type requires a colon and then a percent
s and my substitution is the constant webhook.
Okay.
So that's the address we're going to listen on port 84, any IP address on this particular machine.
And then we have to define what's handler's URL.
And the handler in this case is just a call to output routes.
Okay.
Now, of course, to have access to that variable app, I'm probably going to want to put a receiver
right here receiver.
So app pointer to config, that makes more sense.
And I have access to apt routes.
And with that SRB variable, I'll just print out some information.
So I'll say app dot info log and I'll print out print line.
Starting Web server went off to start the server.
And that is as simple as calling.
Well, I'm going to populate the variable error.
When I call server listing answer, I check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
If I can't start the web server, I'm just going to panic.
Logged out panic with the error.
Okay.
And up here in the main function, I just call app dot server.
And that should allow me to actually start the application now.
So let's open our terminal and clear the screen.
And if I do, unless there's my Makefile, so I should be able to type make start and it builds my application.
And now it's running and it's running.
You might notice in the background I have my command prompt back.
Okay, so it actually started.
Now if I try to hit that, I'm going to get a blank screen because my handler is empty right now for
the home page.
But I can also type make it stop and that should stop it.
And it stopped.
Perfect.
So we're much closer now.
So the next step is to actually go and make this handler the home page, render some kind of home page.
Okay.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.