So we have this home page handler.
We have a route to this handler and we can compile and start our application.
But of course, we can't actually display pages yet.
So to make that happen, we need to write some code that will render go templates.
And we actually need some templates and a save some time because this is not a course on writing go
templates.
If you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a file called Templates Dot Zip.
You can download that, unzip it and then put it right here in the cmd web folder and in it'll be in
a templates folder.
But make sure all of these HTML files are in a folder called templates.
And let's have a look at these.
These are pretty simple.
So of course, the base start layout don't go to HTML.
That's the base layout for every template.
And as you can see, we just define it with the name base.
We give it a dock type and an opening HTML tag, an opening body tag, a closing body tag and closing
a HTML tag and everything else is either another template, as is the case for the header.
The Napper, this thing called alerts, the footer and the ones that are left over are blocks where
we can specify the content where we want for our actual page.
So we have one for content and we have one for JavaScript.
Okay.
And that should be sufficient for our purposes.
And all of these included ones.
Well, they have the name dot partial dot go each HTML.
So the header for example, looks like this header dot partial HTML.
And there it is.
You have a head section that imports the bootstrap JavaScript or access that I'll be using and I just
override one of the things in the default bootstrap.
I like the labels on forms to be in bold.
The footer which is right here.
Footer up.
Partial duck html.
Not surprisingly, it displays a footer and you can see I'm going to be passing some data to this template.
DOT Now is the value of time.
DOT Now and then I just read the year from it and print that out and I import the boots bootstrap JavaScript.
Okay, so the templates are nothing special.
They're pretty easy to use and of course we'll be modifying some of these as time goes on.
This will give us something to start with.
So that's the template, those are the templates themselves.
Now I actually need to create something that will render those templates.
So in CMT, when let's close the templates folder and let's create a new file in there, which I'll
call render up.
And this is where we'll put our renderer.
And of course this is in Package Main and the first thing I'll do is declare a variable just called
path to templates.
I'm going to do this.
So when I write tests, I won't run into the problem of having having to somehow override a string that's
a constant.
So I'll just put the path, the templates which will be the root level of my application DOT, then
CMT, then web, then templates.
Okay, that's where the template is, your store.
And now I'm also going to need something to store data in that I'm going to pass to the templates.
So I'll just create a struct type, I'll call it template data and it will be a struct.
And this is the kind of things I'm going to be passing the templates.
I might not use all of these, but I'm going to put them in there anyway just in case I need them.
So I might need to pass a string map, a map of strings, and it's a map of string string.
Okay.
And I might need one for ints, one for floats, and then data that I can store anything in.
So the next one I'll call in math.
And it's a map of string, which is the key I'll use to look things up in integers and then say a float
map, which is a map of type string float 64.
And then data.
I can just put anything I want in there.
So a map of string and I can use any because I'm using go 1.8 or one point 18.2, I think.
But if you're not if you're using an earlier one, well, you should upgrade your go.
But if you can't for some reason just put interface like that, it's functionally equivalent to the
type or the new keyword any and that only came out and go 1.18.
I'm also going to want to pass messages so like alerts of some sort and I'll use one for flash, just
a catchall.
And I said type string.
I'll also be passing warnings possibly of type string and error of type string.
Okay, I'll format those depending on what they are.
If it's a success message, it'll be green.
If it's an error message will be read.
Something like that.
I'll also need to know if the users are authenticated, so I'll just make it an integer.
One You're authenticated.
Zero, you're not.
And I'm going to be passing a time value called now because I'm using that in the footer and I just
timed up time.
Okay.
And the last thing I might want to pass to a template is a user type.
Okay, now, that doesn't exist yet.
I'm going to put it here like this user and it will be a pointer to data dot user, which we haven't
actually implemented yet.
So I'll comment that.
So let me say this will be coming back to that later on.
Once we have the user's table and so forth set up in the database and have all the necessary data types
and models associated with that.
So that's just a placeholder just to remind me later on.
Now let's start with a simple render function func with the receiver app pointer to config and I'll
just call this render.
Then when I go to render a page, I'm going to pass it.
I'm going to need certain information.
I'm going to need the response writer because I have something I have to have something to write to.
WPC To be the response writer right there and the request pointer to HDP dot request.
I'm also going to need the name of the template.
I want to render some T for template that's just a string.
And the last thing is template data.
What data am I going to be passing to the template?
And every template will get some data and that will be a pointer to the type I just define template
to.
Okay.
So as I'm sure you're aware, the way the go templates work is pretty straightforward.
But if I have one template that depends on a partial or a layout or anything like that, then I need
to include all of those templates and direct the full path name to every one of them.
When I go to to pass the templates, so let's make it really easy on ourselves as to declare variable
partials and that is assigned the value of a slice of string.
Okay.
And then I'll put in every single partial that I have and I'll do it.
Of course, this way format is printouts and my format string will be percent SW slash and then the
name of the template I have to have.
But if you look at them, you'll see that you have to have based on layout go html layout not go HTML.
Okay.
And my substitution for that will be passed to templates.
That's my first one.
Now I'll duplicate this for more times.
One, two, three, four.
And then I'll just change the name over here.
So I had to have based on layout, and then I have to have header, not partial.
And then I have to have never partial.
That's just a standard bootstrap navigation bar that appears at the top of the screen.
Then I have to have footer partial.
And the last thing I have to have is called alerts dot partial.
Okay.
And that's where I'll display a flash message, success message or a warning message.
We'll look at that later on.
So right now, I have that slice of strings.
Now I need to declare a new variable template slice.
And that will be of the type a slice of string.
Okay.
And what I'm going to do is take all of these, the ones that are in this slice of strings called partial.
And the one I've received here and I'll put them together into this slice.
And this is a little lengthier than it has to be, but it's simple enough.
So I'll say template, slice, dot or equals append and I'm going to append to template slice.
Format.
S print f then my format string is percent s slash percent.
S And my two subset substitutions are path to templates and t, which I received as a parameter to this
function.
I see I missed an error.
That's better.
Okay.
So that's now in the slice template slice and then I'll put everything else in there.
So I could have just appended this to that, but that's fine.
I'm just making it very, very readable.
This makes it clear that these have to be here for every template I want to render, and this is the
actual template I want to render.
So I'll go for ignoring the first parameter, but I'll pay attention to the current iteration and I'll
arrange through partials.
Okay then all I do now is say template slice equals append template slice x.
Okay, so now I have them in there and it's my IDs.
Ivey's already giving me warnings saying there's a more concise way to do this, but I don't care.
This is sufficient for my purposes now when this render function is called, because that last parameter,
the data I want to pass to the template that might or might not have a value, which is why I made it
made it a pointer, because at this point I can say if that's a nil, if there's nothing in that last
parameter, when I go to render a template, then I'll say, if t d is equal to nil, I'll say T is
equal to a reference to template data.
Again, template data if that's okay.
So now it's an empty item, which is at least not a nil because I can't do anything with nil.
Now I need to pass the templates and this is standard stuff you do with the template html, that package
from the standard library.
So I'll declare a variable tempo while checking for an error when I call template files right there
and I'm going to pass the files template slice, dot, dot, dot, everything in that slice.
So pass them all.
Check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil,
then I'll save that UDP error
and I'll give it w e r dot error and I'll just call it htp dot status internal server error.
Okay.
And I'll also return because I can't go any further now to make it more useful for myself.
Here's for I can use that apt error log and print out the error print line.
On the air.
And that will give me something I can look at to see what went wrong.
Don't.
I've done that.
The last step is to execute the template.
If there is a sign the value of tempo to execute and I'm going to pass it w and I'm also for it now
I'll say nil.
Okay.
But I'm going to pass some data in there and check for an error.
Error is not equal to nil.
Then again, I'll go with these lines right here.
Copy and paste.
Okay.
Now that, Neal, this is where I'm going to be passing template or data to a template and we're going
to be doing that all the time.
But there are certain kinds of data I want to pass to every single template.
So what could I do to make sure that every template get some data?
What I can do is write another function and I'll do it right below this one and I'll call this func
with the receiver app pointer to config again and I'll call this one and default data and it's going
to require TD, which is a pointer to template data.
It's going to require the hour, which is the request to pointer to HTTP a pointer to HTTP request,
and it's going to return a pointer to template it.
Now let's give ourselves some room here and start writing this pretty easy.
We already have the type defined at the top of this file.
We have flash data warning, so on and so forth.
So what we can do here is say TD Dot Flash, the very first one that's going to be equal to from the
app receiver on the session I'm going to call pop string.
And what that will do is make sure that as soon as this data is read, it's removed from the session,
which is really convenient for messages that you only want to display once.
Now the parameters for that, it requires the context.
Well, I get that from the request marked context, and it also requires the key to look up, which
I'll call flash, which seems to make the most sense.
Okay, now I'll duplicate that two more times and I'll change this one to warning this one to error.
And I'll assume that the key I'm going to use to get this information out of the session is warning
for warning and not surprisingly, error for error.
Okay.
Now, the next thing I want to find out, because this is this site, this subscription site we're building,
it's going to have a login screen and it's going to allow people to buy things.
I need to have some means of determining whether or not someone is authenticated.
Now, how am I going to do that?
Well, what I'm going to do is write another function to check to see if someone is authenticated and
call it from here.
So let's come down here below this and say func app pointer to config and we'll call this one is authenticated.
Okay.
And it's going to require require just a request a pointer to HDP dot request because from that I can
get session information and it's going to return a bullet.
True or false?
And all I have to do is to see when someone is logged in.
Is there some way I can tell whether or not that user's actually authenticated?
Well, what I'll do, just like here, I'm assuming there's going to be a flash or a warning or an error
in the session.
I'll assume that when someone logs into the site, I'll put a value in the session and I'll probably
call it user ID.
That seems to make the most sense.
So I'll say exists, which is a variable I'm checking or creating right now, and I'll just call from
app dot session dot exists.
And all that requires is the context, ah, dot context.
And what I'm looking for, and I'll call it user ID, which I usually do.
Okay.
So that will be true.
Exists will be true.
If I can find something in this user session with that key and it will be false otherwise.
So all I have to do now is say instead of assigning a variable, I can just say return.
That seems a little cleaner.
Okay.
And up here I can say TD dot is 15 dot authenticated equals app dot is authenticated right there and
hand that.
Okay.
So what do we have here?
That's not going to work because this is a tight end and this is a tight ball.
Maybe I should do it this way instead.
If app is authenticated or if that returns true, then do something.
Okay.
And I'll say TD dot authenticated equals.
True.
And then I come up here.
There's a reason I'm doing this and we're thinking this through.
Let me go up to the template data and see authenticated.
I'll make that a bool.
Like that.
When I come back down here, there are other things I want to do.
If this user is authenticated.
Okay.
And for now, I'm going to put a comment in here to do get more user information.
So that information, we can't get it right now because we don't have an actual user's table in the
database.
But this is just a to do comment to remind me to put some information in there.
And the last thing I want to populate in this for right now is the current date and time.
So I'll say t now is equal to the time dot now.
Okay.
And then I just return to the.
So now let's go back up here.
And instead of passing nil, when I execute the template here in line 52, now I just call app dot and
default data.
When I hand that it's two required parameters to enter.
So this way we'll have whatever information was passed as data in the call to the render function.
Plus, we'll have all of this default data that we just added down here and we can add to this as time
goes on or as required.
Okay.
So with that now I can go over to my handlers and I can render this home page app dot render.
And it requires, if you recall, w are the name of the template which is home dot page dot and go each
html, go html and I'm not going to pass this any data.
So nil.
Okay, so we call that and that should be it.
Now, this still won't work because we're using session information and we need to somehow tell our
handlers and the rest of our application about this session.
We had the session stored in config, but there's one more step required before we can actually try
to render a template and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.