So we're at the point now where we can actually start pushing events from our application to our connected
clients and we're already pushing some events, so let's just make sure everything works the way that
we think it's going to.
And I'll tell you right now, it's not going to at least not perfectly.
So right now, I'm looking at the handlers dutko and I'm looking at these start monitoring our Torgau
monitoring function.
And I'm going to go to the start monitoring right here.
So when monitoring starts at the very beginning, we're already triggering one at one thing and pushing
it to the public channel.
We're triggering the app starting event and pushing it some data.
And the data is just monitoring is starting.
And what happens when we push that?
Well, nothing happens right now because we're not listening for that event.
So let's go back to our site wide JavaScript that's stored in the jet file and look for the part where
we're creating our channels.
So here we create our public channel named Public Channel, and we're binding to something called a
test event, which we did a long time ago.
So let's change that event to app starting.
And this event name exactly matches what I'm pushing right here.
App Dash starting matches app Dash starting.
So you would think that when we actually toggle our monitoring off and then put it back on, we're going
to get this alert.
Let's see if that works.
So I'll stop my application and I'll start my application and I'll hide this window and I'll go back
to my Web browser and I'll just go to any page.
So there monitoring is off.
I am going to turn it on.
Let me open the JavaScript console to make sure there's no errors.
I'll turn it on there.
Nothing happened.
Well, why did nothing happen?
Well, nothing happened because of the way the JavaScript works.
So let's go back down to the bottom here.
When I actually turn monitoring on, I'm calling update system and update system calls this function
and this function actually in the in the go code.
If you recall, we're setting the necessary variable monitoring underscore live in our app.
Preferences are our application wide config.
We're setting that to the correct value.
But JavaScript doesn't work exactly the way that you think it would when you're reading the code.
So this is firing and it's not waiting for anything to happen.
It's immediately toggle toggling the monitoring.
So what I could do is I could work with JavaScript promises, wait for the first function to execute
and when it's finished, then execute the second one.
That's a lot of work.
And since this is a one off, I'm just going to go back to my code, which calls Torgau monitoring.
So I'll go to my roots file and I'll find Torgau monitoring.
And all I'm going to do here is just manually set this right away.
So I will say, if we're starting monitoring right now, I'm writing to the console or writing to our
application log, but I'll also set the necessary value in the preferences right here.
And that way it will work.
At least I think it will.
So let's so go repo dot preference map, no repo app preference map.
And I'm going to look for the key monitoring underscore Leive and I'm going to set that too because
we're turning it on here.
It's equal to one.
And I'll just copy this line.
And the very first thing I do after I put it to the log when turning it off is set it to off.
Zero.
And I'll stop my application, start my application.
And when I go back to my screen here, because the application was starting, it pushed that event.
So it seems like it's working.
Let's make sure I'll turn it off, OK, and I'll turn it back on.
And I should get pushed that event.
And I do.
So now I know that it's actually pushing the events the way that it's supposed to.
So logically, if you think it through, when I go back to my code here and hide this window and look
at the JavaScript jet, just OzJet file right at the top, all I need to do here find to the public
channel for every event I want to push.
And right now I'm just pointing to one, which reminds me, we probably should go back to our roots
file and find that testing we had up here, which is push your test.
And I'm first of all, I'm going to get rid of this test pusher because I don't need it anymore.
That was just to make sure things are working.
So I'll delete that.
Then I'll go back to my roots file and delete this line because we don't need that anymore.
And that's just something that's cluttering up our code.
So what we need to do is to look at the kinds of events we're going to be pushing to our JavaScript
file.
So let me go in here, read a few comments, things we want to look for.
This is dim, but I'm just going to read it out loud as I do it.
I want to look for service goes down.
I want to look for service, comes up.
In other words, a healthy service becomes an unhealthy service, becomes a healthy service or a problem.
Service becomes a healthy service.
So they go down, they come up or I just want to look for service status changed that maybe will cover
all of the cases.
We'll look at that when we actually start writing that code.
And we also want to know, has the schedule changed and monitoring is turned off.
Now, that may not be all of the cases that I want to look for, but it seems to me that that covers
the vast majority of them right now.
So these are the kinds of things we're going to be looking for.
So we're going to bind to every one of those events and perform some logic, updating tables, giving
alerts, removing things from tables, whatever it may be.
We'll be looking for all of those as time goes on.
So let's go back and look at our start monitoring.
When we start, we're pushing an event and then down here, when we loop through the services, we're
also pushing next run event and schedule changed event.
So I'm not sure what that is, but I'm going to look for that and put it in the code here in my comments.
And we want to also look for next run event changes.
OK, so we may not do anything with that, but it's the kinds of things that I need to start thinking
about right now.
I don't want to just jump in and start code coding and hope for the best.
I want to think logically about all of the cases where I need to change something on any screen that
any connected user might be looking at or to display an alert or something like that.
So those are the kinds of things that we're going to looking for.
So since we're here anyway, and I know I'm going to look for the monitoring is turned off event center
route's file, let me go their routes file and we're toggling our monitoring service.
Let's find that again right here, toggling monitoring.
So at this point, when I'm turning monitoring on, I could push an event.
I could just go back to my start monitoring.
Copy this.
Go back over here to my.
I lost it.
Handlers don't go torgau monitoring, so I could also push and push a notification right here if I wanted
to, so I could after I stop the scheduler, push this and say monitoring is off, change the message.
And call this Apte stopping, OK, and then now that I'm going to be pushing this event and we'll do
this a little more logically momentarily, but this is just to make sure that we can actually push a
second event.
If I go back to my jet file and copy this and paste it here and change it to app stopping and change
it to say warning alert.
And then stop my application and started.
When I come back to my Web browser and reload this, when I turn it off and click, OK, monitoring
is off, so that works perfectly.
So there's a bunch of things we need to do in the next few lectures to trap for all of those cases.
And I think the simplest thing to work with now that we have you know, we know we can actually push
events and receive them on the client side is to actually start a local Web server.
And I'll provide you the code for that, that you can just download, compile and run to your heart's
content and then actually turn monitoring on and wait for the time to elapse.
So the schedule actually executes.
It checks our local service on host local host Port 80 80.
And I want that to move from here to here in real time.
So let's see if we can do that in the next lecture or two.