So we're getting much closer to having an actual useful application, but there are still some things
to do.
And what I want to turn my attention to right now is this item, which is the schedule.
And if we click on that currently, it just displays an empty table and there's no logic behind it to
display a schedule at all.
And of course, the goal here is to make this page list, all of the things that are scheduled to run
to show us the House, to show us the service, what the schedule is, whether it's three minutes or
in our case, 10 seconds, because we just have one item right now when it last ran and when its next
going to run.
And we want this to update in real time.
So I should be able to, when I'm done, watch this page and see my one entry and watch the previous
and next values change based upon when it runs in the background.
So in order to make that happen, there's a few changes we have to do.
First of all, I need to have some kind of data structure to hold the information necessary for this
this particular table.
So let's go back to our ID and I'm going to open models don't go and in models don't go.
We're simply going to add a new member to this or a new entry to this and I'll call it schedule.
So at the very bottom, I'll give it a comment schedule model.
That's enough for now.
And it's a type and I'll call it a schedule and it's just a struct and it's going to hold some information.
So first of all, like most of them, it'll have an ID that's in and it will also have an entry ID.
And of course, that is of type Kronborg entry ID from our Chron package.
And we need that for the monitor map.
It has the entry itself, which is Kronborg entry.
And again, that's tied to our monitoring package.
The host is just a string, so I have some information to display.
The service is just a string.
In our case, it'll be localhost and HTP for hosting service last run from HHS, which is of time time
and that's last run from the host services host Service Idee, which I'd better spell right.
And that will just be an end and the text for the actual schedule, scheduled text, which is just a
string.
OK, so I have a model now and that is a place where I can put the necessary information.
Now, if we go back to our lives, think about this one for a minute, we have our host, which is a
string and that's the host name.
But when we get a host service by IDEM, I'm going to look at the host postgrads and find right here,
get host service by ID.
I actually don't populate this.
There's a place in the model to store the necessary information, but I actually don't get it in this
query.
And I added that member to the model for host service a while ago.
But I think it might be useful just to simplify things.
Let's just get that information too.
So I'm going to add a host name and it means I'm going to have to join the host table.
So I will left join hosts.
Try that again, join hosts h on and it would be host ID matches ID and then I'll just take this member
that I've added to my select statement and add it right down here at the very bottom.
HMS Host, I hostname, that's what I want, and put a comma at the end.
OK, so now when I call this method using my repository, I have the hostname pre populated.
So that's in there and I know I need it for the schedule table.
So we've got that in place.
Now let's go to a file that was part of the package that you initially downloaded, called scheduled
ago.
And all that does is I have a method here called list entries that lists the schedule entries on this
page, scheduled jet.
So let's make some changes to that.
So what I'm going to be passing to it, of course, is the A slice, a variable version, and I'll just
call it items.
It's a slice slice of model's schedule, that model we created just a few moments ago.
And what I need to do is actually to get the schedule slice populated with the necessary information.
And remember, we're not actually pulling information out of the database at this point.
Instead, we're going to look at the schedule that's running in the background as part of our current
package.
And we have all of the information related to that schedule stored in our.
Application wide config with a member named Monitor Map, so I'm just going to loop through that, so
I'll save for key and value our assigned range and I'm going to range through repoll dot app, dot monitor
map.
I'm just going to go through every single entry in our monitor map.
And when I get in there, well, each time I go through will create a new value or new variable called
item and it's of type models schedule.
So to get the information in that necessary item item ID, the first member in that struct is the ID
and that will be equal to the key.
So, OK, so now I have the ID, next I want to get the ID and that's in.
So item entry ID and that's the actual value that's stored in our map.
So now I've got both of the pieces of information from that map.
Now I actually want to get the entry itself.
So item entry and this is the actual entry that's used by the current package to run a particular job.
So that's going to be equal to and we can get that right from our app DOT scheduler sorry, repo dot
app, dot scheduler.
And I just call a method on that entry and I pass it the value the V that that I'm getting from my monitor
map.
So that gets me my entry.
And if you point this you'll see it just returns type Kronborg entry and I need that.
So I have that information not.
Next, I need to get the hose service, so hose service and potentially to air our assigned the value
of repo DB don't get host service.
By ID and my ID in this case is the key from that monitor map, so I have the service and I'll just
check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll say log print line error and I'll just return because I don't
want to go any further.
Something's gone wrong.
Otherwise my item scheduled text is assigned the value of and I'll just build a string format on Sprint
F and it will be at every and then percent s percent D and my placeholders are replaced with H.
S dot.
Schedule number and start schedule unit goes backwards, yeah, should be D and S. So that gives me
my schedule text that I can have that I can display and item last run from post service.
Well, that's easy.
That's how service at last check.
And item host is equal to host service dot hostname, which we just added to this query.
So that works out all right.
Postal service item host there, that's better.
And item service is equal to service service.
Service name.
And now I just append this to my slice of items, so items equals append items.
OK, now I have that all built now in a minute, you'll see that this isn't ideal.
Actually you won't see it.
So I'll have to describe it to you because we just have one entry in this right now.
I actually need to be able to sort this this slice because I want to sort it in a particular fashion.
And what I'm going to get from the monitor map could be in any order because, as you know, maps are
not sorted and you can't sort of map.
And we're getting our information from a map, our monitor map.
So I actually need to sort this.
And fortunately, it's unfortunately, it's not really easy to do that.
There's actually a couple of things I need to do.
The first thing is I need to define a new type, which I'll call by host because I want to sort this
by host.
And that's going to be of a type by host, which is of models, a slice of model schedule.
So I've defined that type and all I have to do is to create three methods on this type that will allow
me to sort a slice.
So basically I'm satisfying an interface requirement by creating three functions.
So the first one is called Leam.
So Leam or func, and this is tied to has the receiver of by host because I'm satisfying an interface
requirement is Llyn and it returns in it.
And all I'm going to do here is say return Lenn of a.
OK, I got something wrong here.
Yeah, I need to have my parentheses.
OK, so there's the first requirement, so Len.
Is used to sort by host was a but a comment in there, as you're supposed to, the second function you
need to satisfy this requirement is called less and less again, is just is used to sort by host.
So let's create the funk.
It has the same receiver by host.
It's called Less and Less.
Takes a couple of arguments, I and J, both of which are Aints and it returns a ball.
And all I'm going to do here is write a really simple one line bit of logic.
I'll return a index.
I so I'm getting a from my receiver looking at the index of I.
Dr. Host is less than a Jay.
Host, so I'm using this to start the sorting process, and if you've taken any introductory computer
science course, you'll be really familiar with this logic.
And the last one is called Swap and Swap.
He's used to sort by host funk a by host as my receiver, and it's called Swap and Swap actually takes
to INCI and J and it returns and Ent..
And the logic for this is a index I.
A index, Jay.
Is equal to a index, Jay.
A index are.
And I think you have to be it's OK, so if there's no errors here and there are, this doesn't return
on it.
Try that again there, so I have no errors there, so that means I now have satisfied the necessary
interfaces requirements that will allow me to sort my my slice by hosts.
So after I finish all of this, I say sort the slice by host, sort, dot, sort, and I'm going to
sort by host and I'm going to pass by host.
Items.
OK, so that should sort my slice now we're not going to see that immediately because we only have one
host, one service, but this will will sort it for us when we have more than one host and more than
one service.
Now, I want to pass some data to my template.
Data is a sign the value of make and we're using jet via map, which I may never do again because I'm
getting a little annoyed with the errors in my idy, but it is a good templating package and then we
just put some values in data, data, data set and I'll call it items and I'll simply put in my items.
And then down here when I render this template, I pass it my data.
So that should suffice for the logic required to list our entries on the page.
But we still need to go and update the actual schedule page.
So let's find that.
So here in the body part, I'll just range through those items and all I have to do is range items and
clothes that and.
And inside, I just put in table rows and because I know I'm going to be updating this schedule in real
time, I think it might be appropriate to give this some kind of ID so I can find individual entries
as required.
And I think the easiest way to do that is just to say ID equals and call it something I'm not using
anywhere else.
Schedule Dasch and then I'll just pass an ID.
So each row will have a unique idea.
So that's my tier and I'm going to have one, two, three, four, five entries in this table or five
TDs.
So the first one is just the host TD and that's just a host because that's what we called it in the
model.
The second one is the service, which I just called a service.
I called it service.
So I use service here as he Vicki.
That's correct.
The third one will be the schedule, and that's called schedule text in our model.
Next comes our previous run.
So, of course, we need to make a decision here and we need to use that date after year one function
we used earlier to allow us to determine whether or not to display a date here so we can just put an
if statement if schedule after year one.
And I just passing the value from my slice.
Last run from Hose Services H.S..
If that's true, then do something else.
Do something else.
And an end.
So in here, if the data populated in this member of the slice is actually after the first day of the
first month of the year one, then just print it out date from layout, we'll use our our date from
layout function and we want to pass it last run from HS and we want to pass a format string which will
use two thousand six zero one zero two and then three zero four zero five p.m. just to make it readable
for humans and closer parentheses and close our double quotes.
Otherwise, I'll just put in spending.
And the last one is pretty much the same thing, it just has a different value so I can copy all of
this.
Pasted in here and change last run from HFS to dot entry and entry has a value bought next, and that's
not coming from a model that we defined that actually comes right from the cron package.
So we'll copy this entry next.
Replace it in here.
And for bad things, a little better.
OK, so this should actually work, so if I start my application and start my application, let's see
what we got wrong.
And I'll switch to my Web browser and make sure the schedule is running, it is or the monitoring is
running and I'll just go to this page.
OK, so I do have a schedule after year one is not available in current.
So that's line 45.
So I do have a typo somewhere.
Let's find that line 45 right here.
If schedule after year one, it's actually date after year one.
Wrong function name.
And the same thing here, so I shouldn't have to restart my application because we're in development
mode and we'll load it again and there it is.
That works exactly as I want.
So the next step is actually to update this schedule page in real time and we have to go back to WebSocket
to make that happen.
But now that we have this table and it has the appropriate I.D. on the row and let's make sure it does
on the schedule table, do I have an idea?
Yes, I gave it an idea of schedule table.
Now we have this all set up so we can start writing the logic necessary to update that page in real
time.
And we'll get started on that in the next election.