So now that we have this scheduled table showing up properly, we will actually want to do something
with it using Web sockets in JavaScript and so on and so forth and things like this.
So, for example, I have monitoring running right now and I have one thing being monitored, so I have
one entry and my schedule table.
And I want, first of all, a safe return monitoring off like this.
Well, of course, this should go back to an empty table with just a message saying that there's no
scheduled checks here.
And when I turn it back on, it should add all of the entries one at a time as they're actually added
to the schedule.
And of course, we just have one row.
So one thing will get entered.
And then as the schedule runs this this previous and next date and time stamp, that should be updated
in real time.
And if I went, for example, over to the overview page and looked at my host and turned off a service,
that individual service should be removed from that table.
Well, let's start with the easy one.
Let's modify the code so that when scheduling is turned off like this, that this becomes an empty table.
And that's pretty straightforward.
So let's go over to our idea.
And I'm looking at Jast Jet, and we already have an event we're listening to called App Stopping.
And this seems a logical place to actually remove all of the entries from that table and populated with
the no scheduled checks text.
So let's do that.
So first of all, we need to make sure that that element, which has the name of the idea of scheduled
table, exists on the page.
And we'll just check for that like we have right along.
Let scheduled table exists, equal bang bang document, get element by ID and I'm looking for schedule
table like that if scheduled table exists.
So if it does exist, then get a reference to it.
Let's schedule table equal document, get element by ID and again schedule table.
So now we have a reference to it and we just delete all of the rows and that's pretty simple.
We just say schedule table dot t bodies.
Zero Interreg tml.
Equals nothing, so that empties it out, but of course, we don't want to empty it out entirely.
We also want to put a road in there that says there are no scheduled checks.
So let's do that.
Let neuro equal schedule table dot t bodies.
Zero.
Insert a row and again, we need to use minus one because we don't want it to appear above the heading
of the table.
Let new cell equal neuro.
Insert herself at position zero and new cell set, it's attribute call span to be equal to five.
And so.
In our e-mail equals no scheduled checks, and I'm going to type it exactly like that because later
on I'll check to see if that text exists anywhere in the table and that determines whether or not I
have to delete the no scheduled checks.
So that should be, in theory, all that we have to do now to be sure.
I'm going to stop my application, turn it on.
It's running so hard this go back to my browser window.
I'll refresh this page to make sure that everything is current and I'll say turn monitoring on the monitor
is off right now.
So let's turn it on.
Let's refresh the page and let's delete the content from this page.
And it worked.
OK, so that was easy.
So we've now got that part working as well.
The other thing we have to do is to go back to our idee and look for perform checks, go.
So let's open that, perform checks don't go.
And let's find the test service for host, which is where is that right here.
Test service for host.
What I'm going to do here is right before this to do send email to clients.
I'm going to put another event in here.
One I'm going to do is I'm going to broadcast a schedule changed event because once I test a service
for a host, the schedule will have changed.
We'll have executed a scheduled item and then we'll schedule a new one.
So here I want to broadcast schedule changed event, and that's pretty straightforward.
So how do we do that?
Well, first of all, because of the way that I store dates in the database and I don't like null dates,
I'm going to have to define that year one very variable again.
So I'll just say you're one is assigned the value of time date and I'm going to make the year zero zero
zero one, the month one, the day one, then zero zero zero one.
And I'll just make it time UTC and that gives me a date I can check against.
OK, and because I'm going to be pushing an event over WebSocket, I need to create a date.
A variable data is assigned the value of make a map string string.
And in that data variable, I want to put in the information about the event that just ran the host
service that I'm testing and I want to broadcast.
The schedule has changed.
So let's put some data in their data and we need the host service ID that's going to be equal to Stoveken
I to a and it's just Housetop ID because I already have the host service very variable defined in this
particular method.
Now I need the service data service ID and I may not use that, but as I always tend to do, I'll push
as much information as I might need in the future.
Sterkel into a and this one is an escort service ID.
And I'll also add the whole study data host I'd stirred into a whole host ID.
And here's where I'm going to use my your one variable, so I'm going to write an if statement if Abduh
scheduler dot entry from repo dot app dot monitor map.
And I'm going to look at the key hosted service dog ID dog next, which is a method built into the scheduler,
is after year one.
So if there's a value in the scheduler for this entry and its next run is after year one, in other
words, it's something in the future, then it's a valid date.
Then I'll populate data.
Next run, which are going to be using on the schedule table is equal to repo dot app, dot scheduler,
dot entry.
And I'm looking for repo dot app, dot, monitor, map, and the key once again is dot ID, our host
service ID.
Next, and that gets me the time to time, and I will just format it as a string and my layout will
be our standard layout.
2006 zero one zero two three zero four zero five.
P.M. And that will give you the date in the correct format, but if it's not after your one else, it's
not really been scheduled yet.
So I'll just put data next run is equal depending a string.
OK, so we have that few other things we need DataDot our data Lastra.
Well, that's really the current time so we can just say equals time dot now and call the format and
I'll just copy what we did appear to save all that typing copy.
Paste.
OK, so that gives us her last run, it just ran this instant.
So this is valid data host.
The hostname is equal to a chest of hostname data service.
I want to know the service and that's equal to start service dot service name.
Data schedule, because we need to display that on that table and that's just going to be formatted
as a string, so we'll just format it as a string format, as print F at every and it's a an int and
a string replaced with a start schedule number and start schedule unit and that will give it to us in
the correct format.
Next, we want the status which we may not use, but it's not going to hurt to pass it.
And status is equal to our new status in this case because we've just checked for the status of this
host and restoring that value in the variable.
New news status data icon is equal to escort service dot icon.
OK, so we've got all that populated.
Let's broadcast the message repo dot broadcast message and we're going to broadcast to the public channel.
And we're going to broadcast a schedule changed event and we're going to pass it data.
So what we need to do next is to go to James Jet and actually listen for that event, so let's just
make sure everything is wired up properly.
Let's put an event in here and I'll put it right here, an event listener, public channel bind.
And I'm going to listen for the event.
We're just pushed pushed from our code schedule, changed event.
And that will be an anonymous function that takes some data.
And right now, let's just say console, dot log.
Got change event, and we'll get rid of this in a minute if it works, so let's stop our application,
start our application, go back to our browser, make sure the JavaScript console is open.
And it is.
And I will turn this off, reload the page just to make sure everything is current.
I will turn the schedule on and I got a change of heart.
Good.
So I know that works.
So let's go back and fix this JavaScript to do more than just print to the console.
So here and just check.
Let's find that again.
Get rid of this, this little console log because that's not useful.
And what do we want to do here?
Well, first of all, we want to make sure that when this event fires, we only care if the user happens
to be on the schedule page.
So once again, we can just covid this right here.
We can say let's schedule table exists, copy that, paste it in here.
And then again, we're going to have an if statement.
So I should have copied the whole thing, but I'll just copy this in here, paste it and delete all
of this content and think about what we're going to do.
So if the schedule has changed, the first thing we need to do is to get a reference to the table.
So I'll undo what I just deleted and keep that reference to the table.
OK, now we have to check to see if the table contains no scheduled checks, which means it has the
row that says there are no scheduled check.
So let's see if it has that left table content.
Equal scheduled table dot in our e-mail.
If table content includes no scheduled checks, which I have to spell right or won't work, then we
have one row in that table that has no scheduled checks.
So we have to delete it.
So we'll just say let RO count equal table.
Scheduled table, dot rose, dot length and loop through that for let are equal row count minus one
because we don't want to get rid of the top row of the table is greater than zero because we only want
to affect one row on the table ie minus minus.
And we'll delete that row schedule table dot delete row.
All right.
OK, so that's the first thing we have to do.
The next things we want to do is to delete the existing row for the host service schedule, check for
the host service that just ran.
So delete existing row.
Let Rowe exists equal, bang, bang, we're checking to see if that Rowe actually exists, document
doget element by ID and what we're looking for is named Schedule Dasch plus data host service IDY.
Because if you look at the scheduled OzJet page, every time we have a row in this table, it uses the
idea of schedule dash the host service ID.
So that will tell us if it exists, if Roe exists.
Then let RO equal document get element by ID schedule Dasch plus data DOT Postal Service I.T. that gets
is a reference to the ROE and Rodon parent node dot remove child.
Roe, which is how we deleted Roe from a table in JavaScript.
OK, so that Roe is now gone.
Next, we need to create a new Roe, let new Roe equal schedule table dot t bodies.
Index of zero, insert row and again, minus one.
So that creates a new row now we just put all of our attributes and TDs in there, so let's set an attribute
first neuro dot.
Set attribute and the attribute is ID and the value is going to be scheduled, Dasch plus data DOT host
service ID.
OK, so we've got to roll the row has the appropriate ID.
Let's just create some cells and put them in there.
Let new cell equal new row dot insert a cell apposition zero, which is our first one and that is the
hostname.
We'll create some new text, a new text node.
Let new text, equal document.
Create text node and we'll create a text node that has the value of data, host the hostname and new
cell.
A Penn child, new text, so there's our first our second TD new cell.
Equals.
New row.
Insert a cell apposition, one that we can just copy this because it'll save some typing, so I'll copy
this.
I don't need to let part paste that in there.
And this one, the second value in there is actually the service data service.
And I'll copy this whole thing pasted here.
Give it the index of two.
And this one is the schedule.
And the third one is last run, and that's a position three.
Now, the fourth one is the next run, so I need to actually check well, first of all, I can copy
this part and paste it in here and put it in the correct position for me and do a check if DataDot next
run.
If that's undefined.
If that's equal.
Exactly.
To undefined, just in case we don't have a validate in there.
I'll just put in new text equals document dot create text node and I'll put it in here pending.
Because chances are if we get our information pushed out before the event is actually scheduled, lame,
we may not have a valid date in there.
And I just want to trap for all the cases.
But if we do have to validate, let's use that instead.
ELT's new text.
Equals data, dot, document, dot, create text node, and I want data dot next run, and if we have
the data, it's already in the correct format.
So there we go.
And now we just append that to the appropriate cell.
New cell, a Penn child.
New text.
And this should be correct.
OK, so let's stop our application, start our application just to make sure everything is current,
go back to a Web browser, reload this page.
We have one value in there.
And now I turn it off and it should go away.
And it does.
And I want to turn it back on in the next 10 seconds, I should see my one event show up in this table.
And that was pretty fast, I must have been right at the 10 seconds and if we keep watching, this should
change after 10 seconds.
And it did so that all works correctly.
All right, the next step is to deal with situations where if you come to my overview page, well,
actually, let's go back to the schedule page and I'll close this JavaScript witness so we have a little
more room.
So I'm looking at the schedule page in one tab.
But if I go to the House page in another tab and go to localhost and find IT services and turn this
service off, it's done that.
But if I go back to this screen, this still shows that that service is going to be checked and that
will never update because it's actually been taken out of the schedule or will be taken out of the schedule
by the time we're done.
So I want this when I actually click on this service and turn it on and off, I need to either add it
to the schedule if I'm setting it to active and fire off the necessary request to change the schedule
on the schedule page.
And if I turn it off, I want to remove it from the schedule page and actually remove it from the schedule,
because right now this will turn it off in the database, but it has no effect on our schedule that's
running in the background.
So we have to take care of that and we'll do that in the next lecture.