So things are starting to look good with his schedule page, and it appears that everything functions
the way we want to so far, but we did leave one little thing out.
So if you'll notice, I'm looking at the schedule page right now and have monitoring turned on and everything
seems OK.
And if I turn monitoring off, everything still seems OK.
But cosmetically, we left one thing out with monitoring of if I refresh this page, the no scheduled
checks line doesn't show up and that bothers me.
So let's go put that in there.
It'll just take a moment.
So I'll go back to my I.D. and I'm looking at scheduled jet.
And all we have to do here is check for the length of the items variable.
So I'll put an if statement in if Leane items is greater than zero.
Then do this, so let me indent this.
And then at the bottom.
Else we'll just put an empty row with a one TD and a the appropriate call spanning their tier TD call
span equals five.
No scheduled checks and closed the if statement.
And and that should take care of it.
Let me get the TSA where it belongs, though.
That looks better.
OK, so let's verify this works.
I'll save it and go back to my browser and reload this page perfect and let's turn it on good and let's
turn it off good and reload the page.
Perfect.
OK, so now we want to move on to this part.
When I'm looking at a host and looking at IT services, when I turn this service off, whether scheduling,
let's say scheduling is on, when I turn this service off right now, this works.
It changes the appropriate field in the appropriate role in the database, but it doesn't actually remove
this this service from our schedule.
And when I turn it back on it again, it updates the database, but it doesn't actually make any changes
whatsoever to the schedule that's running in the background.
And we need to fix that.
So let's go back to our ID and let's look at perform checks.
Don't go.
And what I'm looking for is the test service for host right here.
So we need to make some changes to this.
So this code runs after a host service is tested and what we're doing here, right down here.
So from this part on, when we say broadcast schedule changed event and that's what I want to do.
I want to broadcast that his schedule has changed not just when a service is tested, but also when
we turn a host service on or off.
So what I'm going to do is create a new method down here and I will put it right here and I will call
it func and it will have our repo receiver.
I would call it push schedule changed event, and it will take two parameters, which will be a models
hosted service, and it will also take new status, which is going to be a string.
What I'm going to do is move all of this code out of here, so I'll grab this stuff.
And I'll cut it right out of here and put it down on this new function.
OK, so we'll clean this up in a minute.
Let's go back up here.
And all we need to do at this point is simply call that method repo.
Push, schedule, changed event and pass it house and our new status.
OK, so now that I've moved this out of here and actually put it in its own function, I can call it
from anywhere, and that will allow us to call this method when needed, when turning a host service
on or off.
So the question is, where do we want to call this from when we're turning a host service on or off?
Well, let's go look at our routes file and we'll figure out what method we need to end this to.
So let me open up routes, routes go and let's find the part where we turn a service on or off.
And it's right here.
We're making a post request to slash admin slash hosts that slash Tuggle service.
And that brings up Tuggle service for host, which is inside our handlers.
So let's write some comments here and figure out what we want to do.
So right here, after we update the database and before we send the JSON, we need to do a couple of
things.
So I'll put some comments in.
We need to, first of all, broadcast.
So we're going to broadcast over Web sockets that the service status has changed and then we want to
either add or remove post service from the schedule.
And that's basically an if statement.
So we're saying if active, because that's what we're getting right up here.
If active is equal to one, then we want to add to schedule.
Otherwise, we want to remove from schedule.
OK, so we don't have any methods that allow us to do that easily right now.
We'll have to either add the host service to the schedule or remove it from the schedule.
What we're going to do, of course, is we're only going to broadcast that it's been added to the schedule
or removed from the schedule if the monitoring is actually running, because if it's not running, it
doesn't really matter.
But we'll take care of that in the methods themselves.
So in order to do a broadcast, we need to have both the host service and the host.
So let's get that information.
So right up here after broadcast, let's get the host service.
And I won't bother checking for an error because that's something I'll leave as an exercise for you.
But I'll call Repo DB and then I want to get the host service.
But do I have the host service ID?
At this point?
What I have is the host ID and the service ID and I can't get that without actually adding a method.
So I'm going to name this method right now and I'll give it a nice long name.
Get post service.
By hosting ID, service ID, because those are the two pieces of information I have and I'll just pass
it post ID and service ID.
Now, this method doesn't exist yet, so let's go create that.
So I'll go over to host underscore postgrads and the very bottom.
I'll put it in a new function func which will have the receiver of a pointer to postgrads DB B repo
and that's the name.
And it's going to take as let's make sure I'm getting this right.
I said host ID and then service ID, so host ID and service ID, both of which are INS.
And what does it return.
It returns a model's.
Model, host, service and potentially an error.
OK, so as I always do, I'm going to scroll up and find my contacts code, copy that and pasted in
here and write my query.
And the query is nothing special.
It's very similar to what we've done before.
I am going to select the host service ID, the host service host and the host service service.
Whether or not it's active.
The schedule, no.
The schedule unit.
The last check.
The status.
The created at the updated at and then I'll join the services table and get the service ID again, even
though I don't need it, the service name, whether or not the service is active, it's Ikon.
It's created at and it's updated at.
And finally I'll join the host table and get the hostname and I'm going to get that from host services.
HHS left join services s on start service ID equals Estcourt ID and I'll join the host table.
Hosts H on HSN, hosts underscore ID equals ID and my where clause hs dot host ID equals dollar sign
one and H.S. dot service ID equals dollar sign to.
OK, now I'll create a variable to store a result in var his models post service and I'll just do my
query.
Row is assigned the value of Magdeburg query row context, handed the context and the query and our
host ID and our service ID and we'll check for an error and scan the results in Rodust scan and we'll
scan them into our newly created a variable.
So we're getting the ID and I'll duplicate this a few times.
Then we get the host ID.
And the service idee.
An active and scheduled number.
And schedule unit.
Last check and a few more duplications.
Step status created at Updated, and now we're into the service table, so service dot, ID and duplicate
had a couple of times then service name.
Service active service Eikon.
Service created at the service, updated at and finally the hostname that we added a while ago.
Hostname.
And we'll check for another.
If error is not equal to nil, we'll just return and the error.
Otherwise, we return.
Yes and no.
So let's give this a comment.
Gets a host service by host and service Idi Amin copy its signature.
And open our repository and just put this right in here, now, we can get back to our handlers and
that air should go away.
So now we have the host service.
The other thing we need to call our broadcast is actually the host and we can get that easily enough
host.
And again, I'll ignore the error and you shouldn't is equal to report dbag get hosted by ID and put
in our host ID.
OK, so now that we have both of these things, we can actually use them to broadcast as necessary.
So let's go up here or down here to our if statement and if active is equal to one, let's do it right
here to start with.
So we'll say repo.
And now I want to push this.
I want to push the schedule change event so I can say push schedule change to that and give it to us
now because we're pushing this right now and the schedule hasn't run.
Our status is just pending.
OK, so that pushes our schedule change event and let's go see what that does.
So we just copied and pasted this code.
Let's make sure this is all right.
So we're broadcasting this information and.
This all looks correct, so that's a good start.
So we're not pushing that event now.
The other thing we want to do, and it looks like I have an error here somewhere, where is that?
H unused variable H.
OK, I'm not using that right now, but I'm going to use it in a moment, so we're going to need that
because we need to broadcast as well the fact that the status has changed.
So let's go back to our perform checks right here.
And just like I extracted the information from here to a new function, I'm also going to grab all of
this information, all of this code.
I'm going to grab this out of here and I'm going to come down right here, right after this function
and create a new one.
And I will call this and it'll have the receiver of Repo DB Repo and I'm going to call this push status
changed event.
That way, I don't have to have duplicated code and for parameters, this will have a H, which is of
type models that host it will also have the host service of type models, host service.
And finally, it will take a new status, which is a string, and it doesn't return anything.
And let me paste that code in there and come back up here and inside this if statement, we just call
the function we just created, repo push status changed.
And give it our host and our host service and our new status, so now that this exists as its own function,
we can call that in our handlers.
So just as we pushed a schedule changed event, we can also call repo dot, push status, changed event
and give it our host and our host service.
And again, the status is just pending.
So now we've pushed the fact that the schedule has changed and we've pushed the fact that the status
has changed.
Is there anything else we need to do here?
Yes, we need to add it to the monitor map.
And that's the part that, again, I'll just call a function and then go right the function repo and
I'll call one add to monitor map and pass it to host service.
And that doesn't exist yet, but it will in a moment.
And here all I have to do is say repo remove from monitor map.
Now let's go create these functions.
So I'll go put them in my perform checks file again and I'll just put them at the very bottom.
So let's create two functions.
Func with the receiver repo of DB Repo and to monitor map and it takes HS, which is a model host service.
And I'll just copy this and paste it here and call this remove from monitor map.
OK, so let's do the ad one first, and this is really straightforward, but again, we don't want to
make any changes to the monitor map unless monitoring is live.
So let's put a little if statement in there.
If repoll dot app, dot preference map and I'm looking for monitoring Dasch live.
Now, underscore Leive if that's equal to one and do this otherwise don't do anything else.
So I'll just copy this.
And paste it down here, so if monitoring is not live and this function is called, nothing happens,
but if it is live, what do I want to do?
Well, I want to do the same sort of thing I did when we started up our monitoring in the first place.
I want to create a variable which I'll call J of type job, which we've defined right in this package.
And then I want to make JS hosting service ID equal to the host service that's passed to us, its ID
and then I want to schedule this.
So I'm getting back a schedule ID, which is an it potentially an error that's assigned the value of
repo app.
I call my scheduler and I just add a job and what I'm adding is again it needs to be, it needs to have
a few parameters and we'll build the first one using 14. Sprint F.
And I'm just going to use the syntax that our scheduler expects at every present day for an eight percent
is for a string and then substitute from home service our schedule number and then from host service,
our schedule unit.
And the last parameter is just the job, J.
OK, so that will schedule it.
And again, I should probably check for an error.
I'll say if error is is not equal to nil, I'll just log the error log print line error and I'll return.
And of course, in your own code, you could perform whatever logic is appropriate for your case.
Otherwise, we just add this to our monitor map, repo dot app, dot monitor map.
And I'm going to add in the key of ID for our host service ID and that's equal to the new schedule ID.
We just got back.
So that's now added to our map.
Now let's broadcast the fact that this has taken place so we'll create a data variable, our payload
that's assigned the value of make map, string, string and as usual, I'll put all the information
I think I might need in there.
So I'll give it a message, even though I'm not using it right now.
And the message is just scheduling.
And I'm going to duplicate this a couple of times just to save some typing.
The second thing I'll put in there is the host service.
I'd host service ID and that's going to be equal to I need to convert it to a string.
So I'll say Sterkel and.
Eye to eye, and I'm going to pass in the House service ID, the next thing I want is the next run and
that's just going to be a string and I'm just going to put pending because we just added it.
So it hasn't run yet.
The service data service, it's just the service name is equal to escort service, not service name.
The hostname data host is equal to hostname.
The last run data, last run, I'll make that equal to Høst at last check dot format and pass in our
standard formatting string twenty six zero one zero two and then three column zero for Colon zero five
pm to give it a nice human readable format and data schedule.
Well, that's just what we used up above.
That's simply the format as print bit here.
So let's copy that.
And paste it right here and I broadcast this report, broadcast message, and the channel is the public
channel and the event is schedule changed event.
And the payload is our data.
All right, so that will add it to the monitor map now removing it from the monitor map.
That's really straightforward.
That's simply calling our scheduler.
Repo app, DOT scheduler.
And calling remove and we're going to remove the parameter it takes is a repo app, dot monitor map.
And then the key is Edek.
So that removes it from there and now we'll just broadcast the fact that this has changed, so we'll
just say may create a data variable again, data is a sign the value of make the map, string, string.
And all I want to push here is data post service ID is a sign the value of Østergaard eye to a.
He ID and then broadcast that, and I'll just copy this line pasted in here, and that should take care
of it.
So it's clean this up a little bit.
That looks better.
Let's make sure everything compiles.
Good.
OK, so everything compiles, so now we have this schedule changed where we need to ingest.
I actually got that wrong.
It's not schedule changed event here for this last one, it's schedule item, dash removed event.
That's all that I want to push there.
I'm glad I caught that right now.
I would have been looking that for that for half an hour.
OK, so now we need to make some changes to our Jagjit file.
So let's go over to our Jagjit and up here just before the schedule changed event.
Let's Vinda the schedule removed event, the one that I almost left out.
So in our public channel we want to bind to schedule item removed event and that will again be an anonymous
function that takes some data.
And let me make sure I've got that name right.
Schedule, dash item, dash, remove, dash event.
Let's go back to perform Chekist schedule dash item, dash removed event or dash event.
Perfect.
OK, so inside of this we're going to do the same sort of thing we did in every other case.
We want this to fire any time an item is removed from the schedule, but we only want the code inside
the anonymous function to execute.
If there is an item on the page that has an ID that we check for.
So let's just look for let ro exists equal bang bang document douget element by ID and I'm looking for
a role on our schedule table which will have the ID of Schedule Dasch plus our host service ID, which
we're getting in from our data variable hosting service ID.
If that exists.
If Roe exists, I want to get rid of it.
So let's get a reference to it, so I copied this code.
And say, let Roe equal paste, that will get me a reference to the ROE, and now we use our standard
Java JavaScript syntax for removing a row from a table row, parent node, dot remove child row.
So that will get rid of it.
Now we need to again check to see if we need to add a no scheduled
checks.
And since we only have one actual hosted service, we're checking this will definitely fire.
So if we get a reference to the table, let current table equal.
Document.
Get owned by ID, and we called that schedule Dasch table.
And I know this is going to exist inside of this if statement, because if it didn't, the role that
we were looking for in the first place would not it would not have existed.
This would have returned false.
And this this code would never execute.
So now we say if current table rose.
Length.
Is equal exactly to one in that case, we need to add a new.
So we'll create a row, let new row equal current table Dorte bodies at index zero, insert a row and
give it the key of minus or give it the parameter of minus one.
And then we create a cell.
Let new cell equal new row insert a cell at position zero.
And new cell door inner HTML is equal to.
No scheduled checks, lower case C, and before that, I have to give it an attribute, new cell set
attribute and I want to set call span equal to five.
All right.
So that should actually work.
So let's try this.
Let's stop our application, just to be sure.
Compiler application.
Hide this, go back to a Web browser, and what I'm going to do is make sure we're monitoring, I'll
go to the schedule.
Perfect.
That's showing up now.
I'm going to leave this tab open, open a new tab, but I'm going to go to the host house page when
I do that.
So this should still be running in the background, listening for events.
And I'll go to localhost and I'll go to managed services and I'm going to open the JavaScript console
just to look for any errors.
And actually, I'll open the JavaScript console on this tab as well.
Now, when I make this inactive, what should happen is it should make all the necessary changes in
the database.
It should remove it from our schedule and then it should update this table by removing this row and
putting in a no scheduled checks.
So let's see what we got wrong, if anything.
OK, so those changes were saved, no JavaScript errors over here and over here, it says no scheduled
checks.
Perfect.
Now, let's go back here and turn this on.
OK, I got a message I got another message here and this updated in real time, let's watch it to make
sure it was actually added to the schedule.
No, that didn't seem to fire.
Let's go back and find out why.
So I'm fairly certain it has to be somewhere in this method and to monitor map, so let's see what we
have wrong here.
Aha, you can't use an ampersand because the syntax is actually an 8th sign.
All right.
So let's look at that.
And there's exactly the error zeros, ampersand, every it should have been at every.
So let's stop that.
Run this again.
Go back to our our Web browser.
Let's clear the console, make sure monitoring is on and it is OK, reload everything and look at our
managed services page.
And over here, I'll refresh refresh our schedule page.
OK, so that has one entry in there right now and it just updated.
So I know everything is going as it should.
Now I turn this off.
This should be empty.
Perfect.
Now I turn it back on and go back here.
And this pending should change within 10 seconds.
And it does OK, so that seems to be working properly.
There's only one more thing I want to take care of and it's just a little oversight on my part.
So right now, everything seems to be working properly.
And if I turn monitoring off on this page, the schedule goes as it should.
And if I turn it back on, it goes as it should.
But let me show you something on this page and I'll close the JavaScript console.
So in this tab, I'm looking at my house page and it says monitoring is on and on this tab.
I'm looking at the schedule page and it says monitoring is on.
Let me turn this one off.
Perfect.
But let me go back to the other tab.
It still shows that monitoring is on, even though it isn't and everything will work properly.
But this is a simple cosmetic change that will take us two seconds to fix.
So let me go back to my Edem and let me look at the layout jet file right here.
So this code right here is the toggle and it has an idea of monitoring live.
And if I go to my Jagjit jet and look, I already have two events that bind to the applications, monitoring,
starting and stopping.
So all I have to do here is add a little bit of JavaScript code.
Very, very simple.
First thing I'll do when monitoring is turned on, I will let toggle.
And that's just a variable name I'm choosing equal a reference to document doget element by ID and I'm
looking for monitoring live.
So I have that and I'm just going to make sure that it gets checked.
Toggle checked equals true.
And I'll just copy these two lines of code and I'll paste them in the app stopping event that we're
listening to.
So when we get this event app stopping will set the checkmark to false go back here, reload this page
monitoring is off, reload this page monitoring is off.
Now, I'll turn it on and look at the other tab and it should be turned on.
And it is.
And I'll turn it off here in this tab and go back to the other tab.
And it should be off.
And it is.
And that's all there is to it.
All right.
We're getting much closer to having this is a useful application.
We have a few more things to do.
And eventually I want to add a couple of more services to monitor and we'll get started on that in the
next lecture.