So there's one more place where we have to push the fact that a host service status has changed to all
our connected clients over Web sockets, and it's right here, I'm going to look at the host localhost
and I'll look at the problem services.
And in my case, I have a problem.
My Web server is not running and I am monitoring.
So this is being checked in real time.
And if I click check now, it does do the check, but it never pushes the fact that the host service
status has changed if it has changed.
So if I manage to get to this tab and click this button and the Web server has come up, I need to update
this table, which works now.
But I also need to push the fact that the host service status has changed over WebSocket, and that's
really easy.
So let's go back to our Edek and I'm looking at my roots file and the code that is called when you click
that check now button is this line right here.
So there's the URL and this is the handler test check.
So let's bring that up.
I actually left myself a comment right here.
Broadcast service status changed event, but the comments actually in the wrong place.
Let's move it.
And it's in the wrong place because I had that comment after we updated the database.
And I need to actually do that check after I test the service, but before I update the database.
And I do that just with a simple if statement, if new status, which I just got back by calling test
service for host in the variable here.
If that's not equal to the status of the host service, before I update the database, then I want to
broadcast the fact that the host service status has changed over WebSocket.
And now that we've extracted the code that does that to its own function, this becomes really trivial.
Repo dot push status changed event.
Give it the host, which I already have, the host service, which I already have and my new status.
OK, and that's literally all we have to do.
So let's stop the application, start it back up.
I'll go over and reload that page just to make sure that everything is working the way it's supposed
to be.
Go to my problems tab.
Now I'm going to go back and start the service that is being monitored here and get back to the screen
before ten seconds elapse and click this check now button.
So let me go back to my ID, switch to the web server and go run Main and very quickly go back and click
check now.
There it pushed it and everything worked as it's expected to let me just look at the log file to make
sure that there's no errors in there and there are not.
So that's all there is for that one.
Let's move on.