So things are moving along pretty nicely right now, and we only have a few things left to do.
First of all, on the left hand side of my application, I have this page called Events, and currently
it doesn't do anything.
It's just generating an empty table.
And if you look at the handler for this, it's just generating a file and not doing anything at all.
It's just writing HTML to the screen and we want to fix this.
So this page should list all of the events in chronological order that took place.
So a host went down or a service went down or it came back up just so we can have a log of what took
place and when it took place.
And if we look at our database over in post go is my client.
I'm looking at the vigilante database.
There is nowhere to store events in here at all.
So we need to create a new table and I'll call mine events.
So I'll go back to my ID, open my terminal, stop my application and clear the screen and I'll just
generate a migration for this.
So to generate Fiz and I'll call this Create Events table.
Try that again.
I guess I left the E generate.
That's better.
OK, so this gives me two empty migration's right here, and I'll open the up one first and I will just
copy the code from an existing up right here.
Let's copy that just to say some typing and paste it into the up migration and make sure you get the
right migration and ends ended up phase.
So this will be a table called events.
And I'll just fix this before I forget.
This has to be events as well.
And I want an ID, that's for sure.
And I want a host ID or a host service ID, which will be an integer.
I'll give it no defaults.
And I want a host, Idy, which will also be an integer with no defaults.
Then I want the service name
like HTP, in our case, I want the hostname.
And what else do I want?
I want the message, what do we get back following the last test when something changed?
I'm going to make this a little bit longer, just in case.
I'll make it 512.
And that's all that I really need because created an updated that are added for me by Fiz.
So that should be the up.
Now let's get the down as well.
I'll just copy this to make sure I get it correct and I'll go to the down event for this one, our new
migration and change the table name to events.
All right, let's try running this migration.
Make sure you're in the right direction.
I am so to migrate and that should create the table for us.
So when I go back to my client, my database client, and reload this screen, I should have an event
table.
And there it is.
And that all looks correct.
Perfect.
OK, so now I've got the table created.
We need to write some database methods to insert and read from this database.
We don't need any updates because events are never going to be updated.
They're just going to be entered and read.
So let's go back to our code and find our internal repository DB repo and I'll just put it right in
the one we've been using right along.
So first of all, let's write an insert event func and this will have the receiver of Postgrads DB Repo
and I'll call it insert event and it will take an argument, a model that that doesn't exist yet.
But I'll create that in a moment.
I'll call it E models dot event and it doesn't return anything except an error potentially.
So before we go any further, let's go to our models and add an event type event is a struct.
It has an ID, which is an INT, it has a hosted service ID, which is an INT.
It has a host ID, which is an INT.
It has a service name, which is a string.
It has a hostname, which is a string.
It has a message which is a string.
And it has created that which is time, time and updated at which is time, not time.
OK, let's give this a comment.
Event model, that's enough for now, and I'll go back to host Postgres.
OK, so now that error goes away and as I always do, let me copy the contact stuff from the method
right above this one and paste it in there and write a query, first of all, to say return it nil just
so we can have that out of the way.
And my statement is assign the value of
insert into events and we don't need the ID, but we do need the host service ID, the host ID, the
service name.
The hostname and I'll go to the next line.
The message created at and updated at Values Dollar Sign one and how many are there, one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven dollar sign.
Two dollar sign.
Three dollar sign for dollar sign, five dollar signs, six dollar signs, seven, I don't care about
returning the idea or anything because I just want to insert this in the database.
So we're going to insert now so we don't care about the result.
We do care about the error is a sign the value of IMDB, not exact context, handed the context, handed
our statement, and then I'll put these on separate lines so they're more readable.
So the first argument is idot host service idee and I'll duplicate this a few times.
The second one is the host ID, the third one is service name.
The fourth one is hostname.
The fifth one is the actual message we're getting back as a result of the test where the state has changed.
And.
Time now and time now, now that we have everything we need here, let's go look at this.
First of all, let's just finish this up.
We'll check for the error.
If error is not equal to nil, return error, otherwise return nil.
OK, so that takes care of the insert event.
But let's make sure we have everything we need because I have a feeling I missed something inserts an
event into the database.
OK, so let's go back and look at that screen on our web app event type.
I don't think I have anywhere for that.
So let's go back and just run our migration down.
So to migrate down.
That should delete our event table and let's go back into our migration, which is right here, and
added event type in there as well.
We'll make that a string.
So we'll call this I'll put it right as the second thing to call them
event type has to be double quotes.
Which is a string
and it has no default, so we'll just put those like that close our parentheses and let's try writing
that migration again, so to migrate there.
Now we'll have to go fix our model and write here event type, which will be a string.
OK, and back to host up Postgres.
We want to insert event type as the third one, which means this goes to eight because we have a new
thing we're inserting here and idot event type.
OK, so that's our insert.
That should take care of that.
All right.
But we also need some means of getting all of the records that exist sorted properly.
So func M Postgrads DB Repo.
I'll just call this get all events and it takes no arguments and it returns a slice of models Daudt
event and potentially an error.
Copy the context stuff pasted in here and read our query queries.
Assign the value of select ID.
Postal Service ID now, event type, event type, Postal Service ID.
Hosted, so event type, host service, I'd host hosted service name, host name, and I'll go to the
next line.
Message created at an updated app from from events ordered by created.
OK, so that's our query.
Now let's execute it.
First of all, let's create a variable to store our results in VAR events is a type slice of models
event.
So we have rows potentially an error or assign the value of.
Magdeburg query context and at the context, handed our query check for an error, if error is not equal
to nil, then.
Return events and error.
Defer Roseburg close so we don't run into a memory leak.
And now for DOT next, we'll create a variable to store the current iteration of the row var e now EV
is of type models event.
And error is a sign the value of rose dot scam and I'll scan into the newly created variable ampersand
Eve ID and duplicate that a few times.
The second argument is event type.
The third argument is hosted service ID.
The fourth one is host ID.
The fifth one is the service name.
Next is Hostname.
After that comes message then created and updated at which will never change because you're never updating
this, but I'll grab it anyway.
OK, check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return events and the error otherwise appended to the slice and
our variable is called events equals append events and Evvie.
And finally return events and nil.
OK, let's give this a comment.
Gets all events and copy signature.
And go to the repository and paste it in there and then go back again and get the other one we created
and copy its signature.
And go back to the repository and paste that in there.
OK, so now we have this information.
So let's go back to our roots file.
We have a means of getting this information and let's find out what the URL is to display that page
slash admin slash events.
So let's find that handler right here.
So it's just called events.
And here we want to get all the events.
And of course, we don't have any at the moment, but we can go get an empty slice.
So this will turn into a sign because we need to actually have it here.
There is a sign the value of repo dbag get all events right there if error is not equal to nil.
Actually, I need two arguments here, events, and er, that's better if er is not equal to nil, I'll
just log print, line the error and return and you'll do better.
Er checking in your production code, of course.
Now we need to have a data variable is a sign the value of make jet lag var map and data set events
and we'll just put in our events variable and pass that right here.
Data.
OK, so this should compile and run, let's make sure it does before we go any further, we'll run this.
OK, and let's go load that event's page just to make sure that things show up, even though there's
no data in there and we have an error and the error is syntax error.
So that's an error in our get all events.
I left a closing parentheses, which you undoubtedly noticed.
So let me go fix that, get all of that.
So insert into events this values this that one's OK.
Select ID event type.
Where did that come from.
That's better.
OK, so let's stop it and start it again.
And just reload this page and there it's displaying nothing because there's nothing to display, but
let's go fix that template before we go any further.
So the template is called let me hide this back to our handlers events jet.
So let's go find events dot jet right here.
And we're just going to put a range in here.
So I'll say if Lenn events is greater than zero.
ELT's.
And.
So if it's greater than zero, then we want to range through all the events, range events.
And and inside of that will have a table row and then some TDs, and the first one will be the event
type, which will be Daudt event type.
And I'll just duplicate this one, two, three, four more times, two, three, four.
So dot hostname, dot service name.
And then we're going to have a date and time will be.
Take from Lambe said, I called it, I can't remember.
I think it's called date from layout, and then we pass it the argument of created ad.
And we passed that the format that we want to use, which is two zero six zero one zero two three zero
four zero five p.m. and the event type is the last thing is the message.
OK, so that part should work.
If there's nothing in there, then just display tr td call span equals one, two, three, four, five.
No events.
OK, so that should compile.
If I get everything right now I think I'd look at that.
Good thing I noticed it there.
Let's try that.
Reload this and it should say no entries found events.
Unclosed less parentheses online, 45, line 45 right here.
Try that again, reload.
There it is, no events.
So it has no events in there whatsoever.
So now let's go and insert events.
Now, we have a method of doing that in the database, but where do we actually want to insert events?
Well, let's go back here.
We want to insert events any time the status changes.
So let's find out for perform checks.
Go right here and let's see where we do.
Events have changed.
Well, we want to do that, obviously, on test check.
No.
Not manual check.
We want to test service for host right there.
So here we test the service for the host, then we broadcast to clients if appropriate, if the status
has changed.
And it seems to me that this is obviously the place where we want to put in the fact that an event has
taken place.
So that's as simple as air is assigned.
The value of repo dbag insert an event and we have to put in an event.
So we'll build up that model right here.
The event is of type models event.
And it's event dot, actually, let's do it this way, it's a little easier event is a sign the value
of models dot event and we'll just say fill all fields and deleted because we're not using it.
OK, event type.
We'll have to figure out what that is in a minute.
I'll get back to that in a moment.
Hosted service ID.
Well, we have the host service idiots who ID Hoshide is idee service name is escort service DOT service
name.
Hostname is a dot hostname or we can get it from the host.
It doesn't matter the message.
So what is the message.
Well we get the message when we actually.
Via message, a new status, right, their message.
So message created and updated at our time dot now.
And time, not now, so the only thing we haven't dealt with here is the event type and what should
that be?
Well, I would think that it's nothing more than the new status.
So let's put in new status and that will be a problem, healthy pending warning, that sort of thing.
And that should take care of it for us.
So we have the area here.
Let's check for the error.
If error is not equal to nil, I'll just log there.
OK, so that will push in the new event.
OK, so I'm going to put a comment in here save event.
Now, let's stop our application, start our application and see if we can make this work, so I'll
go back to my overview.
Currently, I have one healthy service and all I should have to do is go back to my idy switched to
my Web server that I have running in the background and stop it and come back here.
And this should change in 10 seconds.
And I should see something in the schedules table so changed.
And I have a problem.
Not the schedule table.
The events table.
And I have no events, why not?
Syntax error at ordinaire message is I'm sloppy today, so we'll go fix that, and that would be in
the insert part in House Postgrads.
Hide this.
Insert into events.
Oh, yeah, I do that all the time.
Leave that comma out.
OK, so let's stop this.
Start this.
Go back to my my, uh, my Web browser, look at the overview page, and this time I'll start the Web
server to force the change in status and a reported healthy.
Now, if I go to the events page, I have a healthy perfect.
So now we have a means of displaying all of our events.
And I used a little plugin that gives a nice dynamic table and Padgett's when you get past 10 entries
and you can look at the source code for that.
I'm sure you're familiar with this sort of thing anyway.
So that one is done.
The next thing and this has been bothering me for some time is if we go back to the overview and we
look at the healthy services or any of these, that message is left empty.
And if you look in the database, there's actually nowhere to store that.
So let me bring up my my client and go to hosted services.
I have nowhere to put the last message in there.
I have last check, but I don't have last message.
So I'm going to add a column to the database and populate that and we'll take care of that in the next
election.