So before we get started updating the message column on the various tables, I did overlook one thing
in the last lecture and I have right here on the screen in front of us, the same file in two different
windows.
So on the right hand side is what we did last time where we built up an event model and then we inserted
it into the database.
And that is in the test service for host function, which is exactly what it should be doing.
But if we manually check a service, so if I'm back in my Web browser and I'm looking at localhost and
I look at it's one problem service that it has right now, if I clicked that check now button and the
status changes, it's not actually saving the event and I need to do that.
And that, of course, is again in the perform dash checks go file under the method named test check.
And all I have to do is after I test the host service and before I actually write the data right to
the database, the new status, I just have to put that same coded.
And the only change necessary is to change this colon equals into an equal sign and that takes care
of that problem.
And now the events table is updated, whether it's a regularly scheduled monitor check or it's one that
we've done manually by clicking that check now button.
OK, the next thing I want to do is back on the overview page.
If I look at any of the screens behind these four boxes, like the Problems Service, for example,
I want something to show up in this message column because that really bothers me.
And it's something that's been bothering me for a while and it's not difficult to fix.
But what it does require is a change to our database.
So if I look at my database, I'm looking at the host services table.
Nowhere in here do I have a place to put the last message we got.
I have a last check, so I'll just add a last underscore message, column of type string.
So let's go right on migration to do that.
So back in my ID, I will close this window, open my terminal, stop the application, clear the screen
and write a migration.
So to generate fiz, add last message to host services and I'll have that.
OK, now I'll open my browser on the left hand side, find the up migration and write that migration.
And that's just as simple as add underscore column open parentheses and then in quotes the name of the
table hosted services, then the name of the column which I'm going to call last underscore message,
then it's type which is string and then it's default.
And I am going to give this a default because I already have some entries in my host services table.
And if I don't give it a default or get an error, am I default will just be an empty string and I'll
close my curly brackets and close the parentheses.
And that's it for that one.
And the down migration is just drop underscore column, the table name hosted services and the column
name last message, and that's it for that one.
So now I should be able to run that migration.
So to migrate.
There it is.
And if you look at the table in the database right here, it's additive.
Perfect.
So we need to add that to our models.
So let me close these two migrations and go to our models file and find hosts service right here.
And I will add last message of type string to that.
OK, so since we made a change to our model and added a column in the database, we have to make some
changes in hosts or host underscore Posterous.
So let's find where we have to do that.
So first of all, let's just search for to make it easy, I'll search for hosting services, OK?
Not there.
Here.
What's this one?
This is getting all hosts.
OK, we may as well get it in there.
It's not going to hurt or anything.
So we'll add at the very end of the query for the services last message.
And that's the last thing I'm selecting.
So I'll add it here at the end of this part where I'm scanning and we're scanning it into the last message.
Now, I'll search for host underscore services again.
And this is updating that's just updating the active status.
So that doesn't matter.
But the next one is update ho service.
I definitely want to add it here.
So I'll put comma last message equals dollar sign nine, which changes this to dollar sign ten.
And that means I have to put my parameter right here.
Last message.
OK, and let's see if there's anywhere else.
Get service by status, and this is getting a service by status, services by status, and yet I have
to put it there as well.
So Staut last message, and that will be the last thing that I'm grabbing.
So that would be right here.
And H last message.
OK, let's check for one search for host underscore services again.
And this is get host service by IID.
I definitely need it there.
So I'll put my comma in and add H.
S dot last message and that's the last thing I'm selecting.
So it goes right here.
Last message and again, search for host underscore services and this is get services to monitor.
Do I need it there.
It's not going to hurt anything to do it.
And I'm returning the models of service.
So let's put it in their last message and that's the last thing I'm collecting.
So I'll put it in right here.
Last message and again, search for host underscore services.
And this is getting hosted service by host service.
I'd definitely need it there.
So comma
dot, last message and it's the last thing I'm selecting.
So it goes at the last of this list or the end of this list.
Last message, one more check for host underscore services.
And we're going back to the top.
And we've already done everything from this point on, OK, so that updates are postgrads.
I had to pause here and insert this little snippet into the lecture because I inadvertently deleted
something I shouldn't have and I didn't want you to get confused.
So I'm looking at the healthy DOGIT file.
And now that we have our new model for host services, I need to add something in here.
And this is in the empty column where I want the message on display.
And all I have to put in here is dot last message.
Otherwise, when we go back and try to look at this page, we'll still be seeing an empty column even
though we have the necessary information in the database.
So I apologize for the intrusive nature of this little snippet, but I need to put it in or things won't
make sense near the end of this lecture.
Now, when do we populate that field?
Well, I think the most obvious place to do this is right here and perform checks.
We're already making a change to the host service record.
And it's right here.
And this is in the method called test check.
So we're doing that in a manual check.
Let's just find what else we're doing that where do we update the host service status in the database?
I'm just searching for update host service.
So that's a status count we're passing at a hosted service right here.
Yeah, so this gets called update host service status count gets called on schedule check.
And right here, we're already changing the status and we can actually just actually pass that another
argument.
So we have here the new status.
We have the host service.
We can we're actually passing it the message already.
So this is the perfect spot to do it.
If we can just say last message equals message and that should do it for automated checks.
So let's try this.
Let's stop our application.
Start our application, go back and look and see what our status is look like right now, so we have
one problem service and let's go back and start our Web server and go back and watch this.
And the problem service should go away.
There it is.
And let's look under healthy services and we have our message posted there.
Perfect.
So that's for automated checks.
The only other place to do this is and I'm going to switch back to my correct window.
The only other place to do this is on the manual, which is called Test Check right here.
So here we broadcast the service and we did exactly the same thing right here.
We already have our message.
So we just put in here a dot.
Last message equals MSJ, and that should take care of it for that.
So the only other change is to go back to healthy jet, find this last message and I'll copy that.
And now we open the other three windows.
So problems we can just paste that right in here and warning, which is right here and the last one
is pending right here.
And that should take care of it.
OK, so now we have those fields in or those columns in the tables populated with data, and I feel
better about that.
All right.
We'll move on in the next lecture.