So far, all we've been doing is pushing events to a public channel that all authenticated users can
see, and we actually have the ability using this push her library and our push for compatible server
to send things to private channels and private channels can work anywhere you want.
So I'm looking at Jagjit right now and I'm going to create a new variable let private channel and I'm
going to write some code here to demonstrate how to send things to a private channel.
It's not really appropriate for our use case with this monitoring software, but I'll show you how it
works.
It's pretty straightforward.
That's going to be equal to, again, Pusher.
And we're going to subscribe and I want to subscribe to a private channel.
But what I want to do is subscribe to a private channel that is specific to this user.
In other words, something in the system, in our application pushes an event, but only one particular
user gets that event.
So what I subscribe to here, of course, is my user I.D. And where am I going to get that?
Well, if you look at Helper's, don't go in the starter code.
This is that line 76 of Helper's ago.
Actually add some default data.
And if I'm logged in, I store information about the user in the session or in the not in the session
in the data that's pushed to all templates.
So I have this, this TD user and I can access that anywhere in any template if I'm authenticated simply
by saying user ID because it's the user model.
So now I'm subscribing in effect to a private channel dash and then the user ID.
And one thing to be really cautious about when you're creating public channels, they must begin with
the word public.
When you're creating private channels, they must begin with the word private, all in lowercase, exactly
as I have it here in these two examples.
So now that I subscribe to this, let's actually listen to an event and I'm going to create an artificial
event that will send to this authenticated user.
OK, so I'll simply say private channel, dot bind and I will bind for an event called Private Message.
And again, this is an artificial event that I'm going to create and send with a little bit of sample
code.
And again, it's a function and it takes the data that's passed back to us by the server.
And all I'm going to do here is taking advantage of that little prompt JavaScript module, which I called
attention.
I'll just display an alert.
And I'll just populate two things, HTML, which I'll get from the data variable that's passed to this
anonymous function and sent by the application itself, which we'll get to momentarily, and we'll look
for a message and I'll give it an icon and I'll just call that success.
Doesn't matter what the icon is, I'm just showing how you can send things to a private channel.
So now I'm listening to that event, but we don't have anything that sends it yet.
So I'm going to go over to my push or go file and I'll just create a simple sample code right here and
I'll call it func.
It'll have the repo of Star DB repo and it's a handler and I'll call it send a private message and because
it's a handler requires a response writer and a pointer to a request.
And here I'm just going to build up and send a really simple message.
So I'll assume I'm going to get some variables from the URL.
So you are variables, things that are encoded as a get request.
And the first one will be MSgt, which is a message and I'll just get that from arguido dot query dot
get and I'll look for the key of MSG and then I need the user ID and I'll just call that ID and ID.
So now I have a message and the user id I want to send this to.
So let's build up a data variable which is a type map, string string and this is what we're going to
use to send to our pusher compatible server and data, I'll call it message is the key is equal to the
message that we grab from the URL and now I'll just trigger my my client and send it.
And I'm not going to bother doing anything else other than sending this over pusher's.
So when we actually call the URL, we'll get a blank screen.
But that's fine.
We just want to trigger the event, so I'll ignore the error.
And that's equal to app dot.
Try that again.
Repo dot app dot WC client dot trigger and I'll trigger two and I have to build up a string here.
So format as print f I'm going to trigger two private dash channel dash and then a string because I'm
getting the idea as a string and I'll just put it in there.
So that will send it to my case because I'm going to send it to user ID, one private dash channel dash
one.
The second key is our event, which is a private message.
That's what we're listening for in our Jagjit.
And the data is just the data.
OK, so I'll give this a comment and I'll just call it is sample code too for sending to private channel.
OK, now we need to put something in our roots.
I have a typo here somewhere.
Right here.
Make a map.
String, string, that's better.
Now let's open our roots file and just create a dummy route to send this to, so I'll put it in the
authenticated section and I'll make it the very first route and I'll call it a sample code for sending
to private channel and I'll just call it as a Getrude Muxtape get.
And the pattern will be slash admin is added by this code up here, then slash private message and that
will call handlers.
Repo dot send private message.
OK, so this is now ready to test, and again, it's going to be a really simple thing, so let me stop
my application.
Start my application, I'll go back and reload this page and I have to log in again for some reason,
admin at example, dot com password, remember me?
Log in.
OK, let's first of all, look at our JavaScript.
So I'm going to look at the source code and search for private channel.
And you can see here I'm actually binding to private dash channel dash one.
OK, so this is working now.
I'm going to open another browser window and make it smaller just so I can actually test this and I
am logged in already.
So let me go to localhost 4000, make sure I'm logged in.
I am.
And let's change that you url to and I'll change it to admin slash send.
Not just private message as thought it was private message, and I will give it some arguments, Ms.
G equals hello and I'll put a 20 in there just to encode a properly world ampersand ID equals one.
Now, let me drag this down so we can see the other screen return.
And there it is, and the only user that would get that message is the one that subscribe to private
channel DASH one, which because the user ID is unique among users, only this person would get it.
And that's all there is for sending private messages.