So we need to install a local mail server and it is a testing mail server, and while you could actually
populate the necessary configurations right in your server configuration, when you're sending mail
and send it through a live server in development, that's never a good idea and it's never a good idea
because occasionally at some point you will be working with data that includes actual email addresses
and you'll be sending emails left, right and center without realizing you're actually sending to real
people.
So the way we get around that is by installing a local mail server and using that instead.
Or you could use mail trapped or one of the commercial services.
But I find mail hug are really easy to use package.
And if you're on a Mac, then this lecture will show you how to install it on a Macintosh.
If you're on Windows, then it's a little different.
So I'll have a separate lecture for that because I need to be in front of a Windows machine to do it.
But first of all, go here, go to my blog and when you scroll down, it'll tell you how to install
it.
And on Mac it says Use Broo update and install Malha.
Now, you can't do that unless you happen to have homebrew already installed if you don't go install
it.
It's a really simple process and it's incredibly useful.
Homebrew has thousands and thousands of packages which are of immense use to developers.
For example, we could have set up postgrads using homebrew on a Mac or on a Mac and it would be just
as just as functional as the one that I had you install.
Actually, I'm using postgrads installed through Homebrew anyway to install it.
Copy this command as it appears here.
So just copy it or click the copy button.
Not even easier.
Go to your favorite terminal, open a new window and paste it in and then run it.
Now I already have it installed so I'm not going to install it, but this will actually install it for
you and it will take a little while.
So once that's done, you just use the commands right on this page back here, copy and paste this.
And when you do that, once it's installed mail hug, you will be able to run it by using the command
line or more more usefully, you can actually use this command Broo Services start mail hook and that
will start it for you.
I have it stopped right now, running right now.
So I'll stop it.
I'll stop the service
bus services, stop mail hug.
And brew services start mail hug, I guess they didn't have it running and we'll start it.
So now it's running.
So now that it's running, I can go to my favorite browser and type in HTTP called English Localhost
Colen eight 025.
So it's running on a port eight 025 and there is mail hug up and running.
So install that.
And in the next lecture I'll show Windows people how to install it on your Windows machine.