So starting a mail hog on windows is actually really, really easy, you just download it from the site,
as I showed you with the last lecture, and you drag it to your desktop or put it wherever you want
and double click on it.
And once it's double clicked, it will actually start up.
So I can go to my favorite Web browser.
And connect to localhost a25.
And there's mail hug, so just make sure you have it running when you're trying to test the email functionality
from your application and you'll be good.
Now, if it's not running, you'll get an error.
So just go start it up and try again and you'll be fine and to quit out of it.
It's pretty straightforward.
Just close this window and that's all there is to it.
It couldn't be simpler.