So now that we have male hogge installed, at least I'm using male hug, you can use whatever system
you want to trap female.
We need to make some changes to our application.
So right now I'm looking at the settings page, which I get to by clicking on settings.
And before I do anything, let's go look at the database.
So in the database on my vigilante database, I'm looking at the preferences table and right now there
are only three things in there.
So weather monitoring is live, the check interval unit and the check interval amount.
When I go back here to my settings, first of all, you have to put a irlam, so I'll put the URL of
my application in here.
We're not doing anything with that, but it needs to be in there.
And I figure if we're going to make this a production application at some point, you might use that.
So I put it in there.
Then on the second tab, a notifications, I'll say I want to receive messages by email and I'll put
my name in here.
And since I'm using a dummy dummy server, I can use whatever I want and I'll leave text message empty.
And then for mail server settings because I'm using mail hog localhost is my SMTP server.
The port is ten twenty five.
The mail is sent from and again this is just a dummy thing.
Alerts that example dot com alerts that example.
Dot com and mail hug doesn't require a username or a password.
So I'll save this and I'll save and continue.
And I want to go back and look at the preferences table and reload it.
We have a lot more things in here and we'll be using some of these in this lecture.
So now we have that set up.
So it's possible to send email from our application.
But of course, we're not actually doing that yet.
So if we go back to our source code, you'll notice under Internal and the Helpers package, I have
a file called sendmail dot com, and that's a little tiny helper function that we can use to send email
from anywhere in our application.
And it grabs default information like the we can actually get rid of this entirely.
So we don't.
I copied this code for sending emails from from another application and we do need to make some changes
to it.
But this is our simple function and all it does is pass something to our our app variable, which I
said in the helper's package to a channel which I called MailChimp, and we pass a job in there.
And the job is of type channel data mail job, which we get right from here, channel data, mail data.
And this again I copied from an existing project has way more information, way more members than we
actually need in this.
But it's not going to hurt anything to leave it there.
And under command web.
We have jobs, Dasch Dutko.
And here's where we need to make some changes.
This is a really common pattern.
I actually got it from the guerrilla group, the people that made guerrilla websocket.
That's the pattern.
And all it does is make sure that we can handle a high volume of things coming into our mail chart.
So since this application might be monitoring 100 servers with ten services each, for example, we
could potentially be sending a lot of email.
So rather than just doing a simple kind of send mail I could find in a tutorial online, I thought I'd
put some production quality code in here for you.
The part we need to change the very bottom, the part that says process, mail, Q job.
And we need to make some changes here because I'm using things that don't exist in this application.
For example, this was taken from an application that didn't use jet templates.
It used goaland templates.
And this function expects to find a template cache, which we don't have.
So you can delete all of this everything right from the beginning of this function down to this return,
closing parentheses or closing brace.
So delete that, then scroll on down.
And just below the data struct right here, this data struct, just below that, we need to add some
code and we need to add some code that tells this function where to find a standard goaland template.
So I'll create a variable called pads and it's assigned the value of a slice of string and we'll have
one string in there pointing to a file that doesn't exist yet, mailed a template and we'll make that
in a minute, so don't worry about it.
So that gives me a variable.
Now I need to actually pass that template.
So t just a variable name I'm choosing is assigned template dot must and then template new.
And we want to get mailed today.
That's the name of the template we're going to be using and then dot persse files and pass in pads,
dot, dot, dot, all of the values that we find in this string, OK?
And I just use this because you might have more mail templates you want to use and make them all available
to your particular application.
So now that we've passed that, everything else should stay pretty much the same.
And as you can see here, there's a lot of code we're not actually using, but it's set up.
So you can use this with very few changes in production.
So we've done that part.
The next question is where do we send email?
So we left ourselves a to do comment here in performed dash checks ago and the Tudou says send email
or SMS if appropriate.
So obviously the only time we want to send notifications is for background checks.
When people test a service manually, they're going to get the necessary feedback right on the screen.
So we don't want to give them feedback on the screen and then send them an email and then send them
a text that just gets irritating.
So we'll just do it here in this function, which is called test service for hosts.
And this is the one that runs as part of our schedule in the background.
And that's where we want to send alerts.
And we already have this broadcast to clients, if appropriate, that checks the new status against
the old status.
And this this if statement seems to be the logical place to send email or SMS.
So we'll cut this comment out of here and I will paste it right here, get rid of the two do and the
Sims part and just give myself another Tudou to do.
Send SMS if appropriate approach Pritt.
OK, under what situations do we want to send email.
What if you think it through.
There's only.
One situation, and that is where the status has changed and the old status was not pending because
it was a pending service, you can just watch it.
So I'm going to make that decision.
I'll say, first of all, if in our preference map, repo app preference, map the preference and I'll
go look at this database table again.
The preference that says notify via email is equal to one.
And remember, that's a string.
So if notified via email is equal to one as a string, then I know I want to receive notifications via
email.
And the second thing I'll check is to make sure that we're not having an old status of pending FHA status,
which is our old status, if that is not equal to pending, because I don't want to get alerted every
time the first healthy check shows up, I just want to know when there's problems or when something
comes back from a problem state.
So here's where we want to send email.
So go back to our sendmail function, send dash mail, go in the helpers package that expects to find
something of channel data, dot mail data type.
So let's create one of those.
So I'll create the variable and I'll call it mom for mail.
Message is of type channel data.
Mail data, and in that, I'll put in only two things to name who's going to get this, the name of
the person who's receiving it, and we get that from repoll app preference map.
And again, if you look over in the in the preferences table.
Here you'll see that I have my name and it's notify, underscore name, notify, underscore name and
I'll duplicate that.
And the second thing I want to specify is to address and that is, again, back in our database, we
can find my email, notify underscore email.
Notify, underscore email.
OK, so I've made this variable.
Now I want to populate one more part of that mail data object.
And the only part I'm interested in for this course, and I'll look at it, is this content, which
is of type template HTML.
But I'm going to have different kind of content.
I shall do the subject to I'll have different kind of kinds of content and a different subject based
upon what the value of new statuses.
And remember, we get our message and new status when we run our check for the service http.
So let's go down here and just do an if statement if new status is equal to healthy.
They don't have a certain subject and a certain piece of content else, if new status is equal to and
the second one will be problem, I'll have a different subject and a different piece of content else.
If new status is equal to warning, we don't have any warnings right now.
So I can leave that empty for the moment and come back in populated if necessary.
So let's do the healthy one.
First of all, I want to get a subject, my subject.
Is equal to format or Sprint F and my subject will be really simple, healthy in all caps.
Service percent s on percent s.
And that's all I need for the subject, and I'll replace those placeholders with the service name,
age, service, service name and the host name on hostname.
OK, so let's copy that and paste it here and just changes to problem in all caps.
OK, now let's build up our message and these are going to be really, really simple messages in really
plain looking emails.
I'm not going to put any formatting in there at all.
You can do that to your heart's content if you so desire.
So much content can't be a string.
It has to be of type template HTML, but we can cast it to that template HTML.
And inside of that I'll have a format dot print f statement and just make it as simple as I can.
So I'll say service percent s on percent.
S reported healthy status and that's all I need.
OK, or maybe I can put the message in there too.
So let's wrap this whole thing in a paragraph tag.
And change these quotes to back ticks so I can go to the second line.
An extra back there that's better and on the next line, I'll just put in my placeholders or another
paragraph of text P and I'll just say healthy status reported.
I'll make it strong, healthy.
Our message received
percent, yes, and close that paragraph tag and put in my three placeholders, which are escort service,
that service name has on hostname and the message we got.
OK, so that can be copied and we'll modify it for the second one for our problem status.
And I'll paste it in there and I'll say, instead of reported healthy status, a reported problem
and on the second line, everything else should be the same.
OK, and I'll leave this one empty because we don't have any warnings right now and we'll come back
and do that if necessary.
So now we've built up our message and all we need to do is send the email.
And that's as simple as helpers don't send mail and we pass it.
Emam Our mail message, which is of type channel data dot mail did.
So the last thing we need to do is to go over to our views folder and create that new file that we expect
to find.
So I'll create a new file and it's got to be called mailed template for template and I'll just use my
built in Emet function HTML five to quickly put in an HTML template.
It doesn't need a title.
I'll ignore all of this.
It should be fine for our purposes and inside the body.
I just have a have to have a place to put content.
All right, now, let's see if this works, let's stop our application, start our application.
Go back and look and see what the status of things currently are, so we have one healthy service,
which means I have my Web server running in the background.
So let's go.
Stop that.
There's my Web server or stop it.
Go back and watch this.
That should switch to problem, and it did.
Let's go look at our log file in our application, invalid syntax in male command.
So I got a problem there somewhere.
Let's see what we have wrong.
It must be and perform checks.
To name is notify, name to address is notify email.
And then we send it, so we go to Sendmail, the Frum stuff, you remember I deleted that a while ago.
Let's just undo that.
You can't send it without a valid sender and receiver or sender name and send her email.
All right.
Let's stop this.
Run it again.
Go back, look at our services.
We should have one problem, let's make that problem go away.
So I'll switch to my Web server, my test web server, start that back up.
Go watch my application.
And it reports healthy and let's look at our log file and hopefully there'll be no error messages in
their email sent.
Perfect.
And I already have mail hog running, so I should have an alert and I do service HTP on localhost report
of healthy status.
It's got the correct subject.
Now let's make that a problem again.
So I'll go back to the inbox here and I'll delete the messages so I don't have to figure out which one
is the most recent.
And I'll stop my web server go back and watch this again.
This should switch to problem and it does.
And we should have a new email message that says problem service HTP on localhost er connecting.
OK, so now we can send emails and you can make whatever changes you want to the HTML template.
You can make it more attractive if you wish to, but for our purposes we just want to send emails.
So in the next lecture we'll take care of this bit, we'll go to our settings and specify that we want
to receive SMS messages.
OK, so we'll take care of that in the next lecture.