So one of the things we need is a local server with a local service to monitor and I mean, I suppose
we could just try to monitor Google and hope that it goes down to see when things go wrong.
But that might take a while.
So instead, we've already entered a host on our application called Localhost, and it listens on port
eighty eighty for an HTTP service.
So the simplest way to make this work is just to compile this very, very short program that listens
on Port 80 and returns Hello World.
And that's all that it does.
So this is a very short program.
I've actually added to this full source code for this to the course resources for this page.
And once you have it, you can just run it by saying, you know, go run Dudko.
And that will listen on Port AT&amp;T.
And that's what it does.
It's now listening on Port AT&amp;T.
So if I go to my favorite Web browser and try to go to HTP Collins localhost AT&amp;T, it actually returns
Hello World.
So we can start that and stop it as necessary to make sure that services are being monitored properly.
And we'll start doing that in the next lecture.