So the last bit of key functionality we need to add to our project in terms of notifications is sending
notifications via SMS or text message, and we'll do that using Twilio.
And what we'll do is create a developer account, a trial account that gives us a certain balance to
use for testing.
And provided you do this in the next month or two, you should have no problem doing this and having
it cost you nothing.
So go to this Eurail Twilio dot com and I've put a link to that in the course resources sign up and
you'll get a trial account.
And once you've done that, you'll get to the console page and the console page looks just like this
and you're going to have an account.
Essid and an off token.
This is public.
Doesn't matter if anybody else sees this.
This is private.
So I'm not going to show that to you, even though I'm going to change it after this lecture is done.
I can copy it just by copying it right here.
So in my application, before we do anything else, let's set this up.
So I've gone to the Settings page and clicked on the SMS tab over here and I will say, yes, enable
text notifications and I'm going to choose the one provider that I'm doing in this course.
There are other providers and they all follow a very similar format.
So I'll choose Twilio and I'll put in my Twilio phone number, which I'll get in a minute.
But let's get our key first.
So I'll go back to here and I'll choose this.
Copy my essid.
And paste it in here and go to my here and copy the off Tolkan.
And pasted in here.
Now, in order to make this as simple as possible, I've also posted a link to the a blog post put up
by Twilio that talks about using gold and sending SMS messages, and you'll find that right here.
So, again, this URL is copied and pasted into the course resources for this lecture.
And what you want to do is scroll down to the part that says, I don't know why they're there.
Formatting is off and some of the text is behind images, but it doesn't really matter for our purposes.
So this is the part you want to look at.
Say hello to Twilio and that will take you through all of the steps necessary to to get a trial account
up and going.
And at the time that I'm recording this, at least you get fifteen dollars and fifty cents in test balance
so you can test things out.
So follow these instructions and get it all set up.
And you'll also see the part where it asks you to get a phone number and get that phone number and paste
it in here and I'll go get mine and paste it in here and then we'll pick it up in the next lecture and
actually start sending test SMS messages.