So just to make this as simple as possible, I'm going to create a new account on Twilio as well and
I'll use a different email here just so I can get a new account and you can follow along just in case
you're having difficulties.
So I'll generate a password and I use one password to generate passwords.
So I'll copy this one and paste it in here and I'll change it after this lecture because I think you
just saw it.
But that's OK.
I accept the terms and conditions.
I'll start the free trial and I will save this as Twilio there.
OK, so they sent me an email.
I'll pause this, go verify everything and come back and continue.
OK, so I went and clicked on verify email in the appropriate message that I received and it took me
to this screen.
Now I've already got an off token aside, so I'm going to copy those.
I'll copy my new side and go back to my other screen here.
Close this one and go back to Vigilante and go to settings and put in under my Twilio.
I'll put my new aside, so I'll paste that in there.
Then I'll go back here and get my new off token.
Copy that, paste that in here and now I'll get a trial number.
So I'll get this trial number and I will copy this right like that.
And I'm just going to take the default one.
And again, you should pay attention if you're actually getting charged for text messages.
You may not want to do this, but I'm getting rid of the hyphen and everything, all the hyphens and
put on the parentheses and putting a plus sign in front of it.
OK, so now I have that and under notifications now I actually want to receive them by text message
as well.
And I'll simply put in my own cell phone number and I'll blurt out so I don't get any phone calls from
anybody else.
And save this.
OK, so that's now saved.
So let's go back to the console councillor's.
I should have everything I need at this point to get started.
So I've got that set up in the next lecture will actually write the necessary code to send SMS messages.