So in the last lecture, I actually closed the dialogue that gave me my test, Twilio number two, quickly,
I should have clicked save, so I had to go and get a new phone number.
And hopefully you didn't do that.
If you did back in your Twilio console, you'll still have a get test number here or something.
Just so just click that.
Choose the default number, click save and then it will give you the number to paste into your preferences
in exactly the right format.
So copy and paste that.
So I have a number that's functional.
Now let's go back to our Idy and start writing some code and I'm going to write the code in a package
and the package I will call SMS.
I don't have to put it in a package, but I'm going to say I'll create a new directory in my internal
folder called.
Esme's and inside of Esme's, I'll create a new go file, which I will call Twilio Dutko and I will
add that to my repository and I'll just write the function and it's pretty straightforward.
I'll read a funk and I'll just call it send or send text, send text with send text while you keep it
short and it will take a few parameters to and message, both of which will be strings.
So the number I want to send it to and the message I want to send and I will also pass it on my app,
which will be of type a pointer to config app config because we're going to use some values from our
app config.
So we need that now.
I'll grab my secrets.
So my secret, this is the Essid or the the the token from Twilio.
Twilio, because I've saved that in my preferences screen that's now in my preference map.
So I can just grab that from app preference map.
Dot, dot, dot, dot in square brackets.
Twilio underscore auth, underscore token because that's what it's called, hidden preferences.
And you can look in the database and see that for yourself.
And the key is again from my preference map and this one is called Twilio Underscore Side.
So I need those two two pieces of information to send anything and the U are l I actually got directly
out of that blog post that I pointed you to a couple of lectures ago, and I need to build a euro as
a string, so I'll use my format as print f function and I'll pace are putting the url hebes colon slash
slash api dot twilio dot com slash twenty ten dash zero four dash zero one slash accounts with a capital
a slash and then I'll put a percent percent s for a placeholder slash messages dot Jason and the placeholder
is replaced with my key.
OK, so that gives me my, my key which replaces this percent.
S so now I have my euro and all I have to do is follow the instructions in that tutorial which are ever
so simple.
Message data is a variable I'm going to create of type U.
URL values.
And for some reason, my I.D. did not import that for me, so I'll just go put it in myself.
Net slash Yoro.
I see what I did, I made a mistake there.
Let's just delete this you URL and call this you a string.
That's the problem.
OK, so it should have been pointed it for me, but I actually accidentally called that you URL, which
is a package name, and you ought not to do that sort of thing.
So now I have an empty message data and let's put some stuff in there.
So according to the blog post, I need to have message data set and the first thing is to add the value
for that we're getting from our parameters to the next thing is message data set from and use the uppercase
letters exactly as I'm doing right here.
And I'll get that from my preference map app preference map.
And I'm looking for the key Twilio phone number, which is the test number.
Next, we want the body of the text message data set body with a capital B, and that will be equal
to the message which we're taking as a parameter up here.
And now we need to set up a message data reader, and that is a sign the value of a pointer to strings,
not new reader.
And we're just creating a new reader, as you would in any go application.
And this is going to be encoding our message data.
And code, and I can tell you, are euro values into a reader, and we need that to do the next step.
So the next step is to create an HDTV client, which I'll just call client.
And that's assign the value of ampersand HTP client with the curly braces after it.
And now we just make a request, so we're going to get the result and potentially something I'm going
to ignore and we're going to do an HTP got new request and the method is post because we're posting
to that URL and we're posting to you earlier string, which we defined right up here.
And we're going to pass it a reference to our message data reader, which gives us our post values for
a post request.
And after that, we set our basic off the authentication.
And this is straight out of that blog post, set basic off.
And our username is our key and our password is our secret, which we got from our app preference map.
And now we want to say except Jason.
So request header dot.
And.
Except.
And then application Jason, Jason,
and at another header request header, add content, dash type exactly like that.
The case matters here application.
X w w w dash form dash yoro encoded.
And make sure I type that right, x w w form, you are uncoated.
Yup, that's correct.
And then we get a response response and I'll ignore the second parameter is assigned the value of client
not do.
The request.
And if restante status code is greater than or equal to 200 and the status code from the RESP is less
than 300.
Status code.
And things are good, so we get our data, we'll create a new variable VAD data, which is a map string,
and it's going to hold any type we want.
So I'll put an interface in there.
The second as the type of the string here.
Now we want to decode this decoder is a sign the value of Jason's new new decoder and we pass it the
response body.
And now we decode things.
Error is a sign the value of Decoder Decode, and we're decoding a reference to data if error is not
equal to nil.
I'll just log the error log print line error and I'll return.
I don't want to go any further.
It didn't work.
Down here, closing this statement or this statement, we add an ounce, so if we don't get a status
code in this range, then we have something that's gone wrong.
And again, I'll do exactly the same thing I did here, log and return.
And I will I can't log in and I'll just say they're sending SMS, OK?
And you can do whatever error checking you wanting there finally will say return nil now to actually
have a return type up here.
Error there.
That's better.
So here will return an error and here will return errors.
New error sending SMS.
Wrong response code.
And errors are not supposed to start with a capital letter, so there so that's a function that will
allow us to send our text now back and perform checks.
Let's go find that to do and see if we want to actually send that response message.
So let's get rid of the two.
And again, we have some conditions we want to check before we actually send things.
So we'll say if repo dot app, dot preference map and I'm looking for the key in there, which is notify
via SMS.
And that is equal to the string value of one that we want to send our response.
OK, and this doesn't belong here, of course.
Let's get this out of here.
Maybe it does.
Let's see where the check is that we're inside the correct spot.
So here we're checking to see if the old status is not equal to the new status.
So we're where we need to be good.
So two is going to be assigned the value of what are we texting to where we're texting to from repo
dot app, dot preference map.
And we're looking for the key SMS notify.
No.
And the message we'll just make that an empty string, because we need to build different messages.
So just as we did up here, we need to say if new status is equal to healthy, so a copy that and paste
it and then I'll do an else else.
If new status is equal to the problem, we're going to do something else else.
If new status is equal to warning, we'll do something else.
And all we're doing here is just building a message.
So we'll say MSgt equals format, Sprint F and the text will be something as simple as because this
is healthy service percent s on percent s is healthy and replace that with an escort service service
name and address hostname.
And I'll copy this.
And paste it and paste it and I can say, is reports a problem and this time I actually want to get
a third thing in this text message, so I'll put percent.
S.
And what I want here, of course, is MSgt.
The message we got after we tested our host and I'll just copy this one and use it to replace this one,
reports a warning and then we just text it so pretty straightforward after if we say error is a sign,
the value of SMS, our new package does send text to Twilio and it wants a two.
Well, we already have that.
It wants the message MSG, which, you know, I'm got variable shadowing going on, going on here.
Let me fix this SMS message.
Copy, paste, paste, paste, paste.
OK, so I actually would have had the wrong message up here because I created a new variable with the
name MSG there, which was sloppy on my part.
And I apologize, but I'm glad I caught it.
So to message.
And we want our app, which is repo app.
And we checked for an error, if error is not equal to nil and I'll just log print line error, error,
sending SMS in, perform checks go and the error.
OK, so that should do it.
So if I actually stop my application, start my application.
Everything should be set up properly, so let's go back and see what's actually going to happen.
So let's go to notifications and I'll turn on by text message.
So that's turned on.
Let me save it.
OK, we have one problem service.
So let me switch back to my.
I'd eat and turn over to my Web browser and I'm going to turn the volume up on my phone just to make
sure that everything is going to work the way that it should.
And if this works properly, once I start my main dock, go and quickly switch back to my Web browser,
it reported healthy.
And if you heard that ding, I got a text.
And if I read it, it says.
Sent from your Twilio trial account service HTTP on localhost is healthy, and that's exactly what I
wanted to see.
So that's all there is to sending texts.
Now, if you want to save your trial balance, make sure you go back to settings and go to notifications
and turn text message off and safe.
Now, word of caution again, if you're getting charged for international texts and the local number
it gave you was not a local number, then don't do this.
Otherwise, it might be costing you money.
But the logic for doing it is very straightforward.
And if you ever need to send SMS from a ghost account or go application, it's really straightforward
to do it.
So you can use Twilio, you can use next MO.
I think next month is actually part of Vonage, but I'm not sure.
But there are lots of services out there and they're all relatively inexpensive.
But what I'm developing, I don't want to be paying money that I'm probably not billing anybody else
for just to get things working.
So a trial account is the way to go?
Well, that takes care of the core functionality for our application.
There's a few cosmetic things we can clean up and we will before we're done.
But the next thing I want to do is just to try monitoring a couple of new services and we'll do that
in the next section.