So now that we have a local Web server listening on Port 80, ready to start and minds not running right
now, and you're shouldn't be either, and if it is, please stop it.
What I want to do is to write code so that every time our scheduled check runs in the background and
we just have one right now listening to or watching our local localhost, Port 884, the HTTP service,
if the status that I have in the database changes after I monitor it, I want this page to be updated.
So in our case, I want the one that displayed right here to change to a zero.
If I start the Web service and it actually finds it and says everything's healthy and I want the healthy
service to be incremented by one.
So this becomes a zero, this becomes a one.
And how are we going to make that happen?
Well, actually, right now, if you look at our code and I go to the file, perform dash checks, don't
go the function that runs every time we run a schedule check has nothing in it.
So it's not going to do anything.
And passing it a host service ID and I'm running a schedule check, but nothing actually happens.
So just to make sure that my schedule is actually running the way that I think it is, I'm going to
put a log print line and then a few stars so I can see things running check for and then I'll just put
the whole service idea here, which is passed as a parameter, this function.
OK, so that will now actually do something I can watch and make sure that the schedule is firing.
And because I'm an impatient individual, I'm going to go to my database and I'm going to look at the
host services table and I'm going to change the schedule number from the default of three minutes to
say ten seconds, which I would never do on a production server, because that's far too frequent and
it's putting unnecessary load on a on a production server.
But it's perfect for development.
Ten seconds.
I can wait that long, so I'll save those changes.
Then I'll go back to my application and I'll stop it if it's running and it is and I'll run it.
So it starts up and I'll go back to my actual Web browser, reload the page to make sure everything's
current and I'll turn monitoring on and monitoring is now starting.
And what I'm going to do is come back here and wait 10 seconds.
There he ran the check for one.
Let's make sure it runs a second time.
And there it is now, Isleton monitoring off, OK?
And when I come back here and watch it again and wait 10 seconds.
Four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
OK, now I know it's working and that's perfect.
So I'm going to stop my application and I'll do something more useful than simply printing to the log
file.
So what I'm going to do here, I'm passing it a host service.
And what I will actually want to do is to call the test service for host, which is way down here somewhere.
Let's find it test service for hosts.
And it requires the host model and it requires the host service model and returns to strings.
OK, so I can go get the host and go get the host service.
That's easy enough.
So hosts service.
I'll get first because that's the first thing I have and I need to check for an error and that is repo.
Try that again.
Repo db dot get host service by ID and I'll pass it in the parameter.
I've received post service ID and I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, I'll just log print line error and I'll return because I don't want to
go any further if something's gone wrong.
Now I've got the whole service.
Let's get the host.
Host and error are equal to repo db dot get hosted by ID and I get this from Scott.
Host it.
Now I have the host and I'll just copy my error message and return this and I can run the check, so
I'm going to get two things back from that.
And what am I getting back?
Let's find them again.
Test service for host.
I'm getting back the new status and the message.
OK, so new status and the message are assigned the value of repo test service for host.
Pass it the host and pass it the host service and then I'll just print those out.
OK, so log print line.
New status is new status and message is a message which might be empty, but we'll find out in a minute.
So that should be a comma.
OK, so I've got that information and I'm just going to start my application again.
Run it.
And wait 10 seconds.
Make sure that works, as I expect.
Maybe I stopped my host monitoring, I think I did turn it back on.
And wait 10 seconds.
There it is, so new, says problem and message, is the air connecting?
Now I'm going to switch my terminal, my ID, I have the Hello World app running opened in the background
here or in a different window.
So I'll run it.
I'll say, go, run, man.
Go and quickly switch back to my other one and now it's healthy.
OK, so I know that my service checks are working exactly as I want.
So what I want to do, I'm going to start my application just so it's not doing anything in the background.
What I want to do here is no question that I want to make some changes at this point.
So let's write some comments.
I want, first of all, to update the host service record in the database with status if changed.
And I definitely want to update the last check record.
OK, so back in our database, in my house service, if I look at the structure, I have the status
which is right here, and I also have the date and time of the last check, which defaults to year one,
January the 1st at one second after midnight.
So I definitely want to update that.
And that's really easy.
So I can just I I've already got the host status record right here, HFS, so I just update those.
So after I call test service for host, I'm going to say state status is equal to my new status, which
might not have changed.
And last check is equal to time now and then I just update update the record in the database.
So error equals repo DB dot update.
And what I want to update here is how service.
So I have that somewhere.
There it is.
And I just passed my ho ho service model and I check for an error and I'll just copy and paste this,
put it in here.
Now let's get this comment in the right location because it doesn't belong there and down here it comes.
Right after I do the test house for service there, so this test of the service and we get a response
and then we update the record in the database, and that's all that it is.
It's all that we really need to do.
So I can get rid of this, but I'll leave it there for right now after we've done this.
At this point, we need to make a decision if the host status hosted service has changed broadcast to
all clients.
And I'll put another comment here, because we're also going to want to, if appropriate,
appropriate send email or SMS message.
So we're not going to do that for a little while.
But presumably the people that are actually using software like this to monitor host services don't
spend their entire day and night watching a webpage.
Presumably they're going to be away sometimes and you want to alert them if something has gone wrong
or something has come back that has already gone down.
And the easiest way to do that is to send an email message or a text message, and we'll do that near
the end of the course.
But right now, this is the part that's of interest to us if the whole service status has changed broadcast
to our clients.
So this is the point where we're going to over in our JavaScript file.
We're going to bind to the public channel, listen for a specific event, a service status has changed
and do something.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.