So now we're at the point where we actually want to broadcast a message to all connected clients if
the service status or the host service status has changed since the last check.
And we need to do that before we actually update the database, before we change his status with news
status.
So we actually need to do that right here.
So I'm going to take this comment and cut it out of here and move it up to here, because this is where
we actually have to do it.
So all we need to do is to say if new status is not equal to star status, then we need to do something.
So here's where we broadcast and we're also, if appropriate, we'll send her email.
We need to do that before we update the database or before we update our service record.
So this is the part where we want to do it and we need to broadcast a service and we already know how
to do that.
It's really straightforward.
So the way we've been doing it right along.
Let me scroll down here till I find one.
We actually do it like, well, it's not in here, must be in the handler's.
We find the trigger trigger right here.
We do it like this and this works so I could copy this, I could go back to perform checks or my where's
it here?
Right here, I could paste that in there and broadcast that message, and that will work, but if you
think about it all we're really doing every time we trigger app client trigger, we're passing a channel
name, we're passing it a app, starting our app, stopping one of our messages wherever the thing we're
looking for on our client JavaScript and some data.
So we could simplify this just by writing a function.
Let's do that.
So let's create a new function and I'll put it right below this one and we can move it somewhere later
if we don't like it where it is.
But that's OK.
We'll just say func and it doesn't need the it does need the reposts, so we'll have to give it up.
The repo and the repo will be of type a point or two DB repo and we'll call this broadcast message and
we'll take three arguments.
We'll take the channel we want to go to.
We'll take the message, not the message.
Or will we call that.
We'll call it message type.
And then those are both strings and it's taking the data, which is a map of string.
OK, and we can just take this logic right here, cut it out of this, paste it into here and make the
data message we don't need this part at all because we're passing data as a parameter.
We're triggering it.
We're triggering it to a specific channel and we're triggering the message type.
And that's all that we have to do.
So this will simplify things a little bit.
So up here, when I want to broadcast this, all I need to do is to create a data variable, which is
a make map, string, string and put DataDot message or data.
The key is message and put some string in there.
So and then of course, once I populate that, which I'll do in a minute, I actually want to broadcast
that.
So I just say repo broadcast message and I'm broadcasting it to the public channel and I'll call the
event status host service status changed and I'll pass on my data.
OK, I just think that's clear now.
It doesn't save a lot of lines of text, but it does save some.
And I just think that's cleaner.
And we'll have to go through and clean up any other places where we're triggering a call to our W.S.
client to use this syntax instead.
But that won't be very difficult at all.
So I'm going to broadcast that.
And what do I want to broadcast?
What I want to broadcast here, broadcast here is a message saying that the status is changed and let's
put in the message so format, not def.
Host.
Service.
And then I'll put in a string on the host has changed to whatever the new statuses and just populate
that with escort service.
Service, name, address, each dot hostname and new status.
And that should take care of it for us.
So that should broadcast it to everyone on the public channel and this is what we're looking for.
So let's copy that.
And let's go to our Jagjit and Bond to that event on the public channel.
So here.
Public channel bind to this event and will call a function and pass it the data.
And all we need to do here right now to make this work is you say any alert, I'll just say success
alert.
And DataDot message.
And that should actually work, so let's stop this.
Start this.
Make sure that my application is not running.
It isn't OK.
And look at my database before I started to make sure that everything is going to work the way that
I want to.
So the content of this one service and I'll refresh is it currently has a status of problem.
So when I start my application and it starts monitoring, nothing should change until I start that Web
server.
So let's go back here, start our application on our vigilante's.
So that's running.
We'll be in a moment.
There it is, it's running and see if we have monitoring turned on a refresh the page.
We do.
OK, so this should every 10 seconds run.
And I think I'm still printing to the log file their.
So running Chuck.
Let's just stop in the it.
Turn it back on.
OK, so monitoring is on.
They're so, er, connected now, I may have to go back and check my startup code to make sure it's
actually starting the monitoring because I'm not sure that it is.
I may have removed something that's supposed to turn it on, but this is enough for right now.
So let's return a couple of times and start our Web server.
And watch this.
Their host service was changed to healthy, so it actually worked the way that I wanted it to.
Now, we've not updated this screen yet, but if I reload the page, it moves over.
So the next thing we're going to want to do is to write some code that actually updates this page.
So we'll take care of that in the next lecture.
And we'll also make sure that when we actually start our application, that monitoring is actually turned
on if it's turned on in the database, because it looks like we have an error there somewhere.
But we'll look at that in the next lecture.