OK, before we do anything else, let me draw your attention to a mistake that I made, I think, a
couple of years ago, I'm in the set up app file, Inside Command Web setup dash app DOGO.
And at this point, the very bottom of that set up app function actually start the monitoring.
And if you recall a couple of lectures ago, I said we don't need to start the schedule here.
Well, actually we do, but only in certain situations.
We want to check our preference map app preference map.
We want to look for monitoring Leive.
If that is equal to one, then I need to start monitoring.
I need to start the schedule because I actually I create all of the things here, but at no point do
I actually start it.
I would have to go and toggle it off and then on again in order to have scheduled monitoring taking
place.
So we'll just run that and it is apt scheduler start and that takes care of it.
So now if I clear this and start the application, if I look at the database first to see what the status
is.
So in the database preferences, it's set to true.
So it should start monitoring at this point 10 seconds after it compiles a return a couple of times,
it will actually start monitoring and printing that stuff out to the console.
And there it goes, so that works.
Now our next step, I shall leave this running for the moment.
Our next step is to update this page.
So I'm on this page right now.
I am monitoring and I have one problem service which is accurate and everything else is set to zero
because I only have one service on monitoring.
And what I want to do is.
Every time a service changes status, these counts need to be updated and I need to push that information
to our connected clients and if they're on this page, but only if they're on this page to update these
service counts.
OK, so let's get started doing that now.
Let's go back and look at our perform checks, which is right here.
So at this point when I'm running my schedule check, I get my house service, I get my host, I test
the service, and then I have a response coming back.
And the condition I'm using to check here right now is if new status is not equal to host to host service
status, as it was in the past.
In other words, if the existing status prior to this check running doesn't equal the new status that
I got back from this check running, then I'm pushing a message off and all I'm doing right now is displaying
a warning alert or something like that.
And we actually want to make it a little more useful.
The problem is, if this is my check, if I'm saying if the new status is equal to the host status and
I say, well, go get the service counts, I'm actually getting the service counts as they exist in
the database before I update the host service.
So that's not good.
We can't actually do our updating of the overview page right here.
So let's change this instead.
Let's just put a connection right here, OK?
We'll say host status, social service status changed is a sign the value of falls, and then we'll
just want to check if.
New status.
It's not equal to the old status.
Then Postal Service status changed is equal to true.
Now, this is a little wordy, but it will get the service done or get the job done for us.
So I have it set to false initially, assuming nothing is going to change and then I actually need to
set it to true if this check has changed the status of this whole service that we're checking.
So now I can take this variable and put it in here.
Instead, and that will still execute properly and then down here after I update this, I can say if
hose service status changed again, if it's true, then I can update my service counts.
How are we going to do that?
Well, let's go back here and look at this for a moment.
We're already displaying the counts here at some point.
And that suggests that when I render this page, I have some means of getting the correct service count.
And in fact, I do.
I can go back to my roots file and look at the bit that's displaying the dashboard right here, admin
dashboard.
And I already have the logic to grab all of this information right here.
So I'll copy this and I'll come back here and are back to my correct code, underperform checks.
And here I want to get those counts.
OK, and then I want to create a new data variable.
So I'll say data is assigned the value of and this is locally scope.
So it's only exists within the scope of this particular block of code.
Make map, string, string.
And I will now populate my data with all of these variables, so data and I'll call it healthy count.
As equal to healthy.
And of course, this is giving us an ENT and I need to make it a string, so I'll just convert it to
a string str confirm I to a and healthy and I'll duplicate that three more times and do one for spending.
One for a problem.
And one for warning.
And I'll just change these labels.
Warning count.
Problem count.
And pendent count, and now I'll do exactly the same thing I did up here, so we'll just copy this broadcast
bit and I'll paste it right in here.
So we're broadcasting, but this time I don't want to.
Broadcast host's service status changed.
Let's say hosts service count changed.
OK, so I'll create a new thing that I'm listening for.
Now, all it's going to pass is our data variable, which will consist of just these four bits of information.
So let's copy the event we're listening for.
Actually, it's going to screw it up so we can do this there.
Let me copy the event we're listening for.
Go back to my Jasjeet page and bind to a new event.
So just as we have here hosted service status change, let's just say public channel.
And I want to bind to this event now, it's a service county's changed and again, we're executing a
function and passing their data into that function.
And in here, I need to update those things that exist on this page over here.
So these numbers and that's the only thing I'm interested in.
So if we go look at the dashboard jet file, which is where these exist, this is down in mind around
the line.
Thirty five.
And here I'm listing the number of healthy the number of all of these things.
OK, so the first thing I'm going to do is when I initially put this together, I thought I'd be nice
to put the S on the end of this.
I don't want to deal with that logic right now.
That's too much.
So I'm just going to change on a simplified by putting it?
S in parentheses.
It just means I don't have to execute extra JavaScript to add or delete an S as necessary.
And that's just really a little value.
So I'll just fix all of these.
The second thing I want to do is I need some means of addressing this number, which might be zero,
might be one, but when I get on my my event that I'm listening for, I want to change this.
So I'm just going to wrap it in an in a span with an idea equals healthy count.
And that's exist nowhere else in my application.
So this is something I can test for and close that span.
So I'll copy this and put it on all of these and then change the IDs as necessary and close the tags
as necessary here.
And I will close those tags by copying this and pasting it here and here.
And here and then changing the IDs to the correct things so it's not healthy count, it will be a warning
count and this one will be problem count and this one will be pending count.
OK, so now I have a means of getting to this information and updating using JavaScript, so the first
time it's rendered, it'll be using the information passed to this template.
But if we're on this page and we receive that event, we want to update it.
So let me go back to the JavaScript and here's what we want to do it.
And the first thing to bear in mind is we only want the code that we're listening to here to actually
execute if we receive this event and we're on that page so we can just do a simple test, we can say
let healthy count exists, which is just a variable on creating equal to two exclamation marks, which
will turn the result into a boolean value and document doget element viddy.
And I'll look for a healthy count and if that exists, then execute the necessary code.
So I'll say if healthy count exists, then do this.
And if it doesn't, it means we're on a page where that particular ID healthy count doesn't exist.
Therefore this will never execute.
And it's pretty straightforward at this point.
We just change those four values with our information passed in our data variable.
So we say document.
Get element by ID, healthy count.
That inner HTML.
Is equal to DataDot, healthy count.
Which is what we passed from our perform checks right here, healthy count, so we do the same thing
for the next three.
So I'll duplicate this three more times and change this one to problem, problem, count, but spell
it right or won't work.
And changes to problem count.
And change this to say pending count.
And change this to pending account and change this one to what's the last one warning warning count
becomes.
Warning count, now, if I stop my application and check to see if my Web server is running, it's not
and look at our database just to see what it's currently set to and look at my house services.
OK, so we currently have a problem, and that's exactly what I want.
So I want to test this.
So let's go back and start vigilante.
So it's starting.
Go back and refresh this page so we know it's working because I just got that message saying it all
started.
We have one problem now.
I'm going to go back to my Web server.
Here and started.
And quickly go back here to watch this and hopefully this will update the zero change of this one changed
with zero and this change to a one perfect that worked.
Now let's go back and stop that Web server and wait 10 seconds or less.
And it changed problem and went back.
So everything works exactly as I want.
And of course, because I'm checking for the existence of that I.D. healthy count, that code that that
populates the correct values up here will only execute on this page.
So the only thing I have to bear in mind is that no point on any other page should I have the idea of
healthy count unless I have those other three warning count problem count pending count there as well.
Otherwise, I'll get a JavaScript error.
And you want to avoid that.
OK, so, so far so good.
Let's move on in the next lecture and start doing other things.