So we have our host service status count updating in real time on the overview page, and that's great.
And what we want to do next is to in the hosts, we don't just want to change the status count right
now.
I have one entry under the problems tab.
And when this status changes, when, for example, the Web server comes back up, I want this entry
in this table to disappear and I want it to be moved over here to healthy.
And I probably want some kind of little alert up here just to notify people that the state is this changed,
that the service came back up.
But before we do that, if we go back to our performed checks, don't go file this code under scheduled
check is starting to look pretty ugly.
We're doing a lot of things in here that we don't actually need to do in here.
So this is the method that is called when our scheduled schedule in the background fires off a request
to check a service.
So right now, every 10 seconds, once this is running, it checks the status of this for a particular
service ID.
And we just have one right now.
It goes and gets the host service.
We need to keep doing that.
Then it goes and gets the host by ID.
Then it tests the service and that's great.
We absolutely want to do that.
But all this code from about here right down to the end of this method doesn't belong here.
We probably should move that to its own method just to keep things a little bit cleaner.
So what I'm going to do is come down here just below this and create a new function.
And I will call this.
It's a function.
It has to have the repo of DB repo and I'll call this update host service status count and it will take
a few parameters.
We might need the host in the host service, so I'll put those in there for now.
H which is a type model start host host service which is of type models, dot post service and I'll
pass in two more things.
I'll pass in the new status and I'll pass in a message both of type string.
And this doesn't return anything.
And what I want to do in here effectively is pretty much everything from about.
This point on, so I'm going to cut that in here and then I'm going to paste it down here and we'll
fix these errors in a minute.
Let's go up here right now and see what we're going to do.
I'm getting a new status and a message, and I'm getting an error because I'm not doing anything with
message.
And I have this whole service service status changed, equal defaults, and I don't need that anymore.
So I'm going to get rid of it.
All I really want to check is does my new status match my old status?
And if it doesn't, then I don't want to set a variable.
Let's just call that method we just created.
So we'll call repo update host service status count and pass it the host and the host service and our
new status and our message.
Try that again.
New status and our message.
OK, so that fires that off.
Now let's get down to this method, we just created this part.
If the host or if we're broadcasting a message, I'm going to get rid of that.
I'm just going to comment today because we're not going to do that here.
And I'll leave it there as a reminder to go back and fix it later.
The next thing we want to do.
Is to update the host service record in the database with status, which will have changed.
And we'll just change the comment to.
And last check, because this is this method will only get cold if the host service status has changed
since the last check.
So we know this is going to fire, so we don't need to do that check at all.
And now we'll update the host service.
And then again, we don't need the if here so we can get rid of this because this will only get cold
if the status has changed.
And let's move this back over to here, OK, that looks a little bit cleaner.
So let's think about this for a minute, if this whole service status has changed and it has because
we're in here, we want to broadcast our clients now, do we want to do that in this method?
We actually don't.
Not at all.
So instead, where's the logical place to broadcast that the host service status has changed?
And this is the kind of event we're going to use to change, for example, this information back in
my Web browser from the problems tab to the healthy tab.
That's the event we want to broadcast.
And where's the logical place to do that?
Well, let's go up here when we call test service for host from scheduled check.
This is the method that actually tests the service and that gets us down here.
So at this point, if the status has changed, then we want to broadcast everything to the client.
So let's put it to do message in here to do broadcast to clients if appropriate.
OK, so I think that's the logical place to send this off, because this is the point when we're doing
the test service for host, we already know the old host service status because that's passed in right
here.
And we can simply do a check at this point.
We do the we get our new status set right here.
At this point, we can test new status against the existing status and broadcast the message to the
clients.
I think that makes sense.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.