So now we want this code and perform checks that go to actually delete this content, this table from
the problems table, populate it over here and display a message any time we receive the appropriate
event from Pusha or a Pusha compatible server.
So first thing I can do is get rid of this comment docos.
I they don't need it anymore, so I'll delete that.
And it looks like we're not actually using the models host, but I'm going to leave that there because
I might need it later and it's not hurting anything at the moment, subject to ignore the fact that
that parameter is not being used.
Now, we want to get down to the part where we actually test the service.
So let's find that this test service for hosts, this is the part we're going to work on right now.
And in here, we only have one case we're watching for.
We're testing for HTP.
And when we add extra services, there'll be other cases here.
And here's what we want to broadcast to clients, if appropriate.
So how are we going to do that?
Well, we already have the host service and this is prior to the host service being updated in the database.
So the status in there is the status as it existed prior to the check.
And here we're declaring a new variable called new status.
That will be the status after the check.
So by the time we get down here to this Tudou statement, all we have to do is do a simple check.
If got status, which is the old status is not equal to new status, then we want to broadcast to all
clients.
Now, what kind of information do we want to broadcast?
So we'll broadcast to clients if appropriate.
What kind of information do we want to broadcast?
Well, we know it's going to have a data payload and we know that's going to be a type of type of map,
string, string.
So let's create that variable and let's start populating it with all the information that we want.
And I'm going to put as much as I think I might need and then some just to be safe.
So I'll put in, first of all, the host ID because I have that information.
And I got to close the parentheses here.
So the host I.D., it has to be in a string format, so I need to convert it to a string I to a store,
convert it to a and that's just HS homestudy.
So I need that.
And I may also I know I'm definitely going to need the service ID, so I'll call it host service ID
and that's just HFS ID.
And then I probably want the hostname data hostname, and that's just a string, so I can just pull
that right from the host record hostname.
Equals.
And I probably want the service name, so data service name.
And that's equal to host service, service, service name.
And I probably want the icon, data icon.
And that will be able to service the icon, not just the strings and on conversion necessary, the new
status data status.
Equals our new status.
Is there anything else, probably the message and broadcasting that message is pretty straightforward,
but in this case, I'm going to make it shorter than the last time we did it.
So I'll just say data message is equal to and I'll use formatter as printf so I can build my string
percent s on percent s reports.
S and a populate that with the service name, which is a service dot, sir, his name, the hostname
h dot hostname and the new status.
OK, so there's my my message, and the last thing I'm going to put in there is the last check.
And that's just the current time and date when I can just build that by using Time Now format and give
it the same format string we used before using those interesting date formatting syntax.
And I will build it in the correct format, so there's our data.
Now I want to broadcast this repo broadcast message, which we built a little while ago, and we're
going to put it to the public channel.
And the event we want is hosting service status changed because that's where that's what we're listening
for on our JavaScript, which will get to in a moment and we pass it the data.
OK, so that will broadcast the message for us.
Now, after that, let's put another to do in here to do this is the point, I think, where we want
to send email or SMS if appropriate, and we'll get to that later on.
OK, so we've built that now we need to actually go over to our JavaScript, which is in just DOGIT,
and find the part that we need to modify.
And what we're looking for here is host service status changed.
Now, I got an error here somewhere.
Let me find that.
So it says that it put him in front of this make map string strength.
That's better.
OK, let's go back to our Java JavaScript and look at the method we want to change.
What we're pushing from perform checks is hosting service status changed.
And in our on the public channel and in our JavaScript, we're binding to the public channel and looking
for hosted service data changed.
And this is what we want.
So let's get rid of this successfully because it obscures the very top of the screen.
I don't want to put something that's a little less intrusive in there, so I'll put in a tension toast
and I'll just pass in some parameters as we did before.
Message is DataDot message.
The icon, I'll just make it info, because it'll apply for all the situations that were at the timer
are set to say 30 seconds.
So thirty thousand milliseconds timer, not time.
And the last thing I want to put in there is the show Close Button, and I'll set that to true and let
people close it if they don't want to wait the 30 seconds for it to disappear.
So let's make sure this all works before we go any further.
So I'm going to open my terminal, stop my application.
Start my application.
Make sure that pusher is running, and it is so that's fine, so my IP is running, then I'll go back
to my terminal window or my browser window, look at the problems page and refresh it and make sure
that the problem is still there.
It is.
Now, I'll go start my Web server and make sure I schlemiel for the JavaScript console first so the
console is empty.
Perfect.
Now I'll go back to my other Idy window and start this little test web server, the one that we're monitoring.
So now go back to my browser and watch this.
And I should see a little alert, a pop up here, a little tost alert once I turn on monitoring, of
course, that monitoring started.
And there it is, HTP on localhost reports healthy and I should be able to close this and I can so we
now we know we can actually remove this row and move it over here because everything's talking to each
other the way that it should be.
So let me go back to my code and get to the correct I.D. window and minimize this.
And let's look at think about how we're going to make this take place, because all the logic we want
is going to go right in here.
We might move it to another function later on.
But just to get it working, let's put it in here for right now.
So let's write some comments.
So update tables.
The first thing I want to do is to remove existing table row if it exists.
And that's important because we don't want to try to remove a table from a row that doesn't exist anywhere
on the current browser window.
So we have to check to make sure that it exists and then remove it.
OK, so that's the first thing we want to do.
The second thing we want to do is to.
Update the tables.
If they exist, which means we have to have some means of getting some means of getting a hold of the
appropriate table, so let's think about those two things.
First of all.
First of all, how are we going to remove the existing table if it exists?
Because we have no means right now of actually getting that information.
So let's open our host jet file.
And let's find every place we were writing a table row that has a status.
So that starts, let's see, not here, because this is the services tab, it's this one, this is the
very first one.
And what I want to find is this table row.
So if, say, we have a service we're monitoring and it changes from healthy to problem, then we want
that ROE to disappear, which means we have to have a means of getting a hold of it.
So let's just give it an ID ID equals and we'll just call it host Dasch Service Dash and then put in
the ID, which is the host service ID, because there's only one entry possible for any given service
there.
You're never going to have a service showing up in two rows in any of these four tables.
At the same time, either it's in one state or it's in another state.
So that's a means of getting a hold of it.
So we've got that.
Let's copy this content right here and add it to the other tables.
So I've copied that.
I'm unhealthy.
I'll go down to the next one, which is warning.
I'll find the table row.
And paste that in there.
OK, and then I'll go down to the next one, which is right here.
And I'll pasted in again, my ID is showing an error because I have two elements with the same ID,
but we actually generate the Jimal, that's no longer the case.
So I'm not worried about that at all.
And the last one is pending.
OK, so now we have a means of getting a hold of those actual rows.
Let's make sure that part works before we do anything else.
OK, so I'll go back to my JavaScript and I will remove the existing table row if it exists.
So I will get the table row by building a string and then I'll check to see if it exists.
So I'll say let exists and that's just a variable I'm creating equal to the double bang.
So I'm going to get another return value that's going to be either true or false and trying to get that
that element by ID.
So document get element by ID and I'm looking for host Dasch service Dasch plus data dot post service
ID.
And where does this value come from?
Well we're in the host service status changed binding to the public channel and we're getting the data
right here in this variable called data and that's passed right here when I call this data and the host
host service ID and that has to exactly match what I'm checking for is equal to the host service.
So let's go back to our JavaScript.
Now I know whether it exists or not, and I can just simply check to see if it does in an if statement
if it exists.
That means somewhere on the currently open browser window, there is a document that has the element
ID or has the ID of host Dasch Service Dash, whatever the host service ideas.
And all I have to do is to actually get rid of that row.
So I'll say console Dooralong trying to remove row just so we have something to look at in our JavaScript
console and I'll get rid of it.
Let ro equal document doget element by ID and again I'm looking for host Dasch Service Dashi and then
the ID passed in there.
OK, like that.
But it's not this way of course.
Let me get this formatted properly Dash.
Plus, data dot postal service services, so that gets me the row and I have a reference to it, I just
get rid of it.
And here's how you delete table rows in JavaScript, rogue parent node.
Remove child and pass back in the row right there, so we get our row variable here and that points
to the correct here and then we tell JavaScript, go to the element you just found, find its parent
and remove the child that matches this syntax, which is the role we just found.
So that should get rid of it.
So let me put another JavaScript console or console log in their console dialog, trying to remove row
and I will start my application just to make sure it's current started back up.
And go back to my my Web browser, we're watching the JavaScript console.
Let me reload this.
Look at the problems tab.
There are no problems.
Look at the healthy tab.
So we have an entry and healthy and I will go kill the Web server.
So this should update in real time.
And all it will do at this point is delete that road from problems.
We have to add it back into healthy or whatever it is, depending on what the status change.
So let me go back to my ID and stop this Web server and quickly go back to my.
And it worked.
Trying to remove road, trying to remove it worked.
OK, now that fired twice.
I'm not sure why, but I'll figure that out in a little while.
At the moment, I know this is working.
OK, so back to my JavaScript and get to the correct browser window and hide this.
And it printed twice because I told it to.
OK, so I can get rid of these.
Now I know this works.
So once we've actually removed that row, if it exists now, we need to update the tables if they exist
and again, we're going to need some means of identifying the actual tables and we do that again back
on host.
So let's find hosken.
And let's find the first table.
Which is way up here after the services, here's our first table.
So at this point, I have a table and I have no means of getting access to that table.
So it means I need to give it an ID and I'll just call it this one will be the healthy table.
And I'm choosing this name because the data I'm passing back from perform checks has an entry called
status and that's going to be healthy.
Warning problem are pending.
So I can use this status, this this value status is in our payload to actually find the right table.
So we have a healthy table.
Now let's go down to find the next one.
This will be the warning table.
ID equals warning table and go to the next one.
This one will be the problem, table ID equals the problem table, and I'm using a hyphen, I've got
to remember that.
And finally pending.
ID equals pending table.
OK, so now I have a means of getting access to those tables.
So here back in our JavaScript, let's make sure that the table actually exists.
So I'll do the same thing I did up here.
I'll say let table exists.
He exists, bang bang document, get element ID.
And this time I'm looking for data status, which will be one of healthy problem pending or warning
plus Dasch table.
And that exactly matches the idea of the table that I might have to adoro to.
So, again, I'll just check to see if it exists, if this time its table exists, if that exists,
then I have to adoro to a table.
So how do you add a road to a table in JavaScript?
First of all, let's say console dialogue, trying to add row two plus data dot status.
Plus table, just so I have something that I can look at to make sure I'm trying to update the correct
table, well, actually adding a table row is not that difficult, but it does take a little bit of
work.
First of all, you've got to get a reference to the table you want to update and I'll call that table
ref, so I'll say.
Let table read the reference to the table equal to document doget element by ID, and it's the same
thing I have right here.
Data status plus Dasch table.
So now I have a reference to it.
Now we need to create a new Rolet new row.
That's just a variable name I'm choosing equal to table Riffe, which I just got, and then get the
body of that table teh bodies.
And I want the first entry.
And I want to insert a row and I need to put minus one there so it gets in the right place, if you
just go with zero, it's not going to go where you want because we actually have a row at the top of
the table, minus one gets it in the right spot.
OK, so there's our new row and now we need to set some attributes for it.
And if we go back to our jet file host jet and look at the rows, we're adding like this one, for example,
the row we're adding has to have an I.D. that will allow us to find it again, because after we add
this row to the table, the status might change again.
The user might still be looking at this table without refreshing their browser or going somewhere else.
So we need to be able to build it exactly as it has to be.
So back in our JavaScript, let's create a row with the correct attribute.
So I'll say my new row, which I just created in the previous line, and I'll set an attribute on it.
And the attribute I want to set is ID and I want to give it this name host service Dasch plus data hosting
service.
Spelt right Postal Service ID, OK, so that will give us a row with the correct attribute and that's
the correct ID attribute and we need that.
So now we need to insert the first TD.
And how many trees do we have?
I think we only have three.
So we're going to be doing this one at a time, inserting the values for all three of these tables cells
in that table row.
So we'll create a new cell, let new cell equal to.
New robe, which is the robe we just created, dot insert itself, and we want this to be in the first
position, which is actually zero, not one.
So we create the cell and now we just said it's TML, so we'll say new cell.
Not inner turmoil is equal to and I'm going to use the tactics because I'm going to take advantage of
the JavaScript templating that's available to us, it just makes it much easier to edit and much easier
to read.
And what we need here, if we go back to host jet is exactly the kinds of things we're finding from
here to here.
We need to populate it with exactly the same syntax and we get the values for the various attributes
and so forth from the data that's passed to us by PUSHER, our data which is passed right here.
So let's do that.
So the first thing we need is a spin and the class is going to be equal to and here's where I'm going
to take advantage of the JavaScript templating function dollar sign and then in curly braces.
But I want and that's the icon which we have in data icon.
So that's it's class and then I just close that span because we're taking advantage of the font, awesome
icons, and after that I want the service name, which again I'm getting from my day to day service
underscore name pass to us by our pusher server.
And after that, I have another spam.
And you can see that right here in hosts.
Yet we have this part.
So we need to make that go in there.
So I'm going to copy this and then I'll just paste it in there and I'll format it properly.
And I'll just make sure that this all gets populated with the correct information.
I can't put it in this way because this is being rendered by JavaScript did not go.
So get rid of that and put in data host service and our status is not pending hardcoded.
Otherwise, we'll have that on every single table.
We'll just put in data status.
Like that.
OK, so that's our first TD.
Now we need to insert our second TD and I can get rid of this blank line.
And maybe move this up here as well, just to save some space, so let's do our second tee'd insert,
second TD.
Now what goes in the second TD?
Let's go over and have a look and host our check.
Our second TD is the date of time of the last check when we passed that already.
So we can just grab that right out of here very easily.
So we need to create another cell this time.
I don't say let because I'm going to use the same variable.
New cell equals new row.
Don't insert cell and now in my position, too, which is one, because we start counting at zero and
I'll just check the status if data status.
Is not equal exactly to spending then printed out new, so the ordinary HTML equals.
And then I'll just use the same syntax like this.
DataDot pending.
Otherwise, it's in the pending states and we don't have a date in time to print, so we'll say ELT's
new cell, the interim HTML is equal simply to pending, which is what we have by default, and the
third row is actually empty.
So for right now, it is anyway.
So we'll create another third row or not row TD, insert third TD.
So we'll just again use that same variable.
New cell is equal to new row dot, insert a cell and this time the position is two and we'll just leave
that empty room populated at all.
So that actually unless I have a typographical error, should work.
So I'll save this.
I probably don't have to stop and start my application just so I know everything is clean.
I'll go back to my Web browser, reload this page and look at the tabs.
So I have nothing under healthy, nothing under warning.
I do have one problem.
OK, so let's go back and restart our web server and then quickly switch back to our browser so it goes
and off.
I go to my browser and I want to see this row disappear and then it should reappear under the healthy
tab and I should get a little alert as well.
So it disappeared.
We got the alert, let's look under the healthy tap and there it is.
Last check is actually undefined, so I must have a typo there somewhere.
Let's go back and look at this.
So I'll minimize this and get to the part where we're putting the last check in data dump pending.
Why don't I put pending their last check?
So I'll save this.
Reload this, look at the healthy.
OK, so the last check is correct there.
Now I want it to show up in the problems tab, so I'll reactivate this or activate this just so I can
stop the Web server and quickly come back.
So let's go back here, find our Web server window, open the terminal and stop it and quickly go back
here and wait up to 10 seconds.
And there it is.
Everything appeared exactly as it should.
I was still not doing anything with the message.
I could actually populate that.
But that's not critical for our exercise.
Right now.
We're working with JavaScript, so I'll leave that as an exercise for you if you want to populate with
that, that you just need to make sure there's a necessary place in the database to store it and store
it after every check or after the status changes on a check.
OK, so that seems to work and we're getting much closer to where we need to be.
So we'll move on in the next lecture and try to see what else we can do with this, because we still
have some things to change.
For example, if I look at the hosts page or not, the host page, the overview page, we're not updating
this table in real time and we should be able to do that.
And it's not that difficult.
And the same with all the other three services.
So actually, that'd be a great exercise for you.
You should have enough information at your disposal right now to be able to remove an entry from this
table if there's a healthy service and it's status changes while you're looking at this page.
So you should be able to remove that and you shouldn't have to write very much JavaScript at all.
So it should be really, really straightforward for you to make the changes to this table and the other
three that are behind these three links.
So why don't you give that a shot?
You have everything at your disposal right now to make that take place.
And on the next lecture, I'll show you how I did it.