So I thought I'd go over the goals for this exercise in a little more detail before you get started.
So I'm on the overview page of our site and I'm talking about the pages behind these four boxes.
So, for example, I have the healthy services and right now I have one healthy service and I want to
write code or I want you to write code such that when we receive the appropriate event, if this hosted
service HDP has changed from healthy to some other state, then it gets removed from this table and
gets added automatically to another table.
So if I happen to be looking at, for example, this table, I have no warning services right now.
Well, we don't have any warning services.
Let's go to the problem services instead.
I have no problem services right now.
Now, let's assume I'm looking at this page and the service goes down.
Well, this page should get updated in real time.
So you're going to have to, first of all, push the property event and have a listener for that event
in your JavaScript binding to the public channel.
And if this service changes to a problem state, in my case, then you look at this table, which means
you have to have some means of addressing this table.
You check to see if it has the no service row, if that's the only thing in there, you need to remove
that and then you add the appropriate role for the new problem service.
So that's the goal for this particular exercise.
So you shouldn't have any trouble with it.
And if you do, don't worry.
In the next lecture, I'll show you what I've done and post the code with the appropriate solution to
the resources for that page.
So good luck.
Give it a try.
It's important that you actually try to do things on your own and don't just watch somebody else.
And I'm sure you won't have any problems at all.