So I hope you made it all right with the exercise, it shouldn't have been terribly challenging for
you, but I'm going to go through my solution, and your solution may not be identical to my solution.
And that's OK.
I have posted the code to my solution to this lecture under the course resources, as I always do.
So I go through what I did and I'm not going to make you watch me build it because this is relatively
straightforward.
So the very first thing I did is and I'm going to use the healthy services page as an example.
I removed a column, I removed the status column because that's not useful information.
You're only going to see status healthy for all of these.
And that just made things a little cleaner for me.
And if you left it in, that's fine.
So on the HTML for this page and I'll go back to my ID, this is the healthy page.
The first thing I did was to give the table and ID healthy table and I named all of my IDs for all four
of those tables using the actual status that's being pushed by my triggered event in the code.
So if it's the healthy table I'm dealing with, I'm using healthy Dasch table or pending Dasch table
problem Dasch table.
Just the first part of the ID exactly.
Matches the status of the service in question.
So the second thing I did.
Was for every row in this table, I gave it the idea of host Dasch service Dasch and the idea of the
host service.
So I have a means of addressing the specific service for a given table.
So I made that change.
And of course, I changed this three to this, four to three because I deleted a column.
So those are the only changes I made on each of the four tables for healthy pending problem and warning.
And then in my JavaScript, it's a little bit different.
And you may not have followed exactly the same logic that I did, but you probably got to the same place.
So the first thing I did was public channel.
I actually removed much of the logic from this binding to the public channel event and instead I created
two generic functions that I can use anywhere I need to.
So delete a whole service row and update a host service row.
So all I'm going to do is, rather than putting all of the logic right in this particular anonymous
function inside the bind to the host service status changed.
I simply call two functions.
So the first thing I call is delete, delete, host service row, which is this function right here.
And the first thing I check, of course, is does the element that I'm looking for, this particular
row exist?
And I use that double bang syntax that I've been using right along.
If it does exist, then get that row, get a reference to that row using host service ID, which is
the only parameter pass to this function.
And I delete that row and then I check to see if it was the last row that I need to add in a no services
row or no.
Yeah, no services row in that table.
So we don't know what table, we don't know what table might exist, so we have to check them all.
So rather than writing for functions, one for the healthy table, one for the pending morning and problem
and so forth, I just wrote a simple array and the contents of that array are the four possible statuses
that I'm going to look for so that I loop through that array each time and I check to see if that table
exists.
So I'm looking first of all, does the healthy table exist?
So I create a variable called let current table exists equal and this will be true or false.
Look to see if there's an element on the page that has the ID of, in the first case, healthy Dasch
table.
And if you find it, then let's get a reference to that table.
And if the number of rows in that table is exactly one, then we just have the heading room.
So I just put in a no service row and that updates the table in real time.
So that's the first call to delete post service row.
The second one is add a new one at a new row to the table if that exists and that calls this function
right down here, which follows logic almost identical to what we've been doing right along.
First of all, check to see if the data status and it would be in the case of going from healthy to
problem, it would look for problem Dasch table.
And if it finds it, get a reference to the table check to see if the HTML of that table contains the
text.
No services exactly like that.
And if it does, we have a no services row.
So we delete that and then we just insert the correct row or insert the new row and give it the proper
ID and our ID host service.
The host service ID exactly matches what I'm using right here in the Healthy Jett example.
And all I do is insert the necessary TDRS for that row and that's all that I did.
So hopefully you didn't have any problem with with this, but if you did, don't worry.
You can download the source code from the resources on this lecture and compare what I did with what
you did.