In this section of the course, we're going to begin connecting celebrities to a database, and we're
going to support two databases in this course Postgres and MariaDB, which is a drop in replacement
for MySchool, and we're going to start with Postgres.
So we're going to need a driver, obviously, to connect to Postgres.
And in the go world, we go to my web browser.
There are two this one Jack C slash PDX.
And this is a native postscript driver that actually supports Postgres only connections.
And it also supports the database SQL interface.
And that's the one we're going to use because I want to make my code as portable as possible.
The other one is over here Lib P Q, and for a very long time, this was the go to driver anytime you
wanted to connect a go program to a Postgres database.
But if you actually go down here.
And read the status, it says this package is currently in maintenance mode, which means blah blah
blah blah, and then we recommend using PDX.
So finally, that debate over which driver to use appears to be settled.
So we'll be using this one.
Jack CPG And there's a link to this in the course resources for this lecture, so you can go read the
documentation at your convenience.
But let's get started.
Back to our I.D. and I'm going to switch to the celebrity's package.
That's the project I'm going to work on.
And the first thing I'll do is create a file at the root level of this project called Driver Doggo.
And here's where we'll open our connection to the database.
So obviously it needs a package declaration package.
Main climate again, package celebrities.
I at least I'm consistent in this mistake.
Celebrities?
That's better.
OK.
Integrate function and it will have the receiver of Pointer to select us.
And I'll call this open DB because that's what we're going to do is open a connection to the database
and it will take two parameters DB type, and that's going to be Postgres to start with and DSM, the
data source the string to connect to the database.
So both of these are strings and it's going to return, potentially hopefully going to return a pointer
to SQL DB and also let we do the import their cycle.
Dart PD lets you do the import.
For me, it did, and also potentially an error.
So this is pretty straightforward.
And remember, we're going to be reading the database type from the dot com file, and we're telling
people to specify either Michael or MariaDB or Postgres.
And of course, people will think of the Postgres database as being Postgres, but we actually need
the connection string or the DB type of P.G. X.
So we'll just do a simple if statement.
If GB Typekit is equal to Postgres or DV type is equal to PostgreSQL because you can never trust people
to type what they need to type DB Typekit the change to TJX, because that's what we need to connect
to Postgres now in order to open a connection.
One of the very first things we're going to have to do is install some packages to support PKG X, so
fortunately, it's pretty easy.
So I'm going to open my terminal window and this is right in the documentation for this package for
Jack C slash PDX.
We want to go get GitHub dot com slash Jack C slash pg con.
So let's go get.
And of course, I left the CIA, so let's try that again.
Jack CPG can't.
That's better, and we'll clear the screen as the first one we need.
We also want to go get GitHub dot com slash Jack C slash.
And we want PG X slash v four and a v five is out.
Please use V for for this course and you can upgrade to V five after the fact or V six or whatever it
is.
Let's go get that.
OK.
And then I'm going to hit the up arrow and put slash Steve B because we're going is the standard libraries
sequel driver and we need this package.
There are now those are all there.
So let's go up to our top of our file and I'll close the terminal window.
I need to import those.
I need to import them, even if I don't use them explicitly.
So I'll wrap this whole thing in parentheses.
And I'll add the following lines GitHub with an underscore to start with the blank identifier, which
says, Yeah, I'm not going to use this explicitly in this package or in this file, but import it anyway.
GitHub dot com slash Jack C slash.
PG Kong.
OK.
And then I'll duplicate that and get rid of the PG con part and make it PG X slash before they're going,
I'll duplicate that again and I'll add to the end of that slash STD, Libby.
OK, so now those are all available to me and I need them right here.
So what I'm going to do is use the standard Go Sequel Driver and get a database connection, DV comma
error or assign the value of and we're going to call sequel the sequel package open.
And we're going to open DB type, which in our case will be PG for now.
And whatever the connection string is, DSN OK, and we'll check for an error if error is not equal
to nil.
We'll return nil.
And the error says otherwise.
Let's try pinging this to make sure it actually connects to the database.
So air is now equal to DB Dot Ping.
And again, we'll check for errors when we copy this and I'll paste it in there.
And if all that worked and it will, eventually we'll return our pool of connections.
Give them nil.
OK, so the next step, and it's not a difficult one, is to actually go back to the main dgo or the
celebrity star go file and build a connection string based upon the values that are specified in the
dot on file.
And of course, the dot on file is in our My App project, and we'll get started on that in the next
election.