So at this point, we have a bunch of methods available to us here in the user model and I mean my app
project and I'm looking at user account.
So we have all of these functions right here.
Let's try them out.
We know that some of them work, but there are almost certainly problems in this and we'll catch those
when we start work on the testing of this particular file, which we'll be doing before, too.
So before we go too much further, let's just try out a login page.
So I'm going to go to the roots, file rootstock, go in my app and I'm going to add a root right here.
And I'll put it like this ADA app dot roots, dot get and I'll call it slash users slash log in and
it will go to a handler that doesn't exist yet.
A dog handlers.
I'll go Page Dot as we call it, user log in.
And of course, we're going to have to have a post root for that as well because we want to create a
form on that page, which doesn't exist yet.
So make this one post, which I better spell right?
And I'll call the handler.
Post user logging.
So let's go to our handlers file.
And inside of that, I'll create a new file and I'll call it off.
Dash handlers duco and I'm putting them in a separate file because ultimately, when we create a command
line application and allow users to type something like celebrities make off, it should create all
the necessary database tables and it should copy files into our project just to make things easier for
the user.
So as handlers go off, dash handlers don't go, and that's in package handlers.
And what we'll do here is create a function with the receiver of a point or two handlers.
And this one needs to be called user login.
And this will display the page that's that people use to log in.
So Whv, the response writer and our pointer to football request
and this is dead simple error will be equal to each dot app dot render and will render using W R and
we'll create a file called Log Inkjet in a minute with no data for now, and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then.
And it's render the page that's better.
And we'll just say for now, scrap the analogue print line there.
OK, so that's our user login page.
Now let's go back over to our views and create a new file called Log Inkjet, a low GI and jnt.
So this is really a simple view that extends our base layer.
So it extends dot layout dot slash layouts slash you meant that I call that file I.
It was based on, yeah, based object based Typekit, and it has to have a browser title.
So block browser title.
And we'll call this log in to the end
and we'll put in our CSV.
But leave it empty block CC with just an end.
And our page content, block page content and an intake.
And in the middle, of course, we want our login page.
So H-2 class equals and we'll put some merging at the top using bootstraps to class and center text
center, and we'll call this log in and closer each.
To that, we'll put an H.R. horizontal rule and form method equals post action equals slash users slash
log in.
We just added the goes to a non-existent handler and I'll give it a name which I don't need, but I'm
going to do it anyway.
Logging form and an ID, which I do need log in dash form and we'll give it a class.
We'll make it using bootstraps equals d dash block and we'll add needs validation because we'll use
bootstraps client side validation and we'll set autocomplete equals off, which you should always do
and log in strings and know validate.
Don't use the browser validation and we'll close our form tag.
And in the middle, we'll put our inputs.
So to start with, I'm going to put this one in.
Input type equals hidden,
which should be in quotes.
Name equals c us rf token.
You know, we don't have that yet.
We're going to have a for too long.
And value equals and I'll just leave it empty for now.
Actually, I can probably put this in here.
Dot c SRF token that might throw an error.
And if it does, I'll delete it later on.
I can't remember if I added that already.
Now we'll have a div class equals maybe three four merging bottom three.
I'll close that in and then we have a label.
We'll log in using username and password in the username will be your email address.
Label equals label four equals email class equals form, dash label, email and close the label tag
and then the input input type equals
email class equals form control form dash control ID equals email and name equals email and we'll make
it required, required equals nothing and we'll set autocomplete equal to email.
Dash knew as long as it's unique, it won't pre populate that form with suggestions, which is exactly
what I want.
So this is my first one.
Now we want a password, so I'll copy all of this and paste it there and make this password and copy
that and put it here.
Typekit calls password I.D. equals password, equals password and make this password new and I'll change
the label to password.
OK, then I'll put him in and put in a button will say a f equals and I'll make this a and a link.
I'm not going to make it a button because I don't want us to try to submit.
And I can just take advantage of bootstrap bootstraps classes that make it look like a button.
So the rest will be JavaScript colon void with a zero in there, so it doesn't do anything,
and I'll put a class equals, say button to make it look like a button and VTM Dash Primary to give
it some color and we'll give it an N. click handler.
I could use a listener button on Click Work just as well on Click Equals, and we'll call a JavaScript
function that doesn't exist yet.
Vow to validate and we'll put log in and slashing.
And then I'll put something in there.
We're not going to use for a little while, but we'll get started on it.
We can put the link here anyway.
I'll put a paragraph tag in.
I'll give it a class equal to Mty Dash to give it some margin on the top.
And I'll close the P tag and I'll make this small so small.
And then a trip equals and I'll go to users slash users plural slash forgot password.
We want people to be able to reset their password and we won't get to this for a while, but we will
get to it.
Forgot password slash a slash.
Small.
OK.
So there's that part.
That's our form.
And after the form closes, I'll just put another way to get back to the homepage.
So Div class equals text dash center slash div, and in here I'll put a class equals Eaton button outline
secondary and the H Ref will be equal to slash.
And I'll say back and three dots.
OK, so that goes is a means of navigating back to the main homepage, and we'll have to put a link
on the home page, but we'll do that in a minute.
And after this, just to give us a little bit of space, I'll just put an empty p in here with a non
breaking space.
Otherwise, it might just look a little crowded.
So there's a content section.
Now let's put some simple JavaScript in, so that goes on our block.
Just like that and we end that.
And in the middle, put a script in here and close the script.
And the script consists of one function function, which I called Val, which takes no parameters,
and we just take advantage of Java Scripts, standard formatting or client side validation.
So we get a reference to our form form equal document get element by ID..
And I'm looking for log in dashboard, and it gives me a reference to my form.
And we just do a simple if statement here.
Let's get some rum up here, if formed.
Check validity.
Equals exactly false, and there's something wrong, we don't want to submit this form and what we put
in there is exactly what Bootstrap tells us to this start event.
Dot prevent default
and this dark event that start propagation, propagation
and form class list.
The ad was dash validated
and return.
There's an error, so don't go any further.
Otherwise, we could pass that if statement, we say formed on class list.
The ad was dash melodies
and formed so that OK, now let's go.
Make sure we have in our base don't get the necessary JavaScript to bootstrap expects to find.
I can't remember if I added that or not.
So we have the CC.
We have a CSR of tokens, so apparently I did actually add that which is good and we did not include
the necessary JavaScript.
So let's go to our web browser and open a new tab and go to get bootstrap.
You can get the link to the JavaScript.
So get started and I want the JavaScript bundle right here.
So I'll copy that and I will go back to my I.D. and add that right here before yield jazz.
So it's available to us.
OK, so if I save that now, I should be able to.
If I go back to here, comment this route because it doesn't exist yet in my roots, file and open my
terminal and say, Make start.
And it should compile.
And it did.
And I should be able to go back to my web browser and reload this and put slash users slash logging,
slash users slash logging.
And there's my log in for it, and I should be able to try to submit this and get the errors here,
indicating that there's required fields.
And I do.
Perfect.
So that handler exists and this screen exists.
So in the next lecture will uncomment this line back in our roots.
File right here and create that handler and try logging in.