So we have our login page displaying more or less correctly, and now we want to actually try to log
a user in.
But before we do that, you might have noticed that I had a typo here in Log Inkjet in a couple of places.
It's auto complete.
Let's put the letter O in there and copy that and paste it down here and down here.
That's better.
Now let's go back to our roots file, which is.
Right here and uncomment this route.
So we have a post user log in handler that we have to define now, so let's go over to our auth handlers
and to that.
So func h pointer to handlers and I need to call this post user login and it needs to take the response
writer because it's a handler and a pointer to a request.
Now, at this point, we need to figure out, do we have enough information to actually log a user in?
In other words, the functions in user account.
So in order to do that, we're going to need to grab the information from the post request.
So let's do that.
First error is assign the value of from the request we call personal right, and we check for an error
if error is not equal to no.
We're not building a full web application, so I'll just write to the screen w dot, right?
And I'll write as a slice of bites.
Aired on air.
OK, and we'll return.
Don't go any further.
And of course, in a real web application, you would do something more here, but we're just making
sure functionality works.
We're not actually building a web application.
We're building an application that makes building web applications much easier.
Now we'll grab our email from the request form.
Not yet.
We're looking for email and we'll get the password password is assigned.
The value of ERDA form don't get password, so we have our email on our password.
How do we get a user in order to compare the password that was entered with the password that is in
the database?
Well, let's go back to our handler's file right here.
OK.
And let's look at the very top what we have in here.
We have ACT-Accelerator start celebrities.
Let's just add the type models because by the time we create our handlers, we actually have our models.
And that's a type data models.
OK, so now if we go back to our its celebrity know file and find the part where we create our handlers.
We can't add the models here because we don't have them yet, but we have them down here at all models.
So after this, we can just say.
My handlers don't models equals Abdul models.
And at that point, we now have access back in our handlers.
We have access to the necessary functions so we can now say user.
And potentially there are assigned the value of H2 models.
Don't users don't get by email.
And then what's available to us and we'll pass in and we check for an error if error is not equal to
no.
And I'll do exactly the same thing I did up here, just right the error, which is sufficient for our
purposes now that we have the user.
We just need to see if the password they've supplied actually matches the hash that we have in the database.
So also create a variable called matches and potentially in error are equal to.
And it's as simple as calling user dot password matches.
And handing that password.
And again, we'll check for an error.
I'll just say if error is not equal to no.
This time, I'll put a little more meaningful message in there w dot right as a slice of bite.
You're validating password and matches is actually a Boolean.
OK, so same thing here, if not matches, then.
And if we want to return after that here, of course return.
I'll just copy this
and I'll change this to invalid password.
Now, if we get past this, then we have a valid user and that valid user's password matches the password
that was typed in to the form.
So at this point, we can actually log the user in by simply saying each dot app dot session Dot put.
I'll want to put it in there, is there user ID.
So our context, which is the first parameter and the key will be user ID and the value is user I.D..
OK.
And I'll say it should be done.
Redirect and I'll take the user back to the home page w.
Our route is slash and HD Typekit status see other, which is fine and that should be sufficient.
So let's try this out.
Let's see if we get everything right.
Let's open our terminal window and take make restart.
So it built that's a good sign.
Now let's go look at our database and see what we have in there, because at this point, I can't actually
remember what we have.
So let's connect to celebrities darker all connect and we'll look under users.
And what I have in there is Trevor with a last name that I changed me out here dot com.
And I believe that this hash is actually for password.
So let's go back to our web browser.
Let's reload this page, and first of all, I'll put in you at their dot com with some password.
It doesn't matter because this user doesn't exist.
And I'll try logging in and it says no more rows in this result set, so couldn't find that user perfect.
Now let's go in here and type in me at here dot com, which does exist in the database.
But let's give it the wrong password one two three four five six Log in.
And it says invalid password.
Let's go back and let's put in me at here rt.com and password and log in.
And we redirect it now, let's go change this homepage to put a link to the log in.
OK, so back over here and we'll find Holmgren right there.
And at this point, I'll duplicate this line and change that to users.
Log in and change this to log in a user and I go back here and refresh this and we have log in to user
and back.
And that's much cleaner.
Now we can also, if we want to actually logging user out, which is an important route to have and
we should have some indication that a user is logged in.
So let's go back to our.
Code and let's switch to the celebrities project, and let's look at our render function, which is
right here.
So at the very top.
We have this value in our template data, and ultimately this is data that's shared with every template
in the system.
And the first one is is authenticated, which is a Boolean seems to me that's a value I could actually
use.
So let's go down to where we're rendering a page which is right here.
So online, 54 in my code, that's the go page.
Let's try the jet page.
So in line 77, in my code, I declare a variable.
That's an empty template.
That's the type that it is.
And if data is not equal to nil, then I populate that.
But I want to add all of that default data that's in the title template data.
To every request, if at all possible.
So what I can do is go up here.
And just after this function, I'll create a new function funk with the receiver.
I've been calling the receiver C for some reason.
A pointer to render and I'll create a function called default data, and it will take as parameters
TD, which is a reference or a pointer to template data.
And the request, which is a pointer to HTTP request and it returns a pointer to template data.
And here's where I can add default data to every request.
Now what I want to do here for my case right now is determine is to determine whether or not there's
a value called user ID with a capital I and a Capital D in the session.
Now can I do that?
Let's see if we have access to the session from our receiver.
See if C Dot session doesn't look like it's there.
So let's go add session to our render package.
So we'll scroll back up at the top and we'll add right in here session, which will be a pointer to
us session manager right there and actually do the import for me.
And it does.
So now let's go back to Celebrity Stop, Go and populate this field session with our session.
So first of all, save this to format it, then I'll go back to celebrities.
Don't go.
And I'll find the part where I create my ringer.
Right here, create rent or create rent versus jump to that.
And in there, let's put session and make that Seedat session.
And that should be enough, so let's save this.
Let's go back to render ago.
And now that I have access to the session in my render package, I can do something as simple as this.
If see, that session don't exists and we have to pass it the context, so it's our context and we're
looking for user ID exactly like that.
If that exists, then by default this user must be authenticated.
So T dot is authenticated as equal to true.
And now we just return to see now this function exists.
If we go back down to our jet page after we have access to a TD variable, we can just do this.
TD equals C Dot default data, and we handed it's two required functions or parameters TD.
And a request.
And presumably this should work.
So before we leave this, is there anything else I can add up here in my default data?
Well, we wanted it map.
What else do we want in our default data, secure?
Let's put that in there.
So in order for secure or not to secure is equal, to see that secure, we can have that one.
And say, Ted ServerName, we're going to need that at some point is equal to seat on ServerName.
You may as well get it now.
And the port to the port is equal to SeaTac Port.
So this is done.
Let's go back to our other code and go to our terminal and type go mud vendor.
Make sure you're in the My App directory, of course, just to get the latest build of the celebrity
code.
So we have access to it and I'll hide my terminal window.
And now right here where it says, go, build something awesome after that, I'll put it listed.
If.
Dot is authenticated.
Make sure you spell it right and an end.
So if someone is actually authenticated, let's do this small day trip equals slash user slash log out
a route that doesn't exist yet, but we'll add it in a minute longer, and that will tell me that you're
actually authenticated.
And if you want to make it even clearer, we can do it like this authenticated
and put a period after log out just so it looks a little bit better and close our small time.
So let's restart our application and make restart.
I'm sure it all compiles and it does.
And let's go back to our web browser.
Let's reload this page.
OK, so I'm not a syndicated, which is not surprising because we're using cookie sessions.
Let's log user in.
And it is me.
Add here dot com with the password password.
Let's see if we got it right.
Log in.
And it says authenticated log out, so I'll try logging it, and it should give me a four or four file
not found.
And it does page not found.
So let's go analog route, which is actually pretty trivial.
So back to our code and let's hydrate terminal window and let's find our roots file, and let's add
a logger, so I'll duplicate this.
It will be a get request and we'll make this logo
that doesn't exist yet and its users love it.
So let's go create a logo, grid or handle.
So here func with the receiver of H Pointer to handlers, and she's called Lugger with W HTP Dot Response
Writer and her pointer to request.
And this is trivial.
It's always good practice.
Anytime you're logging a user in or logging user to do something like this short app, not Session Dot
Renew token.
And that requires just the context and context.
So we renew our token and then each dot app dot session dot remove.
We remove panning at the context or context.
And we want to remove user ID, which is what we put in when the user logged in.
OK.
And then we'll do a redirect back to the homepage or to the login page.
Should be done.
Redirect.
And Redirect requires you and our response writer and request, and we'll take them to users, log in
with the status HTP Dot status, see other, which is fine for our purposes.
So let's try this out.
Let's restart our application.
Make restart.
And let's go back to your Web browser and go back one screen and refresh this, and we should be logged
out at this point because we're defaulting to cookie sessions and we'll take care of that before too
long.
So we're not logged in.
Let's log in to user me here account password, log in and now try logging out, and it takes us back
to the login screen.
And if we go to the home screen, we shouldn't have that authenticated message and we don't.
Perfect.
So there now we can log your user in, we can log a user.
And at this point, a lot of people, particularly people who haven't been developing for very long,
would say, great, let's move on to the next step.
The problem is that we've not actually verified that any of this code over here in users doggo user
dgo.
We haven't actually verified that any of this works or much of this works.
We have managed to get a user by email so were relatively certain that that works and we've managed
to actually compare a password.
So we've done this one down here, password matches, but we've done very few of the other ones.
And what I want to do now is to actually add some additional methods to this, to take care of tokens,
for example.
And then I want to write some tests and writing the tests for these functions because they're written
using Upper Io.
It's going to require that we do both unit tests, which are relatively straightforward, and we can
do that using pretty much just the standard library.
But we're also going to have to do integration tests because one of the disadvantages of upward slash
db, the package we're using when we do things like this, creating a collection right here, creating
collection, getting a result set, it actually doesn't handle a mock database connection.
So we're going to need a live database connection.
Now we could if we wanted to use the database that we're using for development, but I think a better
approach.
And actually, I'm sure it's a better approach is actually to write an integration test that spins up
a Docker image with an empty Postgres database creates the necessary tables and so forth.
And then we use that test database to run our integration tests.
And if everything passes when we finish, we just get rid of that Docker image.
Now, integration tests are a little bit more work, but they're actually fairly critical in our case,
just to make sure that these functions we've written actually do what we think they do, and we'll get
started on that in the next lecture or two.