So this time around, before we actually get to testing, I want to write the necessary functions to
our tokens and go file our token data structure in the My project.
And the first thing I'm going to do is make a change here.
When I made this model initially, I thought, I'm not going to store plaintext in the database.
And of course, there is no place to store it in our current database, but we're going to fix that
in a moment.
As I was preparing these next few lectures, it quickly became apparent to me that it's really convenient
to have that in there.
So let's change this from a dash, which tells upar to ignore it to a field name token.
And that means that I need to make a change in my database.
And the simplest thing to do at this point is to go to the course resources for this lecture and download
a file.
You'll find they're called off, underscore tables don't sequel and it looks like this.
I have it opened in my text item, and you can see it's a little bit different than what we had before.
To start with, I added this function, which actually updates the column updated at for a given table
to the current date and time.
It just automates that for us, so I create this function.
And then after I create the tables, I create a trigger on each table and that just automates the process
for us.
It just makes things a little bit more convenient.
You will also notice on tokens that I actually added this column online.
4:09 In my code, I added that column, so select everything in that file and copy it, then go to your
favorite database client, connect to your database and I'm connected right now to Solaris House, Docker
and the database hilarious.
And I'll just select all of the tables and delete them, and I have to delete them cascaded because,
you know, there there are foreign key dependencies that will cause me grief otherwise.
So I delete those.
Now I'll go to a sequel, the sequel window and paste in the contents of that text file, select all
and execute the selection and that will create the tables for me.
And now they have triggers and it has the necessary column.
All right, so that's out of the way.
Now let's go back to user.
Don't go just really quickly and see if we have any changes we need to make here before we start writing
tests.
And you'll see right away.
And most of you probably noticed this on this get by email function.
I actually say when I'm getting the token, find me in the tokens table.
The tokens for the user were the expiry is less than Typekit now.
And of course, that's the opposite of what it should be.
It should be greater than.
And the same thing down here when we say, get my ID. This should be greater than OK.
That'll just save us a little bit grief, a little bit of grief down the road.
Now let's go back to token dark go and start thinking about the kinds of functions that we want here.
Well, right away, I'm going to say we probably want one with the receiver of Te Pointer two token.
We probably one want one that says, Get user four token OK.
And all it's going to take is one parameter token, which is a string.
And we're going to return potentially a pointer to a user model and an error or nil if there's no error.
OK.
So this is pretty simple.
Let's create a variable called u of type user, and let's create a variable called the token of type
token.
And now let's get a collection just like we did before.
Collection is assigned a value of uppercase collection, and we want tweaked table.
The table name, which, as you can see right here in line 18, is tokens.
OK, so like using my collection, we'll get a result set by calling Collection Dot Find and our condition
is up dots you, Andy and then in Curly Braces Token Colon Space Token.
The parameter pass to this function.
Now it didn't import up for me, so let's see if we can do with a quick fix.
And that worked, OK, so now we have our results set.
And now we'll check for an error and call resort one because we only want one and we're going to read
that into the token, if error is not equal to nil, then we'll just return error or nil and the error.
Otherwise we have our necessary toolkit and now will overwrite the value of collection to be equal to
Upper Dot collection.
And this time, I want to go to the user's table, so I'll just put it in like that.
And a result is now equal to collection dot find.
And we want an up dart condition where it is equal to.
The token got user I.D. right there.
And that should get me the user if that user exists.
Now we'll call we'll check for an error by calling from resort one and read into the variable you,
and that should be our user.
OK.
And if there's an error, will return nil errors or copy this and paste it here.
And now we say you Dot token is equal to the token.
So we populate that necessary field in our user model and we return a reference to, you know, so there's
a first one that allows us to get a user by token.
And clearly we're going to be using that one regularly, particularly when we're authenticating through
an API.
OK.
What else are we going to want to do?
Well, let's say get tokens for user, get all the tokens for a given user.
We might never need it, but let's put it in there.
T pointer to token and we'll say get tokens for user ID and that'll be a user ID, and we'll return
a slice of pointers to token and potentially an error.
And this should be old hat for you now.
We'll create a variable tokens, which will be a slice of pointers to token, which we have to return
and we'll get our collection.
Collection is assigned the value of uppercut collection and we want to get the table to table, which
will return tokens.
And we'll say Rose is a sign.
The value of collection dot find and are up condition is user ID.
The equal is implied so we can just put it in
and we'll check for an error when we read it into tokens.
So error is a sign the value of resident all.
And we want to read into tokens and I'll paste that error check, which I had from last time around.
And if there's no error, we return tokens and no.
OK, so that's when we might need as well.
Let's keep going.
Another one we might need to do.
We might need to get a token by ID.
So Func T point or two token, and we'll just call this one get and it takes one parameter ID, which
is in it, and it returns a pointer to a token and potentially an error.
But again, very simple create a variable token of type token.
We'll get our collection
pointing to the tokens table.
We get a result.
So.
Which is collection to find, and we want an up condition where it is equal to it.
We check for an error when we read from rows one into token.
And again, I'll paste my error check because I still have it and will return a reference to token and
nil.
So there's our get method.
Another one would be get by token, which is very similar.
So let's copy this and paste it here and call it get by token.
But we're not going to take an integer parameter.
We'll take.
Plain text, which is of type, string the plain text version of our token and down here, our condition
is not I.D., our condition is token.
That column I just added to the database and the value is plain text, so those have to match select
stats.
Get by token.
OK, what else do we need to do?
Well, occasionally we need to delete tokens, particularly when a user logs out, for example.
So func te pointer to token and we'll say delete by ID, ID int, and it returns nothing more than an
error or nil if there's no error.
And this is just collection is a the value of upper collection.
And we want T table that gives us our collection and now we want rows is equal to collection dot find.
And since we're finding by primary key primary here, we can just put it there and that will work just
fine.
And we'll say error is equal to dot delete put in our error check.
So a copy and paste copy paste.
And we return our error.
There's only one thing there.
And if there's no error, return nil now it's very infrequent that you would delete a token by I.D.
It's far more common.
I would think that you're going to delete, by token, the plain text version of our token.
OK, but we might need both.
So here we'll put it in plain text of type string.
And here this becomes update condition.
And it is token and that becomes plaintext, and everything else stays the same.
So that's our delete my token.
We're also going to need to insert tokens.
So Func T token insert.
And this will take two parameters because we need to know the token.
So token of type token.
And we're also going to need the user information so we can get their ID first name, things like that
user.
And potentially that returns an error.
And of course, you could pre populate everything you needed in the token variable, but it's faster
to do it this way.
Less code on the other end.
So we'll get a collection.
Collection is assigned the value of upward collection, and we want to table that case as our collection.
Now, if we're going to insert a token, let's delete existing tokens, which you may not want to do.
But in my case, I always do this OK because I'm paranoid and don't want sessions hanging around or
connections hanging around when they don't have to be anymore.
So I'll say Rez is assigned the value of collection got find and my condition will be up second user
ID.
And that's going to be equal to you, the ID, you being the user passed here.
OK.
And it's not a comma, it's a colon,
so that gets me my results, so and I'll just check for an error when I delete them.
Resort delete if error is not equal to nil,
return the error.
And let's give ourselves some room here.
So once they're all deleted, let's make sure that created an updated out first name and email have
been set on the token variable that we received as a parameter.
So Token Dot created up.
This is new, so I can just say time dot now, and this is the same thing for updated.
I
get rid of that.
That's better.
And we're going to want token dot first name will be equal to you dot first name because that's all
I'm storing in there and token.
The email is equal to youdon't email.
So now I have my token populated with all the necessary information so I can just insert it.
I don't care about the returned I.D. error and I already have an error variable, so that becomes an
equals collection.
Don't insert and we insert the token and we check for an error.
So a copy and paste,
and if everything went according to plan, we can return nil.
All right.
So that inserts a token.
We also, of course, need to generate tokens before we can insert them.
So thunk te pointer or two token generate token.
And this is going to take a user I.D. that we need and the time to life, and that will be a timed duration.
How long do we want the token to last?
And of course, we need to return the tokens or return a pointer to token and potentially an error and
generating a token is really straightforward.
First of all, let's create a token.
Variable token is assigned the value of a reference to token and will populate the fields we know about
user I.D. that will be equal to the user I.D.
and that needs to have an event after it.
That's better.
And the expiry, when does it expire?
And they call it expires here.
What do I have at the top before I go any further?
Expires expiry perfect.
OK.
So in the database, I'm calling you expiry in the field in the type is called expires, which is for
you.
So expires it's going to expire at a particular date and time.
And what we're getting is our duration.
So we'll take the current time timed out now and we will add the time to life, which is already in
the form of a duration.
So that will add the duration here to the current date and time.
So we have that information.
We have part of our token set up.
Now we need to generate a token and that's really simple and go random bytes, which is just a variable
name I'm choosing and it consists of, as you might expect, bytes.
So make a slice of byte and we'll make it 16.
OK.
So that's the size.
And now we'll read into random bytes.
So underscore.
I don't care about the first return value, but I do care about the error and we're going to call from
the rand package.
Read.
And that looks like it's there.
So we're going to read random votes, OK, and we'll check for an error.
So we're only I'll say if error is not equal to nil and we have to return values are Richard Nil in
the error.
Otherwise we can keep going.
Return, that's better.
It's a return that if we have an error, but if we get past that and we certainly will, then we need
to populate plain text.
That part of our token, so token plain text and how do we get what we need, which is a string from
all of those random bytes?
It's actually a fairly lengthy command, but it's not complicated.
Based 32 is the package, so we're going to take that from the standard library.
We're going to use standard encoding.
And we're going to add padding in case it's not the right length.
So with padding and the parameter for that is based 32, no padding.
So we're specifying what kind of padding we want, which is no padding whatsoever because it should
be the correct length.
And now we encode this to a string and we're encoding to a string of random bytes.
OK.
And that will give us our token in exactly the right format and will always be the same number of characters
long every time we generate a token.
So that gives us the plain text.
Now we need the hash because we need both of those for the database.
Subhash, which is just a variable I'm declaring is equal to from the S.H., a 2:56 package in crypto.
And we want some 256.
Make sure you get the right one or you'll be banging your head against a wall trying to figure out what
went wrong.
Some 256.
And we're going to take our token plaintext and cast it to a slice of votes.
Slice of byte token.
Plain text that uses our hash.
Now we just populate token dot hash equal to hash.
But we need to convert it to an array to get everything out of it that's not necessary for the format
we need to store.
Otherwise, we'll never be able to authenticate anyone.
And now we just return it, return token and nil.
So that's how we generate tokens.
And as you can see, 133 to 148, there's not very many lines of code there.
OK, so now we can insert tokens, we can generate tokens.
The next thing we need to do is to authenticate a token to make sure a token is actually valid.
So func t pointer to token, and we'll call this one not surprisingly authenticate token, and it will
take as parameters nothing more than the request our pointer to HDP request, and it returns potentially
a pointer to a user and an error or nil if there's no error.
Let's give ourselves some room.
So this is exactly the standard way with authenticated token, and it really doesn't matter whether
that token is stateful token like we're using.
It's very similar if you're doing, say, adjacent token.
OK, so let's go with authorization header, which is just a variable name, I'm declaring that will
be equal to from the request.
Get the headers and the one we want in particular is going to be called authorization, OK, which is
the standard header used for authentication and authorization.
And if there is no header, then we have a problem right away.
If authorization header is equal to an empty string, which is what will happen if it doesn't exist,
then we'll return nil because we don't have a user and then I'll just create an error.
Errors don't new and my error message will be no authorization header received.
OK, but if we get past that, then let's make sure the header is in the correct format.
So I'll call the variable that her purse, which almost everybody does, that's equal to strings dot
and we're going to split the authorization header and we're going to split it on one blank space.
So we expect to find an authorization header that consists of the word bearer with a Capital B, followed
by a space followed by the plain text version of the token the person is going to authenticate with.
That's the standard way you do API authentication.
OK.
So we can check for a couple of obvious things.
If the length of head or parts is not equal to two OK or header parts, the first index is not equal
to the word bear and spell it right or again, you'll have problems.
Then we'll return nil.
So we don't have a user.
And another new error.
Errors dog new, and I'll just put in no authorization header received, which is exactly the same error
I gave before, but when people are trying to authenticate, I just want them to know that I can't authenticate
because you're not giving me enough information.
I don't want to give them specifics.
I want to make it difficult for people to try to figure out how to log in if they're doing something
nefarious.
And that's useful information.
That's enough if you're a valid user trying to write some code.
Now, if we get past both of those, then our token is equal to header parts.
The second index position one because position one, position two, because position one is actually
zero because we start counting from zero in the computer world.
Now let's make sure this token is exactly the right format.
If the length of token is not equal to twenty six, every token will be exactly 26 characters along.
Then I'll return a new error.
So to save some time by copying this and pasting it in here and changing the message to in this case,
I can say token wrong size, and I'm not going to tell them how long it needs to be.
Let them figure it out on their own if they're trying to break it, which they'll never be able to do
anyway if we do our job right.
So we have it now.
Let's try getting our token from the database, so I'll create a variable called T four token.
I'll check for an error and those will come from calling the method.
T get my token that we wrote just a moment ago and I'll hand it token the string.
OK.
And again, if error is not equal to nil,
then return nil and errors don't new.
And in this time, I'll say no matching token felt.
OK, now at this point I made, it might have received the token.
The problem, of course, is that token might have expired.
And if the tokens expired, I want to throw back an error message.
So if T dot expiry.
Expires Dot before if it expires before the current date and time time dot now, then that Typekit took,
it is expired.
OK, then I will return, Neal.
No user and errors dot new and the message will just be expired.
Token guy to spell, right?
OK, so we've checked all of those things.
Now finally, we have a valid token.
We can find the token in the database.
The token is of the right length and all those things.
We have the correct authorization header.
Now we try to get a user user an error.
Our assigned the value of Typekit user for token.
And I just hand it token.
And if everything goes well, then I can return that.
But I do have to make sure that I actually have a user.
So if error is not equal to nil, then return nil and errors dot new.
And all I can say here is no matching user found or whatever you want for an error message.
But if that worked, I can return user and no.
OK.
Seems like a lot of code, but most of it is just making sure that the information is in the correct
format in the header and the rest of it is pretty straightforward.
So we get that token and occasionally someone's going to hand as a token and we need to validate it.
So we'll create another function function T token.
And I'll just say valid token for the name, and it will be nothing more than the plain text version
of our token, which is a string, and I'm going to return a Boolean and potentially an error.
OK, so first thing we'll do is get a user for the token, which I did right here, so I can copy this
and paste it and fix the return type.
And the return type, of course, is going to be false because things are not good.
So no matching user found I was easy.
And again, let's make sure this token has an expired, OK?
First of all, let's make sure it's not empty, which I may not have to do, but I'm going to anyway.
If user token plaintext is equal to an empty string, which is what would happen if we got a user with
no token.
Then let's return.
Faults and no matching token found, which is an error is new, so let's put that in front of it.
Aristotle knew there.
And finally, let's make sure it hasn't expired, so I'll copy this and change it.
Paste it in here and say.
User token dot expires before time now.
Return false.
It's not a valid token.
OK, but if we and the last thing I need to do here is we've passed all those checks, so it is a valid
unexpired token return, true and nil.
Now, if we did everything right and we almost certainly have a typo in there somewhere.
But if we did everything right, we're now at the point where we can start to write tests.
So we'll get started on our tests in the next lecture, and it will probably take a few lectures to
go through all of the tests.