So now that we have our driver don't go file set up and we have a means of connecting to the database,
the next step is to actually build that connection string that allows us to connect to Postgres.
So the very first thing I'm going to do is in type, don't go in the celebrities package.
I'm going to create a couple of new types.
So I'll create a very simple one called and it's not exported database config, and we'll put this in
our config struct.
It will be a struct that it only has a couple of members.
So DSM, which is a string, will be our connection string and also the database.
What database we're going to connect to, which is a string?
OK.
So there's one, and we're also going to create another type and this one will be exported because it
might be useful to our end users who are using celebrities.
So we'll call it database with a Capital D, and it's a struct, and it only has a couple of members
as well.
So it will have the database type, which is a string Postgres, MariaDB, MySchool, whatever.
And then our connection pool, which we're going to get back from.
Driver, don't go.
And it's a pointer to SQL DB.
OK.
So those are the two types now that they're created.
They're available to me.
So let's go back to celebrities and we'll add it right here after session in the celebrities type.
So it's available to her and users.
And I'm going to call it Debbie, and it's a type database which we just added to our system.
OK.
And down in config here, I'll add another one for our configuration.
So we have this if we ever need it, and it will just call it database with a lowercase D because it's
not going to be exported and it's a type database config.
OK.
So let's say this.
So now we have a place to put this information.
So the next thing we need to worry about is how do we build that connection string?
So I'm going to do that way down at the bottom of this file.
I'll create a function that actually gets the information from our dot on file and builds a DSM.
And I'll call it func with the receiver of C Pointer to celebrities, and I'll call it build DSM.
And it takes no parameters, but returns a string.
OK.
So let's create a variable DSM IV type string, and that's where we'll store the final ready to go connection
string.
And we'll make a simple switch statement here because ultimately we're going to support more than just
one database.
So we'll switch on OAC.
Don't get on.
And this is from the dart on file database type.
And our first case will be Postgres,
and we may as well make sure that it could be PostgreSQL like this as well.
OK.
And there we're actually going to build our DSM.
So let's get started.
So our DSN will be equal to and we'll use format as print f and have a format string.
And the format string used by Jack C slash peg X is pretty straightforward.
Host equals some string value port equals some string value user equals some string value DB name,
which I had a spell right.
TBE name is equal to a string.
SSL mode is equal to a string and I'm going to put it in time.
Zone is equal to UTC just as a default, and I'll also add a connect timeout of five seconds.
OK, so five.
And then we replace all of those placeholders with values from our own.
So the first one would be the database host, and that's just O'Scanlon.
And in the dot on file, it's called database underscore host.
I will duplicate that.
Our second value has to be the port and that is database port and duplicate that.
The next one is database user and duplicate that and the next one is the database name leaving password
out for a reason.
You'll see that momentarily.
So database name and then database SSL mode
like that, and it has to be exactly the way it's written in the dot on file, of course.
So that will build a connection string.
Now this builds a connection string with no password, and that's the default for some installations
of Postgres, and we need to support that.
So after we finished building that connection, string was simply put in if statement him if OS.
Might get on.
And we're looking for a database underscore pass, if that's equal to or not equal to an empty string,
then the user is in fact specified a password.
So we'll just add the appropriate value to the connection string.
DSN is equal to format as print out in our format string is percent s, which will be our existing DSN
and then password equals per se and we simply replace those two placeholders with DSM and OS.
Don't get on database pass.
OK, now technically we only have one thing here.
I'm going to put a default in just because it looks good and I like that.
And of course, we can decide what to do with the default at some point.
And down here we say return DSM DSM, which I seem to have trouble typing.
OK, so now we have a means of building our DSM.
And of course, I made the variable here because DSN will be different for MariaDB or my Esquibel or
whatever databases you want to support.
So now that we have this available to us, let's use it.
So let's go back up to the top and.
After we create our lagers and before we begin populating our celerity variable, let's connect to the
database.
So connect to the database and of course, there's only certain situations we want to do that.
So the easiest test is to say if OAC don't get on
database type, that's not equal to nothing, it's not equal to an empty string.
Then I want to connect it to the database so we can do it as easily as this now.
DB, which will be my connection, pool and error, are assigned the value of seed open DB.
That's the drive in the driver dgo file and we handed OAC don't get on database type, which will be
Postgres or piggybacks in our case, and then we need our connection string.
So what we have to put in here is now see on build DSM.
We check for error with error is not equal to nil.
Then what do I want to do?
Well, I actually want to put the arrow, so I'll say air log dot print line.
And I can do that because airlines already defined and I'll print out just the error.
And at that point, I want to stop because if you can't connect to your database, you have big problems.
I'll say, OK, Scott, exit one.
So we've exit it.
But if we get past that now, I can say, see that DB.
In other words, that database type, which is now a field within our celebrities type that's going
to be equal to the type database that will fill in its fields database type.
And that's equal to us.
Don't get on database
type.
Check out a spell, right?
And its connection cool.
Its pool is equal to DB.
So let's see if this works.
First of all, let's switch back to silver toss or switch back to my app and make sure the dot on file
has some values in there.
So first of all, I'll look at my.
Dawn, which is right here, and I'll also look at how close the terminal.
I will also look at my Docker compose right here.
So in Docker compose, I'm expecting database.
I'm expecting the Postgres database to be on port five four three two to have the user Postgres, the
password password and the Postgres database of celebrities.
Perfect.
What's in my daughter on file in my Darren file, I have Postgres localhost port five four three three.
I'll make that five four three two.
The database is Postgres, the password is password and the database name is hilarious and I have my
database SSL mode set up properly.
Perfect.
So let's make sure that our database is running Docker compose, and I'll just say up.
I want to make sure it's actually ready before I try to run this thing.
So it looks like everything is up and running.
OK, so now I'll open a new terminal window by clicking the plus sign here and I will say make start
and see if there's any errors.
So does it go on vendor, it pulls down all of our changes, it built it and it started up and I still
have session load called stored in the middleware there, so I should get rid of that sometime.
But it started up with audio errors, so it seems like we're connected.
But of course, we haven't actually tried anything yet.
So in the next lecture, we'll try doing some simple things with the database just to make sure it's
behaving the way that it should.
And of course, there's one more thing to worry about.
We didn't actually close the database connections at any time, and that's really not polite.
Of course, it will still work if this application stops, if I stop it right now.
Eventually, those connections will timeout and Postgres will close them, but it's nicer to close those
things explicitly.
So we'll take care of that as well in the next election.