So let's try using the database connection we built in the last lecture.
And right now I'm looking at celebrities don't go, and one thing we didn't do last time was populate
this config struct with the database, a field of Typekit database config, and we probably should do
that.
It's pretty straightforward.
So we'll just come down here in, we're in the file celebrities not go looking at the new function and
down where we actually populate see dot config.
We can do that really easily.
We just put in here database.
And of course, that's a type.
Database config and we just populate its two two fields.
So the first one is database.
And of course, that's okay.
Don't get on database type.
And we want database and we may never need this, but it's nice to have the configuration values available
if you need them.
And the DSM, this is not the most efficient code in the world, but we can just call Cedar Bill DSM
again.
And I don't mind doing that because this will only fire once when the application starts up.
So we'll just build a string again and stick it in there.
OK, so that takes care of the changes in celebrities.
Don't go.
Let's switch over to my app and we'll do something right in the roots file.
OK, so right here after our test sessions, let's put a temporary root in their Ader app.
Dog roots don't get and we'll call it test database like that, and we'll have an inline function,
which is bunk with the first parameter being our response.
Writer W.H. Typekit, response writer Because we're just doing it in line handler here and our which
a pointer to a beat up request.
OK, so let's make this dead simple.
And what we'll do is we'll query a table that doesn't exist yet, and we'll go and build that table
manually in a couple of minutes.
But let's do this right now.
So we'll write a query and we'll say select ID and first name from users where ID equals one.
OK, so that's a pretty good sample, and I got to put an assignment operator there.
That's better.
And now we'll simply get a row from the database.
So we're going to use query row context, which is straight out of the sequel package built into the
standard library.
So we'll say row and check for error or assign the value of.
And now we need to get access to our database pool.
And of course, that's trivial now.
Hey, which is from a receiver for application Typekit app and we don't want to open DB now that's the
celebrities type.
And now we want DB and we want pool.
And from that, we just call query context, query row context.
OK.
So from that?
I think there's only one return value from that, but we'll check in a minute.
We it the context, correct context, and we had a query.
And of course, this only gives one value back.
OK, so we look at query row context.
It's return value is a sequel row.
And now we say error is a sign, the value of road scan and we'll scan into two variables.
So let's create those variables.
Just a place to hold these things very ID of Typekit and very name of type string.
And we'll scan from that row into I.D. and name and we'll check for an error.
And we'll say if error is not equal to nil, then we'll just say a Dot app dot error log dot print line.
The error will return.
Otherwise, let's just write this information to the screen, to the browser window.
It won't be pretty, but it will show us that it works format dot f print f and we'll give it the response
writer and a format string that holds an integer and a string and put in it the next.
OK, now this will work as soon as we go and create a file or a value in our database.
So let me make sure I have that running.
I don't think that I do.
I'm not sure.
So let's try make start compose.
They're already running, I guess.
Sounds like it, anyway.
Let's go connect, so I'll go to my favorite database client, which happens to be this one, and I'm
connected to celebrities Docker and there's the database.
So let's create a template or create a table, which I'll call users if that's what I specified in my
my query.
It'll have one column ID there, and then we'll add another column and I called it first name
and text is fine for our purposes.
OK, so let's save this and let's go to the content for this and put a row in there.
And the first name is Trevor, and I'll let the database handle setting the ID.
Let's save this.
Now I have one room, so I should be able to come here and say, make start.
And if we didn't have any typos, you should start out.
It's already starting, so it's mixed up.
And make start.
It's listening.
Let's go to our web browser and try going to the URL slash test dash database and see if we got it right.
So create a new browser window and go to localhost 4000 slash test database and one and Trevor.
So that worked really well.
OK, now the last thing I want to do in this lecture before we make this a little bit better is to go
back to celebrities and make sure we explicitly close the database connections.
So of course, we're going to do that in the celebrity start go file and we can do it right here on
listen and serve.
So this is a function listen and serve that actually starts the the web server.
And of course, we're listening here and we're checking for an error.
Something goes wrong.
But right here, after we declare this serve variable of type HDTV server, let's just say defer c db
dot pool and we'll call close.
So there, when we stop our application, this function will stop.
And as soon as that function stops, we've deferred closing of the database.
And that makes things ever so much cleaner.
Now, obviously, if we go back to my app and we look at that inline route here, this works really
well.
And I love writing Ross sequel, and I love having absolute control over the way that I interact with
my database.
But of course, we're trying to write rewrite a version of Laravel in Go.
And one of the big attractions of Laravel to be developers is the fact that it has an object relational
mapper, an aura that makes interacting with the database ever so much easier.
Well, don't worry, we're going to support sequel like this for people who understand people really
well and are comfortable using it and have want to have, like I do, complete control.
But we will implement something that makes interacting with databases a lot easier, that it removes
your abstract shoo away from writing sequel by hand.
So we'll support both approaches just like Laravel does.
They permit RON database queries and transactions as well and will do precisely the same thing.
All right, let's move on.