So let's keep working on our database connectivity now, I'm right now, I'm looking at the Rootstock
Go file in my app, and the first thing I'll do is get rid of this temporary route because we don't
need that anymore.
So that's gone now, and I will save this and actually clean up my imports.
OK, perfect.
Now what I'm going to do next is create a file in the data directory, and that's a directory that was
created when we started celebrities and currently it's empty.
I want to create a new file in them, and I'm going to call it models, plural.
Don't go.
OK.
And I'll give it this package declaration package data.
Now this package data, that folder is in many ways very similar to the models folder you would find
in older versions of Laravel.
I'm not sure if it's there in the most current version or not, but I know it used to be.
But in any case, it's where we'll store various files that represent the kinds of things we have in
our database and our goal in this lecture.
In the next few, I'm sure, is to implement a structure for models that correspond to tables and data
stored in the database and make it really, really easy for users to work with it.
OK.
So let's get started.
So the first thing I'll do is create a variable VAR db of type pointer to school.
Dot VB, OK, and then I'll create a type called models, not surprisingly.
And it's a struct, and I'll put a comment in here any models inserted here and in the new function,
which doesn't exist yet, but it will in a moment are easily accessible throughout, throughout the
entire application.
OK.
That's our goal.
Now let's create the new function func new and we'll take one parameter, which I'm going to call database
pool because that's what it is of type of pointer to school dot db and it returns the type of models.
OK.
So first of all, before the if statement, let's assign some value to this variable DB that we created
up here.
So DB will be equal to not surprisingly, database pool.
So now this variable has a value and is therefore accessible to the entire package because it's a package
level variable.
Now I'll write that instinct, and I'm going to check to see what database we're using.
So I'll say, if OAC don't get on right there, I'm going to look for database type.
And I'll say, if that's equal to my skill, I should say or and copy this whole thing.
And pasted in there, I make sure they didn't type.
Maria Deeb, which is possible and I want to do something right now, I'm not going to do anything so
to say to do belts.
And the only other one we're going to support in this course is Postgres, and we can assume that this
is going to be Postgres.
And the reason I'm putting this if statement here is because what I want to get started with this time
around is installing something that's very similar to an R M and object relational mapper.
A lot of people that use frameworks like Laravel really don't like to work directly with Scott.
And as I said a couple of lectures ago, I like working with schools, so it's not a problem for me
and probably for many of you as well.
But lots of people expect to have an easy means of interacting with the database, and we're going to
do that.
We're going to do it by using this package.
Let me go to my web browser.
It's called Upper Slash DB, and it's a very easy to use and well written agnostic database layer.
It works with many databases, so I'm going to click on this and there's a link to this in the course
resources for this lecture, I'm going to take the tour and I will skip the first one when it just talks
about how it works.
OK, let's go to the next one.
How do I install this thing?
I have to go get this.
So let's copy that bit.
Go get on a leave at the dash, because sometimes that causes grief.
I'll just go get this and I'm leaving the dollar sign adapter part out because we're going to use Postgres,
OK, and I'll go back to my I.D. and open my terminal and type, go get paste.
And then I'll put right here at the end of this post, Grizz show, I'm actually going get it.
And it does.
And I will do the same thing.
It means we'll do it now and go back to Firefox and look at this, what's the other one called Maya's?
So let's go back here and I'll just backspace over this bit and put in my school.
And it goes and gets it.
Now we have access to both Post-cruise and MySchool with Upper DB.
Once we start using it.
OK, so let's start using it up here at the very top in my import statement, actually actually right
here.
I will say I'm going to import something.
I will say DB two is what I'm going to call it is I'm already using DB and I'll import GitHub dot com
slash upper slash DB slash v4.
OK.
We're not using that yet, so it's going to show me an error.
And I'm also going to import GitHub dot com slash upper slash DB slash v4 slash DApp Tor Adapt or your
slash might ask you, I'll I'll duplicate that and change my ask to Postgres grad.
OK, then down here, I'm going to create a new variable or upper, a package level variable that's
been available to the entire data package and that will be of type two session.
Not session test session.
OK.
Now down here in my old statement.
The second part of that.
So the ELTs part of the if I will say upper and I'll ignore the error for now to get this working is
equal equal to PostgreSQL Dot new and I'll hand it my database pool.
OK.
And here in this one where it's modest, you will, I will say upper and again, ignore the air is equal
to my ask you up.
Don't new.
Try that again, new and I will hand it database pool.
OK, now I still have to import errors and hopefully those will go away soon.
Let me save this and it says it can't find those, even though I know they're installed.
So let's try go mod, then do.
And I want to come back up here.
Those errors all go away except for news, which should be new, and that takes care of them.
OK, so we've imported those, we've got them running.
But this new function needs to return something.
OK?
And what it needs to return is just the type models, so I can just return an empty model for now.
So this will over time give us an easy method of interacting with the database.
So what we'll do next is we'll go and create a real user's table will update the one that we have there
now and make it more useful.
And then we'll actually implement some methods on a user model that takes advantage of the upper functionality
that we just included in our application, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.