So let's keep working on our brand like functionality and actually working with our models.
And right now, I'm looking at the Postgres client that I use, which is postcode for a Mac, and I
want to replace our kind of dummy user table with something more useful.
And in the course resource of this lecture, you'll see a file called User's Skill.
Now I'm going to ask you to download that and copy the contents of that file to your clipboard, then
go to your database client, whatever it may be, and connect to celebrities and bring up the part where
you can look at sequel.
But that's an empty SQL query.
What I'm going to do is paste the contents of that.
Users don't SQL file right in there, and as you can see here, what it will do is drop the table users.
If it exists, that it will create a user's table, then it will create a remember token's table, which
we use for authentication.
And also it will create a token's table which will use for API authentication.
OK.
So once you have it in there, execute that statement.
So I'll execute the whole thing.
I'm going to select it all just to be safe and execute the selection.
And when it finishes, I should have over here when I reload this or refresh this, I should have a
user's table, a token's table and remember token's table perfect.
So now we have some place to put data and we can actually work with it.
Now I'm going to go back to my I.D. and I'm going to make sure I'm in the My App package, and I'm sure
you realize this.
But all of the things we're working on for much of this section rush are going to build in my app.
But over time, those will become part of the Celerity package.
So we'll move things that need to be moved over to this larger test package.
We're actually going to take some things like the SQL file you just ran.
And we're going to build a command line utility that allows us to create a complete authentication system
with one command from the command line, but it'll be a while before we get there.
In the interim, let's go back to our data directory and let's create a new file in here called user
ago.
So I'm going to go singular.
The model user corresponds to the database table called users plural, and that's the convention I'm
going to use, and we'll make sure it's possible to override that convention because sometimes you have
to do that sort of thing, particularly if you're trying to migrate an old database to a newer web framework.
So I've created that user file and I'll give it its package decoration package data.
And inside of this, I'll begin by describing in a struct the database fields and matching them to data
I can use can go so simple type user with a capital u.
I'm going to be exporting this and it's a script and it has.
The first thing it has is an ID field of Typekit, and I need to add this so that upar can work with
it.
A descriptive description in tactics like this.
And if you've never used the back key before, it's the one on my keyboard just below the escape key
in the top left and you describe the matching that should take place to upper.
I have to say column and then in quotation marks ID, comma omit empty, OK, and then close that.
And that's saying to upper anytime somebody uses the type user, the field I.D., which is a capital
I Capital D that matches the Field ID in the database.
And if it's empty, just leave it out if you're actually trying to work with it.
OK, so let's make sure that we have something for all of our fields.
We have a first name, which is a string, and in the database, I'm going to call that first underscore
name.
And if you look at your database, that's how I named it.
Then I'll duplicate this and make that lasting
and in the database that is called, not surprisingly, the last underscore name.
And then I'll duplicate it again and make this one email, which I have to spell right email.
And then the database is just called email.
OK, and then I'll duplicate that again or go to the next line and say, active is user active or not?
That's just in it and in the database that is called active user active.
OK.
So you can see it's not necessary to have an absolute correspondence between what your name, your field
here and what you call it in the database.
OK.
So active.
Then you have password
and that is a string, and it's not going to be the real password.
It'll be a hash of the password, but I'm sure you guessed that already.
But in the database, I call the password and then I'll have created at.
Which is time, time and in the database that's called DV created duplicate that I make this updated.
And in the database, I call the updated that I'm going to put another one here.
OK?
And it's going to cause an error for a bit, but don't worry about that.
It's a token and it's a type token, and this is what causes the error.
So don't have that type described yet, but we will before too long in the database.
I'm going to put a dash in quotation marks that says, Ignore that that does not exist.
OK.
So there's my user type, and I'm going to now create another type, another file in my data directory
called not surprisingly, token doggo.
And this will have the package declaration of data.
And in that, I'm going to have a type called token, which is a strapped.
OK, so now when I go back to user, error goes away so I can save this to format it and go back the
token.
Analysts describe its fields.
OK, so the ID is in it and in the database.
I'm going to call it Heidi, and then because I'm going to be using tokens largely with API authentication.
I mean, so Phil, this bit as well in Jason, this will be called I.D..
So that's my first field.
My second one is user ID, and that'll be an integer.
And in the database that would be called user underscore ID.
And Jason, I'll call it the same thing.
User underscore I.D. and then I'll have first name, which is a string.
And in the database, I'm going to call that first underscore name and adjacent.
I'll call that first underscore name.
Then I will have their email address, which is true, and you can probably guess what comes next.
D.B. Cohen Email.
And Jason Cohen email in quotation marks.
Then I'll have plain text.
OK, that's what we're going to store plain text tokens and that'll be a string and that doesn't exist
in the database.
So I'll put D.B. Colon on a dash that says, ignore that.
But in Jason, I do have to have that because that's how be passing a token to a user when they do API
authentication.
OK.
And then I'll have hash, and this is a slice of bytes.
And in the database, we do store that and we store it as a token hash
and Jason.
I'm not going to pass that at all.
So I'll the colon and then quotation marks around the dash.
Then I'll have created an updated out, so I'm going to go copy that was from user to save a little
bit of time.
So copy those who back the token and paste them in and then I need to import time.
So I didn't really save that much time.
Time got time there.
That does my import and it should be updated at.
Good thing, I know it's not here that would cause me grief down the road, which means I need to fix
it.
A user as well at their there.
So now I have created updated and the last thing I need for a token, of course, is tokens don't last
forever, expire at some point, so expires and that will be timed on time and in the database.
I'll call that.
Expires and in Jason, I'll call that expires.
OK.
I also need to do the Jason Typekit for created out and updated out Jason created.
And here they're here.
Jason created.
OK, so there's that type and we have created an updated up.
And what's why is it?
Give me a warning here.
Now they're updated.
That's better.
IEDs are so helpful.
OK, so I have a type for token and I have a type for user.
Now obviously this isn't enough.
This just describes how the data in this struct is mapped to the data in the database.
And of course, we need to do more than that.
And one of the things you often have to do is if you're working with legacy data, for example, your
user's table might not be called users, you might be called customers or something like that.
But anyway, you need some means of overwriting in the convention.
That I'm following is the same convention that Upper DB follows, and that is the single type user maps
to the plural ized version of that users in the database.
And you need some means of overwriting that.
So let's do that really quickly.
So in user, don't go out of function and it's going to have the receiver of you a pointer to that type,
which means that this function is available any time you have the type user.
And this is what's going to make working with the database ever so much easier.
I'm just going to call this function table.
It takes no arguments and it returns a string.
And all I'm going to do is, say, return users.
Now, any time I need to refer to the table, which corresponds to user my type user.
I can override it.
So if my table is actually called customers, I just change this to customers in the table function,
and that makes things a lot easier.
Now let's try something really simple.
Let's say I want to get all of the users from the database.
Now, if you take another courses from me, you might be familiar with me creating a package called
database or something like that and then just writing some school and getting it directly.
And we're taking a slightly different approach in this course, and that is to make as much of our database
interaction as possible tied to individual models.
So let's try an example here.
We'll say thank you pointer to type user.
I'll just call this get all.
OK.
And it has some condition now.
That condition is where we begin to use upper condition and that type is up dot condition.
Now, where is up up doesn't exist, but I'm about to add it manually and I'm going to give it the alias
up here in my import statements.
So I'll wrap this whole thing in quotation marks.
OK.
And then because I want it to be as readable as possible, I will import up, which is actually GitHub
dot com slash upper with two PS slash db slash the four.
What the OK.
And now down here I have up condition.
And that actually should be up second.
I knew that that was sloppy.
So we'll be passing a condition to this function.
Get off.
OK.
So here is how we interact with our database, and of course, we need to return something.
What I'm going to return is not surprisingly, because this is the get all function on the users, a
slice of a pointer to user,
and I'm also potentially going to return an error.
So how do I query the database using upper?
Well, it's pretty straightforward.
The very first thing you have to do is upper refers to things that are stored in the database as collections.
So I'm going to follow their naming convention.
Call this a collection.
That's my variable.
A collection is assigned the value of Upper Dot collection.
Now I could if I wanted to just put users like that and that would work fine.
But we have this function table.
They actually returns the actual name of the table here.
So why don't we take advantage of that instead?
You don't table now that gives me a collection.
OK.
That's a reference to a certain bit of the database.
Now I need a place to store the information and give her a chance overall, which will be a slice of
pointers to users.
And now this is as simple as saying my results, which I call wrens, are assigned the value of collection,
which I declare their on line.
Twenty six.
Dot find using whatever condition was passed as a parameter to this function.
OK, that gives me a result.
And now I'll try to use that result by saying I'll check for error is assign the value of RTÉ's the
all and read the results into the all variable I declared online.
Twenty eight.
That's pretty simple.
OK, now I don't need to specify the fields that I want everything that's matched using those DB colon
tags back in the user struct that's all handled by Upor, which is remarkably convenient.
So if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll return nil and the error.
Otherwise, I'll say return all.
And no, and that's all that I have to do.
So for people that like working with our MS, this is remarkably user friendly.
OK, now we can do a get all function.
We can also do things like, well, what else?
What are the other things you need to do quite regularly with users?
Well, maybe you need to look them up by email.
So let's create a function that does that.
Thank you, user.
So it's tied to the user model.
Get by, you know, and we're going to take one value here, which is email of type string, and we're
going to return potentially a pointer to a user if we can find it and potentially an error if we can't
or if something goes wrong.
So once again, how do we make this work?
Pretty much the same as we did in the last one, we'll say for the user, which is a place to store
the user.
It's a type user.
So there's there's a we're going to store our data and we get a collection.
A collection is assigned the value of our collection and we're again going to use that table to get
the correct cabling.
Then we get a result and we say on our collection, call find and we're going to specify our condition.
And here's the first time we've used in our poor condition.
But it's really simple.
We just set up dot com and then in curly brackets, we want email equals and a comma or a colon.
And then, you know, the parameter was passed to this function.
So we're going to find all records in the database where email is equal to the email supplied to this
function.
OK.
And now I'm only expecting to find one user by email because that's the way we typically store things
in user tables.
So we'll say error is assign the value of from the results.
Give me one only one and read into the user the variable I declared right up on line 40.
OK.
And we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, return nil in the error.
Otherwise we can do something as simple as return, ampersand the user and know.
And that gives me a pointer to user and new error.
Now the only thing missing here, of course, is that there are situations where you actually want to
get the user by email and get any tokens that are associated with that user.
We can prove that we can just put some more Upper Darby logic right here.
So we'll declare a variable ver token of type token, which we define just a few minutes ago.
And now we'll make a collection this time.
Try that in the next line collection.
Now it's equal to so I'm overwriting the value of collection with Upper Dot Collection, and I'm going
to call a variable or a function that I may not have written yet.
So it'll be a token dot table like that.
Apparently, I didn't write it.
So let's go write that right now.
I'll just copy this from user doggo and go over to token Darko pasted in there and make this point to
say teh token.
Make it return tokens, because that's what it's called in the database.
And I want to go back to user.
This is all taken care of.
So I have now got my collection, so I'll say result is equal to.
I don't need the assignment as I already have a variable rez is equal to on my collection, which now
points to the tokens table.
I want to find with the condition abscond in curly brackets.
User underscore ID, which has to be in quotes.
User underscore ID.
And you don't need to put the equals sign, it's assumed, but I'd like to make it readable, so I'll
put that there.
Then column the user ID.
And because it's a token, I want to make sure the token hasn't expired.
So we'll say expiry is less than.
Then column time.
Now.
Now, I might potentially get more than one token back, so I'll just make sure I get the most recent
one order by created at descending.
And that should give me the most recent token, if any.
OK, so air is now equal to resort one.
And I'm going to read that into token and I'll check for an error and I'll just copy and paste this
and modify it as necessary.
OK?
Because we do need to modify this because the error might be, you know, I can't find the token for
this user, but you've already found a valid user.
So in this case will change it.
A little bit will make it a little bit more useful because I don't want a return error if I've actually
found the user, but that user happens to have no tokens.
So instead, I'll say if error is not equal to here from the upper package error new record.
And the air is not equal to again from the upper package or no more rows in that situation.
I want to return Neal and error because if the air is no, there's no record matching or there's no
more rows of matching.
But I do have a valid user.
I want to return that valid user.
So I put my error check and then I put a more detailed error check.
OK.
And assuming I actually get that, I can just say the user token is equal to token.
And if I didn't find a token, it's an empty token verb declared right here.
It has the default values, nothing in it.
But if I did find the token, then it's a valid token and our return that.
Now these are only two of the various functions we're going to have associated with our user table.
But this lecture is getting pretty long, so I'll end it here and we'll pick it up in the next one.
Hopefully, you can see that for people that like working with our MS.
This becomes remarkably useful and very easy to work with and actually has a lot more functionality
that will be exploring in the coming lectures.