So let's keep working on the user model.
And this is inside the data directory in my app, and as I said before, this is not code.
We're going to ask the end user to write this is code that will automatically be added to a project
when we run a command line utility, which we haven't started yet.
And type something like celebrities make off and that will generate all of the appropriate database
tables and the models for authentication.
But before we go too much further, I did have a mistake last time around, as I sometimes do, and
it's inside that token.
Don't go far and it's right here the expires.
This in the database is not called expired expires.
It's called expiring.
And that's something that I often do is I spend way too much time agonizing over what variables and
database fields should be called.
And apparently, at some point in the past, I thought it should be called expires, but ultimately
went back to expiry anyway.
That takes care of that.
Now let's go back to user Dongo, and let's look at that.
Get all function right here on Line twenty five in User ID and go in my code.
Well, this actually has a condition, a parameter it accepts.
But the name of this method or this function get all implies there is no condition.
I want to get all users.
So let's fix that.
We'll just get rid of this.
And I had that in there just so we could see how conditions work, but we'll be working with those a
lot as time goes on.
So all we have to do is delete that parameter and delete this.
And we also maybe we should order them by last name.
So I'll say order by and I just order by the following last name.
OK.
So that takes care of that.
So we have get all which returns all users.
We have to get by email, which returns a user by email and includes a token, if any.
What other kinds of functions do we want?
Well, maybe we want to be able to get a user by ID.
That's something you're going to do a lot.
So let's add a new function.
Func and again, it's tied to the receiver point to user, and we'll just call this one get and it will
take one parameter ID, which is an integer, and it will return potentially a pointer to a user and
possibly an error.
And again, this is really straightforward.
So we declare the variable that we're going to read the results into and I'll call it the user like
I did before and it's a type user.
Then we create our collection and that's a sign of the value of Upper Dot collection, and we get the
table name from Udeid Table.
Then we get a result, which I'll call Rez.
And that's a sign the value of from the collection variable.
We just got Dot find and we specify or condition abscond and in curly brackets, Heidi.
And that should be equal to it.
And as I said before, you can if you want to put the equal sign in there, but if you leave out any
comparison operator equals is assumed.
OK.
And then we read the result in the variable.
So we'll say error is assign the value of reds and I'm only expecting to find one.
So we'll use the one function and I'm going to read it into the user.
And if there's an error, if error is not equal to nil, then I'll return nil and the error.
But assuming we got that far.
What do we want to do next?
We'll get the token and we'll check for expired tokens, and that's pretty much exactly the same logic
we have up here.
So a copy that and paste it down here.
And all I have to do is return a reference to the user because we're returning a pointer and no.
And that takes care of it.
So now we can get a user by email, we can get a user by ID.
And of course, there's other things we want to do here.
We also want to be able to update users.
So let's create a new function.
I'll give ourselves some room here.
Thank you.
User pointed to user, That's our receiver.
We'll just call this one update and we're going to update in this case, the user and we'll pass the
entire model user and we'll return an error, possibly.
So this is really, really simple.
And one of the nice features of using something like upper, even though I prefer to do a sequel, is
that it's much less code so I can write the user dot updated at because we want to make sure that's
updated to the current timestamp time.
OK, now one line, then we get our collection that's assigned the value of or down collection.
And again, we call you Dot Table that gets her collection.
We get a results that result is equal to.
Collection, not find try that again.
Collection find, and we're going to find by these Friday, the user.
Got it.
You're updating existing users, so there's already an either.
We'll check for an error and say resource update.
And we're going to update you using the user a reference to the the user, which we actually received
as a call to this function.
And we check for there if error is not equal to nil return error, otherwise return nil.
So that is what one two three four five six seven eight nine ten lines of code, including the actual
function signature.
And we update a user record with that little bit of code.
So that's pretty straightforward.
So now we can find all the users, we can get a user by email, we can get a user by ID, we can update
a user.
What else do we need to do?
Well, we also need to delete users.
So thank you pointer to user, and we'll just call this one delete and we'll delete.
Saved by ID ident and we'll return an error.
Potentially exactly the same logic collection is assigned the value of upper collection, and we call
you a table that gives us our collection.
Rez is assigned the value of collection.
Got fined and we're going to find by ID and I will delete it.
Error is a the value of resort delete with no parameters and we check for an error.
So I was copy and paste this code pasted here and now we can delete users priority.
So what else do we need to do?
Well, we also need to be able to insert users.
So let's say thank you pointer to user and we'll call it insert.
And it will take one parameter the user of type user, and it will return an integer, which is the
ID of the newly inserted record and potentially an error if something goes wrong.
Same logic as before, except that we have a password field for users, so we actually need to generate
a hash from a password.
Unfortunately, Go makes that remarkably easy.
So we'll say I'll call the hashed password or the hash of the password hash because we're going to create
a new hash and potentially an error.
And those are populated by calling from the standard library Decrypt
Dot generate from a password.
And that requires two parameters.
The first one is a slice of bytes, so a slice of byte.
We're going to cast the value of whatever the password is.
The user password and how expensive do we want to make this operation?
Twelve is a really good number for that sort of thing.
We'll check for error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll return, say, zero for the ID because the insert didn't take place and the error.
Now, for some reason, it did not import B for me, so I can fix that up here and import B script and
that is from.
Golang dot org slash x slash crypto slash decrypt.
Not to make this all work, just say go on vendor that should go and get that package for me acting.
OK.
That's one of the irritating things about using Go Mod vendor, but it's not that difficult.
So let's go back down here, and I think I said that the crypto is part of the standard library.
It's not.
It's part of the well, you can see right from the URL that we imported Googling dot or slash x.
So it's part of GO, but it's not actually included in the standard library.
But anyway, anyway, it's made by the go authors.
So I'm OK with it.
So now we have our new hash.
Now let's make sure that.
They created and updated values are set to time Dot now because we're inserting a new user, so we'll
just make sure they use are not created as equals time dot now and the user updated is equal to time
dot now.
Now they may have been set by the end user, but I never assume anything.
And we also need to populate the password with the new hash.
So the user password and that's needs to be in the form of a string and what we get back from generate
from password is actually a slice of bytes.
So we'll just say string new hash.
OK, now it's as simple as calling getting a collection.
So collection was assigned the value of the upper dot collection from you to the table or UK table.
And we say Red's an error and we call on the collection variable, the method insert, and we're going
to insert the user and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return zero and the error.
Now we want the first return parameter from the insert function that we're the one we're working on
right now to actually be an integer.
And of course, the problem is that different databases return that sort of thing in a different format.
So I can't just say return resort I.D., which is a function available to us.
Instead, I need to convert that to an ant because this function might be called using Postgres or MariaDB
or MongoDB or any of the databases that are supported by the Upper Dev package.
So what I'm going to do is go back over to the models start go, which will be added automatically,
just like the user package.
I'm going to add a function here and I'll call it get insert ID and it will take one parameter, which
is an AI, and it will be a type that we get from the DB two package, which is actually as you can
see it in the import statement, GitHub dot com slash upper slash DB slash v4.
So I'm going to make this type DB two dart ID and it's going to always return in int.
OK.
So we'll declare a variable aid type is a sign, the value of what you need to get the ID type from
the variable I that's passed to this.
And that's you go.
That's really easy.
You just called the format package and you look for a printout and you put it in a format string and
it's nothing more than a percent uppercase T.
We substitute the I for that percent percent uppercase T, and that will give us the type.
Now we just say if I type is equal to in sixty four, and that's what Postgres returns as the inserted
ID.
Then we'll return int I cast two in 64.
And if it's not of typing in 64, and that's all I care about in this course because we're just supporting
my skill and post-cruise, then we just return on cast to an end.
OK, so now we have this function available to any of the models inside of the data package.
So back in user doggo, all I have to do now is, say, declare a variable ID and that will be the in
the ID of the record we just inserted and we called yet insert ID and we handed resort ID, which is
the function built right into our results.
Set our res variable.
OK, so now it's in the format I needed to be so I can say return ID and no.
And there's our insert function now.
There's no validation on this yet, and don't worry about that.
We'll also be adding validation to every model that's included in this package in this celebrity's package.
But for right now, let's just get it working.
So we have our insert.
Now what other things and these are things specific to the user model?
What other things are we possibly going to have to do?
Well, we need to add users.
We can do that and update them.
We can do that and delete them.
We can do that and get a list of all the users or get a user by email or by ID.
But users also very frequently have to reset their password.
So let's read a function for that.
Thank you.
Point your to user and we'll just call this reset password and it will take an ID, which is the user
ID, and it will take the new password, which will be a string and will return, potentially here.
And again, this is really, really simple.
So we do need to generate a new hash for the password, whatever they're changing a password to, and
that's pretty much the same as what we did right at the insert function, new hash in error or assign
the value of from the Decrypt package.
And we're going to say generate from password.
And again, we need a slice of bytes.
So we'll cast password to a slice of bytes and we'll use the 12 as a how complex to make this this hash,
if error is not equal to nil and we'll just return the error.
And now we just update the user's password.
And that's as simple as calling the user and potentially an error.
We're going to populate the user with the user record from the database and we'll just call you don't
get which we've already written, so we can call that a at the.
And again, if there's an error or turn the error.
So let me copy this and paste it here.
So now let's take you which is the receiver for this function and say the use password is equal to string
new hash.
And now updating the user as simple as saying air is equal to the user DAAD update with a pointer to
you and we'll check for an error, so we'll just copy this code
and paste it right here.
Get rid of that blank line.
And if we get past that, we return now.
OK, this lecture is beginning to get a bit long, and we've not tested any of this code yet.
But don't worry about that.
There's undoubtedly an error or two in there somewhere, but it's pretty close.
So we'll end this lecture here and we'll pick it up in the next one, and we'll do things like making
sure that a user's password matches whatever they type in and the last of the functions we need for
most use cases when you're doing database operations for a user.