So let's finish up the functionality for our user model, and there's really only one more method to
write, and we still have to do validation, but we'll get to that before too long.
So I'm looking at user doggo in the data directory of my app, and I'm going to add one more function
here at the very end.
And this is the one where we can check to see if a password matches.
So of course, this function will be called when someone is authenticating using a form on a web page
or authenticating using the API or something like that.
So, all right, a new function again with the receiver of you pointer to a user and I'll just call
this password matches and it will take one parameter a plain text password, which is a string, and
it returns a bool, potentially an error.
So this is really straightforward.
We'll check for an error when we call from the beach package.
We're going to call compare hash and password, and that requires two parameters the hashed password,
which is remarkably hard to say and the password both are slices of bytes.
So no problem will compare casting it to a slice of bytes.
You don't password the one that we have in the database against a slice of bytes
plaintext.
And we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we're going to do a switch statement here because there's a couple of things we need to take into
account.
Switch.
And we're going to switch on case errors.
Dot is and if it is, we're looking for the error and the error happens to be from the B Package B Crip.
ERA mismatched hash and password right there.
OK, so if that's the error that we want to do something and we don't need those curly brackets, I
do that all the time.
It's a code.
So in this case will return false and no, OK.
And if that's not the case, then we'll just catch everything with default and the default is return
false and the error.
So the first case, everything worked, but the password doesn't match in the second case, something
else went wrong.
But if we get past all of those and we return true with no error and that's all we really need to do.
So it's a very simple function.
And the next step, of course, is to actually try some of these out and make sure that they work and
we'll get started on that in the next lecture.