So now that we have this user model, let's take advantage of it.
And there's a couple of things we have to do before we can actually do anything, but they're not that
difficult.
So to start with, I want to go over to my models, don't go file.
And again, I'm still in the my app package.
And in here we have this type models with a comment.
Any models inserted here and in the new function are easily accessible throughout the entire application.
Well, let's put some in here, so I'll put in a field called users of type user and I'll put in another
one called tokens of type token and down here, where I return models in the new function.
I'll just add those.
So I'll say users is now equal to user.
What's that?
The new user and tokens is equal to token like that?
OK, now of course, I have to use this.
So let's go back to our main Don file and here in type application, I'm going to add a new field to
the application.
Well, that is not surprisingly going to be called models, and it's a type data dot models.
OK.
So I've added that now in the in it application function.
I can come down here and just before I return the app, all I have to do is say App Dot models is equal
to data dot new.
I'm calling that new function now and I'll hand it my database pool, which I have in App Dot, app,
dot TV pool and then initializes my models.
So that means I now have access to the user type and all of its associated functions anywhere I need
to have them.
So let's go back and try this out and we'll try it really quickly in the roots file.
So we're going to put a new test route right here, so I'll have it as a get request data app.
Don't routes render routes?
Don't, and I'll call this one create dash and user, and I'll inline the function.
Func Whv Response Sportswriter are as a pointer to a checkpoint request, and in there the first thing
I'll do is I'll create a variable you, which will be of type data dot user.
I'll just populate some information in there.
So I need first name and I'll make that my name and I need a last name, so I'll duplicate this.
Try that again.
Last name solver
and I need an email, so I'll say email me at here dot com and I need it to be active or not.
So I'll make it one to make this an active user and a password, and I'll just make that password.
OK.
So now that I've declared that I can actually do things like this, it will be the newly inserted ID
when we insert this into the database and check for an error.
And now it's as simple as calling a dot models, dot user users dot insert and I insert you.
And that should, in theory, insert it now.
If it doesn't, let's make sure we find out why.
If error is not equal to nil, so we might have mistakes in that code, we'll say any Dot app dot error
log print line the error and we'll just return.
So we'll get a blank screen, which is fine.
But if it worked, I should be able to call format dot f print separate f.
My format string will lead my W first.
My response writer and my format string will be percent de colon percent us and in there I'll put.
And I'll put in as well.
Say You dot first name.
OK, so that should print out the ID in my database and then my first name.
Trevor, in my case.
OK.
So before we do that, of course, we need to make sure that our database is running.
So in case it's not, I'll say Docker compose.
And that should start everything up for me and I could use my make file.
But this works as well, and I don't want it to run in the background because I don't want to try anything
until I know that it's actually running the database.
That is.
So that looks good, seems to be starting now, so I'll go to my database client postcode and I will
connect to Celebrity Stalker.
And it should connect and it did.
And if I look in the user's table, that should be empty and it is now open a new terminal window.
And I'll type may start to get my application going.
And we have an undefined format error.
Where is that?
All right, here, we didn't get an import for the format statement.
That's no big deal.
We'll just go import format FMD.
I do that all the time.
So now we'll try clearing the screen, make start.
OK.
So it started, so let's go to our web browser.
First of all, as make sure everything is still working by going to localhost four thousand.
And there it is.
Let's go to local who's 4000 slash create dash user and see if we got it right.
One and Trevor, let me go back to my database and look in the table user's table, so that would be
under post to go refresh.
And there it is.
I have successfully inserted a user, all right, in the next lecture, we'll get started testing all
of the functionality we've just added just to make sure it all works.