So let's try working on some additional test routes just to make sure that things work the way that
we expect in the user model.
So we already have one here that allows us to create a user.
And of course, we can do one to get a user and update a user.
Now updating a user and that sort of thing, it would be really convenient if I could generate a random
string.
And we can put that functionality right in my app.
But that's the sort of thing you need to do a lot when you're working on a web applications.
So let's go back to the celebrity's package.
And right here in helpers, don't go.
I'm going to add something at the very top.
I've already copied this to my clipboard because there's no point in you watching me type this.
It's very simple.
It's just a constant called random string, and it consists of all of the lowercase letters in the alphabet,
all of the uppercase characters in the alphabet.
And then an underscore and a plus sign.
And that's just something that I'm going to use to generate a random string.
Now down here, I'll put it right after the constant.
It doesn't matter where it goes or create a new function with the receiver of C pointer to celebrities,
so it'll be available in my My App package.
And I would call this random string, and it will take one parameter.
Which is in an integer.
How long should it be?
And it's just a number and it returns a string.
And this is dead simple.
I'll create two variables as an hour.
Doesn't matter what they're called, and I will make a slice of room and end and then comma a slice
of room random string.
So I'm just creating two slices of rooms, one that is of the length end and the other one that has
a random string as its entries.
OK.
And after that, I will say for I is assigned the value of range through s and here I'll just say P
comma and I'll ignore the second return value is equal to from the rand package.
Dot.
And we're getting it from crypto rand.
And I want Prime.
That's the one right there.
And I'll say random reader length her.
And then X and Y are assigned the value of from the P variable I just created from the Rand package,
you sixty four.
And you isn't 64.
Lynn, her.
I put you in it unit that should be you it.
And that again, that looks better.
And then finally, S.R. the index of the slice as is equal to error and I get.
X percent.
Wow!
Simple math.
OK.
And once that's done, I return this as a string and that allows me to get a random string.
So let's give this a comment
generates a random string of length n from values in the contest.
Random string.
OK, so that's dead simple, and that will be available to us when I go back here and open my terminal
and type goal mind bender.
So I'm back in my app now, so that's available to us and that will be really convenient when we go
through the test routes we want to do here.
So now that we have that out of the way, let's try some additional test routes.
So let's try one that says, Get all users.
So I'll create another route a dot app, dot roots, dot and get and I'll call this one slash get dash
pole dash users.
And again, I'll inline the function.
So func w dot response rider or pointer to issue repeat our request.
And here pretty straightforward.
I will say users and potentially an error are assigned values from a models dot user.
Users get Oh, and I'll check for an error and I'll just copy this code right here to save some time.
And if that works, I can say for I don't care about the index, but I do care about the individual
entry, which I'll call X and I'll just range through users and I'll say format dot, print f.
W.
And just the last name, X.Org, last name, and I should work.
And it's not protests.
It's f print.
That's better half print.
That's better.
OK.
So I should be able now to open my terminal and say, make restart.
We'll be using that random function in a bit.
There it is.
Let's go back to our Web browser, and let's change this to get all users and get all the users.
And there it is, printed out the last name of the one user in the database so that one seems to work.
Let's keep going.
So we'll hide the terminal, give ourselves some room and let's create another function.
Another route with an inline function.
Eight app routes don't get.
And this time I'll make it get a user by ID slash and get dash user slash, and then we'll use cheese
placeholder like that.
And that will again be an inline function.
Func W.H added up sportswriter and our pointer to HTP Dot request.
And here I want to get a user by ID, so I'll take advantage of the function that's available to us
from chy and convert to an end.
I need the ID to be at it.
And in this case, I'll ignore the error because this is a test route there.
Assign the value of from the Sturt Collins package.
We want a try and we want to get cheeky URL perram and we're looking from the request.
We're looking for it and that gives me the ID that's in the URL.
And now I'll get a user ID you.
And this time I'll ignore the error.
I'm hoping it's going to work properly, and if it doesn't, I'll go put the error.
Check back in with our eight models.
Users don't get and we hand it ID.
And if this worked, I should be able to say something as simple as format dot f f and give it a format
string.
And I'll go with, say, percent as an percent s and percent s has to w as its first parameter, the
response writer and replace those with you'd first name your last name.
And maybe the email address error you don't email.
And I should be able to restart my application.
Make restart.
And I only have one user in the database and it's ID one, so I should be able to go to get Dash user
slash one.
Let's try that.
Slash yet, dash user slash one, the only entry in the database.
And of course, it didn't work.
Get Dash user slash ID, get dash user slash ID, and this is why you don't skip error checking.
So let's try this.
Error, and we'll put out the error to the look.
Sometimes I'm an optimist.
It never pays off.
Let's make restart.
You see, there's an error 500 there, but I don't know what it is.
There it goes.
Let's give ourselves some blank lines and reload this page and go see what the error actually is.
Column expiry does not exist.
Seriously, let's go find out what it's actually called.
So back to the database.
And go to users now, go to tokens.
I have expiry.
So where did I get that wrong?
Column expiry?
Does not exist.
Rootstock go 55.
So I'm 55 as users get.
So let's find out what we have wrong there.
Obviously, there's something wrong here.
We have the user.
So this part seems to work.
And it's down here.
So Rez is collection dot find and we want to conduct table, and that returns.
Maybe it's the name of the table.
That's wrong.
Yeah.
That's better.
So that was a stupid mistake.
Make restart.
I'm sure you noticed that when I put the table function on the tokens file, but hopefully at least
one of you did not because I don't want to be the only person that made a stupid mistake like that.
And let's go back here and reload this.
And there it is.
Trevor Solr me out here talking.
That's much better.
OK, so we have that function working.
Let's go back to our roots and do one more before we move on roots.
Now, let's try updating a user.
Here's where we can use that random string function, we just wrote.
So we'll add a third or another test route.
Eight app routes does not render routes don't get.
And this time I'll make it slash update dash user.
And then again, I'll put the ID right in the URL, so I know which user to update again, an inline
function HP the response writer and ah, as a pointer to opt out request.
And here we'll say once again we need the idea of the user so I can grab that from the previous one
right here just to save some time.
Paste that in there.
Now we'll get that user so you an error or assign the value of a dart models, but users don't get it.
And we'll check for the error this time because it didn't work out so well last time.
It rarely does.
So if we get past that, I have the user, so let's change the last name to you, last name equals and
I hear a call by a random string aide or app dot random string and we'll make it, say, 10 characters
long.
OK, so that gives me a random last name.
And now we'll update it.
Error is equal to you, dot update.
And we just hand it.
A pointer to you, and we'll check for an error, which I should still have on my clipboard, and I
will print out the updated last name.
Format test print.
F. Updated last name to present us and it would be your last name and we need to put the W before that,
which seems to be an error.
A new error that I make all the time.
OK, let's restart this.
Make restart.
And this time will refresh the Web browser to make sure it works once we change this to update user.
Analysis will look in the database and make sure it actually changed it to one plus Elle and the rest
of those characters.
So over here, users refresh.
And it did.
So that works well.
Perfect.
OK, so clearly these seem to be working as expected.
Now what I want to do next is we want to be able to show off our functionality is when we go to this
page.
Localhost four thousand.
I want to add a things to try here that allows me to add a user, update user and delete user, and
we'll get started on that sort of thing in the next lecture.