Hello and welcome to Golang programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about complex numbers and indecision.
We want to talk about the others data types concept.
Billions, the Boolean data type represents only one bit of information, either true or false, and
is defined as bold when declaring it as a data.
The values of type Boolean are not converted implicitly or explicitly to any other type.
Default value for bold is false.
Now let's go to your school program and illustrate how to use off billions.
First, we'd be fine tuning variables by issue time and assign values to them.
So the right is TR one column equals and initialize it by the Value Gold program.
Go to the next line and define another variable light as the are to call, and he calls and initialize
it by all characters uppercase go through pro range.
OK.
Go to the next line and define another variable like is TR tree calling equals and initialize it by
value.
Lite value of SDR won't go through your own.
OK, now you want to compare the values of the two variables SDR one and SDR two, and put the result
of their value equal or unequal inside the result one variable.
So go to the next line and define another variable like resolved.
One call in equals SDR one equal equal SDR to.
If the values of these two variables are equal to each other, the value of truth is assigned to the
result one variable.
Otherwise, the value of funds is assigned to it.
We also do this competition for the two variables SDR one and SDR three, and put the value in result
to variable.
So go to the next line and define another variable like resolved two column equals SDR one equal equal
to SDR treat.
Now display the values of result variables sold, right, FP.
Resolved, one caller resolved one.
Go to the next line, F.B..
Resolved to call and resolve to and go to the next line and display type of these variables.
So be right if Earth time are resolved.
One caller person, Theodorakis, resolved one and set it back his classroom and if tie all resolved
blue collar person, he and said, resolved to.
OK.
Reformat the court, save the project and execute the program.
Now run the comment, go round the back.
Is this mean that go?
Now we can see the output resolved, one is false and result, too is true and type of result one in
result two is bold.
OK, we could define Boolean variable and initialize them in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.