Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about brilliance.
And in this session, we want to talk about the other data types concept.
Strings in go language strings can be seen as a collection of characters, we can be of length one one
character.
But it's usually longer as string is always written in double quotes.
Now you can see the syntax.
So this string data type represents a sequence of Unicode code points or in other words, we can say
string is a sequence of immutable bytes means Vanessa String is created.
You cannot change.
That is string is string may contain arbitrary data, including bytes with zero value in the human Griddy.
But for now, let's go to the school program to illustrate how to use this string.
First, define a variable, which is those strings used from short declaration.
So the right SDR column equals and initialize it by GO.
True crime means.
Thank.
And go to the next line.
In this case, you want to display the value of SDR, so you're right, if the value of this TR color
percent is lowered case because the type of stories assuming we use from percent as lowercase as formatted
string and we said SDR.
Go to the next line and display type of the variable.
So be right if if the tongue is still on.
Column per cent t upper case, and we said, OK, here we want to display the length of the string.
So use from limb function, the limb function gets the string as argument and returns the length of
the string as integer.
So go to the next line and write as if.
The land all is the Colin Person D, because return type of limb function is integers, so we use from
person to ask for more testing and calling lend function and sit is serious argument to it.
Put it back as less and end of each line for go to a new line,
reformat the code, save the project and execute the program by running the common goal.
The does this mean that go now we can see the output.
The value of SDR is go programming language.
The type of SDR is history and the length of history is 23 due to the importance of history.
This topic will be fully explored in future chapters.
OK, we have reached the end of this session.
I hope you take full advantage of this session onto next session.
Goodbye.