Hello and welcome to go programming language.
I am happy Tourism Resume Year is director of these training course with more than 20 years of programming
experience in C, C++, C Sharp Dot Net, Java as free Python Goal and Flutter and other programming
languages in this course.
I have tried to fully teach the concepts of girl programming language from basic to advanced, so every
individual at any level of programming could start this course and it completely.
Even if you have no knowledge of programming and want to get acquainted with the programming language
for the first time, do not worry, because this course is designed in such a way that you can learn
programming concepts from basic to advanced and easily learn the course.
This course begins with simple concepts such as installing go land on the operating system, defining
variables, data types and operators, and will go on with the intermediate concepts like collection
pointers, concurrency files and directories, and will be concluded with advanced concepts including
database GWR in Political Boffa, G.R., PC, Rest API and web socket.
Nowadays, several points have to be considered important when using a programming language, some of
which will be a stated first connection between programming, language and database.
For this purpose, in this course, we have completed the database training and examine its concepts
from the beginning.
For example, a programmer needs E r diagram knowledge to connect his program to a database in order
to be able to design and display his database according to his needs in the applications.
In this course, we will explain to you how to design a database and with what symbols its components
are displayed so that any other program that can see and implement the E.R. diagram.
In addition, implementing a database is done in such a way that the program that has the possibility
to use DUR database wherever they want.
In this way, the database is made as dynamic, which does not depend on any a specific class or restaurant,
and is a step.
You first get acquainted with the database commands and do examples in the next step.
You do the goal in connection with the database and implement the project in this field.
Then, in the advanced steps, you can use the GAWIN framework, which is a popular framework in the
go language to connect the go to the database.
In this tutorial, devel known MySQL database is explained and used it in the projects, but you will
also be able to use other databases.
Second, relationship between the programming language and other programming languages or different
services.
In other words, the programming language must be able to communicate with the outside world.
Nowadays, various technologies such as Protocol, G.R., PC and RESTful are used to carry this important
job.
I will explain and implement these three technologies in details through different projects, and we
use a combination of different technologies such as database JSON, restful GI PC protocol buffer in
the project separately.
For example, I will communicate with the server food and blister edit or delete data in the database
or fetch them by learning these technologies.
You will be able to implement various types of programs on the web and connect to other services or
applications without having knowledge of the programming, language and exchange data with them.
Third, concurrency topic as processors became more powerful, endure processing capacity increased.
Programmers thought they could use the increase in prices, of course, to increase the speed and performance
of their applications and to perform many of the operations of the program in parallel.
One of the teams that every programmer pays attention, any programming language is the topic of concurrency
in order to properly manage the execution of the program.
In parallel, concurrency is one of the most important things in learning go language, which makes
the program created with the language very powerful and fast.
In this course, we will talk about this topic in full detail and give various examples for that subject.
Let's Typekit can be considered a bigger step in improving the performance of web applications that
require.
And real time data exchange, and even today they are showing up in many multi-user online games and
chat applications.
That's like it is a protocol for establishing a two way fast connection between client and server.
The purpose of introducing this protocol is to minimize the delays caused by your request response communication
HTP, contrary to the methods introduced earlier.
That's Typekit is a protocol based on TCP and different from Stibbe, which allows a permanent two way
communication between the client and the server, only to a single port in this tutorial.
I will fully explain the vets socket and implement the chat project in different lines.
I will also create a web layer in which a chat project will have the ability to ask and receive messages
from the browser in addition to different clients.
In the end, by finishing this training course, you will become a goal and developer and will be able
to implement various programs and projects with goal language such as networking, distributed fonctionne
service APIs, that service rep applications and their communications with clients.
Minimal frameworks for web applications and alike in the best possible way.
For all the lessons of this course, slides have been prepared, aligned with pictures, tables and
diagrams, which you will see during the training so that the important and key concepts are fully explained.
Also, examples have been presented for all the lessons of this training course, which could be easily
accessed.
The best connection between us is the Q&amp;A section.
You can ask your questions there and get the right answers.
Please ask any questions in the related section so that I can give you the right answer as soon as possible.
I hope you finish this training course successfully and enjoy programming with Go Like Goodbye.