Hello and welcome to the Go Line programming language course.
And introduction to Go Lanc Go is an Open-Source programming language.
It's a statically typed and produces compiled mixing code binaries.
Developers say that Google's goal language is the sea for a 21st century when it comes to syntax.
This meal programming language includes tooling that allows you to safely use memory, manage optics,
collect garbage and provide aesthetic typing along with concurrency.
Best features of GO programming language compiled.
Garbage collected, designed for multiple processors and easy to read quotes.
The main goal of creating GO was to combine the best features of other programming languages, such
as ease of use with state of the art productivity, high level efficiency, along with the static typing
and advanced performance for networking and the full use of multicore power.
You might want to know why gore is rising.
The reason is that Go has the same performance as C and is much easier to maintain that your wall as
we need no virtual machine, no warning or period and no jar, hell and so on.
Let's have a look at the other Gauland advantages that spanned less time and money to develop an app.
You don't need a huge take a stack if you are using go for your project, ask, create and then go language,
actually compile to native machine code and don't need any interpreter or virtual machine.
These are some means that GO apps will work faster and won't require the warming up, we have just mentioned
use go for a range of apps.
Go is a really flexible language able to solve a lot of problems.
You can use it for system and network programming, big data, machine learning, audio and video editing
and more.
Get more performance at a wider audience for your app similarly to C or C++.
Go is a compiled language and doesn't require any interpretation.
Correspondingly, the absence of an interpreter frees up power and gives a go build app way more performance,
which will surely be appreciated by users.
Moreover, God knows how to properly manage allocated memory.
More good news is that a Google based application is less demanding in terms of system requirements.
This is good for users with all their devices as they will get to enjoy your app too.
And with more people using your application, you will be getting more money.
Worry less about the app crashing, though, was created to use the full potential of multiple course.
Moreover, the language can properly use all the processor resources, so it's perfect for running an
app in the background as a single process.
This is possible thanks to go routines which are used instead of threats and require much less ram due
to their known system threat nature.
This is why the risk of a Go app crashing due to lack of memory is lower.
Is it a fine go developers for your project going is blowing up?
If you look at the 2018 developers survey by the Stack Overflow, you will see that go is one, the
top five most loved and most wanted languages.
More and more professionals are diving into the world of Go, according to recent research.
You can only define over one million six hundred and thirty three thousand GO developers on the market
in 2018, which is a 60 percent increase compared to 2017, according to the Google survey.
More and more contributors to go are coming from the go community.
This also means that there are more and more people becoming go professionals.
Developers can easily sample GO apps.
There is a serious advantage for those who aren't ready to hire a go expert for support and maintenance.
Go Court has clear and neat syntax and requires little effort to learn.
So developers, you already what we can learn all they need to within just a couple of days.
This will allow your developers to support your existing app.
What are the advantages of using go for your project?
Why is good language popular?
Besides the cute mascot, Go brings a whole set of advantages.
The language began rising almost as soon as it was released back in 2009.
It quickly a start, drifting from the number 65 language toward the top positions around the world.
Then Business Insider called gold.
The hottest programming language of 2016, according to the Thiel Index.
Goes rating went way up and a bit down in 2017.
But in 2018, it has continuously gone up, as shown in the graph below.
Rank.
These diagrams summarize the result of our December 2018 user survey, along with our commentary and
insights.
We are grateful to everyone who provided their feedback to the survey to help shape the future of go
like we asked about people's expertise and preference among programming languages.
Go ranked highest amount respondents first choices in both expertise and preference.
Expertise well, in this chart, based on statistics, we actually showed a ranking of programming languages
based on your expertise.
As you can see, go language is about 90 percent, Python 56 percent and Java 42 percent.
And finally, C++ 24 until five-person your specialty go languages is still top of the expert line diagram.
Preferences and the other diagram based on this statistic that show that the preferences of programming
languages, as you can see go language is about nine to three percent, Python fifty three percent and
Rust 90 percent and finally C++ 18 and B 11 percent GO is clearly attracting many programmers from dynamic
languages.
What projects can you use go for gore will definitely do the trick if you are planning to develop down
the line services for your application.
More than that, gore is good for scalable, high performance apps.
We list some apps and services that are enjoying the benefits of Google Cloud services as the creator
of Google.
Google is using the language to provide cloud infrastructure.
It offers top performance and its capability to the Google Cloud platform.
But there are even more well-known cloud businesses out there are using Google for the same reason,
such as Dropbox Turf for Kubernetes and Dutcher media platforms.
YouTube, SoundCloud and Netflix choose Go to fight with high loads on their sites, SoundCloud uses
this language for deploying some internal services within their complex projects on demand services.
The toxic giant over was looking to improve map processing speeds as people loaded geo fence look ups,
sending literally thousands of queries per second.
Go ahead!
Uber significantly reduce the timing of providing services to users, which was much appreciated by
users.
Aside from the services and products, Google provides key tooling for mobile app development.
This is why we will soon see even more examples of going mobile applications and propelling some other
industries as well.
Also, Go is still a relatively young programming language.
It has gained popularity among real business masters like Google, Netflix or Uber and others who use
Go to scale their products innovative high performance goals, quickly changing for a base, providing
more and more tools for mobile and web development.
And remarkably, decreasing the time and cost of app development and software news outlets.
Back in 2012, BBC started using goal language for backend development and some of the elements of their
internal analytics services.
Go Lang designers.
Google was produced in 2007 and launched in 2009 and introduced to the public.
Robert Creamer dropped Pike and Ken Thompson are Google's top three go programming language designers.
The trial started with the goal of creating a language similar to the C programming language that is
a part of a fool, as it is which eventually launched into the modern programming language, object
oriented pointer, his methods and etc..
And as a result, were able to launch a high performance, fast and efficient language to market and
introduce to the public.
Competition between five language by according benchmarks, well, a competition has been made between
the top five programming languages by benchmarks based on hardware and software amount, which the go
language is still at the top of the other languages in the table and occupies about 80 percent C-sharp.
Also 79 percent, not jazz, 74 percent Java 17 and Python six to eight percent.
And in hardware and software items such as memory, CPU, serialization, error handling and ET all
have been compared in escort.
The best ideas for Golang development, according to statistics conducted by Golang programming, was
the percentage of programming environments used for these language.
Ease is statistically expressed in this chart.
We can see the uses of each of the integrated development environments, so we see go land.
Top of the others by Terry five percent inverse code.
About twenty two percent and see the others.
And in the end, I hope you can communicate well with the go language and method is powerful and efficient
language and enjoy the word of the go programming language.