Hello and welcome to the Golden Age programming language course in the previous session.
We talked about arena space industry, and in this session, we want to talk about the other strengths
concept.
Train service.
This method is used to train the trailing extreme from beginning this week, if the given string does
not contain the specified suffix string, then dysfunctional returns the original string without any
changes.
Now you can see the syntax.
Here, SDR represent the original history and self-esteem, represent the suffix string.
Now let's go to a school program to illustrate how to train a suffix estranged from the given the string.
First, creating and initializing to or and using shorthand declaration, define a variable like SC
or Van Hollen equals welcome to go through ground language and define another body to like SDR to and
assign value to eat like theses that trillion of go length
before trimming the now displayed these two varieties first into message if the first strings before
trimming and display these two varieties, FP is still wrong.
And if the Your True
OK Now training pair fix this string from the given string using 3nd suffix function first define variable
like result one calling equals from the strings package
call 3mm suffix function treen suffix function first name of variable is stillborn and another argument
is suffix.
For the example, in this case, we set programming language
OK and define another variable life result to call in equals.
The Strings Package The string suffix function
sets name of value list or two and sets suffixes.
String line for this case.
Hell.
OK, now given to displaying this result after trimming suffix string values.
So copy these three lines and paste here.
Change these values after and variables is still going to result from this year to to the result to
the format.
The call save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output we were able to modify, our guys are sitting through the trim subpixel space
function for SDR one after trimming.
We have welcome to go and for SDR to very good after trimming we have this is the tutorial of go using
the trim suffix function.
We were able to separate the value of the programming language from and off the variable volume and
return the rest to the value.
And in the second variable, because the desired value of the trim suffix was not present a desire desired
swing.
The original string was returned in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.