Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
suffix, and in this session we want to talk about the other strings concept.
Three Perfect's.
This method is used to train the leading perfect system from the given string.
If the given string does not contain the specified perfect string, then dysfunctional returns the original
string without any change.
Now you can see the syntax.
Here, SDR represent the original estrange and prefix SDR represent the prefix string.
Now let's go to the school program to illustrate how to trim the prefix the string from the given.
This string first creating an initializing to a string using shorthand declaration is the wrong call.
It equals welcome to school programming language.
SDR to call and equals.
This is the tutorial.
Go blank.
Okay, before training.
First, we displayed these two variables.
If they sit in the Sage Strings D for training
and display these two variables, if he is still learning
and if he is still to.
Now training perfect this from the given as strings using clearly fixed function.
So define another variable like result.
One call equals film the strings package invoked treme. perfect function.
Three.
Prefix function first sit.
Estrange the one and said prefix value for the example in this case, then come to.
And define another area to result to calling equals the strings package called three Perfect's
sit name of variable or two and say for office, for example, language in this case.
Now we display the results after three imperfect systems value.
Copy these two lines and paste here and change these value gesture one to resolved for.
And this year, to resolve to
reformat the code, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output extremes after trimming go programming language and for very evil to is.
This is the tutorial of goal.
We were able to modify our desired strings through the tree into a fixed function, using the tree into
a fixed function.
We were able to separate the value of the welcome too, from first of the very bad and return your rest
to the value of it.
And in the second variable, because the desired variable for the train perfect was not present within
the desired history.
The original string was returned in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish sheet and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.