Hello and welcome to the goal and programming language course in the previous session.
We talk about replays function in Estrin and in this session we want to talk about the other extreme
concept.
Go blank index function.
Then the expansion enables searching particular takes within estranged its walk simply by matching the
specific takes in history.
Now you can see the syntax if found, then it returns the specific position starting with zero.
And if not found, then it returns minus one.
Now let's go to your school program to illustrate how to use in the expansion in history.
For example, we want to search a USD value that first Neller is thought by the uppercase character
within the Australia it's targeting by using index function.
So right, FP use string strings package and involved index function set for first arguement us through
Alia and set for second argument.
We set a new test to repeat the previous Sampat, except that all the characters in the Australian string
are lowercase.
So if the
Strings
Dot
Index
Australia set value for first argument and for second argument is a USD and one other centre.
In this case, we want to search a uppercase character in Australia, so we write if the strings make
a dot index function
and its value for first argument us through earlier and for second argument is set a averages and do
another Sampa.
In this case, we search a lowercase character in Australia.
So we write if the Strings Dots Index for first argument, we set Australia and for second value that
we set a lowercase reformat, they could save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output for first we have zero for second, we have minus one for third.
We have zero and four force.
We have fine.
Except for the second example, the index of the these are the Siemens retail and all.
Sampat now go to a slide and continue.
Go blank last index function, the last thing this function enables searching particular text character
or listing with an asterisk.
It returns the index of the last index of text or tracks during testing.
Now you can see the syntax.
If found, then it returns to a specific position as starting with zero and if not found, then it will
return as minus one.
Let's go to the school program to illustrate how to use last index function.
First clear, the last school.
For example, we want to serve as a character within the Australia extreme by using the last in the
expansion FP from Airstreams package, the call last thing expansion for first arguement, we set value
Australia and for second value, we set a lower case and go to the next line and repeat the previous
sample, except that the character a is often the case.
So if this drinks package the last index for first argument, we said Australia and for second value,
we said a proper case before they could save the project, then execute the program.
Now we can see the output for first we have eight and four.
Second, we have minus one.
For the first example, the index of the desired is doing is returned.
OK, we have reached the end of this decision.
I hope you have taken full advantage of this decision until next session.
Goodbye.