Hello and welcome to the goal and putting it on language course in the previous session, we talked
about that the strings are immutable.
And in this session, we want to talk about the other this strings concept.
Iterate over a string.
You can iterate over history using full range loop, this loop can iterate over the Unicode code point
for a string.
Now you can see the scene techs here.
The index is the variable, which is saw the first bite of UTF eight encoded could point and see it's
AH is toward the characters of the given string and SDR is a string.
Now let's go to this school program to illustrate how to iterate over a string.
First, define a string variable and initialize it for the example in.
Value calling equals go programming language now create a range in the fall for ETRADE characters of
value string for index see edge calling equals range.
Value.
And in this case, the bone to display index number and index value of each character of value a string.
So if if the value of index per cent, the conversion characters set for index number, ease and conversion
character for characters is c a person C lowercase.
So set it for character batches, list and set index and see it's re reformat the called Save the Project
and execute the program.
Now we can see the output results to print all the characters of the.
These are listing separately with its index number.
For the example, value of index zero is G approaches.
Value of index one is all lowercase and value of Index 20 is a large piece.
In order not to prolong the time on decision, you will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.