Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
iterate over history and indecision.
We want to talk about the other extremist concept.
Access the individual point of this stream.
This ring is another bite so we can access each bite of the given history.
Now let's go to the school curriculum to illustrate how to access the bias of this stream.
First, creating an initializing doing SDR calling equals sit value, go to ground
now, accessing the bonds of the given history by defining a for loop for I call an equals zero I less
than linear history and variable in this case is this TR and our last plus four set the condition for
loop we used from the limits to obtain the length of this string.
So in the body, a statement like quotes if this index.
First, St D equals Person C and as T quote equals Person V for Congress and character for Person de
CET I.
And Person C is TR Index I and person.
The history are index AI again display index number of y by involved AI variable and display index value
by S TR Index AI and Person C as cognition, character and display ASCII code of each bi character.
Y Person V as conversion character for SDR AI reformat the call, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output for the example, index eight equals eight and ASCII code equals 97 or Index
five equals O and ASCII code equals 111.
So we could access index value and ASCII could of each character of string in order not to prolong the
time of decision to be finished, and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.