Hello and welcome to the goal and programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
access to individual by of the ice rink.
And in this session, we want to talk about the other extreme concept.
Find the length of the Earth shrink.
In Go Link, you can find the length of the string using two functions.
One is lamb and another is wrong.
Count in this from using lean function.
It returns the number of bytes of this range using room count in a string function.
It returns the total number of drone presents in this room.
Now let's go to this school with program to illustrate how to find the length of this string.
First, creating an initializing astronaut using shorthand declaration.
So define a variable like SDR column equals and said this string value welcome.
To go programming language display this year, the FP is strange value and so valuable off.
Now finding the length of the ice rink using limb function.
So define a variable like the lengths one column he calls and call LEN function and sit is your variable
as argument.
Now, displaying the length of this range, if he lands flown by land function in and said lands long
here.
And in another case, we want to find the length of the string using room count in a string function.
So define another variable like lengths to call in equals wrong counting.
The string is in Typekit UTF eight, so invoke UTF eight UTF eight dot long count in this string and
set.
It's your variable as argument.
So go to the next line and display the length of IS three in the end, if he links to Y.
Jerome Count in a strange function column and set it in links to
reform at the courts, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output length swung by land function history for and links to by wrong counting.
The string function is three four.
You could find links of string variable by two ways first, by laying function and the other by wrong
count in a string function in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.