Hello and welcome to the godown programming language course in the previous session, we talked about
ministering in goal.
And in this session, we want to talk about the audio strings concept.
Turning left.
This function is used to train the left hand side, the specified in the function Unicode components
of this strings.
Now you can see the syntax.
Here is the already present, the content is strong and contests represent the left hand side elements,
which you want to train in the given history.
Now let's go to this school program to illustrate team left hand side elements from this week.
First, creating an initializing to a using shorthand declaration in this case, declare a string and
assign value to it, which includes a number of exclamation marks and an asterisk.
Now define a variable like SDR, one column equals and set value exclamation marks, then come to go
programming
language and asterisk.
Go to the next line and declare another as string and the sound value to it, which contains a number
of add sign and dollar sign.
Define that even SDR to call equals set value.
Add, sign, add sign.
This is to a trio of go lang and dollar sign thylacine
before trimming the now displayed these two variables.
If P the strings B4 training
and display two variables FP History, or Wong said variable is still unknown.
And as the SDR tool and set variable S2 are true, no trimming the given string using trim left function
first define the variable like resolved.
One column equals Pichai's strings dot watch three left name of string this TR one and set the string
to be trained from the car.
This, for the example here is exclamation marks and the DS for another string resolved to call and
equals the strings by cage.
There are three left name of string.
In this case it is s t r two and set.
This seem to be trained from the car and the setting for the example.
And it's time now we want to display the results after trimming values.
So copy these two lines.
Paste here after trimming.
And said Vidal's name resolved long and resolved to reformat the code, save the projects and execute
the program.
Now we can see the output, we were able to modify our desired airstream through the train lift function
and exclamation marks and at songlines remove from string value in order not to prolong the time of
decision.
We will finish it and we will continue to contend in the next session.
Goodbye.