Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in the 30th session, we talked about turning
left to history, and in this session we want to talk about the other extreme concept.
3M writes.
This function is used to trim the right hand side as specified in the function Unicode components of
this strength.
Now you can see the syntax.
Here, SDR represent the content is streamed and contest to represent the right hand side elements which
you want to train in the given history.
Now let's go to this school program to illustrate trim right hand side elements from this drink first,
creating an initial listening to history using shorthand declaration now declare rest, drink and assign
value to it, which includes a number of exclamation marks and asterisks.
For the example, define a variable like SDR.
One column equals, as clearly mentioned, Mark Welcome to go programming
language and asterisk march.
And declare another three and assign value to it, which contains a number of acts and dollar sign.
Define another body it in is TR tool column equals at sign outside.
This is the two three on
go link and the other sign dollars sign.
Before training will now display these two variables.
First, write a message FP the strings before training and display two variables.
FP this TR one
variable is still and it is fair to call, column and name of disregulated is still true now.
Training day given the strings using team write function.
First, define a variable like result while calling equals from the strings package involved trim write
function.
First name of a string just to our wall and sit there seemed to be trimmed from the current esteem,
for example, here is asterisk.
OK.
The trim right metagenome of the asterisk right hand side of this street value do these for another
variable, but define another variable result.
Two column equals the.
There are three right?
Name of a string or two.
And said this seemed to be trimmed from the current listing.
For the example, here is dollar sign.
Now we want displaying the results after trimming rightist strings value.
So copy these three lines and go to this line and paste here and change this value after and change
the result wrong and change your tool to resolve to perform at the code.
Save the project and execute the program to the package folder and go wrong.
So it's like, Yes, let's make that go.
Now we can see the output we were able to modify.
Our desired is sitting through the three right function and asterisk, and the other song has removed
from its strings value in order not to prolong the time of position.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.