Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about AM right this week and in this session, we want to talk about
the other restraints concept.
Trim is space.
This function is used to train all the leading and trailing why the space from this specify this drink.
Now you can see the scene techs.
Let's go to this school program to illustrate how to train ride to space from this drink.
First, creating an initializing to a string using shorthand declaration, now declaring a string and
assign value to it, and we put some wider space at the beginning and end of this string values define
the history like it's a long column.
You could put some whitespace asterisk.
And welcome to go programming
language, asterisk and some whitespace and declare another string and assign value to it.
That value of this string is sought as and which to assign some different history or to very little
call and equals some future faces I'd sign.
I'd say this is the uh, who like.
That sign outside some healthy spaces before training.
We now display these two variables.
If the first printed message is three weeks before training.
And believed these two variables, FP, they're still warm, it's still warm, and if the still are
to call in and said it's still too late.
OK, now streaming via this space from the given strength using three Nastase function.
Defining a variable like result, one column equals a strength package and call Trina space function
three.
Space function and synonym name of a string.
The star won't go to the next line defined another variable, right?
These are two crawling equals this strings package and through three space function and said SDR to
an argument for this function.
Now we want to dispelling the results after trimming a space strings value.
So copy these three lines and case in this line and change these values after.
Resolved, long,
resolved to leave, followed at the court, save the project, then execute the program.
Now we can see the output we were able to modify our these are listed in through the trim of space function
before calling the a space function that are empty spaces at the beginning and end of the string values.
But after calling to trim the space function, Dante's spaces at the beginning and end of the strings
values are deleted in order not to prolong the time a decision will finished and will continue the content
in the next session.
Goodbye.