Hello and welcome to the golden and programming language course in the previous session, we talked
about function declaration, and in this session we want to talk about the other function concept
creating a simple function.
A declaration function begins with the keyboard, followed by the name you want to function to have
a paid off prances and then a ballot containing your functions code.
Simple function takes no parameter and returns no values.
Now go to this code and illustrate how to create a simple function.
First, create a project folder for the example, named Park Share and create a file.
I mean, the article read Package
Package me first create the simple function that has nuts, parameters and returned values for the example
form set a name like super function.
It paid off parenthesis and curly brackets.
Now we can define a simple function without any parameters, and the returned values here are just print
ahead of word as per a statement.
The he.
Hello.
What saved the project?
It's time to confirm your function.
One, creating function, you give a definition of what the function has to do to use a function, you
will have to call the function to perform the defined task.
When a program calls a function, the program control is transferred to the call function.
It can't function, performs a defined task and then its return a statement is executed or when its
function and in closing braces reached its returns.
The program comes back to the main program.
Now, create the main function and invoke define function inside a fine name
and now invoke this simple function simple function.
Reform of the code.
Save the project and execute the program.
First, go to the function package, see the function and run the program.
Go the bank is the main tool.
Now we can see the output.
We could define the function name simple function that has no parameters and no return values.
And can this function inside man function and execute in a c, the value of a statement that is hello
in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.