Head on and then come to the gold and programming language course in the previous session, we talked
about function with parameters and indecision.
We want to talk about the other function concept.
Function with return times, their return is a value that the function returns to the conning function
bit and completes its task.
You use the written statement to send the value back to user defined function.
You can return the value as a literal value or retain a variable when it function returns the value
to the user defined function.
You must restore that value in either a local or global variable.
Now you can see the syntax.
So go to the school program and illustrate how to use function with return tight finish, creating a
function with two parameters of each type that adds together and return and each value function and
set parameters type like X by the tight end and lie by the Typekit.
And I don't have the parentheses set the return type.
He didn't go to the body of function defined a variable named the total death restores some of two variables
to Todd Colin because x plus y go to the next line and return total variable as return times return
to town validator.
Now, save the project and go to the main function and invoke app function inside it.
The main function calling app function and values as arguments inside it has set the return value of
function in a variable for the example.
Create a variable for return value on involved and function first at set two arguments for the example
20 comma 30.
This function returns and end type value, so sign this function to a variable.
For the example, some column equals and display value.
Add some value.
If F.
Some
X plus y equals person de la Kazan's set the variable song here, save the project and execute the program.
Now we can see the output sum of X Plus Y equals fifty in this sample to add function, takes input
off to integer numbers and returns and integer values, as some of them together in order not to prolong
the time of decision, will initiate and continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.