OK so we've reached the end of this course.
This has been an unusual course for me but I've totally enjoyed it.
Usually when I create a course I have a very clear much more clear idea of what the Course is going
to be about and where it's going.
And this one has been really free form and also fun.
I like having fun and all my classes but it's been fun in a different way.
Just like I don't know where this is going.
And so that's been really good.
A good time.
But the primary thing I want to convey to you in this video is if you are watching this video you are
a unique individual.
You are above and beyond average.
You have gone farther than most.
Go.
You're putting in the work to build the life you want.
At the beginning this course I spent some time talking about the importance of humanity and what it
takes to succeed as a student and also as an individual on life and having grit and persistence.
And so I just want to commend you for working all the way through this course and adding this drop to
your bucket because drop by drop the bucket gets filled and persistently patiently.
You are bound to succeed.
And hopefully I can even serve as a role model for that because all humans we are all human we are all
alike in the same way.
We all have our our strengths and our weaknesses.
We all have our hopes and our fears.
And we you know have things that we do well and don't do well and we can all improve if we work at learning.
And so hopefully I've even been taught some of that for you in this course because we went into territory
of which I knew very little about.
And so it's been great to collaborate with you Daniel and to be able to learn from you and to have been
a part of this course.
So I hope it's been a benefit to you.
And I just wanted to take a moment to congratulate you and tell you to pat yourself on the back because
you're doing what everybody on this planet should be doing.
We'll try to make a comparison about who's doing how much but you know the more we each individually
improve our own lives one person at a time you know that's making this entire world a better place.
So as that cliche goes but it's true.
You have anything you want to say to just maybe speaking to your success as a coder and how you've gotten
to where you've gotten or anything on say the students congratulate.
This is kind of like good job into the course.
I'm the one who gets a few so you can tell that humanities humanities background all the books and everything.
Yeah yeah.
No.
Congratulations on getting through it all.
There's a lot here and I know the GOP Tea Party at least was we we're kind of winging it a little bit
with very little preparation ahead of time.
And so if you manage to get through all that and you learn something great.
Congratulations.
Yeah yeah.
And he got a little bit meaty there at the end so good job getting through the course we got a couple
more videos for you in the next video we're going to give you a few next steps where you can go after
this and and then we're also going to ask you to leave a review in the video after that.
That helps other students find the score.
So we'll see you in the next two videos.
Oh and if we we sometimes create roles so that video might still be coming for you so hopefully that
will leave you with a smile on your face.
All right.
See you the next few final videos.