So next steps you could take after completing this course as Daniel and I are going to embark upon creating
yet another go course right after this one and it's going to have more web orientation.
I'm really striving to keep my courses shorter so somewhere under 15 hours and and so we're really working
on trying to break those courses up and there's a reason for that which maybe at some point I'll explain.
But take a look on this platform wherever you are finding this course.
Take a look under my account Todd McCloud or under Daniel Hoffman's account and see what other courses
we have out there and if you enjoyed this course Come join us in another course.
We have courses on go programming that are coming.
I also have a whole selection of courses covering other skills office applications soft skills meditation
and mindfulness have been something that's been important to me I want to do a bunch of courses on investing
because that's my traditional academic training.
Believe it or not was an economics business and finance and so that's something that eventually I want
to get to also.
But that's gonna be a little bit out but maybe they're done by now.
Go check out our accounts see what other classes are there are of ours.
Be a great next step to continue forwarding your skill fit skill set and keep learning.
Life is about growing if you're not growing you're dead or close to dead right.
But all living things grow.
That's what that's what we're here to do.
So remember that and keep growing keep learning keep becoming better and improving and life's just going
to get better because yeah that's that's the way it goes and reference those introductory videos where
I talked about all that.
All right.
So those are good next steps.
Oh and then also you could connect with me on Twitter and and you could message me there or tweet and
tag me.
And that's the quickest way to reach me.
And if you need to email me have included my email there for any reason you need to email me.
You got anything you want and you got a social media.
No I say off all that was security.
All right.
If you need to get in touch with Daniel tweet to me tag me and say Todd get this to Daniel.
See you in the next video.