All right.
So maybe the final maybe the second the final video on this course is just set.
Please leave a review.
Leaving review really helps other students find this course that's how algorithms work and search algorithms
like the look see how many reviews how many people went through the course all that stuff.
So if you enjoyed the course please leave us a great review on the platform and if you have suggestions
for improvement I reference the contact information I provided in the previous video.
My twitter or my email please send me those suggestions for improvement directly and I do enjoy and
appreciate hearing them I really believe in the collaborative spirit we all get better together and
that's a two way road.
And so just to illustrate that one of the things I do in my courses now as I provide personal anecdotes
into my videos so that people who are in a rush don't have to sit through my stories of my friend Joe
or whoever.
But you know I save those for the end of the video.
So I do take the feedback that I hear from students and make the courses even better.
So if you have suggestions for making the courses even better.
Definitely message me on Twitter or email me and and if you enjoyed this course we'd really appreciate
it if you leave us a great review because that helps other students find the course and then that just
makes everything better.
All right.
So thanks for taking this course and thanks for leaving a review if you enjoyed it.