In this section of the course, we're going to just take care of a little bit of housekeeping, for
example, we have reddish installed and we're using it now.
And one of the things that our session package supports is storing sessions in redness, and that makes
a lot of sense.
It's actually faster than storing them in the database.
So we're going to take care of that, and we'll also take care of implementing CSS RF protection and
finally speeding things up by disabling some debug info based upon whether or not we're going to production
or development.
So right now, I'm in this alert house package and we're going to take care of implementing Redis sessions
first.
So I'm looking at the file celebrities don't go.
And if you recall one of the things we did right here in Line 91 in my code of celebrities don't go
is we decided whether or not we should take care of implementing a retest cache.
But of course, the other thing we need to do here is to not just worry about whether or not a cache
is being used with Redis, but also whether sessions are being used with credits.
So let's modify this if statement by putting in or condition here and say, Oh s don't get on.
We're going to look for the key session underscore type in the dot on file, if that's equal to Redis.
We also need to create this my read his cache.
And of course, the problem is that right now, this variable, my read, his cache only exists within
the scope of this if statement.
And that is, as you can see, if we point at it of type a pointer to cache portraitist cache.
So what I'm going to do is get rid of the assignment operator here and go up to the top of the file
and create a variable with this name of the type pointer to cache readies cache.
So let's go up here and we can put it anywhere.
But I'll put it right after my constants.
I'll say ver my Redis cache of type a pointer to cache readies cache.
OK, so now once once we set it in this if statement, it's available in other places and we're actually
going to need it in other places as well.
So this part has taken care of.
We've modified our if statement.
Now let's go down to where we create our session right here.
So what I'm going to do is add some fields that contain non nil values to my type session.
So we can do that, of course, with the switch state.
And we'll have to make a change to the session type itself in a moment.
But let's get this out of the way.
First, we'll switch on C dot config dot session type.
So our first case will be Redis,
and we're going to do something in that case in a moment.
And our second case, and there's no call in after case, I don't know why I put that there.
I often do.
Our second case will be MySchool or Postgres or Maria.
TBE emails will put Postgres Q will there as well, because sometimes people type that and we'll do
something with that as well.
In that case, and this is the only one we can take care of right now, we'll say.
Sache says our variable cesse de pool is equal to Cedar DB School.
And of course, that means I can probably take this right out of here because in point of fact, that
might be set to nil.
People might be using sessions, but not a database, so that takes care of the first situation.
OK.
And we don't need a comma there.
Now this case, what if it's Redis?
Well, I want to set Redis my Redis pool, and I can't put that in the field DB pool because those are
different types.
So let's go find our session type wherever that is
right here.
Let's add another field to that, and we'll call it red is cool, and that will be of type a pointer
to cache Dot.
Read his cache.
And of course, he didn't report that for me, but that's no problem.
We can import that.
Actually, that's a type pointer to read a school.
That's better.
And that did the import for me.
So let's save that, and let's go back to celebrities now, and let's change this case of readies to
be, says Dot.
Is pool is equal to.
My reader's cache, dconf, not forget dot com.
There now we have a case for readies, a case for MySchool, Postgres, MariaDB and PostgreSQL.
And of course, the default case is do nothing because we don't specify a default case, so those don't
get set.
And the nice thing about this, of course, is we're only setting fields that have a non nil value,
and that's kind of important.
So after that?
We ended our session and we have to make any changes in there.
Let's go have a look.
And of course there is because although we've now assigned a reddish pool to the appropriate fields
in the session type, we actually don't have the diretta store installed.
So let's take care of that.
I don't think we do anyway.
So let's scroll on down here.
Yes, we have a case for race, but we actually haven't installed the reddest store type for the Alex
Edwards sex package.
So let's open a terminal and clearer screen and type go get.
And I've copied it to my clipper already.
It's GitHub dot com slash Alex Edwards slash x slash Reddit store.
So let's go get that.
And there it is.
It's available to us now.
And I think all we have to do right here on Line 58 in my code in the Switch statement is say Session
Dot Store is equal to.
And now we take advantage of the package we just installed, which is register store new and we hand
it secret is cool.
And that should, in theory, take care of it.
And all we have to do now is switch to our other a project, my app and open our doors on file
on and find our session type and make it read us.
Now, if I open my terminal and start my application because it's running.
And start my application.
Everything compiled, that's a good sign.
Let's switch to our web browser and see if this works.
So I'll go back to the homepage and I'm not currently logged in, so logging in actually sets the sessional
variable, so let's try that.
So and I think it's Mia here dot com with password, but we'll find out in a minute it could be my email
address.
We're logged in and we're authenticated, so I should be able to refresh this page and still see it.
So now it's using recessions and recessions are very fast.
So that was relatively painless.
So let's move on and now finally implement see us rf protection.