So I've been talking about cross site request, forgery protection for a long time, and we've never
done anything with it, and we're finally going to get around to implementing it and it is dead simple.
So right now, I'm looking at the celebrity's page from our Maya project, and if I use source on this
page, you'll see that I have at the top.
This Meditech Mehta name equals cc rf dash token with an empty content.
That's because we've not actually implemented generating CSR of tokens and CSR of tokens are nothing
more than a means of ensuring that a request made say when you post a form, for example, is actually
being made from a page on your site.
So whatever value is in the CSR token field is compared with what it should be, and it changes every
time you make a new request to the site.
So, for example, if I tried to log any user here and I view source on this page and I look for C s
r f and then search again here I have a hidden field in my form.
Input Typekit was hidden and the name is CC.
RF underscore token.
And again, it has no value.
So we're going to change that.
We're going to implement CC rf protection.
And in the go world, if you're using CSR f protection, you're almost certainly using this package.
Justness slash.
No, sir.
And it is dead simple.
There's very little coded.
As you can see here, half of this code is tests, and it works really, really well.
So let's go get that.
So I'm going to copy the URL to this repository right here copy and I'll go back to my ID and I'll make
sure I'm in the celebrities project and I'm not.
So let's go get that.
I open my terminal window type, go get and paste in the URL GitHub dot com slash J U s t i NHS slash.
No, sir.
Then that goes and gets it for me.
So now that I have it, I need to use it.
And if you look at the documentation on the page, you'll discover the easiest way to use this.
In fact, the only way to use this really right now is to go to your middleware.
So let's find our middleware wherever that is right here.
Right now, we just have one.
The session load middleware and what we'll do is add another one func with a receiver of C pointer to
celebrities, and we'll call this one noser, which is a great name, because that's the name of the
package we're using.
And it takes one parameter next of type HTP dot handler and it returns in a dot handler.
Now, first thing I'm going to do is get a C SRF handler, which I'm going to call C SRF handler, and
that comes from the no surf package.
No surf.
And hopefully it'll find for me, no surf right there.
Dot knew.
And that requires one parameter, which we received as a call to this function next, and it should
be handled.
OK.
So that creates a handler for me.
And now I need to determine whether or not I should be using secure cookies because this, of course,
sets a cookie on every request.
And we only want it to be secure if we're in production, in development, we don't.
But fortunately, we can do that pretty easily.
So I'll create a variable called secure and I'll ignore the error.
And that comes from using the stricken package from the standard library.
We want pass bool because we have in our seeked config dart cookie dart secure.
We have a text string which is either true or false, and pass bool will turn that into what it needed
to be a Boolean with the appropriate true or false value.
And now I just set my base cookie.
And then we can figure CSR if, in other words, it's a CSR of handler variable we created, we'll call
on that set based cookie.
And that requires one value of type HTP cookie right there.
We just populate its fields.
So first thing, it should be only I'm going to set that.
That's true because I'm only going to be making HTP http requests.
Path for this cookie is the entire application, so Slash takes care of that.
Is it secure?
And of course, that's the variable which is got secure.
So if we're running in production, I'm going to assume that you're running an HDB, and if you're not,
you should be.
So that's a valid way to set that value.
And we set the same site attribute and I'll set mine to HGTV Dot.
Same site, strict mode.
Same site, but are spelt right?
Strict mode You can use lax mode if you want.
That will probably work for you, but I'm really security conscious, so I'm going to set mine to secure
to strict mode.
And finally, what domain are we going to be using this cookie with?
We could leave that empty and it would default to the domain that you're actually serving it from.
But I like to be specific, and we have that in court config cookie dot domain.
All right.
And what we do after that is return.
See us our f handle it.
Now, once we implement this middleware and we're about to, every request to the site will actually
include and generate and return back to the user the appropriate CSF token.
Now, if there are situations like domains, for example, where you don't want that to have to happen,
you could put this in here.
Something like this see us our f handler, DOD exempt glaube and say, I'm not going to worry about
validating CC RF tokens from domains like some API and then the star, because this is a glob, you
want to match everything that begins with that.
Now, I'm not going to do that.
I want it on every request.
OK.
So we've now got this middleware, but of course, we're not using it, and I don't want to make the
end user put the middleware in place.
I'm actually going to do it myself for everyone so they don't have to do anything.
So I'll go to my roots file and I'll just use that so much.
Don't use and I want to use c don't know, surf.
So is that everything I need to do?
If you think about it?
I've now got a CSR CSR token being generated on every request, but how do I get that to my templates?
Well, let's go to our render package right here.
And in that render package, we have a function called default data.
And this is data that is handed to every single template on the site.
And if you look just above this in the template data struct, we already have a place for CSR of tokens.
So I want to add my CSR token to the data that is passed to every template in the site.
So I'll just hit return here and I'll populate that field.
TD, I don't see us are of token and that is going to be equal to.
We just called no serve, no serve dot token.
Didn't seem to get it for me.
No, sir.
There is.
Dot token.
And it requires one parameter and that is the request order.
We already have that right up here.
We get our request as a parameter passed to this function, and that should be all I have to do.
So let's switch over to our other application.
My app.
And just before we go any further because I already have it on my clipboard, I'm going to save a little
bit of time and say, Go get paste in that URL for no surf because I'll need it in a minute.
And I will start my application make restart.
I'm not sure if it's running or not, but we'll find out.
Yes, it is.
So it stops it.
It starts it.
And let's go back to your Web browser and see if that token is in there.
So back to our web browser and switch over to the celebrity's page.
Go back to the home page and let's view source on this page.
And there you can see that the token has been generated and passed to this template.
And if I reload it, that token should change every time I reload, and it does perfect.
And the same thing should happen if I close this and go to the log in a user page.
If I view the source on that, there's the token here and it's also up in the meta tag where I want
it to be.
And if I reload it, those should both change to exactly the same thing.
And they do.
OK, now let's go back to our homepage, and I'm actually going to add a link right here to that cache
page that we did.
So let me go back to my celebrity's project because I'm going to try it out on that.
So back to my I.D. and I'll hide the terminal and I'll go to my home page, which is HomeKit, and I'll
just add a link at the bottom.
OK, so we'll duplicate this and call this one.
Cash and the path for that, if I recall correctly, was cash dash test.
Now let's go back to our web browser and reload this.
So there's cash, so let's click on it.
And I'm also going to open my terminal or my JavaScript console, and I'm looking at the network tab
in the developer tools.
And what I'm going to do is try setting something here and it's not going to work.
So I'll set A and B and I'll click Save in cash and then we'll look over here and see what went wrong.
And you can see I have an error 400, which means bad request.
And this is because we're not actually validating the CC rf token that's handed to our handler with
the fetch request, and we need to fix that.
And it's pretty easy to fix.
Now, this is not something you need to do with regular form submissions.
All you have to do there is make sure you have a hidden field named exactly six underscore CC RF underscore
token and that its value is set to the current six of token.
And nothing else matters.
It all just magically happens.
But here we're actually doing a fetch request and we in fact, are passing the cross rf token as part
of our JSON payload.
And you can see that right here and we look at request.
You can see we're passing the token, but we're not doing anything with it on the back end.
So let's go fix that.
So back over to our code and this time I'm going to look at my handlers, my cash handlers right here.
So we'll start with the first one, save in cash, and of course, here's where we need to validate
that CSR of token.
And it's pretty simple.
So I'll come down here right after I read the Jason.
But before I try to set anything in the cash at this point, I need to verify manually because this
is not a regular form submission.
I need to verify that that token is correct.
So I'll say, if not, no serve is.
We just imported the new serve package in here.
So that'll work.
And all we do is call verify token.
And we hand it no surf dot token with the request and we compare it to user input dot CSR.
So if that's not valid and we need to do something and normally you would send back some kind of error
message or whatever you want, but I'm just going to throw an error five hundred.
So doesn't really matter here.
This is just a test case.
So of course, I've done it for this handler, but I also need to do it for we've just done save in
cash.
Let's go down here to the next one after we read this and get from cash will paste it in there and we'll
go down again further to delete from cash and after either Jason will verify that and down here.
Finally, I think there's one more empty cash after we read the JSON, we paste that in there.
Now let's stop our application, make stop, start our application.
Make start.
And if we did everything right, this should now work.
Let's go back and see if we got it right.
So back to our web browser, reload the page.
All clear, all these requests, and I'll try setting Alpha to beta save in cash.
And I got an error for her.
I should've worked.
That's not good.
I know what I missed.
Let's go back to our celebrities project, so over to our code and open this up and find our middleware.
So we're actually making a post to slash API and it's looking for a field.
A post value in that request is looking for a field named CSR underscore token.
So you remember a little while ago when I said, I'm not going to add that little bit right here, that
exempt club actually, in fact, do need that.
So I'm going to add that here.
So I'll say CSR as handlers dot exempt glaube, and I'll exempt anything that begins with slash API
slash and anything after that.
And that way it'll say, OK, this is a request to slash API slash.
It's a post request to a URL that begins with slash API.
So in this case, I'll just exempt it.
I'm not going to test to see it to ensure that it has a post request with a form value named C underscore
c SRF underscore token.
So that was my mistake.
That was silly.
So I've added that let's go back now to our other project right here.
Let's restart the application, make restart, and this time it should work.
So it started.
Let's go back to our Web browser.
Let's reload the page.
Now, let's try it again.
So this time I've cleared the console over here, the network traffic and I'll say save in cash, and
now it's saved in the cash.
And now I've got to get it from the cash to make sure that works.
So Alfa.
Get firm cash, and that works great and delete from cash, I'll foolish foolish just empty the entire
cash.
Empty the cash.
And if I try to get it, it shouldn't be there and everything works as expected.
So that's pretty straightforward.
Now let's just verify one more thing.
Let's go back to the home page, and let's make sure that logging a user, in our view, the source
on that and there should be two values with CSR of token here.
There's the first one right here.
And the second one is the hidden field on my form.
OK, so this is a hidden field and it has to be named CSI RF underscore token and the value comes right
from the template data that is passed to every template in the system.
And this and this are identical as they should be.
Now, if I was to go and try to log in right now, it'll work just fine.
But if I was to remove this field, comment that out or hide it or just delete it entirely and then
try to log in, it would not work because that middleware will say, Well, this is not a route that
begins with slash API.
It is a post request, and I can't find a valid value for a post request or a post field named CC RF
underscore token.
So I'm just going to throw an error 400 bad request.
OK, so now we have extra protection and it's really, really easy for end users to implement it.