So this time around, I want to increase the speed of our renderer, particularly our jet template render.
And right now, I'm in the Celebrity House project and I'm looking at the celebrities go file and I'm
around the line one hundred and forty seven where I declare that variable views of type jet dot news
site.
And if you recall, I added this line jet in development mode.
And what that does, of course, is it allows us to work on templates without having to restart our
application every time we make a change to a jet template.
So if the application is started and I change some text on a template, I can just reload the page in
a web browser and it shows right up.
Now, if that was disabled, what would happen is it would read all of the templates.
Each time a template is accessed, it reads that template and saves it in memory, and it just keeps
it there forever so I can make all the changes.
I wanted to a template, but until I recompile my application or rerun my application, I would never
see the changes and that's irritating when you're in development.
But what that also means is it takes longer to render the templates because it has to read it off the
file system every time, pass it, do all sorts of things with it.
And that actually puts more stress on the garbage collector for GO as well because we're putting things
into memory, and every time a page is loaded, little bits of memory get set and they have to be cleaned
up by the garbage collector.
And that just slows things down.
And that's no good, OK for development, but not for production.
And let's see just how much of an impact this has on how long it takes for things to load.
So with this hilarious project, I'm going to create a little utility function that will measure the
time that it takes for any particular function to execute.
So create a new file.
I'm going to put it in its own file and I'll call it utils.
Don't go.
It doesn't matter what I call it, but I'm going to call utils dot go.
And of course, that's in packaged celebrities.
And I'll create one function here with a receiver of C, a pointer to celebrities.
And I'll call it load time.
OK.
And it takes one parameter which I'll call start, and it's a type time dot time right there.
And that should do the import for me.
And it did.
And it doesn't return anything.
OK.
So what I'm going to do is declare a variable called elapsed and that's assigned the value of time dot
since start.
We're just doing a subtraction here from one time subtracting one time from another time to get the
time elapsed.
And now I need to get the name of the function that called this function because we're going to put
load time into another function and we're going to prepend the word, defer to it so we won't execute
until the calling function actually finishes, OK, and that allows us to figure out how long that function
took to run.
So I'm going to declare a variable called PC for program color and the function I'm going to call from.
The runtime package actually returns for things, but I don't care about the next three, so I'll use
the blank identifier and we're going to use the runtime package, which is part of the standard library.
And we're going to call from that color and give it the required parameter one.
Just give me the one level of color.
OK, so now I have an elapsed than I have on a PC.
Now I want to learn more about the function that actually called this one.
OK.
So I'll call this func OBJ doesn't matter what I call it, I just need a name for the function.
That's all I'm trying to get out of this.
And again, I'll call the runtime package, and this time I will call func for P C, which gives me
the function that actually called this, and I can get the name out of that, and I handed the program
color.
And now we'll create a regular expression that allows me to extract the name from the calling function.
And it's a little complicated, complex, the rejects, but don't worry about it, just Typekit it.
So we'll call this one runtime.
-- just the name I'm choosing.
That's a sign.
The value of Reg X, which is right in the standard library, rejects P, so rejects P Dot must compile
and reject strings are always hard to read.
I'm going to put them in back, Tex, so I don't have to escape things with quotes and the first character
is a carrot, then a dart, then an asterisk, then a slash.
And get this right or it won't work.
You'll still get values.
It just won't be what you're looking for.
So slash then dot.
Then in parentheses dot start close the parentheses.
And then a dollar sign.
OK.
So make sure you type that right.
So there's my rejects must compile.
And next, I'll get the name of my function.
Finally, by calling runtime funk dot, replace all string.
And I'm going to pass it.
First of all, funk obj and get the name of that again.
Funk object name, comma and then in quotation marks dollar sign one.
OK.
And finally, I can print something to the console, which is all I really want to do in this function
anyway.
OK.
So what I'm going to put in there when I'm going to print is see dot info, log dot print line.
And I'll just print out I'll use format to death.
I know I can do it a different way, but this works.
My format string is load time column and then a string took and then another string, and my replacements
for those two s's are name and elapsed.
OK, so now I have this function, and once I switch to my other application, I'll do a Gomaa vendor
to make sure that it knows about the function I just added from the celebrity's package, and I'm looking
in the Handler's doggo file, which of course, is inside the Hemmer's folder.
OK, now what I'm going to do is right here in the home function, I'm going to put this in.
I'm going to use that function.
We just used defer and I'll go to H Dot app dot load time, right?
That and I'll just handed timed right now.
OK?
And I did the import of time for me, so life is good.
Hopefully, that arrow will go away in a minute because it's actually up there.
It did.
OK, so now restart my application.
Make a restart.
So that stops.
It builds it.
And now I'm going to go to my Web browser and just load the whole homepage a couple of times and see
how long it takes when we have jet in development mode turned on.
So reload once, twice, three times.
And if I go back now and look at my console, I can see right here.
It took eight hundred and fourteen mutes to Trinity four 320.
OK, now eight hundred and fourteen, and then a two hundred and eighty four, then three twenty.
So a wide range.
But those are the numbers.
Now let's switch back to celebrities.
Go back to celebrities.
Don't go in.
Let's comment.
Jet in development mode out in me where we declare the verb use.
So that's commented out now.
Now we'll switch back to my other application and I'll restart my app.
Make restart.
I remember there were 14 two hundred and eighty four and three hundred and twenty.
Which seems pretty fast, really.
Now I'll go back to my Web browser and I'll reload the page three more times once.
Twice.
Three times.
And it looked about the same amount of time to me.
I can't see any difference when you look in the console instead of 800 and some of the very first time
it took seven hundred and eighty two because it passed it once then is stored it in memory in every
request.
After that, look how much it drops down.
Forty seven seventeen, it becomes a lot faster and it's also not cluttering up memory and forcing the
garbage collector to work really hard.
So what I want to do somehow is to go back to celebrities and basically say when I'm in development
mode, when I'm working as a developer, I want this to be there.
But when I'm not, I don't want it to be there.
And of course, that's pretty easy.
We have right in our own file something that's called debug.
So we populated the celebrities type with a variable called debug, which is true or false.
So all I really need to do is this if sea dog debug right there, then do one thing else do something
else.
And of course, if I'm in debug mode, I want to cut this out of here, actually, and do that, I want
all of this.
Cut all of these, so we're I'm declaring The View's variable and then setting secret views.
I'll cut that one out.
I'll paste one in here and I'll paste one in here.
Now, if if I'm in debug mode, I don't want that comment at all.
I want that there.
But if I am in production mode, I'm not in debug otherwise and I don't want it there, so I'll just
delete that line entirely.
All right.
Now let's go back to our other application.
My app.
And let's look at our data on file and make sure that debug is set to true.
It is, but in production, I'll set that defaults and I'm not going to be reloading the jet templates
from disk every time I turn around and cluttering up memory.
Instead, they'll just be read and passed once and then stored in memory until the next time the application
restarts.
And that is far more efficient.