So welcome to working with concurrency and go.
In this course we're going to cover just how effective and how useful the programming language known
as GO is at writing concurrent programs.
And we're going to have a look at why and when you should use concurrency and when you shouldn't.
Okay, now go has a very different approach to concurrency than most other programming languages, and
it's summed up by this statement, which was produced by the authors of Go Don't Communicate by sharing
memory, share memory by communicating.
And of course, this begs the question who's communicating?
What's going on here?
Who's talking to whom?
Well, Ingo, it's remarkably easy to fire something off so that it runs in the background.
So say you're writing a program and you have two functions and you want them to run at the same time
to make that happen, you just type the word, go before the call to those functions and suddenly they're
running concurrently in the background.
But once you fire something off into the background, how do you talk to it?
Well, there's a number of ways of talking to it.
You can use primitives.
And this comes from something called the sync package in go standard library, where you can lock something,
you can say, I'm using this, nobody else can touch this until I'm done with it.
Or you can say Once I'm done this program, I'm going to tell something called a wake group that I'm
finished so you can do it that way.
Or and this is the more common way and the more useful way and I think the more productive way in go.
You can have go routines, talk to one another using something called channels, and we'll be covering
channels extensively as this course goes on.
Now, if you were to take that statement and break it down into, you know, longer sentences that make
more sense, you might restate it this way don't over engineer your program by using shared memory and
complicated synchronization primitives instead use message passing between go routines so that variables
and data can be used in the appropriate sequence.
And I think, you know, this is a bit wordy, but it makes things, I think a little bit clearer.
Don't just lock memory or say to someone, Hey, I'm using this, you can't use it.
Instead, just pass data around using channels and channels, as far as I know, are pretty much unique
to go and they're incredibly useful and we'll be covering those in detail as time goes on.
Now, another thing to bear in mind, a golden rule for concurrency.
If you don't need it, don't use it.
Concurrent programming is error prone, even go, which makes it easier.
It doesn't make it easy, it just makes it easier.
And when you're running concurrent programs, it's remarkably easy to introduce a problem that you might
not see for months or in some cases, even years.
Okay, so if you don't need concurrency, just don't use it.
So in other words, keep your application's complexity as simple as you possibly can.
Keep things to a minimum.
It's easier to write this kind of code.
It's easier to understand this kind of code, and it's easier to maintain this kind of code.
But having said that, there are lots of situations when concurrency just makes sense.
Now, what are we going to cover in this course?
We're going to start by looking at the basic types in the sink package.
Those would be mutex is sometimes called semaphores and weight groups, and we'll go through three classic
computer science problems.
And here's what will have a detailed look at channels in the Sleeping Barbara problem, which I'll get
to momentarily.
So we're going to look at the producer consumer problem.
We're going to write a simple text based program that takes the problem of something that's being produced.
In this case, we're going to be a pizzeria and something that's being consumed, people placing orders
for pizzas and we're going to solve concurrency problems.
Using that example, we'll also have a look at the dining philosopher problem, which is a lot of fun,
and I'll go through that in detail when we get to that part of the course.
But it's a really interesting problem.
That's a bit of a challenge to solve.
And the last classic problem we're going to look at is the sleeping barber problem.
Again, this one is a lot of fun and all three of these are highly contrived examples, exactly what
you would find in a first year computer science course, but the classics for a reason.
These kinds of problems give students excellent exposure to the problems you find in concurrent programming,
and they also force students to figure out the most efficient means of solving these problems.
So once you've gone through these three problems with me, you'll have a solid understanding of when
and where to use mutex, when and where to use weight groups and when and where to use channels and
the different kinds of channels and so forth that you have at your disposal in go.
Now, once we're finished those three problems, we're also going to have a look at a more real world
scenario.
And this is where we build a subset of some larger imaginary service.
So in this service, consumers have the ability to register, to create an account, to have that account
verified through email, and then they can buy one of a series of available subscriptions.
And I'm calling those and this isn't terribly original, but here you go.
Bronze, silver and gold packages.
Now, once they buy these packages, one of these packages, we're going to generate an invoice, we're
going to send an email and we're going to generate a PDF manual, a customized PDF manual that we'll
send to that user.
Now, the invoice will be dead simple.
The manual will be dead simple because those things aren't important for what we're trying to cover
in this course.
What's important is we're going to do those things concurrently, and we'll also figure out how to write
tests for concurrent programs, which is absolutely critical.
Any time you're writing concurrent programming, just because it's so easy to introduce an error and
not be aware that you've done so.
All right.
This will be a lot of fun.
Let's get started.