So I don't want to spend a lot of time talking about myself, but I suspect it's important to at least
give some kind of introduction.
I have been working in the software industry as an independent contractor for 25 years.
I'll show a little bit more now, and I've also been teaching at the university level since 1991, which
means I do have a Ph.D. actually, I have a Ph.D. in English literature and computer science and in
education.
But don't hold that against me.
I teach at the university because I enjoy it, and it is certainly not my main source of income.
I have won a bunch of awards regionally, nationally and internationally, including an Apple Award
at one point.
And I've held contracts with KeyBank, with General Motors, with Hewlett Packard, with Sprint and
many, many others across Canada, the United States and Europe.
And well mean I could talk about myself endlessly, but at the end of the day, I've been working in
this field for a long time.
I've been teaching for a long time and I really enjoy teaching.
So let's get to it.