Chances are you already have go installed.
But if not, let's install it and let's make sure we have the latest version.
So to get go, we go to go door dev and there's a link to this in the course resources for this lecture.
And we click this download button right here and that pops up a new window and you have your feature
downloads.
If you're on Windows, you want this version.
And at the time I record this go 1.18 is just out.
If you're on a mac with an intel processor, you want this one.
If you're on Linux, you want this one, and if you're on one of the newer Macs, you're not going to
want to get Darwin amd64, you're going to want to come down here and get Darwin Arm64 That's the one
you want if you have an apple chip.
So download that and install it and it's a very straightforward process and let's move on.