Chances are you probably already have your favorite ID for working with go.
But if not.
Visual Studio code is free and it will do the job.
Now there's a link to this page and of course resources for this lecture.
Now, as you can see, you can download Visual Studio code for Windows, for Linux or for Mac.
And again, pay attention on the Mac part.
You can go universal, which will work for everything, or you can get one specifically for Intel Chip
or specifically for Apple silicon.
So download that and once you've got it downloaded, start it up.
And I already have it running here.
There's a few extensions you're going to want to install and the first ones you're going to want are
the go ones.
So I want to bring up the command palette and I'm going to search for and you can see right here, I'm
searching for go colon space and then start typing install and you're going to want the install update
tools and then click on that and then click on the top checkbox which will check everything here and
click okay and you'll see it processing all of the various extensions and it's all done.
So that's ready to go.
And the other thing you're going to want to do is to go to the extensions button here on the left hand
side.
It's third from the bottom in my case.
And I'm going to look for Go's template syntax, and that's my casual gym.
So search for go template syntax and click that.
And I already have it installed, but you'll see an install button.
So install that and we'll be all set.
That should be everything we need to get started.