So at some point during this course, you're probably going to want some help.
You run into a problem you can't solve on your own and you need some assistance, and I'm happy to provide
that.
But when you ask for help, there's a few steps you should take.
Number one, search online.
And chances are, you're going to do that by default.
But just to be safe.
Look online.
If you've run into a problem, chances are somebody has run into that before.
And a quick search on Google or your favorite search engine might give you the answer you're looking
for.
The second thing you can do if that doesn't help is in every lecture you'll be able to download the
source code for that lecture as it exists at the end of that lecture.
So you can always compare your code to mine and that might provide some assistance as well.
If that doesn't help, check the Q&amp;A section.
Somebody might have already asked a question very similar to yours, and the answer you're looking for
might be found there.
Finally, feel free to ask a question of your own in the Q&amp;A section, but if you do so, make sure
you give me some code to look at.
Ideally, give me a link to your git repository if you have one.
If not, please be sure to include enough code so that I can look at what you're doing and try to provide
some useful assistance.
Otherwise, I'm just guessing, and that's not terribly helpful.
All right.
Let's move on.