I just want to take a few moments to talk about mistakes.
Mistakes happen all the time in software development.
And since this is an intermediate course, chances are you've made a few mistakes of your own.
Well, one of the things I wanted to suggest is that during this course, I am going to make mistakes
and I'm not going to edit them out of the lectures.
Everyone makes mistakes.
And in fact, making mistakes is part of the software development process.
Chances are, if you're a developer, you spend at least five or 6 hours every week, if not considerably
more, fixing your own mistakes or fixing someone else's.
So as this course goes on, I will inevitably make mistakes.
Some of them will be trivial and some will be somewhat less than trivial.
But I'm not going to edit them out.
Instead, I'll let you watch me identify and fix those problems.
And that's just a little heads up.
I always find it a little amusing to watch polished, heavily edited lectures where people appear to
be absolutely perfect in every way.
And we're not.
We're all human.
We make mistakes.
You do?
I do.
And you're going to get to see me make more than one, I'm sure.