Hello and welcome to the Gold Anchor Academy language course in this issue, and we want to continue
the variable concept.
In the previous session, we could define the variables without the type.
And in this case, we consider the case where the expression is removed.
If the expression is removed, then the variable holds zero values for defined like zero four, no false
for Bosnians in need for end fees and response time.
So there is no such concept of an initialized variable in gold language.
Now let's do an example for this case.
First, we define two variables that declared in initialize without expiration, so we write that variable
one by the time end and without initialize.
Now go to the next line and define another variant and like that value the two by the time string and
VAR
variable three by the time followed.
64.
Now displayed a variable, so do the following F.A. dance print of the value of variable one columns
per cent, the back slash and insert rally about one and do this print EF four and other variables like
affinity dot print of
the value of variable to column because the variable too is studying.
So we define per cent s as format testing and practice list and insert variable two and four variable
three.
We write a Fenty's Dot Print F
the value of variable three columns because the type of variable threes float 64.
So we said per cent f as convert to character or format testing for this value of a backslash and set
variable three.
Now reformat the code, save the project and execute the curriculum.
So go to terminal and run the comment.
Go round backslash.
May that go.
Now we can see the output.
The value of variable one is zero.
The value of variable two is NEEN and the value of variable three is zero point zero.
So we could define variables without expression and c the default value for them.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it.
Then we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.