Hello and welcome to the Go programming language course in the previous session, we could define variables
without expression and indecision.
Do you want to do another case?
If you use time, then you are allowed to declare multiple variables of the same time in the single
declaration.
For this case, we define three variables in line.
So we write that define variable name like variable, one comma defined and another variable name variable
two comma and variable three.
And these three variables has the same type line integer.
And now we initialize them one by one for variable one.
For example, we set two comma for second variable or variable to be set, for example, 403 and fifty
four and four variable three we set, for example, sixty seven.
We were able to define multiple variables of the same time are declared and initialized in a single
line.
Now go to the next line and display the values of these variables.
If and you don't treat if
the value of vanity building one column percent, the back is less an insert variable.
One, we said Person D as formatted sitting because all the variable has the integer type.
So copy these lines and paste it for another variable.
And now change the variable names and messages variable to
valuable tool and three insert variable three.
Now reformat the code, save the project and execute the program.
Just go to a terminal, go to a project folder.
See the variables.
Clearer screen and execute program by the comment Go Run Dot matches, less Maine dot gov.
Now we can see the output.
The value of variable one is to the value of variable to is four hundred and fifty four and the value
of variable 367.
So in this case, we could define multiple variables of the same type in the single declaration in order
not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it, then we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.