Hello and welcome to the golden programming language course in this part of your station.
They could define multiple variables of the same type in the single declaration and in decision.
We want to do another case.
If you remove time, then you are allowed to declare multiple variables of a different type in the single
declaration, the type of value that is determined by the initialized values.
Let's go to do an example.
First, define multiple variables of different types.
So we write that variable in one comma variable two comma variable three and don't define any time for
each variable equals and initialize then.
For example, for the variable one, we set two and four second variable.
We set a string value, for example, go blank.
And for the third variable, we said the float value, for example, six to seven point fifty six.
Now we were able to define multiple variables of different tides are declared in initialized in the
single line.
So let's go to display the about variables by the print f function.
So the right thing to do art print off the value of variable number one column setters and these formats
thing for the variable one because the value of it is.
And so the type of this variable, should the integer and go to the next section, insert name of variable
and go to the next line and set a time of the variable.
So we write F.A. Dot Print F, the type of variable one column person to operate a case for display.
The type of the variable we used from T as formatted string and search name override is variable, so
copy these two lines and go to a new line.
Paste here for display and other variables, for example, for variable two because it initialized by
the string values.
So we change the formatted string to the person s and change name or variable to variable tool
variable two
and four variable three.
Because we initialize this variable by the float value, we change it two percent F.
Formatted string.
And we changed name of variable to variable three.
OK.
To be able to display each value in the output on a new line, we use back legend at the end of the
comment.
So the add back is finish and end of each comment.
Reformat the code and save the project and execute the program.
Now go to Terminal First Go Good project folders variables here is getting around the project by the
comment Go wrong, the back is this man that glow.
OK, now we can see the output.
The value of variable one is two and type of this variable is in the value of second.
Variable is go blank and type of it is extreme and the value are variable.
Three is sixty seven point fifty six and the time of this variable is flawed.
So we could define multiple variables of a different type in the singular declaration.
In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.