Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in the previous session, we could define
multiple variables of a different type in the single declaration.
And in this session, we want to do another case.
If you declared a variable Veit-Wild, assigning it a value go blank will automatically bind a different
value to the variable.
Let's do an example.
First, define some variable without initialize.
Then, for example, that no one by the time followed 32 and that norm two by the time
16.
And that first name by the time is three.
And why, for example, married by the time, Paul.
OK.
We could define for variable without initialize, then in this case, the compiler considers the default
value for the defined variable and base of its type, assigned the default value to that variable.
Now we want to display the value of these variables, so we'll be right if emptied out field and
known one and FP.
No to FP.
First name and FP.
OK.
Reformat the call, save the project and execute the program first, go to the project folder, see
the variables clear screen and execute the program by the comment Go round dot slash.
May that go.
Now we can see the output.
The default value for the number one by the time flow 32 is zero.
The default value for the nom to by the time integer is zero.
The default value for the first name by the time is string is Neal and the default value for the mattei
by the time Boolean is false.
Now we could see that Golang initialize the variables by the default values in order, not by allowing
the time of decision and will finish it, and we'll continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.