Hello and welcome to the golems programming language course in the previous session.
We could define variable without assigning it and go land automatically will bind the default value
to the variable.
And in this session, we want to do another case variables declaration can be grouped together into
blocks for greater readability and good quality.
So let's do an example to do this.
First, use the VAD keyboard and then create open and close practices and define its variable between
parentheses.
So we write that he will open and close prophecies and define variables between them.
For example, first name initialise by the value chain.
Go to the next line.
Define another variable like no one equals 300.
And number two equals twenty point sixty five.
And define another variable like mad8 equals.
True.
In this case, we defined four variables by the type string integer float and Boolean.
Now go out of the ballpark and display these variables.
So we write FP first name.
Go to the next line FP No.
One and display No.
Two
and display Boolean variable merit.
OK.
Reformat the code, save the project and execute the program.
So go to Terminal first to screen, go to Project Folder, see the variables and run the program by
the comment.
Go run the text.
That's me that go.
Now we can see the output.
In this case, we could define variables.
Declaration can be grouped together into blocks in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.