In this section of the course, I want to turn her attention to another classic problem that you find
in the field of computer science, and it's one that's called the dining philosophers.
So let's have a look at what the problem is.
Well, like the last problem, this one was introduced by Dijkstra in 1965.
So it's been around for a while and it's been solved in many different ways.
And here's the basis of the problem.
Five philosophers live in a house together, and they always eat together, always at the same table,
and they always sit in the same place.
So that's one given.
The second thing is that they always eat a special kind of spaghetti, and this requires two forks.
You have to have two forks in order to be able to eat this spaghetti.
It's really thick or something like that.
It doesn't matter.
The point is, you have to have two forks.
Now there are two forks next to each plate.
But the way that they're arranged means that no two neighbors can be eating at the same time.
Now, the problem is, how do you write a program that ensures that no philosopher will starve?
Now, what will make this a little bit clearer is an illustration, a picture.
Let's see how the table is laid out.
So we have a round table, we have five plates, and every plate has two forks beside it.
But there are only five forks.
If we had one more, this wouldn't be much of an issue, but we don't.
So the problem is, if the philosopher in the lower left hand corner wants to eat, he has to get both
forks, but he's sharing a fork with his neighbor.
So it's a highly contrived problem, but it's an excellent example of the kind of problem where concurrency
is a good solution.
Now, in this section with the dining philosophers, we're going to go over not channels.
We're going to leave those to a later problem.
Instead, we'll solve this problem using the sink package with sink, dot, wait group and sink mutex.
Okay, let's get started.