So let's get started with our Dining Philosophers project.
And as I said in the introduction, I'm not going to solve this using channels.
We'll get back to those before too long, so don't worry about that.
Instead, I'm going to solve this using the sink package, sink, dot mutex and sink dot wait group.
So I have a new folder open here in Visual Studio code and as usual, I'll open my terminal and type
go mod in it and I'll just call mine dining.
Okay, so that creates my goal mod file.
Now I'll create a new file as usual, mico.
And this is in package main and it's going to have at least one function, of course, for me.
Now, when I'm writing code, I typically like to put a comment at the top that gives me a statement
of the problem, and there's no point in you watching me type that out.
So I've copied it to my clipboard and I'm going to paste it in here.
Okay.
So let's go through this again.
The dining philosophers is a well-known problem in computer science, and we have five philosophers
who live in a house.
They always eat together and they always sit at the same place in the table.
And the problem that they have is that they're eating spaghetti that requires two forks.
Now there are two forks next to each plate, but as that illustration I showed you in the introduction
demonstrates, we have five plates and five forks, and this is the problem.
No two neighbors can be eating at the same time.
So how am I going to solve that problem?
Well, let's write some comments like I normally do.
I'm going to have to have some variables.
So I'll put variables here and I'll just list the kind of variables I need to have.
I'm going to have to have, first of all, the philosophers.
No question about that.
Okay.
And I'm also going to have to keep track of things like, you know, who's eating, who's not eating.
I'm not sure.
But I know I'm going to have to have some variables and we'll populate those as we figure out exactly
what they are.
And in the main function, I'm probably going to want to print an introduction.
So some kind of introduction, introductory screen.
I'm going to print that out.
And I'm also going to have to make each philosopher try to eat.
So how am I going to do that?
Well, I'm probably going to spawn one go routine for each philosopher.
And that go routine will run until the philosophers finished eating.
Okay, so that's simple enough.
So that means I'm going to have to have some kind of for loop.
So maybe I'll have a list of philosophers.
Let's get a variable in here right now.
Just so we have something to work with, I'll create a variable, a package level variable called philosophers.
And it's going to be a slice of strings.
So I'll make it equal to a slice of string and I'll put in a bunch of philosophers.
Okay, so we'll just choose five.
So we'll have, say, Plato, and we'll have Socrates and maybe Aristotle, Haskell and Locke.
And again, it doesn't matter what these names are, we just need to have five of them.
Okay.
And I don't need parentheses around these.
I don't know where those came from.
My first lecture of the day.
So I have one coffee in me.
I'm going to blame it on that.
So now I have some philosophers.
And down here, I'm going to spit spawn some kind of go routine by going through that list of philosophers.
Well, that's easy, you know.
All I have to say is for say I index is starts at zero.
And I'm going to go as long as I have the length of philosophers.
So then of philosophers and I'll add one each time through.
And then I'll call a go routine or spawn a go routine.
So maybe I'll call that dining problem.
Go dining problem.
Now, that doesn't exist yet, and I don't know what kind of parameters I'm going to send to it.
But this gets us this gets us started.
So up here, above the main function, I'll just create a function called dining problem.
And I won't do anything right now.
I'll leave it empty.
But at least now my code is in showing me an error.
Okay, so I'm going to have to do that.
And somehow I'm going to have to make sure that when I spawn this go routine for a given philosopher,
that I have a means of keeping track of who has what fork in which hand.
In other words, this philosopher, the one that's that's called when I first spawn this go routine,
that person can't eat until they can get both the left fork and the right fork in their hand.
Okay, so we'll figure out how to do that before too long, probably here.
I'm going to have to have some kind of weight group, so maybe a backup of my variables.
I create a weight group here.
Var WG is a type sync dot weight group.
Okay.
So that means here, before I go into this for loop, I'm probably going to want to start that weight
group to get the correct number of semaphores in there.
So I'll just say WG and however long my slices strings philosopher's is okay and down here I'm definitely
going to have to wait.
WG To wait.
And of course, up at the dining problem, I want to defer.
WG Not done.
Okay, so that's a good start.
There's the overall structure of my program now.
There's a lot to figure out right now, but in essence, this is a good starting position.
So the thing to think about right now is what am I going to do up here in dining problem?
How am I going to ensure that a given philosopher is able to pick up both the left and right fork?
So this is enough to get us started.
In the next lecture, we'll have a look at how we determine whether or not someone is able to pick up
both forks.