So let's keep going with our dining philosophers problem.
And what I want to think about this time is the mutex.
We need to lock certain resources.
We know that we only have five forks and we also know that in order to be able to eat, a given philosopher
must be able to get both forks.
But before we do that, I have a spelling mistake here and it will bother me endlessly if I don't fix
it.
So let's change our two philosophers and copy and paste it here and paste it here.
And I may as well spell philosopher right here as well.
Okay, so let's think about the new taxes.
Now, I know that I have five philosophers in this slice of strings, and I know that I'm going to be
spawning one go routine for each philosopher.
And I have my weight group here and I'm waiting for it here and everything seems good.
But I do need to be able to pass, first of all, some information to the go routine, what philosopher
y dealing with.
And I'm also going to to be able to pass it to new taxes, one for the left fork and one for the right
fork.
So this is easy enough.
What a philosopher we going to pass.
Well, that will be philosophers at index.
All right.
Okay, so that will pass that parameter, which means up here, I have to be able to take that parameter.
So I'll just put it in philosopher and that will be of type string.
Okay, so that's the first thing I'm going to want to get.
I'm also going to want to get up here to New Texas and I'll call them just for the sake of simplicity,
dominant hand, which I have to spell, have dominant hand and other hand.
So for right and left and they're both going to be pointers to sync me mutex.
And of course that means I need to pass them here.
So where am I going to create those new taxes?
I suppose if I wanted to, I can create an array and put one new text for each fork, but that's going
to get complicated really quickly.
So instead, let's think about this.
Well, the first time through this, I'm going to want to be able to pass both the left fork and the
right fork.
Now I can create the right for that's easily done.
So let's do that one to start with.
Okay.
So inside of this for loop, I'll create a new tax for the right fork and I need it to be a pointer,
so I'll just say fork.
Right?
That's as good as a name as any.
That's a sign.
The value of a reference to the type synchrony tax right there.
Okay, so now I have the right for it, which means I can pass it right here.
So I'll pass fork.
Right.
Which I have to spell.
So that's easy enough.
But what about the other fork?
Well, when I go through this, if you think it through logically, every time I go through this loop.
The previous right fork, the one that's being created right here, that should actually be the left
fork.
So that's easy enough.
I can say fork left is equal to fork, right.
But the first time through, of course, I don't have a left fork, so maybe the place to create that
is outside the loop.
The very first mutex created is the one created before we start spawning go routines.
So I'll say fork left
is a sign the value of again a reference to sync the mutex.
And then I'm going to want to pass that here as well.
So I'll pass the left fork, first fork, left fork, left hand fork, right.
So that actually gives me a mutex and it will be the correct one for every single philosopher.
So the first time we go through this, I'm creating, the first time we start the program, I'm creating
my my left mutex fork left.
Then down here I create my right mutex, and then I pass both of those.
And then what was the right mutex?
Becomes the left mutex.
The next time through the loop.
And that will give me exactly the correct number of new taxes.
Okay.
Now, you might be saying to yourself, I thought you said you're never supposed to copy a mutex once
you create it.
And I seem to be doing that right here.
But remember, these are both pointers, so we're not copying a mutex.
We're making fork left equal to the pointer to an existing mutex.
So it points to the same location in memory and doesn't in fact copy it.
Okay, so we have those now up here in the dining problem.
Here's where we get to the heart of what we're trying to do.
So let's write some comments and we'll start working on them in the next lecture.
First thing I'm going to do is print a message.
I'm dealing with the philosopher, so I might print something like this philosopher is hungry.
Okay, then I'm going to want to lock both forks.
Okay.
So I want to attempt to get a lock or the left fork and the right fork, and this go routine will block
until it gets both of those locks.
Okay, so we'll just stop until I can get both locks.
Then we'll print out another message after that.
So we'll print out a message that the philosopher has both forks, print a message, and the messages
now would be something like philosopher, whatever is now eating and has both forks.
And we'll get to that in the next lecture.
And after that, we need to unlock the mute Texas.
Okay, so that's a good start.
In the next lecture, we'll start actually implementing the code that these comments refer to.