So we're working on the dining problem function, the one that's going to be spawned as one go routine
for each of the philosophers who are trying to eat.
And so far, we have we receive our philosopher as a string, and that's just the name of the philosopher.
So if it's index zero, it'll be Plato, so on and so forth.
And then we have two Mew Texas, one for the dominant hand and one for the other hand.
And let's change the name of those.
Let's call this one left hand or left fork and right fork, just because I have difficulty typing the
word dominant for whatever reason.
Okay, so first thing I want to do is to print out a message.
Now, every time I print a message, I'm going to want to pause a little bit again.
I don't want this screen to zip by at Lightspeed.
So what I'm going to do because I'm going to write a test for this later on is I'm going to come back
up here to our variables and I'll create a variable and I'll call it sleep time for sleep time.
And that's going to be equal to one.
Time's timed out second and the only reason I'm doing this and it didn't import time for me, so let's
try that again timed out second that the only reason I'm doing this is when I write a test I can just
set this variable to zero so it doesn't pause at all.
But in any case, let's print a message.
Now, what's the first message that should be printed out as soon as this go routine fires, as soon
as it's sent off in the background and it executes well, I think I'm just going to say.
Format.
Print line.
And I'll put in philosopher the name of the philosopher and then is hungry.
Now he's seated, seated at the table.
So somebody sat at the table.
Okay.
And then I'll sleep.
And all I have to do now is say, time out, sleep, and I'm going to sleep.
Sleep time.
Okay, so it'll be 1/2 when I run this program.
So that's the very first thing I'm going to do.
Then we say Lock both forks.
Well, let's make it a little more interesting.
I don't want this to execute, you know, really, really quickly.
Let's make sure that each philosopher eats at least three times.
Okay.
So up here, I can declare a constant and I'll just put constants,
and my constant will be constant.
Hunger.
How many times is the philosopher going to get hungry?
And I'm going to assume they're going to eat three times.
Okay, so we have this constant now.
Now back down in our dining problem.
I need to lock both forks, but I need to do it once for each time that this philosopher gets hungry.
Okay, so let's just do a simple for loop for and we'll say index II is assigned the value of hunger.
All right.
Is greater than zero, and each time through will decrement.
All right, one time.
Okay.
And I'll move this curly bracket down to here and tab all this in, and now we can get started on this.
So let's pretend other message here, let's say format or print line and I'll say philosopher
is hungry.
Okay, and I'll sleep again.
Time, dot, sleep, sleep time.
Now I try to get a lock on both forks.
So we'll do the first one.
Say left fork, dot lock.
And again, this go routine will stop.
At this point, it will block until it can get a lock for the left fork.
Okay.
And of course, we have to do the same thing for the other one.
But after we get that fork, print out a message format of print if.
So we'll tab things in a little bit just so it's easier to read.
Then we'll put the philosophers name.
Okay.
And then we'll say picked up the fork to his right.
And our substitution for that is just, of course, philosopher.
So we have that message.
Now we'll duplicate this whole thing and do the same thing for the other fork.
But this time, it's right for clock.
Right fork, lock.
Picked up the fork to his left.
And I have left here and right here.
I don't know where that came from.
Left and right.
That makes more sense.
Okay, so we've picked up two forks at this point.
We've printed out the message.
So now our go our go routine continues on.
And here's where the next comment needs to get populated.
So all we need to say now is right here.
Format dot print line
philosopher has both forks and is eating.
Okay, so we eat now.
We want to rest here for a little bit while he's eating and give him some time to finish that spaghetti.
So we'll say time to sleep.
And this time I'll define another variable up here.
So we'll make this one ver e to time equals.
And how long should he have to eat?
Say, 3 seconds.
Three times.
Time got second.
And again, that's just so.
When I write the tests, I can set this to zero.
Okay.
And we'll make this one each time.
So the philosopher's eating.
And after he's done, of course, he's going to put the forks down.
So we need to unlock the new taxes.
And all we need to say here is right fork, unlock, left fork, unlock, and print out a message.
So format, print F
and we'll put a tab.
And again and we'll say percent ask for the philosophers name.
Put down the fork on his right and the substitution is philosopher and we'll duplicate that and make
this one left.
And just to make things a little more readable, let's take this cut it out of here and paste it in
front of that one and get rid of this blank line.
And that way it seems to make more sense.
You unlock the right fork, print the message, you unlock the left fork, print the message.
Okay.
It doesn't really matter.
It would run so fast, but I just like it better.
And then we'll pass.
Time dot.
Sleep.
Sleep time.
Okay.
So what happens once we finish this big for loop, which will run for hunger times and constant the
constant hunger is set to three well after we get inside of that.
Of course, at this point, the philosopher's actually done eating and that philosopher can get up and
leave the table.
So it lets print out a message, print out, done message.
So we'll say format dog, print line
philosopher is satisfied and then we'll let him pause for a minute.
Don't want to rush him of the door.
So time to sleep.
Sleep time.
And the last thing to do here, of course, is to let us know that this particular philosopher has left
the table.
So we'll put formatted print, long print line, and the philosophers name has left the table.
And at this point we should have locked both forks three times, unlocked both forks three times, and
of course, eaten three times.
Okay, so let's go back down to our main function and see what we have left out of this.
What we need to print our introductory message.
So let's say format the print line
and we'll just put the dining philosophy.
So first problem like that and then I'll duplicated and underline it by using hyphens just so it's nice
and readable.
Here we go.
And now down here.
After the weight group.
Let's print out a closing message.
So format or print line once again and we'll say the table is empty and that's enough.
Okay, so so in theory, at this point, this should work.
So in the next lecture, we'll run it, make sure that everything works as expected, and then we'll
try to complicate the issue a little bit.
Okay, so let's move on.