So let's try out our program and see if we got everything right.
But before we do that, I did have a typo last time around and I think it was a copy and paste error
and I'm sure you noticed it.
But here, when I unlock the new taxes in the dining problem function for some reason I have.
I'm putting down the fork on his right twice.
Of course, this should say left.
Okay, so with that one change, let's open it up and see how it goes.
So go.
Run.
Okay.
So far so good.
Oh.
I see I have some print fs where I didn't put a carriage return in there, but that's not a big deal.
It's running anyway.
So far so good.
People are leaving the table.
Okay.
The table is empty.
Now, as you can see, I should have the carriage return after some print statement.
So let's go fix that.
So print f there should be a slash in here, and I'll copy that and paste it after this print out.
And that was a print line.
And after this print s, this print f and see if we have any more.
Looks like that's it.
So if I run this again now, it should format properly.
Go.
Run, Dot.
That looks better now.
I can see what's going on.
So as you can see, as is to be expected, since this is running concurrently and using new taxes,
things don't occur in perfectly sequential order.
In some cases, we have people picking up a fork on one side and then having to wait for the other one
to be available.
But it is doing exactly what I expected it to do.
Perfect.
So let's complicate things a little bit in the next lecture.
And after that, I'll have a challenge for you.
Okay.
So nothing terribly difficult, but let's move on.