So just for fun, let's add one more thing to this solution to the dining philosopher's problem that
will make it closer to the solution that's actually required by the original version, and that is giving
philosophers time to think.
So what I want to do this time around, and it's not difficult at all, is to add a delay after the
philosopher finishes eating, but before the philosopher drops the forks where he begins to think and
he'll think for some predetermined amount of time.
So what I'll do is come up to the top here and I'll put another variable in, I'll put it in var think
time and that will be equal to 1/2 one times time dot second.
Okay.
And just to make it run a little bit faster, I'll make eating time only 2 seconds.
So I have this variable.
Now, where am I going to put this?
Well, obviously each time the philosopher finishes eating and each philosopher gets hungry and eats
three times, it would be after they start eating, but before they drop the forks.
So right here in the function dining problem after we print this has both forks and is eating message.
But before we unlock the mutex is in print out these messages.
We can just put this in, give the philosopher some time to think and all we are going to do is say
format op print line philosopher.
He's thinking, okay, and then we'll wait the appropriate length of time, time to sleep, and it will
be think time and that's all there is to it.
So now when I run this, I should see that message coming periodically.
Okay, so go run Dot.
And this is just to make it closer to the solution that was actually required back when it was first
proposed in 1965.
And there they are.
They're thinking Plato is thinking at the same time as Aristotle.
It's going a little bit faster now, which is good.
Almost done.
People have left the table and the program ran exactly as intended.
Now, in the next lecture, I'm going to give you a bit of a challenge.
Nothing terribly difficult and something that you have all the information you need to complete successfully.
So we'll have that challenge in the next lecture and then I'll show you how I solve the challenge.
Okay, let's move on.