So this time around, I want to give you a bit of a challenge, and it's not difficult at all.
And bear in mind that if this was a university classroom, I would give you just this right here.
After we covered new taxes and wait groups, this is the information I would have given you with a bit
more detail, of course, but just asking you to complete the problem on your own and you would have
about a week to do it.
But this is not a university classroom, so this challenge is considerably easier.
What I want you to do is to keep track of when each of these philosophers is finished eating.
In other words, they've eaten three times.
They've picked up the forks three times.
They've dropped three drop the first three times and they're done.
And then down here at the very end, after you print out the message, the table is empty, you print
out the order in which people finished.
So that should be pretty straightforward.
You shouldn't have much difficulty with this at all.
Now, how you solve it is entirely up to you, but I'll show you how I solved it in the next lecture.