So I suspect that most of you didn't have much difficulty with this challenge at all.
And I'll show you how I did it and also show you something that is not yet implementing this code.
But I suspect that some of you went most of the way through the problem but left one thing out.
And it's really easy to do that.
And that's, of course, the entire reason why I'm giving you this challenge.
So how did I tackle this?
Well, on line 28 in my code, I declared a new variable called Order Finished, which is just a slice
of strings, which of course is an empty slice of strings once I declare this variable.
Then down here in the dining problem, not inside this for loop, but after we're finished eating the
very end of this function I put in order finished equals append, order finished and philosopher.
In other words, I'm appending the philosopher's name to the slice of strings called order.
Finished.
That's seems simple enough.
Then, at the very end of the program, after the table is empty, I just put in some hyphens just to
separate things and I just used format print F and my format string is order finished with a placeholder
for a string, then a character.
I remembered it this time that I use the join method from the strings package, which is part of the
standard library to explode the order finished slice of strings into a whole bunch of strings separated
by a comma and a space.
So let's run a program.
And this is where I think some of you at least you probably just stopped because you open your terminal
and you said Go run dot and ran the program.
So far, so good.
People are hungry.
They're eating.
Some of them were thinking.
They're eating, thinking.
We'll give this a chance to finish and see what we get for our final string.
We had five philosophers eating.
We should have five people in that last message printed out.
Haskell, Aristotle, Locke, Plato, Socrates.
Everything seems perfect.
And of course, I suspect that some of you stopped here.
And if you did, don't feel bad.
If you're just getting your feet wet with concurrency, you're going to make mistakes.
Okay.
But there is a problem here.
And the problem is, once again, we have a potential race condition now because we have all these delays
in there.
And that's part of the reason why I put them in.
We don't actually see it when we run this program sometimes.
But the reality is that I have one go routine running for each of the philosophers in the background.
So there's five versions of this running concurrently at some point and they're all accessing order
finished.
And of course, what I need to do is to create a mutex for that, a lock and unlock line.
So let's go back up to the top of the program and fix it.
And what I'm going to declare here is a package level variable called order mutex, which is of type
sync of mutex right there.
Okay.
So sync up mutex.
And then down here, lock this.
So order mutex.
Don't lock
and order mutex to unlock.
And now my race condition is gone.
And if you forgot that particular step, don't feel bad at all.
You're not the only person to have an easily hidden race condition appear in their code.
And that's why when you're running any program that has multiple go routines, running concurrently,
it's good to get in the habit of typing.
Go, run, dash, race, dog.
Okay.
All right, so let's move on and write a test for our program.