So as a last step in this section, let's write a simple test for our program.
And this is dead simple.
I'll create a new file called, not surprisingly, main underscore Tesco.
And this is in package main.
Package main.
Okay.
And we'll declare one function here func and I'll call it test underscore main with a parameter T,
which is a pointer to testing T there.
So how are we going to do this?
Well, if you recall, I set up some variables and package level variables over here.
So sleep time, eat time and think time.
And I'm going to set those all to be zero.
So the test will run very, very quickly.
So we'll say eat time is equal to zero times timed out, second to get it in the right type.
Okay.
And we'll do the same thing with think time.
Try that again.
Think time is equal to zero times.
Time to second and finally sleep time is equal to zero eight.
Try that again.
Zero times the time dot second.
Okay.
So I set those to be zero.
So the program should run very quickly and I could do it just like this.
And in fact, some of you, if you did write a test, a good for you, if you did before you finish
the challenge, you might just run main and then you just check to make sure.
A really simple test if the length of and it would be order finished.
The length of that is not equal to five and that again not equal to five.
Then we have an error because you should have five things in that slice.
So what we can say is t dot error wrong number of entries in slice or whatever you want.
Okay.
So if I run the program like this and I clear the screen, just say go test dot.
It passes.
Okay.
Now, here's an interesting thing.
I want to make sure this works many, many times.
So I might do it like this.
Just so let's run the program 100 times for I is assign the value of zero.
I is less than 100.
I plus plus I'm going to run this test 100 times, which means I have to close my parentheses here,
my my curly brackets and format everything.
And before I go through the next iteration, I have to make my slice of strings empty again.
So order finished is equal to just a slice of strings and empty one.
Okay.
And run the program again.
Go test it.
And then I closed the terminal and put this coal to Main exactly where it should be.
Right here.
Cut that out of there.
That was sloppy and cold.
Mean here were supposed to be cold and clear the screen and run the test again.
This should pass.
And it did.
No problem.
But an interesting thing about this, of course, is if I go back to Main go and I comment about this
mutex, order mutex and I come down here and commit these to order, mutex is lock.
Okay.
Lock and unlock.
And go back to my test.
And here's an illustration of just how easy it is to miss a race condition.
And I comment on this line and I comment at the closing race bracket or parentheses for it.
Okay.
And run the test just once.
Go test dot.
It might pass.
And it did.
And I want it again.
And it might past.
Okay.
Now it's caching at this time, so that doesn't help.
But if I uncomment this and run the test 100 times, I'm going to bet it's going to fail at least once.
And it didn't.
Let's make it a thousand times.
We're on it again.
Okay.
And it failed.
Okay?
And it failed in several places, actually.
And it failed because that race condition only shows up once in a while.
Okay.
So I'm going to put this back like it was back to 100 and go back over here and undo my changes.
So undo that, undo that and undo that.
And things are back to where they should be.
So now if I run the test one more time, it should pass as cache this time.
But it even if I clear the cache, that test will pass.
And that's just to demonstrate how I could actually add something to my code as I did last time around.
I added that order that everyone finishes not think about having to implement a new text, write a test
that just runs the code once.
And when I run the code it seems to run perfectly, and when I run the test it seems to run perfectly
unless I use that dash race or run the test many, many times.
So something to be absolutely careful about.
Race conditions can be really hard to spot.
So get in the habit of running your code with that dash race flag and get in the habit of doing the
same thing when you run your tests.
Okay, let's move on in the next section to another classic problem.
And this one we're going to solve just using channels.
We're not going to have any weight groups or any new taxes.
We're going to do everything with channels.
And it's called the Sleeping Barbara problem and it's a lot of fun.