One of the things you often have to do with a Web application is send email, and that's what this section
of the course is all about.
We're going to write functionality right into the celebrity's package that makes it easier to send email
using SMTP servers or one of a number of third party services like Mail Gun to send email using an API.
And right now, I'm in the Celebrity House project and I'll put mail in its own package, so I'm going
to create a new folder over here at the root level of my project, and I'm going to call it Mailer.
And inside of that, I'll create a file called mail logo.
And of course, it has the package mail.
Now we're going to need a number of things in order to send email.
We could, if we wanted, just write a function that sends email and we wait for that function to execute
and then look at the result and on we go.
But that's pretty inefficient because sending mail can be a pretty slow process, and we don't want
sending mail to slow down our application.
So what we'll do instead is create a couple of types one for a mail system, which will have things
like What the domain are we sending from where our mail templates stored?
What's our mail host?
Things like that will also create a type for a an individual message.
So let's get started with that.
So I'll create a type right here, and I'll call it mail with a capital m because it needs to be exported
and it's just a struct and it has a number of fields.
So what sorts of things are we going to need to send mail?
Well, obviously we need to know what domain is it coming from?
And that'll just be a string.
And we're also going to say, where are the mail templates stored?
Because we want to send nicely formatted messages, not just plain text, and that'll be a string as
well.
And that's just a path to a directory.
What's our mail host for sending SMTP or through an API?
We still have to have a host.
What port do we send to?
And that'll be like twenty five or five, eighty seven or for sixty?
We'll store that is a string.
Also, when you log on to as SMTP server to send mail, you need a username, which is going to be a
string and a password, which will also be a string.
Is there SMTP server or a mail service encrypted?
So I'll say encryption, which will be a string.
That'll be something like SSL or tell us what's our default from address?
Also a string and our default from a name, from name, not from from name, but should also be a string.
And then we're going to have one called jobs, and that will be mail jobs.
And that's just going to be a channel, a channel of type message.
And that doesn't exist yet, but it will in a minute.
So don't worry about it.
We'll also want to look for results from that channel.
What happened when we tried to send mail?
So I'll call that results.
And it's a channel of type result, another type that doesn't exist yet, but it will in a moment.
And if we're sending using it, using an API, which API, that'll be a string and we'll have to have
an API key.
We shall also be a string and the URL for that API.
So I call it API URL just so we know what it is.
You URL string.
OK, so there's our first Typekit now we need one for individual messages.
So type of message and this is a mail message and it's just a struct, and it's going to have to have
a few things.
Who was the email message from in case we want to override the default from name or from address?
So from and from name, both of type string.
And who's it to which is a string and the subject of the email, which is a string?
And what template do we want to use?
And that will be a template of some sort like a go template or a template, and we'll call that one
a string as well, because it's just the name of the template.
Does the email have any attachments?
And that will be a slice of string because you might have more than one attachment or no attachments.
And then any data we want to pass to the template when we render it now, we don't know what that's
going to be, so I'll just call it an interface like that.
And we also need our result type.
So and that should be singular result
type result, which is a struct.
And it just has two things.
Success.
Did the mail go successfully or not?
So it's a Boolean and any kind of error.
We got error, which is of type error.
OK.
So there are basic types, so I'll save this to format it.
That looks better now in order to use those channels.
Of course, we need some kind of function that actually listens for mail, so I'm going to create a
function here that's going to have the receiver of M Pointer to the type of mail.
And we're going to listen for male function that takes no arguments.
OK.
And this has an endless for loop because we're going to run this in the background.
And while that's happening, we're going to take anything we get from the jobs channel up there in the
mail type.
And we're going to do something with it, so will declare a variable called MSG because it's going to
be a mail message and that listens for any incoming messages on the jobs channel.
And then we're going to call a function that doesn't exist yet, but it will in a minute, we're going
to call from the receiver M.
We're going to call a function called send and we're going to send the message.
OK, now that doesn't exist yet, but don't worry about it.
But we will check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll do something.
Otherwise we'll do something else.
Now what happens if there is an error?
Scroll up and give us some room here.
If there's an error, when we try to send the message, we need to send some something to the results
channel.
And what we'll send is the fact that the mail didn't go and whatever the error is, so to the channel
end results, we'll send it a result.
And we'll populate his fields as being false on the air.
But if it did go successfully and we'll do the same thing, we'll just send a different payload up results
receives a new result.
And this time.
True success is true with no air.
OK.
So now let's write that function send and we'll just do a stub to get it going right now.
So function receiver of M Pointer to mail.
We want this to be called send and it's going to receive mzgee of type message and this can return potentially
an error.
OK, now at this point, we have to make a decision.
Are we sending using a standard SMTP server, which is considered legacy for most web applications these
days?
Or are we sending this through an API?
So for right now, I'm going to suggest that we're just going to send using SMTP server and we'll take
care of sending using mail gun or another third party service after we get the SMTP it working.
OK.
So I'll just put a comment in here to do.
Are we using an API or SMTP?
OK, so we have to take care of that later on.
But what we're going to do instead right now is we're going to return another function.
We're going to return em which and we're going to call a function that doesn't exist yet called send
SMTP message, and it's going to require the message.
OK.
So obviously, we need to define that function.
So let's create another function func with receiver of importer to mail, and we'll call this one send
SMTP message and it takes one parameter mzgee of typed message, and we'll have that potentially return
in error.
So in order to do this in order to send email, we could if we wanted to just send a standard plain
text email, but that's not really very user friendly.
We like in this world in the 21st century to send messages that have images that use different fonts
that are formatted using CSE's.
But we also need to include in that plain text messages.
So every time we send a message, we're going to send two payloads or two kinds of messages, one that
is a formatted HTML message and one that is a plain text message.
So of course, that means that we're going to have to do something with the content that we receive.
And it also means that when we send messages, we're probably going to have two templates one template
that's for a nicely formatted HTML message and one that's for plain text.
So we're going to have to build an HTML message and we're going to have to build a plain text message
and we might be passing data to those templates.
So we have to keep that in mind as well.
And we're also going to have to decide what kind of mail client are we going to use?
While it's true that Go does have right in a standard library, all of the code necessary to send email.
There are many third party packages that make this a lot less painful.
So we're going to have to decide how to build those templates.
We're going to have to decide how to pass message or data to those templates, and we're going to have
to decide what kind of mail client we want to use safari.
Now, let's just assume that we're going to build two kinds of messages plain text and each chamber.
So we know from right back up in here that we have what template to use and that is in the form of a
string.
So let's come down here and right now, just to get this to work properly, we'll say return nil.
So we don't have an error showing up.
Let's create two more functions function with a receiver of a pointer to mail,
and I'm not going to export this.
I'm going to call this one build each T.M. message, and it will take as parameters, just a message,
MSG type message, and it'll return a string and potentially an error.
OK.
So down here, just to get it working for it now, so it doesn't show me an error, I'll return an empty
string and no, then I'll copy this whole thing.
And I'll paste it here, and I'll say build plain text message,
so these will be two functions we use to build the actual message and then we'll call them from send
SMTP message.
OK, so that's those are two things we're going to have to take care of.
So let's get started with the build HTML message.
What I'm going to do, first of all, is declare a variable called template to render.
And this is the template we're going to use to build our HTML version of the email message, and I'll
just build a string.
So I use format as print f and I'll give it as a format string and it will be %s slash percent s dot
h html template.
I'm going to use go templates.
You can use jet templates if you want to, but I'm going to use go templates right now.
And the replacements for those will be import templates.
Where are the templates stored, the mail templates and MSG template, and that gives me the path to
the templates folder.
And of course, that will be in the folder called mail or something like that in the My App project.
And the name of the individual template will just be the first part of the template to render because
we're going to use that name that's stored in the template field of the typed message in order to find
both the HTML template and the plain text template.
So that'll give me the information I need in order to work with a particular template.
And now I'll declare a variable T for template.
I'll check for an error and I'll call right from the standard library template dot new.
And that requires some kind of name for the template.
And I'll just call it email.
Dash came out just something that we can use when we actually execute the template.
It can be anything you want, but that seems meaningful to me.
OK.
And then I'll call from that PERS files and I'll pass template to render.
We'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil and I'll return an empty string and the error.
So now if we get past that, we actually have the variable T that we can work with.
And what I'll do next is declare a variable of type bytes dot buffer, and I'm going to need that in
order to execute this template.
OK.
So I will declare variable trio of type bytes, dot buffer and scroll up and give ourselves some room
here, and then I'll just execute my template into the variable TPL.
OK.
So if error is equal to key, don't execute template.
I'm going to take the results and read it into my variable TPO that I just declared on the previous
line.
And I'm going to assume that there's something called body in that template and pass it any data that
might exist in our email message.
And I'll check for an error if the error is not equal to nil again, return an empty string in the error.
But if that works, I now have a formatted email message, but I need to get it in the form of a string.
So I'll say formatted message is a sign the value of from my bytes buffer tuple dot string.
And now, instead of returning an empty string, I can return formatted message.
OK, that's a good start.
There's actually one more thing we're going to want to do here, but we'll get to that a little bit
later on.
We're going to want to in-line any CSIS just to make the email, just to make sure the email renders
the way it's supposed to, but we'll take care of that a little bit later on.
So that gives me my build HTML message now my plain text message build plain text message is very similar.
I can actually take this first line or these this first section right here.
Copy and paste it and modify it as necessary.
Because the only real difference that I'm going with right here is that I'm not going to render the
HTML tempo instead of render dot plain dot template.
So I'm going to assume that there's a template.
There are two templates in some folder on this system.
One ends with dot html dot tempo and there's a corresponding one called Dot that ends with dot playing
dot template for plain text messages.
OK.
And then, of course, we can do pretty much the same thing here.
So we'll copy all of this and paste it down here.
I shall replace this paste that down there.
And instead of calling it formatted message, I'll call it playing message
just because that's a more meaningful variable name.
Paste that here.
OK, now this lecture is getting fairly long, but we've got a good start here now.
So when someone calls this channel or send something to the channel jobs, this function will listen
for it.
It'll find it, and it will try to send it.
So it calls MDOT sent em don't send currently doesn't do anything.
It just calls return em send SMTP message, which does nothing.
But in here, this is where we're going to actually take care of the heavy lifting and send the message.
And of course, this send SMTP message will come call, build my message and call build plain text message,
and we'll take care of sending them out.
So in the next lesson will install some packages that we're going to use to send mail, and we'll see
if we can get this actually functional.