So we're almost ready to start working on this function in the mail, don't go file in the mail or folder
in the celebrities project.
And the function, of course, is send a strong message.
And in order to make that as easy as possible, I'm going to install a few packages.
So let me go to my web browser and show you the packages I'm on solo.
So over we go to Firefox.
The first one is go simple mail, and this is an easy way to send mail.
OK, so we're going to install that and that basically creates a mail client, allows us to send mail
at attachments and do all the nice things.
It's very, very well written and it's very easy to use.
So we'll install that and we're also going to install this go.
Primarily what that does is it takes any styling that exists in a HTML email message and enlightens
the CSX.
And that makes it ever so much more readable on a wide variety of email clients.
And a third one is a package that just came out earlier this year, and it's a very good package.
It's actually called Go Mail, and it allows us to send email using mail, gun and Spark Post and one
other third party email client or email API.
So we're going to install these three packages.
So let's go get the first one right down here.
This is go mail and to install it.
We use this.
And again, I'm using version two.
So use version to version three is out.
Wait until the course is over and then upgrade it.
So back to my ID and I'm in the silver tax package, so I'll open my terminal and go get simple mail.
Version two.
So that's available to me.
Let's go back to our web browser and get the inline.
So we're going to get the Go Pre mailer package and here's the code necessary to go get it or the command
necessary to go get it.
So a copy that.
And go back to my idea and paste it in the terminal.
And that gets that, and we may as well install the API one, we will be using it for a little while,
but let's get it anyway.
So down here he must have there's the command to install it, so I'll copy this and paste it in.
They're all the packages are installed.
So let's start using them.
And of course, we're going to be working initially in this send SMTP message bit.
So the very first thing I'm going to do in this function is generate the plaintext and formatted versions
of our message.
So I'll create a variable formatted message and potentially an error.
They're assigned the values given by Dot Build email message.
And I just understand that message and I check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll return the error and we do the same thing for plain text.
So I'll call this one plain message and error, or assign values from M Dot and build plain text message
and hand it message.
And again, I'll copy and paste my error check.
So now I have the necessary HTML version of my message and the plain text version of my message.
And here's where we start using our mailer package.
So to do that, the first thing I'm going to do is create a mail server.
Server is assigned the value of mail, and I'm going to get it from make sure you get the right package
here.
Well, let's actually go over and look at the documentation and see how it's supposed to be initialized
or used.
So back to simple male analyst, look at the usage down here.
So they're importing ghosts, simple male and they create that by using male SMTP client.
Now that's interesting.
Go simple mail is the import and mail is what we're using down here.
Well, let's just try it and see what happens.
So mail dart and what I'm supposed to be calling here.
Is new SMTP client assume top client and there it is right there.
OK, so new A.P. Client.
And now we set its values and we need to set what?
Host, we're going to use a server to host will be equal to AMD or host from our receiver.
We scroll up a little bit here.
We want to set the port server port will be equal to the port.
In the area I'm getting is that port is of type string as an invaluable.
So let's go back up here.
And change court to an aunt.
And then we go back down to our S&amp;P looks better.
So any of the username and password server dot username is equal to M Dot username and server password
is equal to AMD password.
We'll also need the encryption server encryption is equal to DOT encryption.
Now it's giving us an error here, and the error is cannot use Imdad encryption of type string as.
And then it looks like this mail package wants its own encryption type.
So we'll comment that out right now and come back to it and we'll write a function that converts our
encryption of type string into the appropriate type.
And I'll just specify, specify some other default server, don't keep alive.
It's possible to keep this server alive, and I'm going to say false because you can read about that
and said it true if you want to.
But I don't see any value in keeping a connection to the mail server alive at all times.
We'll put it give it some timeouts, server connect timeout, then I'll make that equal to say 10 seconds,
ten times timed at second.
And we also want to send timeout server to send timeout.
We'll make that equal to say 10 seconds as well, 10 times time dot second.
Those seem like reasonable values.
OK, let's go back and look at this encryption.
Well, uncomment this, and what I'll do is call a function that I'm going to write in a moment, indeed.
Get encryption
and I'll pass my encryption string as a parameter.
OK, so I'll come down here.
We'll just put it right after this function, funk with the receiver of M Pointer to mail and I'll call
it, get encryption and it's not exported and it takes a string as a parameter and it will return the
type mail dot encryption.
And this is something that's easy to look it up.
Basically, there are some constants in the mail package one for start TELUS, one for SSL, one for
no encryption, so on and so forth.
So we'll just put a simple switch statement here.
OK.
And of course, it's going to take one argument.
I'll call it e for a string need to give a parameters, and I'll just put a switch statement and switch
on E
and we'll give the various cases.
And the cases will be the sorts of things that people enter into the mail configuration in the data
on file.
So first one case Telus and the vast majority of cases in production.
This is the one they're probably going to use.
All we have to do is return mail dot encryption.
Start Telus right there.
OK, then we'll have a case for a second option SSL.
Some people use that we'll return mail, dot encryption, SSL and other cases.
No encryption case.
None.
We use that in development all the time and we'll return mail dot encryption.
And the default, we need to have a default case.
They don't specify anything.
I'm going to assume that if they're not using not specifying it, the chances are they want Telus.
So I'll return mail dot encryption start Telus right there.
And you can use whatever you want there, but this should do the trick.
So now we have all the basic parameters set on our server, so now we need to create a client to connect
to that server.
We described the server with the server variable and we'll create a client called SMTP client and check
for an error by calling Server Connect, and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, just return the error.
Otherwise, we can start using this client to send a message.
So let's build a mail message that we're going to send using that client by connecting to that server.
OK.
So I'll create an email message called email
and that will be assigned the value of mail, the package.
We just imported new message, which takes no parameters and a better spell email, right?
Otherwise, I'm going to have problems.
So let's set some values in this email dot set from.
And that, of course, will be mzgee from.
And this is using a chain of all methods.
So I'll put a dot there, and just to make it readable, I'll go in the next line.
And two to whom does the message go?
Message two?
And then a dot and then on the next line set subject.
And of course, that's message dark subject.
So that's the basic information we know who it's from, who it's going to and what the subject is.
Now let's add the body.
So of course, we have two bodies to add emailed set Marty and the first one will be of type and this
is a constant for the male package mailed out text html and we're going to put in formatted message.
And the second one is an alternative body emailed and alternative.
And this is of type mail dot text plain right there.
And of course, that's plain message.
Now the next thing we need to do is to check to see if there are any attachments.
And of course, we're getting our attachment as a slice of strings.
And what those the contents of that slice of strings would be, if any, is the full path name to the
file we want to attach to the email message.
So all we have to do is say, if the length of message dot attachments is greater than zero, then we'll
go for ignore the index but pay attention to the individual attachment.
Those are assigned the values of arranging through message board attachments
and for each iteration through all we do is, say, email dot at attachment right there.
X is all it requires is the full path name to the attachment, and I have my parentheses in the wrong
spot here, which I often do.
That's better, so once we've got all that done, it's actually time to try sending the message.
So we'll say error is equal to the email out send.
And we want to send.
Using our S.m.
T.P. client.
And we'll check for an error if the error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll return the error.
Otherwise we return nil, so that should be if we get everything right, all of the logic necessary
to actually send a message using an SMTP server.
So let's go up here and see how this all works.
So something comes into the channel or we call send SMTP message directly and we can do it either way,
but we're going to assume that something comes into the channel.
We try to send it.
If we get no error, then we send back result.
True and nil.
Otherwise we send result, false and error.
OK, so we're going have two ways of sending messages.
We can use it.
Do it by sending something right to the listener for mail function or sending it to the jobs channel,
which is part of our overall mail type.
Or we can call send SMTP message directly.
All right.
Now one last thing I want to do here since we installed the package already is when we're building that
HTML message down here, we want to.
After we get this string, we want to use that csv inline that we had imported at the beginning of this
lecture.
So what we'll do is create a function that does that for us.
OK.
So I'll just put it down at the bottom here or at the bottom.
Create a function with the receiver of imported email.
I will not export it.
I'll just call it inline CC.
And that's going to take string, which I'll call as it's going to return potentially a string and potentially
an error.
And it's really easy to use this package.
So the first thing we do is need to set up some options for our pre mailer because that's what the package
is called so options.
And you can read about this in the documentation, but it's pretty simple.
It's pre mailer dot options.
We just populate its fields.
So I'm going to say that I want to remove classes.
If there are any CSS classes in there, I'll say that's got them in there.
It's not going to hear anything.
And I'm going to say CIUSSS two attributes.
I'll make that false as well.
OK.
And finally, I'm going to say keep Bhengu important, the exclamation that says, use this regardless
as to what any other CSC directive it happens to be, and I'll make that true.
OK, so I have my options.
I'm going to call those options plural, and I will say Primm for pre mailer and check for an error.
They come from pre mailer, new pre miller from string right there.
Because we're receiving our parameter is a string.
And we handed our string.
We want a format or process and a reference to options, and we check for an error if error is not equal
to no.
And we return an empty string and the error.
And now we'll create some HTML new HTML.
I'm just going to call it HTML, and we'll check for an error and we call KREM that variable, which
is declared on line 174 transform.
And again, we check for an error, so I'll copy and paste.
But if we get past that, then everything is good will return HTML and nil.
So now I'm going to have this function.
I can go back up here where I'm building my HTML message and just say formatted message and potentially
an error are now equal to from a receiver.
M will inline the CC and hand it formatted message and we'll check for an error.
So if error is not equal to nil, then we'll return nothing and the error.
Otherwise, we've inclined our CC, which will make the mail much more readable on a wider variety of
email clients.
OK, that's enough for this time around.
In the next lecture, we'll start looking at how we actually use third party APIs like Spark Post or
Mail Gun or SendGrid, and those are the three we're going to support.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.