So we seem to have SMTP mail set up.
Of course, we're not sure if it works yet, but we'll get to that eventually.
But just as a reminder, all the values that you see up here in this type mail, the vast majority of
these come from over here in our in our own file, in my app.
And you can see here we have some TV host username, password, port, so on and so forth.
And I've set mine to default values for local development, and we also have this section mail settings
for API services.
And you don't want to add three values there.
I've copied them and I'm going to paste them in the sense in you watching me type them.
They are Maler underscore API and that will be one of Spark Post or SendGrid or Mail Gun.
The API key and the URL you have to use to call that API.
So put those in there and you can leave them empty for now because you're not going to get to them for
a little while.
Let's go back to our celebrities project and keep going.
So down here where I had that to do message at this point, we're going to make a decision.
Do we send using a SMTP?
And of course, this is only called when we're sending something to the mail channel or do we send using
an API?
So of course, we need to decide, how are we going to determine whether or not something is sent using
it to some server or sent using an API?
I'll simply assume that if we have a value in API in our mail type, then we also have an API key and
an API URL.
Then we're going to send using API.
Otherwise, we'll send it using SMTP.
So we'll just write it if statement.
And of course, you can use whatever approach you wish.
But I'll simply say yes, and I'll put it in parentheses.
Len of MDOT API is greater than zero, and the length of MDOT API key is greater than zero and.
The length of Emden, April Earl is greater than zero.
And I'll make one more check here, I'll say, and import apron is not equal to SMTP in quotes.
This A.P., in case they specified that, then I'm going to send it using an API.
Otherwise, I'm going to return send using a to SMTP message.
But of course, the question is what apps are we using?
What I'll do in here is return a function we haven't written yet and choose API.
And it's going to take MSG as a parameter.
OK, now that function doesn't exist.
So let's go write it right down here will determine which of the three APIs we're going to use.
And of course, that's specified in the on file and we'll do the appropriate action.
So I'll create a function with the receiver of M Pointer to mail.
And I call it choose API, and it takes one parameter MSG of type message, and I'll simply run a simple
switch statement switch and we're going to switch on MDR API, which of course, is populated from the
value that we have in the dart on file.
And we'll have our first case be railgun, which is when we're going to support or spark post, which
is another one we're going to support or SendGrid.
Those are the cases that I'm going to return something and default will be.
Return format, error F.
And my format string is unknown.
API percent pass.
Only male gun spark post or SendGrid accepted,
and I'll replace my percent s with AMD API because they sent me something I don't know.
Now what is the error I have here?
No result.
OK.
We're going to return something, of course, this has to return an error that's better.
But of course, we need something in here in order to satisfy the requirement that this returns either
an error or nil.
And what I'm going to do is call a function that doesn't exist yet, which I think seem to do a fair
bit, but we'll get started on in a moment we return m dot.
Send using API and it takes one parameter mzgee and another parameter $m API.
OK, so let's create that function.
Funk with the receiver of a to male, not nap male.
And it's going to be called send using API, and it takes two parameters.
MSG of type, message and transport, which is a string.
And it potentially returns in error.
OK.
And I'll just put Returnal here.
So at that point, our errors all go away.
And let's give ourselves some room.
Now we're going to send using an API and I'm going to do a little bit of just sanity checking here.
For example, if messaged from
is equal to an empty string, then I'll populate messaged from being equal to EMD from address and you
can do the same thing and send a SMTP if you want to add the firm name if message from Neng is equal
to an empty string.
The more populated it with MSG from name is equal to end up from name.
OK, so now we know we're coming from somebody and APIs will fail if those values are not set.
Now we use our API mail package.
OK, now the API mail package, which is called Go Mail, it requires a config and I need to import
that.
But I want to call it something other than its default name.
So I'm going to go right up to my imports and I'm going to specify what I want and I'm going to call
it API mail, and it's going to come from GitHub dot com slash API and s l e wan seo a r k Ainsley Clark
slash go dash mail.
OK.
So there it is.
Now let's go back down to our code here.
We were actually trying to send using an API and let's set up its configurations.
So CFC assign the value of API mail dot config and we specify its various fields.
Now, if you read the documentation, each of the three APIs were supporting required different configuration
values.
But if you look at the actual source code, you'll discover that specifying ones that aren't used has
no effect whatsoever.
It doesn't hurt anything.
So we're going to specify the URL and that comes from Emden API URL right in our email type.
We're also going to specify the key API key, and that will be IMDA API key.
We're also going to specify what domain is being used, and we get that from eminent domain.
And we need a firm address, which is now MSG up from.
And we need the from name.
And that's MSG from name.
So now that we have the configuration populated, the next step is to get our driver, what driver are
we going to be using to send this so driver?
That's a variable.
I'm declaring I will check for an error.
Those are a sign of the values of a from April, that new client and we give it transport, which which
we received as a a parameter in the call to this function and the configuration we just made.
And we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
It will return the error.
And we're done.
We can't go any further.
But if we get past that, we now follow the same basic logic we did down here when we're sending an
SMTP message so I can copy these ones, getting my plane message and my formatted message and paste
them right here.
And now I set up what the Ainsley Clark package go go dash mail calls the transmission tax is a sign
the value of a reference to API mail dot transmission right there.
And we populists in fields in that recipients.
Who's getting this message?
Well, in our case, we're just sending it to one person.
You can send them more, but I'll leave that as an exercise for you.
A slice of string.
With MSG ought to not template to.
So who's getting it?
Those are the recipients.
What are the what's the subject?
And of course, that's just MSG subject.
What's the HTML version of the email that's are formatted message, formatted message?
And what's the plain text version?
Well, that is plain message.
So that's our transmission.
Now, of course, we want to add attachments, but we'll do that in a minute and attachments.
We're going to put that off at its own function.
It's just cleaner that way.
And the last step for now is to ignore the first returned value.
Look at the error and call Driver Dot send.
And we're going to send to our transmission.
We check for an error so I can copy and paste this code.
And put it right here now, the last thing I want to do for the moment is to actually add API attachments.
OK?
And I'm going to do that at some function and you'll see why it is a little cleaner this way.
So already in a new function with a receiver implanted email and I'll call it add API attachments and
it will take the message and the which, which is a type message and the transmission, which is a type
pointer to API mail dot transmission, and it potentially returns in error.
Let's give ourselves some room.
So what we do here is to say, if the length of our message attachments is greater than zero, then
we'll create a variable, which I'll call attachments.
And it's a type, a slice of API mail dot attachment.
It has its own type for attachments, and we'll say for ignoring the index.
Paying attention to individual entries is equal to range and MSG attachments.
And inside that loop, all we have to do is create an attachment and add it to our slice of attachments
so that our attach, which will be an individual attachment, is a type API mail attachment.
And the content of that and the error are assigned the value of I o util, which is going to read the
file, read file and we're reading X. I have to check for an error if error is not equal to no.
This point, something went wrong, so we'll return the error and we're not.
Otherwise, we can keep going.
So I need to get the name of the file and I need to get the actual bytes of the content and create an
attachment, so I'll get the filing.
That's easy enough.
File name is equal to or assign the value of.
And it's from the File Path package, which is part of the standard library file path dot base X.
That gives me the file name because we have the full path named the file.
In our slice of strings and we said attack dog bites.
That's our attachment of type API e-mail attachment that's just equal to content.
We read right up there in Line 140 and attach, not filing is equal to filing, which we got in line
145.
And now we append our attachment to our slice of attachments, so attachments
equals append attachments attach.
And when we're finished this for loop, we set our to start attachments equal to our slice attachments.
And we return nil.
OK.
So that should take care of that.
And of course, up here, we now need to add our attachments, so we say error is equal to.
M.D..
Add API attachments, and we handed our message than we handed our transmission.
And we took for an error, so we'll copy and paste this.
And that should be good.
So now when we choose our API, it will send using API if we have Morgan or Spark Post or SendGrid specified
in the file, and because we have exported the function send using API, we can actually call it directly
the same way we can call the SMTP function directly.
All right.
We're getting closer.
So the next step, I believe, is to go to the celebrities package and add this functionality the mail
or package right to the core celebrity's code.