So we have our Maler package more or less ready to go, and we can't try it until we hook it up to this
latest project.
And that's where I am right now.
I'm looking at the file celebrities don't go in the celebrities project, and naturally, we want to
make this mailer functionality available, not just within the celebrities project, but also to any
project that imports this package or this module.
So naturally, we need to add a feel to our celebrity type right here at the top of this file.
So I'll add one and I'll call it mail and it's a type mailer.
The package we just created don't.
Mail, and for some reason, it's not importing it, but that's no problem.
We'll just come up here and add it
there, so I'll save this to format it now once we've done that.
We also want to have a place to store our views for male and we have this views folder and we could
use that.
But I think that's awkward.
So I'm going to add another folder here, which is called male, and that's where I'm going to store
the templates I'll use for sending email.
Now, the next thing we need to do is very similar to what we did in other cases, like when we created
our renderer, we need to add a create mehler function.
So let's see where we create the renderer right there.
We'll do it right between a right after our create renderer function.
And all we're really doing here is populating the necessary fields in our mailer dot male type.
So I'll create a function and it will be with receivers, see pointer to celebrities and I'll call this
create mailer.
And it takes new parameters and it returns a mailer dot mail.
Now, if you recall, there's a bunch of things we're specifying in the UN file, and one of those happens
to be the SMTP port that we're going to connect to if we're sending using SMTP.
But of course, that's going to come in the form of a string.
So I'll create a big variable called port and I'll ignore the error and it's going to be assigned the
value of Sturt Con HPI, and I'll simply get that value from the environment as you've already read
the data on file.
So OS don't get OMS and I'm looking for the SMTP underscore port now that I have that in the correct
format.
Let's create a mailer and I'll just call it say for mailer, and that's going to be assigned the value
of the type mailer dot mail.
And we'll populate his fields so domain will be stored.
Get on.
Male underscore Delaine, I believe that's what we called it.
And I'll duplicate this a few times and just make changes.
So after we get the domain, we want where the template stored templates and that's going to be not
coming from the environment instead.
It will be Seedat route pass, the route path to our application, my app in our case.
Plus SGML, the folder that I just created or told it to create when it starts out.
So we need domain, we need templates, we need to host the mail host, SMTP host.
That's what it's called.
We also want the port, and in our case, that's port variable we just created.
And we're also going to need the username.
And that will be lost on get on.
And we're looking for a SMTP underscore username and the password, which is password.
And we're also going to need encryption where we're using for encryption.
And that's SMTP encryption.
And we're going to want our from name, which is SMTP
from underscore name.
Now it's from underscore name.
And then the address from address is from address.
And we need our jobs channel, so let's give ourselves some room and we can just make that right here
jobs.
And that will be make a chan of Mailer's message.
And we want to have some maximum size for that.
And I think a good value would be, say, 20.
OK.
This is not going to be MailChimp, we're not going to be sending millions of e-mails using this.
So Tony is going to allow us to send lots and lots of mail very quickly and we need a results channel
and that will be make Chan of type mailer results.
And again, we'll set it to 20.
OK.
And we also want our API values.
And that would be OK.
Start, get on.
And we're looking for Maler underscore API and we have two more one two.
So API key is Maler underscore key.
And the last one is API.
You are.
And that is the Mehler underscore the URL.
OK.
So we've set up the necessary fields now.
We just return that value return and.
And now, if we go up to where we're populating our celebrities values right here.
We can just stick it in here, see Doug Mailer for Male is equal to see Dot Create Mailer.
And that should populate that value for us.
OK, so the last thing we're going to have to do, of course, is to start the mail channel, to start
the listening and we'll do that right at the end of the new function.
So after we create the renderer, we can just call and we'll use the keyword go to make this run in
the background.
See Dot Mail right there.
Don't listen for.
And that should start it running in the background.
OK, so let's try compiling our actual application and make sure it actually starts.
So I'll switch over to my app and open a terminal window and I'll type of make stop in case it's running.
It's not so clear the screen may start, and it should at least compile.
We can't send mail yet because we haven't specified anything in the dot on the file, but it should
at least start.
OK, so we've actually started that's good in the next lecture, we'll set up a test mail server and
you can use whatever email server you want to, of course, and try it out and see if it actually works.