So in order to try out our Maler package, we of course, need to have some kind of mail server and
you can use them live mail server if you want to.
It's entirely up to you.
But typically in development, we use something like Mail Trapdoors Bio, which is on the screen right
in front of us, and it does have a developer account and it's free and it allows sufficient traffic
for most development purposes.
Another alternative and I've used this in other courses is something called Mail Hook, which you can
download and run locally.
If you're on a Mac and you happen to have homebrew installed, it's as simple as opening a terminal
and typing brew.
Install mail hug all one word, all lowercase, but you can download it and run it, and it's really
easy to use and the instructions are right on this page, and I've put a link to both mail trap and
mail hug on the course resources for this lecture.
I'm going to use Mail Hogg because I have it installed and running.
So first thing we need to do is to go over to our My App project.
And if you look in the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a zip file you can download that
has two things inside of it.
And so unzip that file and put those in your mail folder.
One is called test HTML.
That tempo, and the other one is test explained, up tempo.
And of course, these are very simple files.
So here's the test explain, define body.
Enter your email message content here.
Very simple, and the HTML version is the same thing.
It just wrapped some HTML around it, and it doesn't really matter what the contents of that HTML is.
We just want to be able to mail it.
So once you have that done, the next step is to open up your own file and go down to the very bottom
of the file and populate the appropriate values.
Here, whatever host you're using, I'm on my blog, so I'm using a local host.
And because I'm a mail hog, I use part one zero two five with no encryption, and I also specify my
SMTP from value.
OK.
So once those are all set, we can actually test this out.
So what I'm going to do is open my roots file and I'll simply inline a test route and I'll put it right
here.
So I'll just write my handler right in the route itself, and I'll make this a guess.
Get requests.
So don't get it.
And I'm going to use slash test dash mail as the root to call, and then I'll inline my handler.
So a function with a W.A.S.P. response writer and a request our pointer to issue repeat our request.
And my function will be very simple.
And here's how we send mail.
If everything works as expected, in any case, I'll create a variable called message and it will be
of type mailer, dark message, and I'll put some values in there.
So I'll say it's from doesn't matter what it is because I'm using Mail Hog, but I'll put test at example
dot com.
And I'll put it to and I'll make that you add there dot com.
Again, because I'm using a test, a mailer mail hog.
It really doesn't matter what those values are, as long as they look like email addresses.
And I'll put a subject
and I'll say test subject
sent using func because I'm going to send it by calling the function directly for two to start with
in any case and its template in this case, because in my mail folder, I have two files that start
with the word test.
One ends with dot html duct tape TPL, the other ends with explained oatmeal.
I just put test in here as a string.
I have a spell right or won't work, and I'll say attachments.
I'll just make that, Neal.
I could just leave it empty and it would default to nil and I'll put data.
And of course, that's Neil as well, because I'm not going to actually attach anything to this message
and I'm not passing any data.
The templates, I could leave those empty and they would default to nil.
But I like to be clear.
So now we'll try sending a message.
So I'll give myself some room and scroll up and I'll simply say a dot app, dot mail dot jobs.
That's the jobs channel I'm going to use.
So I'm actually in the Senate using the channels to do the function later.
I'm going to pass into that my message.
And of course, they want to get the result, so we'll call that raise.
That's a sign the value of whatever comes back from a don't mailed results.
And if there's an error, if resort error, if that's not equal to nil, then I'll say aid on app dialogue.
Dot print line.
And I'll just print out Reds dot error.
So we should be able now to compile this and go to test dash mail.
So I'll copy this route.
I'll start the application.
Make restart.
So it's building Solares house, and it's taking some time because it's creating the Voyager database,
but now it's running.
OK, so let's go to our web browser and let's go to celebrities localhost four thousand and I will open
another tab and a look at local host port eight zero two five, which is mail hook.
OK, so there's nothing in mail hub.
So now I can come back here and put the test in the mail and I should just give me a blank screen so
didn't tell it to write anything to the screen or an error in the log file.
So it's set that hopefully.
And if you look in mail, hug.
Nothing showed up.
So let's go look at our error log and see what we got wrong.
This is the first time we're actually testing the mail functionality, so undoubtedly something is wrong.
Mail open mail test, mailed tempo.
So I called it so it's opening the incorrect route.
No such file or directory.
It's looking for slash mail slash test, mailed out template.
So it looks like we have something wrong over here in our silver tax package.
Let's open up the mail file and find out what we specified for the template.
That would be under build.
Each time our message.
And templates, yeah, we probably want to populate that with some useful value, so let's go back to
our celebrity start and go and see what we put in there.
So that would be under create mailer.
Which is down here somewhere.
Create Miller and I put C slash route path.
Plus, slash mail that looks right, then it must be where I specify creating the mailer must be after
a set route path.
Where do I set Route Path?
Yeah.
So here's the problem I created the root path variable here after I created the matter, so let's just
take this and cut it, put it down here after we populate root path.
That's better.
So switch back to our application and restart the app.
So make restart.
And this time it should work.
So it's running.
Let's go back to our Web browser
and just click in the URL bar and hit return and come back to mail hug.
And there's by mail.
It sent it using a channel.
Well, that's pretty straightforward.
Now we can also, of course, call that function directly.
We can go back here.
To visual studio code and find our roots.
And we just comment this part out and instead we can say, Hey, Don App Dot Mail Dot, send us some
TV message and hand it message.
OK.
And that, as you can see, returns an error, so we can do the same thing here, we can say error is
a sign the value of and if there's an error, if there is not equal to nil, then printed out a Dot
app Typekit error log dot print line
error and will return.
And this time we'll write something to the screen so we can say format, dot, f print and print out
sent mail and we have to print it to the response rate, of course.
OK, let's restart the application just to make sure this works.
Make restart.
And now we'll go back to our web browser and I'll clear out everything that's in Mail Hog so those will
be gone or that message is now gone and I'll come back here.
Click on the earlier hit return and I should get a message back.
This time sent mail, which says, Send mail, but oh well, it's a typo.
I can live with that.
And there it is.
Test subject and everything is there and I look at the plain text.
There's the plain text version of the message, so everything seems to work as expected.
Now, of course, the next thing I want to test is sending mail using an API and I'll use Mail Gun because
I already have an account there.
And you may not want to do this part if you don't want to pay for them, because all three of the services
we're supporting actually require a subscription of some sort.
But I can at least test out mail going and make sure that it works as I expect it to, and we'll take
care of that in the next election.