So let's try sending some email using an API, and as I suggested last time around, I will be using
Mail Gun because I have an account there.
And again, you may want to try this out and if so, feel free to do it.
But if you do so, bear in mind that you're probably going to have to pay a little bit of money to male
gun or SendGrid or Spark Post or whichever service you choose to try it.
But in any case, I'm going to use Milka.
Now, obviously, when I send through a mail gun, it's not going to wind up in my mail hog or my test
email server.
So instead of having to use a real email address and I'm going to use info at the really incom that
happens to be the domain or one of the domains that I have live on mail gun and I'm going to send it
to myself.
So I'll send it to my Gmail account
and I'll say test subject sent using an API.
OK, my template is still test.
Everything else stays the same.
Now what I can do is comment this one out, uncomment this one and send it to the channel.
And once I go and make the appropriate changes my own file, it will by default send it using an API.
Because remember when we set up our mail package, we actually checked to see if there are values in
the appropriate entries in the data on file for an API and if they are, if they exist, that's how
we send them out.
So I should have to make no other changes here, but I do have to make a change in my dance.
And you'll notice right here we have our email settings and I have this entry SMTP from.
And it turns out that's not what I'm using.
So you can delete that entirely.
What we have instead is from name and from address and the other one that I didn't bother putting in
last time around because when we're using a real mail server was mail, underscored domain.
But it turns out we actually need that.
OK.
So those changes have to be made.
And the other thing you're going to want to do is to populate these values.
Now I set mine up for Mail Gun and don't bother trying to use this key because I'm going to regenerate
it as soon as this lecture is over, so it'll be a different one.
Now these values, of course, these two mail key and mailer you Earl, they're specific to whatever
API service you're using, for example, on Mail Gun.
I use this URL because I set up my account in North America, but if I did it in Asia or my mail is
being sent from Asia, it's a different you are and different providers have different URLs, but just
consult their documentation to find out the one appropriate for you.
Now that I've made these changes OK, and I set the domain here to what I use on Mail Gun, and it's
not the bare domain name for Mail Gun.
I happen to use Imgur really incom because I wanted to use Mail Gun for sending, but have a different
server for receiving.
So whatever your value is for the domain setting for mail gun, if that's the one you're using, make
sure you duplicate it there.
Exactly well, this just won't work.
So now I should be able to open my terminal and say, make restart the one that's happening.
I'm going to switch to my web browser and look at the log file for Mail Go.
So you can see right here in this log file that the most recent set one was at 20 21 09 29.
Other words, September the 29th at 12:25.
OK, now I'm going to switch back to my other browser window and I'm looking at localhost column 4000
Test Dash Mail, and if I just click Return here, hit return, it should send that message.
So let's go back and look at our log file.
And I'll refresh this.
And there it is, 14, 29, it actually sent it.
It was delivered.
So that seems to work really well.
OK.
And that was relatively painless.
Now there's one other thing I want to do, and we'll take care of that in the next lecture.
And it has to do with these mail templates.
It seems to me that if you're sending e-mail, it might be really convenient if we were to add an option
to our celebrity voice command line application.
That said, you know, make mail with some name and it automatically generates two stub templates.
Read in the appropriate folder for the application, and I want you to save our users some time.
So we'll take care of that, and it's really easy in the next election.