So this time around, we want to improve our celebrities command line application to make it easy for
people to generate email templates.
In other words, they open up a terminal switch to the directory where their application is and just
type Solaris house make mail with some kind of name for their template.
And of course, we do that in this Alatas project.
So let's go to our CMG folder, then the Seelye folder and open up main account.
And of course, the main function here is where we determine what to do.
And if you're down to Line 41, my code when they type, make I fire off request to this function,
do Nick.
So if I open that, that's in the file mate, don't go and I'll have to do is scroll down and find a
spot to add mail.
So I'll put it right here.
Case
Map.
And of course, that's going to require are three.
So I'll make sure that only three exists.
If our three is equal to an empty string, then exit gracefully with a message, a new error.
Errors start new and I'll say you must.
That has to be a string.
You must give the email template a name or whatever you want in there, of course.
But if they get past that, then really all we need to do is to open templates for our templates, which
sounds kind of weird, but you know what I mean?
A starter template for HTML Doc Team Temple and a starter template for playing dot template and copy
those over.
OK.
So what I'm going to do is assume that those exist and they don't, but they will.
Before too long, I'll say HTML mail is assigned the value of cel dot root path plus slash mail, and
I know that folder exists because I created that startup.
Plus that'll take our three convert to lowercase strings dot to lower our own three plus, and I'll
have it end with Dot h html template.
Then I'll duplicate this line and change the variable name to plain mail.
Try that again.
Plain now mail and this one becomes plain oatmeal, so that'll be the the targets where we're putting
the final files.
Now I'll copy file from template,
from template, and I want to copy it from.
This doesn't exist yet, but it will in a few minutes, templates on a Read-Only embedded file system,
mailer mail dot html dot tempo.
And I'm copying that to my mail and I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil and exit gracefully
with the error.
Now I'll copy this whole thing.
Give myself a little more room.
Paste it in here.
Make this an equals instead of an assignment operator, and I'm going to copy plane mail from mail not
playing dot template.
And that should be all I have to do there.
So now let's go to our Templates folder and create a new folder.
Inside of that, a new folder called Maler, which is what I specified here when I reference the templates
creating new files, new file mail dot html template.
And another new file mailed a plane called Temple, and I will go to the actual mail templates that
I'm using in my other application and copy those kind of you can put whatever you want in there.
So here's the one for HTML, a copy that switch back to my celebrity's project.
Make sure I'm looking at the correct file I am pasting back to my app, open test playing, copy the
contents and put it in the plane template and paste that.
Then the only other thing to do is to open our help and update that so show help is the function is
called right from here in main dgo.
So I'll go command, click on it and I'll say make mail, make mail.
And then some name
creates two starter mail templates in the Mail Directory.
So at this point, I should be able to clear my terminal.
Make sure I'm at the root level of my this project.
I am.
And I'll say, make build, underscore Clia, and that should build the command line interface.
Copy it over to my other project, so I'll switch to my other project.
Open a terminal.
Clear the screen.
I'm in the correct directory.
Yes, I'm at the root level of my app, so I should be able to Typekit celebrities make mail and I already
have one called test, so I'll call this one doesn't matter what I use.
Yellow is another.
So let's look at yellow HTML template.
That's an HTML template and yellow plain, and it's all set to go perfect.
Well, that's just a little touch, but it makes life easier for the developer and speeds up the workflow.
And of course, if you're using this for code that you can reuse for projects, you would obviously
make those starter templates a little more sophisticated than I have, but it's entirely up to you.
For example, in the HTML, my starter template might be using one of the CC frameworks that are specifically
for email, and that's perfectly fine.
And if you want to do that, more power to you.
But I just want to make sure that we know how to send email and I'll leave the refinements of the actual
message and formatting of the message to you.
Let's move on.