So we have our Maler package working the way that it's supposed to, and we probably should write some
tests for it now.
Testing email can always be a bit of a challenge.
We could if we wanted to write tests that actually connect to an external mail server, and that would
work just fine.
But of course, introducing an external dependency like that is always a bit of a problem.
So what I'm going to do is very similar to what we did when we tested our data models.
I'm going to pull a Docker image, and the Docker image I'm going to pull is the one for mail hog,
and that will exist only for the duration of our tests.
And it's pretty straightforward.
But of course, the last time we wrote tests using darker.
We did that in our Myat project.
So you're going to want to open your terminal and go and get this go get GitHub dot com slash or slash
Docker test slash v3, and then you'll want to go and want to get V3 slash Docker.
So do those two things.
I've already done that, so there's no point in running those commands again.
And once you have those down, they'll be in your go on file.
So let's start writing some tests.
So in my mailer folder, first of all, I'll set up the testing environment.
I'll create a file called set up underscore test, thought go.
And I'm also going to well, let's give it this package declaration first, so it'll stop complaining.
Package Mailer.
OK, I'm also going to create a folder in here called test data.
And inside of that, I'll create a folder called mail.
And this is where we'll put our test email templates.
So I'll create two empty files new file.
I'll call one test HTML tempo and I'll create another one inside the mail folder a new file called Test
Dot Plain Template now just to get those same values in there.
I'll switch to my other project, my app, and find my templates.
Here's one for HTML.
I'll copy that.
Switch back to celebrities.
Go to test HTML.
Paste that, and then I'll switch over here to my my app and get test plain copy and open test plain
insularity and paste it in there.
Now we have some templates we can work with.
We read our tests.
So let's set up our environment and I'm back in setup underscore test.
Don't go.
And it's very similar to what we did when we tested our data models.
We'll create a variable called pool of type pointer or to Docker Test Pool, and I'll create another
one called resource, and it's a pointer to Docker Test Dart Resource.
And now I'll create another variable, which I'll call Miller, and it is equal to the type male and
I'll populate its fields with values that I want.
So it's domain will be, say, local host
and templates.
They're going to exist in dot slash test data, SGML those files we just created.
OK.
And we want to host, which will be local host
and for port.
I'm going to use Port one zero two six.
Now the default port are Male Horgos one zero two five.
But chances are some of you have that running already on your local machine.
So I'm just going to choose a different port and you choose whatever port works for you.
But 10:26 works.
In my case, OK?
Encryption was set to none because Male Hog doesn't use encryption from address.
It doesn't matter what it is, as long as it's in the form of an email me out here dot com will do from
name.
I'll make it Joe, just a string, and then we'll create our jobs channel.
Jobs will be equal to make Chan of type message.
I'll make it have one.
We only going to be doing one male at a time, so that's fine and results will be make Chan result.
And again, one.
So there's the three variables I'm going to need for sure.
OK, now we'll do my test main function funk test main to set things up.
And of course, that takes one parameter m a pointer to testing the M
and in here we'll get started.
So I'll create a variable called P and check for an error.
And that comes from Docker Test Dart New Pool Just like last time with nothing for a parameter empty
string, and I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then I will just simply say it logged fatal could not connect to Docker, and I'll put the error in
there.
But assuming we got connected to Dr Docker, I'll just separate package level variable pool equal to
Pete.
OK.
Now, assess some options for the darker image that we want to pull and start up.
So UPS is equal to darker test run options, and we populate its fields as follows the repository.
And I think it important Docker test for me.
OK, did.
The repository is male hog slashing male hog.
The tag will be latest.
Just get the latest version of Doctor of Mail Home Environment Variables is a slice of strings.
Exposed parts
is equal to a slice of string.
And I want to expose one zero to five on the Docker image and eight zero to five, which is the web
interface.
OK.
And the port bindings
that will be a map of Docker dot port and then a slice of Docker port binding.
And the first one for ten twenty five that will be equal to host IP
0.0.0.0
and host port will be ten twenty six.
The one I'm going to listen on on my local host machine.
OK, not in the Docker image.
And the next one is 80, twenty five.
Yes, I want to connect to the web interface and that has a value of host IP
0.0.0.0.
All IP addresses and host port will be eight zero two six.
Yes, I want to not delete the Docker image at the end of our tests and look and see what's actually
in there and I'll put in my last comma.
And that takes care of port bindings.
OK.
And there's something missing here, comma and it didn't find Docker dot port.
Why not?
Darker right there, that the right one is not port.
So there's something wrong with my imports.
OK, so I have this one here should not be there and this one should be duplicated and have slashed
Docker after it.
Now let's go import those.
Go get GitHub dot com slash or slash Docker test slash need three.
I thought I had done this, but apparently not.
So it goes and gets it and probably ran Goldman tidy at some point and Docker just to be safe.
There and those arrows go away.
Perfect.
So now I have my option set up.
So the next step is to get a resource, so resource and potentially there come from.
Pool Dot run with options.
And I give it a reference to ops and we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll just logged up print line the error so I can see what it is.
And then I'll say ignore the return value, but call Pool Dot Purge resource and I will stop log that
fatal could not start resource.
So something went wrong with Docker.
That's no problem assuming we get past that.
Now, if you recall, at this point when we were testing our data models, we actually used that back
off functionality and said, Don't go until I can ping the database.
And unfortunately, we can't do that with male hog because there's nothing to ping.
So there's probably some fancy way to get around that.
But I'm just going to call Time Dot Sleep and I'll sleep for, say, two seconds, two times time dot
second.
You might have to go to three or four the first time you run this if you're on a slower machine.
But I'm running in a fairly elderly iMac at the moment, and two seconds does it for me.
So you'll probably be OK with two seconds.
OK, now the next thing you want to do is I'm going to want to start that listing for male channel because
we're going to be using that.
So I'll run go Miller Dot loosened format and that'll run in the background for the duration of our
tests.
Then I'll run the actual tests and get the response code.
So code is assigned the value of from our variable M run.
And then when we're done, we're going to want to purge the Docker image.
So we do that the same way we did before.
If errors assign the value of pool dot purge resource error is not equal to nil, then we'll just say
logged fatal f
could not purge resource percent s and whatever the errors, but too many quotation marks.
That's better.
And finally, after we run that check post exit with whatever the code is, not executable exit and
code, and that will stop the tests, everything exists and it will also kill this listing for mail
that's running in the background.
So there's are set up tests.
So if we get everything right there, I should actually set up our test properly.
Let's write one test and see how it works.
So inside of Mailer, we close this folder inside of Mailer or create a new file that I call mail underscore
test go and it's in Package Mailer.
And let's try testing sending a mail message and SMTP mail message.
OK, so I'll keep my first function func.
I'll call it test mail underscore.
Send SMTP message.
So we'll test that function and it takes, as usual, parameter T of type testing T.
And I probably should have let it do the auto import for me.
Testing Dot T.
It has no return vote.
So first thing I need is a message.
Let's create a message.
MSG is assigned the type of message and we populate some fields.
So we'll say from Is me hat here icon
anything.
This, in the form of an email address from name will be Joe to will be you at their dot com.
And that'll work fine with mail hug subject test template.
And of course, you remember that we put two templates in there, both starting with the word test.
So we use test and attachments.
Let's put an attachment here.
Attachment is a slice of string and I need to attach a file and one that I know is always going to be
available to me is right in the test data folder inside the mail folder.
One called test to mail it up to you, and that will actually add an attachment to the message.
So we have a message.
So let's check for an error and call mail or send SMTP message and hand it message.
If error is not equal to nil, then t the error.
And we'll just say here you can put whatever you want in there, but I'm going to run this test and
see what happens.
So I open my terminal.
I change into the mailer folder.
Make sure I'm in the right folder.
I am and I write, Go test dot.
And that should pull the Docker image, which I probably already had pulled and it passed.
Perfect.
So that seemed to work really well.
Now let's make sure let's go back to our setup test file and let's comment out these lines that actually
purged the resource, in other words, will leave the Docker image running and now run go test dot.
There it goes.
Now let's go to our Web browser and I'll go to Étudie Kogi local host port eight zero two six and that
should give me my web interface and it does, and there's my text message, so it worked exactly as
I expected it should.
OK, so let's go back and write some more tests, actually.
Let's go to Doctor first.
So Doctor is right here and bring up the dashboard.
There is.
And I'll delete this one entirely.
So that's there.
It's running, it's doing its thing, and I will trash it.
So now it's gone, and let's uncomment these lines and set up test just so we'll purge it after everything
is finished running.
And let's read our second test.
So this time, let's try testing, sending using a channel.
So I'll say func test mail.
Underscore send using Chan again with T Pointer to testing Dot T and the Senate using a channel.
We still need a message, so I'll grab the same message I have right here and paste it in there, and
that's fine.
And now I'll say mailer dot jobs variable we set up.
It's available to us.
We got it in our set up short test ago and I just send it MSG, OK?
And now we look for the result, which I'll call raise, and that's assigned a value that comes from
mailer results.
And I'll say, if resort error is not equal to nil, then something went wrong.
OK to error.
And I'll say errors dot new because I need to give it an error.
Failed to send over channel.
OK, so we should be able to run this test now.
I'll clear the screen.
Go Test Dot.
And I passed perfect.
Now, do we test everything we need to when sending to a channel?
No, we didn't.
Let's try this message.
Got two?
I'll set the two address to be a not an email address, not an email address.
And that should return an error when I fire it up.
So I'll just say mailed out jobs.
Yes, MSG, which now has an invalid to address.
OK.
And again, I'll look for a result result is equal to whatever comes from mail or dot results.
And I will say, if resort error is equal to nil, there should be an error and we didn't get one.
So we'll say to error errors dot new, no error received with invalid to address or whatever you want
to put for your message.
So that should work.
Let's run our tests here.
The screen go test dot.
Good.
And let's read our next test.
So we've sent using a SMTP.
We sent it over the channel.
We should test test sending it over an EPR.
But the reality is I don't want to connect to male gun or SendGrid or spark post, and in fact, there's
no real value in me testing sending email over any of those services because the package I'm using that
Ainsley Clark go mail package, he already has tests for all of those things, and I see no value whatsoever
in testing code that already has tests that pass.
So instead, we'll just test the things that we need to for our package.
So I'll say flunk, test mail.
Send using a part.
OK.
And again, T pointer to testing and I'll stroll up and give ourselves some room.
And again, I want the messages, so I'll copy the message I have from up here and paste it down here.
And you can make that a package a little variable if you want it to, but I'm not going to.
So from here, I can actually leave these ones out because we have something in our code that sets those
two values from in from name.
If they're not popular.
OK, so what I'm going to do here is, say, Mailer Dot April, because it's not going to use the API
unless we populate some values in there at all.
Going to populate in there are invalid things like unknown.
So I only want to test a situation where we don't have a valid API set up in our own file.
So I still need something in Mailers API key in there.
I'll just put ABC one two three and I also need a mailer dot API URL.
Just something that's a non-zero length string so I can put HD IPS code slash slash www.youtube.com.
OK.
And now I'll check for an error and call Miller.
Send.
Using a and I'll hand it message, and it requires a second parameter, which I'll just call unknown,
OK, something that should generate an error.
And I check to see if error is equal to nil.
Then something went wrong because I should have an error at this point.
I'll just put the error and I'll just put the error in there.
OK.
You can put whatever you want for a message, and after I'm done, I'm going to reset Mailer April to
an empty string.
Its default value and mailer API key equal to an empty string.
And back to mailer the API URL.
I'll make that an empty string as well.
OK, just to set it back to the same state it was before we run the test.
So let's run the test, you know, test out.
Perfect.
Everything passed.
OK, so that's send using API.
Now let's read another function, which I will call test mail.
And this time I'll test build HTML message with a pointer to testing dot tea.
Now, in reality, this has already been run from the tests that I ran above this, but I always write
a test for every single function that I can.
So again, I want a message, so I'll copy the one I have from up here at the very top one.
Paste it down in here.
So I have the from and from name set, and I'll simply ignore the first return value, but do check
for an error.
And all I have to do is call mailer dot build HTML message and handed the message.
And if the error is not equal to nil, then the error.
And I'll just put the error and you can put whatever message you want in there.
So that's that one.
Now, copy this whole thing and do the same thing.
But this time I'll call build plain message.
And here it's billed plain message, plain text message.
OK, and I run these tests again.
Everything passed, so the next function I want to test.
Let me hide my terminal here, the next function I want to test is actually mail send.
In other word, the send function so func test mail and I'm testing sent T pointer to testing T and
I'll get my message again so I can use this one.
I'll paste it in there.
And all I have to do is call error is a sign of the value of mailer not sent, and my error check will
be exactly the same as up here.
And again, you can put whatever you want in for a message there.
What's this?
It requires the parameter mzgee, of course.
That's correct.
So we test it that way.
And then again, we want to test because because we reset our values up here for mailer API.
API key in API URL, we set those to empty strings.
Therefore, we called Mailer send it used as SMTP email.
And of course, we want to do the same thing here down here that we did up there.
We want to reset those values to dummy values because I'm not testing SendGrid or Spark Post or Mail
Gun.
I'm just testing the the situation where calling send with invalid credentials in our own file that
should generate an error.
So all I have to do is set those values like I did here, run that test again, change the assignment
operator to an equals sign and check for error being equal to nil because we should have an error with
credentials like this.
OK.
And then again, we'll just copy the code where we set everything back to their default values right
here.
And again, this looks like redundant testing and it is.
But what I'm doing is testing each function individually, which in my experience is never a bad thing.
So that test sending the last thing I have to check is testing choose API.
So func test mail underscore, choose apart with the parameter of T pointer to testing dot t.
Let's give ourselves some room.
And we need a message again, so I'll be up and copy this message and paste this down here.
And we also need to set Mailer API to unknown.
So Mailer API
is equal to unknown.
Anything that's not spark posts and grid SMTP or mail gun.
So anything that's not that and that does the trick.
And we just call error is a sign the value of mail or choose API, and we hand it the message.
And if error is equal to nil, then something went wrong because we should get an error to air in the
air.
And again, you put whatever you want for a message in that.
So let's run our final set of tests and make sure they work.
And it failed, and it is Test Mail, send mail Tesco one to three right here.
And why did you fail?
Well, let's populate this with some actual values here, if you will say did not get an error when
we should have.
And then I'll put s and an error in there.
And that should be nil.
And it's not.
So let's run that test again and see what we're actually getting to make sure that's the one that's
failing.
And if it is, we'll go look at the code.
Here is nil.
OK, so I can get rid of this.
Get rid of this.
That is the one that's failing, so I'll make this back to error.
Now a slick mailer, send and see what it's giving us back.
So send returns an error.
It tries to send the SMTP message.
So we're checking to see if Napier's length is greater than zero in April, key is greater than zero
in April.
That's all greater than zero.
And it's not equal to SMTP.
That should be the case, so it should be calling EMD, choose a PR.
Let's try return.
That's better.
That's why that failed.
So let's go back to mail test and this is why we write tests, of course.
Let's go back here.
Good.
Everything's good.
Let's clear the screen and run our tests.
And this time it should pass.
And it does.
Perfect.
So let's look at our coverage.
And I'm going to type go test dash cover profile equals coverage out, which will run the tests and
put the results in a file called coverage out.
And then I'll run go tool cover and Dash HTML because I want it to open in a web browser and read the
data from coverage dot out.
And I should fire up a web browser and show me the coverage.
So we've got sixty two point seven percent, which is pretty good, because all I really want to test
are the things you see in green, so we can't test that without actually connecting to an API, which
is bad.
We don't want to do that.
I don't care about this stuff down here because I actually don't want to test, as I've said before.
Male gun or any of those services because all of those tests are already written in the package that
I've imported.
But everything else pretty good coverage.
So I'm pretty satisfied with this.
All right.
Let's move on.