So as I mentioned this course we're kind of figuring it out as we go we knew we wanted to give some
more real world hands on examples about creating go projects but we also wanted to hear like we weren't
even sure like OK we want to do another go course.
What should this go course to be about.
And because I wasn't quite sure what it should be about.
Increasingly my life I'm realizing the importance of market research and giving the market the economy
the marketplace giving the marketplace what it wants.
Because if you're going to do an endeavor which you're hoping will find traction in the marketplace
will be valuable and beneficial to others that others will not only be beneficial to them and improve
their lives whether you're making some sort of a product for people to consume like ice cream or something
like that or you're making some software project or you're making a course.
Right.
Like providing what people want it's going to be more successful in the marketplace.
If you're if you give people what is wanted by the marketplace as opposed to creating something and
then trying to push it on the marketplace and create the demand it's much better to meet the demand.
And so because of that I thought well let's just find out what people are looking for.
And I told you when we were thinking about creating this course I went to Twitter and I posted so if
I go to my profile I posted a question to all the people on a lot of go programmers follow me.
I posted a question What would you like to see in the course.
And so creating a project based web dev go lane course need a web dev project create any ideas.
And so there is one hundred and fourteen likes and many different responses.
And so we thought what would be interesting next step for us in our course here is we've looked at get
essentials and get branches and then we looked at go modules and we did a lot of good stuff and go modules
and we had a hands on exercises for each of those.
We thought the next thing which might be interesting to look at would be to crawl these responses and
just to show how a crawler works and go and to pull out.
There's my new puppy.
If you heard that bark pull out pull out those responses and then maybe do a little bit of analysis
on the text just word count or something like that see what some of the larger words are.
But the first step in that process is to crawl it.
And so that's what we're gonna do in this next section or these next sections is we're going to take
a look at these crawlers.
And Daniel has put together two solutions and I haven't had enough time to put together an entire solution
myself.
But between the two of us you're going to see our individual takes on crawlers and you're going to see
our solutions and so that's what's coming up.
Do you have anything you want to add to that intro.
No.
All right.
So pair programming and pair teaching here.
I am going to provide one personal anecdote here so if you're in a rush and you need to get gone you
could jump to the next video now or if you want to hear the personal anecdote.
So over the weekend Daniel already knows this.
Like over the last week my entire family has been hit with the stomach flu and it hit me on Saturday
night.
So Saturday night I was completely laid up in bed all day Sunday.
It's such a rare occasion like I can't remember the last time in my life where I just did not do anything
all day.
I just laid in bed all day.
That's not true.
I did a little bit of house pick up because that needed to happen.
So I was just walking slow and and they didn't eat it all Sunday and then Monday I was like I couldn't
function and now today just back up and I even had to take a nap today and you've known me a long time.
How many times have you known we've been at maybe two or three times over the years you've known me.
So I was like I guess I could take a half.
So yeah.
Anyhow that happens life happens and I'm not 100 percent but I'm game.
So here we go and we'll see in the next video where we're going to jump in.
Taking a look at Daniel's coat.