So we're going to cover in this video is we're going to sink our computers our code and we just want
to continue to sort of demonstrate working on a real project.
And what could happen is a code base moves forward.
So you've got the main code base and then you could have forks off of that and you could have clones
from the main base or clones off the fork and we just want to show how that happens because we both
worked on solutions.
And so when we both got back together this afternoon I had this code base right here where I zero one
two three.
And then over on Daniel's computer and show your code base there's Daniel's computer.
He had zero one two three and then back.
And then he created a folder 0 0 4 scrape and then back on my computer.
Coming back to my computer we had 0 0 4 Krall originally.
So I renamed this.
We just kind of sat together and like where you out yet.
And and we saw that.
So well let me rename mine to 0 0 5.
Kroll Todd and and then Daniel after I did that Daniel went ahead and pushed his code to the main repo.
So you're not working on a fork off the main repo in the main repo that we're talking about here is
is get get have goes to Levin going project and I'm just going to show that.
So you've got a busy tool you've got a visual on it.
So this is the main repo you don't have a fork off of this that you're working on your design doing
a clone to your machine.
Correct.
Right.
And same with me.
And so he did that and then he pushed and that was like sweet.
So now I'm going to pull.
And so let me bring up my terminal and I like this just because it's a little bit more high contrast
and larger text than my little terminal down here.
And so I need to see these in the documents and then go laying project.
And and then now that I'm in there I could see just make sure I have the right directories in there.
And so I could do a get pull.
And when I do a get pull it's going to give me a message says your local changes the following files
would be overwritten by emerge.
Please commit your changes or stash them before you merge.
So you either need to commit these in which case if I commit and then pull I'm going to have a conflict
write merge conflict because my files go mad go Sam I'm saying here are these and then Daniel said here
are these and then give me like they're different ways you resolve those and then you know that's going
to ask me to manually sort of resolve the differences and then say this is what it should look like.
I don't want to have to do that.
I don't want to have to manually sort of resolve the differences.
So the other alternative would be to stash.
And then there's one more alternative but why didn't you tell us a little bit about what stashing means
and what that involves because I've been talking to you get stashes just a stack of uncommitted changes
that you can you can push your changes to.
So right now you've got some changes that have not yet been committed so you could use get stash to
push all your changes that you haven't yet committed into the get stash at the bottom level or at the
top of whatever the stack is currently.
And it's a stack because you can you can you can then stash on top of that and then on top of that.
And on top of that if you wished and then when you you can then flip over to another branch and temporarily
work do your work over there and then you can come back to your original branch and pull your code back
office bash or whatever it's a good way just kind of temporarily say OK I don't need to commit these
just yet I just want to get them out of the way on my own machine only so I can go work somewhere else
if need be so I'd stash even apply to this situation would it even be something that I think about as
a solution for the situation in which I find my computer in relation to master origin in this case or
the guest that if you've got it stashed then your files are no longer changed.
And so you could pull that modern sum but then you're merge conflicts going to happen when you pop off
the stash but it won't require a merge commit in order to resolve because you've never actually committed
your you're part of the changes so it just be a merge conflict at that point and then I'd manually have
to resolve it at that point.
Yes.
So I'd still have to manually resolve it which is what I want to avoid.
So can I stash stuff and then just never deal with it.
That's kind of like the dirty garage of kit.
Yeah yeah.
And there and there is a command to drop your stash to everything that's currently in the stash just
go away.
So I could stash it and then just later say get rid of all that.
Which is basically kind of like throwing it away.
Yes.
All right.
Well that sounds like more than I want to get in to the other idea I had was just like Well let me because
I know that I don't really need to keep track of go mad and go some because what I've changed isn't
anything like the code I added in my folder isn't anything that is mission critical or that I need to
have a record of my solution was to do a get check out and this was going to go check out I'm going
to go check out the two files from get hub and basically overwrite my my go mod and go some files so
this is get checked out and then dash dash and I'm going to add that go some file and then go mod file
does that all look syntactically correct to you.
Yes.
And and what is the dash dash mean in there because that's kind of like a flag but there's no flag like
what's yet.
Yeah.
Get get it has it has a convention that some commands expect files like get add in some commands expect
other stuff like Get check out.
Normally it's for branches but if you need to if it but some of them can do both.
So I get check out works for both files and for branches and the dash dash kind of lets you flip it
to the other modes so check out defaults to branch look morning expecting branches or commit number
or a tag but you can use the dash dash just say OK I'm going to give you files instead to check out
from get in there like a go doc forget it.
Like I did get checkout help am I going to am I going to see yes the athlete about checking yeah get
help check out get help check out I believe we'll give you a no it does not.
Or no.
Yes it will.
To get help check out will then open up in your browser.
Information on get check out.
With all its all the arguments possible and description and so command that that dash dash thing let's
find that dash dash thing where it is going into exploratory territory.
Get check out here and I saw argument get checked out dash dash Pascoe argument disintegration or there
is only one argument given and it is not dash dash to get check out ABC when argued is both a valid
Tre ish e.g. file or directory exists get one usually ask you to disintegrate because checking out a
branch is so common operation however can check out ABC takes ABC as a tree ish in such situations get
out pass back if you want to check out these pass out of the index.
And so I'm just checking out the path a.k.a. ending in a while you see a tree ish structure is some
is either a commit hash a branch name or a tag name.
I think of a tree ish structure as like directory tree where we have folders and then beneath that are
know more folders and more folder will get like commit like history is a big tree.
Yeah and so a branch attack commit no or a tag or all points within that tree within the history.
Yeah.
All right.
So I'm going to do my get check out go some go mod and bring those down.
And then now if I do gets get poll I should be able to pull down no problem and if I look at my code
base I've got Daniel's code base in there and and then I'm going to just added Well I'm just gonna drag
this and drop it in and then I'm going to rename this as 0 3 just to match Daniel's naming I did 2 0.
He did 1 and I will put that as crawled Todd and but since it's named scrape up above we'll get rid
of crawl and we'll just do Todd and this is kind of what I worked on and so we'll just take a look in
the next couple of videos at scraping a.k.a. crawling which is interestingly it kind of in my mind it's
like been pejorative is the word that comes to mind and jaw tive define pejorative is expressing contempt
or dis approval a word expressing contempt or disapproval.
Also not a pejorative but also bastardized which is an interesting word lower in quality or value than
the original form.
Typical as a result of the addition what's the word for when a word takes on like I can't remember right.
I'm not a hundred percent do you know the word that takes on a bad meaning over time.
I can't think of it buddy.
How so.
Crawling and scraping almost has a bad reputation.
Like this is something nefarious that people do but there is a legitimate way to do it within sort of
the ethos of the Web.
And so you just have to his backed what different Web sites say about how you can access their site
and also it is the basis of like the biggest and best search engines like that's basically Google would
not exist if they could not crawl and so crawling is very much something that's part and parcel of the
game of the Web.
And so yeah we're gonna see that you have anything else you want and I know I did but I can't remember
what it was or just going to move for her to see the next video.