So we were just discussing what we talked about in the previous video and just wanted to make it clear
that when we checked out the files.
So we're gonna talk about get ahead in this video.
And I'm gonna avoid making any unsavory jokes.
And like that one.
And
so now we're going to explore what what that means what head is and get.
you know my brain is wanting to process.
So that's.
That's what we want to make sure.
We just want to make it clear that when we are doing get check out I wasn't checking out from M. right.
I was pulling from my kind of what I had in my machine the last state of where go mine and go somewhere
before I'd made you know here's where it was.
The Last Kind of like St..
Comet that was seeing it with you know my origin goes go goes to eleven going project.
This is last comment on my computer.
And then Daniel was also there at one point.
So here's Daniel's computer here's my computer.
I got it like I'm just like it's such a visual person.
And Daniel's computer my computer each have a clone of Go going project Quick get your hand right here
you see this hand.
Daniel's going project.
Here's his computer here's my computer.
And at one point in time this morning when we started working it was all the same commit right.
And then Daniel made some changes and I made some changes and then we were kind of like you know we've
moved the code base forward from where I'm going project was.
And then Daniel committed.
Right.
And his came over right.
So he's now aligned here but I haven't.
Right.
So my changes aren't in there.
So in some ways the commit I have on my machine this is up one more commit.
And so when I said get check out head my changes we're right here I went back and I checked out what
was here and.
And that align with the commit that we all had at one point which then meant that I could pull from
here because it saw oh you have work go something go modular at the last commit.
And you know you're ready to move to the next commit we're go mine and go somewhere.
Did I explain that correctly.
Did that sound.
Not really.
OK.
You get your shot.
So.
So yeah.
So when when you get checked out on a file get goes back to the what it calls the head and it pulls
a copy of the file from the head.
So the head is wherever you are on get.
So if you're on a branch head is at the end of the branch if you're a master it's on the end of M. and
it's on your own machine.
It has nothing to do with get hub get hub has its own master head and such but your own machine has
a head and that's where you are in the get commit treat when you get checkout from a file you get goes
to wherever the last head was and copies the file from head over into your working tree where you actually
are writing code.
So Todd made changes to some to go man go some but the head was still back at the last commit.
Heads always are attached to a comet.
And so he made the changes to go man go some in his working tree and then we did get checkout on those
files get went back to the head which just happened to be at the last commit on master that he had pulled
and it copied the files out into his working treat which then overrode all those changes and now his
status was showed the files had not been modified and to get pull could happen because the files had
not had no longer been modified so when I look at that at the terminal another way we just discussed
this right before this video is right.
Right now like Oh wow.
Because I changed a few things now I need to add these.
So we're just going to quickly add this get comet dash a and add Oh yeah get add sorry get add dash
a yes and get comet dash M and adds you know half completed scrape Todd and and then get push and now
Daniel going over to Daniel's computer let's get everybody's computers current here now Daniel could
do a get pull and there he's got everything on his machine.
Now if I do get status right I'm on branch master your branch is up to date with origin master and what's
your get stats look like on your machine.
So my guess is it isn't.
Yeah.
So I'm on branch pass through my branches up to date and I've got a workspace file which I'm not committing.
So that can be ignored.
All right.
And so is get ignore and get.
Yes.
Yeah we you could create a file can do that.
It's just at the root of your project.
The same place where you get file folders located.
You can create a file called dot get ignore.
Yeah.
And you can put in whatever you want in there and any it's a pattern matching.
So in this case I want Star not sublime workspace right.
Yes.
And now that's going to ignore.
Now if I get status it's now telling me only changes are get ignore it up man.
Let's push that up.
So another another.
So you usually want to have your workspace in there so another one that would be likely to get ignored.
It's like the V it's code workspace
so just in general anything if you've got any build files like if you like he I'm on windows so something
I will probably want to put in here is start out sexy.
I don't want any executable is to be put in in the repo accidentally
adds get your SO.
JUST if he files in the get ignore it won't let you add it.
It won't show up in the get status and the ad will ignore it.
Yeah.
Dad ignores it.
All right.
So you just added that up and Bush and now I'm going to come back to my machine and I'm going to do
it gets that this and and so this has always been a little bit of a point of confusion for me it's like
hey I'm branch master your branch is up to date with G.M. It's not I'm actually behind or G.M. right.
Yeah.
What are your thoughts.
So it gets status tries to be fast so it doesn't actually talk to origin or beer at all.
It's just trying to do it all on your own machine for speed purposes and reliability too.
Yeah because get static get status and the can you can make myths about pushing them.
So I guess that's what's to be fast and efficient for that purpose so it doesn't actually talk to Origin.
So if you want you can do get fetch which get fetch just tells get to go check or join for what's up
to date.
So.
So it get fetch.
Now it knows more you.
But if you do get status now it tells you you are now behind.
Got it.
All right.
So we're going to also covered in this video videos dot get ignore which is good.
And it was covered in previous courses but new material here is get fetch and and then now.
Now when I did my get status I'm behind so I can do my get pull.
Yep.
So yeah I get pull also fetches because it's intended for the network access.
Yes.
So now everything's current again.
So if I do might get status and even if I did get fetch and then did it get status again everything
is is good.
So we're all good.
And that same on both and and then the next thing for us to look at is just to.
I wanted to look at get log.
And so here's here's kind of like one way that I was thinking about head when we were talking between
these videos was had is kind of like the cursor in a text document.
And so my cursor right here would be like right at this point.
Right.
This is the last one that came came up right here.
This is the last comment from Daniel.
And you put that good ignore file in right there.
And so that's where my head is right here and you can even see it saying head is pointing to master
whether your thoughts on that syntax.
So it's just yeah it's just head head right now is an alias for Master.
Right.
So it's just pointing straight to master and and then if I move things forward so I'm going to control
C out of that rescue queue area and and just add some file.
So I'll come back to this code and make some small change I'll break open up my last one and I'm the
end and do small change and I make sure that saved and then come back here and do get status.
And so now things have changed and your branches update with origin master changes not staged.
It's asking me to change those stages and so currently my cursor My head is right here but my code is
is a little bit ahead because I've added something and if I wanted to I could go and I could check this
file back out and checking it back out from ahead head which is this comment that more clearly said
and explained.
Yes OK.
I just want to make sure that that was clearly explained as explained what had was you everything you
want to add to that you can move head around freely you can get it get checked out of file number you
can get check out any branch number you can get check out any commit number so you can you can just
do it get checked out on say any like the previous comment number if you wanted here let's let's check
this out.
This video is getting a little long.
So we're going to continue this in the next video.