So now what we're going to do is we're just going to demonstrate that once more like my code is a little
bit ahead of last.
Check out the last sorry buy codes a little bit ahead the last commit.
And so I'm going to check this file out and just bring it back to where it was here.
And so I'm going to bring this down here.
Copy that and come down to my terminal and get checkout dash dash.
And then that entire file that path and this is where it's tree ish right.
Like here is the location that no treat tree issues to commit is some commit value according to gifts
like length how how we defines stuff a tree ish is a commit OK.
I think you have directory tree but now when I do the get check out if I do might get status everything's
up to date because I rolled it back to I rolled that one file back to where it was at this point.
Back to had and if I look here that comment is gone.
So it's get checked out in action.
What else do you want to say about that.
Your head can be freely moved.
So right now head is pointing to master for Todd but he could just as easily do the get check out to
a branch and now his head to be over at that branch.
Another thing you could do is you can get check out a commit number.
So all the permits that show up with the gate log.
I could take a one of these commit numbers say I want to go back to this previous commit before they
get ignore I could copy that and get check out that commit no and this will give me a nice big warning
about how you are in a detached head state.
You can look around make experimental changes and commit them discard any commits you make in this state
without impacting any branches but if you actually want to retain the cadets you have to create a new
branch
so if you wanted to you could go back to.
So right now I do the get logged and I could see my head is here and it's not pointing to master so
that's where you're currently working.
Yes.
And you can create a branch off of that change and stuff submerge it back up further off line.
So so now I could create a branch off at this point if I wished with the get check dashboard.
Just like normal Mork often though you will do a get check out to a particular tag name too.
I could do it get checked out from this tag so previous head position was at this commit with this commit
message head is now at this commit with this message if I do get log see my head is now in here with
this tag and whereas the top log Oh it doesn't you don't see it.
Yeah.
You see this your lawyer there.
Yes.
Like the top.
Yeah.
Three four four.
So how do you get back up to the top.
So now see I can just do get branch to see again here it also says head is here the star and it's green.
It's not at Master.
So I can just get checkout back to master and now I get log shows.
My head is set now.
All right.
So it's almost it creates its own branch when you move your head to a different one kind of except you
can't really you you can you can go you can move your head back or to a tag and you can make commits
and you step with them.
But as soon as you go away from that point go back to master something.
Yeah.
You can't really get back to those committees anymore you don't.
You don't know how to.
There's nothing labeling that content anymore.
Yeah.
So you know if you but if you go back to another thing and then you create a branch off that point you
now have a name to that to your work off that point and then you should merge that back in the master
if you want it.
Yes OK.
So if you wanted to kind grab something from an old code base an old comment that would be how you do
it.
Yeah.
And then bring it.
Yes let's go get that thing we threw away we actually needed that or commits ago.
Yeah.
You come back there and come back there grab the file create a branch and emerge back to master.
Interesting.
All right.
I hope that was helpful.
Anything more you want to add.
No.
Is it me or is it getting a little bit hot in here.
I think you're doing all right.
All right.
See in the next video.