Dear friends, we have reached to the end of this training course.
I hope this course has been useful enough for you in this course and attend was made to reveal all the
details of go for academy language and separate examples were presented for all sections.
If you have any problem in the section, review that section carefully and do the examples again, then
make examples by your own as well and always remember the more exercises you do, the more professional
you will be.
Now you are be able to do various programmes in different fields, including software design and development,
implementation of web applications and communication with clients, and implementation of various games
and communication programmes.
Since you have completely reviewed concepts of database and go in framework services, including RESTful
and You PC to communicate with other services and applications that socket concepts for game implementation
and real time programmes like chat applications.
Let's look at some of these programmes, which you are now able to write and implement network distribution
services.
Create your own distributed services and contribute to open source projects.
For example, you are able to build network secured clients and server BGR PC kind of native development.
The synchronous features of Google and its high portability makes it sweeter that for building native
cloud applications and GO has been used to build several cloud computing platforms, including Docker
and Kubernetes is an alternative for existing infrastructure.
Another advantage of good language is that many of the softwares we need to use for internet infrastructure
are aging and have many security holes.
Rewriting such items in GO has many benefits.
Better memory security.
Easier deployment of cross-platform and clean cut base for future upgrades are some examples.
Independent facilities and tools.
Another advantage of go language is that girl programs are compiled with minimal external dependencies,
either binary, which makes them ideal for creating utilities and other tools.
Since the Iran quickly and can be easily repaired for redistribution, I hope you have enjoyed this
course and wish you all the best.
Looking forward to meeting you in our next tutorial.
Goodbye.