All right we did a little function over the night.
We did a little bit of thinking or I don't know if this happens with you but like you think I'm not
sure what needs to be done Max.
You go home and you can't sleep and then you wake up in the middle of the night and you go and you get
like Brad you make like one of those sandwiches and you eat and then you're sitting there at the kitchen
table and you're like I don't know if I could go back to sleep and then you're like I totally know we
need to do it tomorrow.
And like the solution comes to you like 3:00 in the morning when you can't sleep.
And and so we really heard a strong positive response from a lot of people about G.P.S..
And so that is coming up but I also realized that we haven't done hands on exercises and hands hands
on our exercises are essential so we're first going to jump any hands on exercises and then we'll do
a little bit of a just kind of two or three G.P.S. and kind of get you going with GOPAC it's not going
to be the full like comprehensive you are now the master jet I see it's not going to be that it's going
to be like this is how you start using it and this is what it is.
Let me see that reverse order actually.
This is what it is and this is how you start using it and and and then that's gonna be it for this course
we found the name for the course finally we realized that it all kind of fits together collaboration
and crawling really like that name Daniel came up with it it's great on going modules get GOPAC and
scrape and Twitter and if that doesn't sell you know cause I don't know what does because I like students
like I heard collaboration crawling I'm like that's the perfect name for the cause.
All right.
But now onto hands on exercises and we're at ninja level 3 which is great.
And the first hands on exercise for this hands on exercise determine whether or not this U.R.L. can
be crawled and that you are Allah's right there so go ahead and pause this video and using what you've
learned in the previous videos that you watched about like validating and checking whether or not you
could crawl go figure out whether or not you're allowed to crawl this this you are all and pause video
could do that when you're done come on back now y'all and we'll show you our solution which we're going
to do right now.
All right.
So for this solution I remember the thing that really stands out to me is we want to do a crawl checker
like we Google crawl checker or something like that online Web site crawler check Web site.
That's not quite what we Googled.
So go back to the outline and I look for checker robots that text validator robots that t t checker.
Right.
And so we're going to drop that in there.
And when we dropped that in there we'll get a bunch search results.
But we can go to this one here so I'm just going to at the same time popped out open and the one that
I want to check is that read It's funny your url.
So can we crawl this.
I'm going to grab it and I'm gonna drop it in and paste it and then scroll down and live.
Ed you want to pasted into the url box.
There you go.
Peace in the url box and add it in.
You need to get the robots that takes t input to that button bigger box blue.
Oh it's all making sense.
So I go to read it dot com and then robots Dot T X T grab it.
And if you hear that little bell in the background that is sweet music to my ears because my favorite
cookies are about to come out of the oven.
I'll give you the recipe to at the end of this video.
All right.
So now I've got that and I'm going to crawl it as I have to choose one calling it out I'll do anything
I have my guide here you see just the very bottom it's just the general and all right since we're making
our own so.
So this is good that I'm doing it because it's one thing to watch it and it's another thing to be like
Oh I totally understood all that.
Wait a minute.
I know nothing.
How do I act.
So I put in the you are all I want to crawl there I choose who I'm going to crawl it as user agent.
It's always struck me as such a weird name but it's the basically the in client server it's the client
is referred to as the user agent right.
Kind of it's one of those more cookies or the browser.
Yeah.
The browsers agent.
The browser is the agent of the user.
Yeah.
Acting on behalf of the user.
I'm here to ask the good questions and and then we do live Ed the rest that's good.
Yes.
Just a test and great successfully completed result allowed and it's allowed.
And I think that a good service that we might be able to build when we get into the next course or the
next next course where we're building a web app would be maybe a robot stock text tester that always
returns.
Oh you could crawl this.
It won't be accurate.
But people always like the result.
All right.
So that's it for my solution to this first hands on exercise we could crawl it.
I know Daniel has something kind of funny and interesting to show you about.
I guess we'll just do it on your machine about the Reddit robot start to 60 and then I'll show you the
recipe for those cookies.
So let's do those two things
so yeah.
Some robots the teeth teeth.
What different user agents have different levels of allowances like they might be more generous.
Google search with the Google bot because they know that is what searches too.
But sometimes some of the user agents can be a little funny like Voltron.
That's an anime out there.
It's a TV show Voltron is not allowed to call anything disallow slash.
Yeah.
So I thought that was pretty funny about one.
It's been the that.
And this one is like really a lot smaller than other ones.
Yeah a lot of wins are usually or giant.
Yeah it's like here is that all all user agents here's their list of rules.
Yeah that's cool.
And that's just the Web convention conviction convention Chan Java robots Dot T X T right at the root
of a site that file there.
So on sites that know what they're doing which is larger sites they shared at least you could find that
robots T T at that location just in case you didn't know that.
All right.
Last thing tell personal anecdote.
No coding for your rush.
You could go to the next video is Jose's oatmeal peanut butter chocolate chip cookies right here.
Best cookies in the world if you're on to peanut butter and chocolate.
These are amazing like a really good thing to learn.
All right.
See in the next video or do the next hands on exercise.