All right.
Welcome to hands on Exercise number two.
And for this hands on exercise use go Cauley and crawl the go Ling Reddit site and I forgot to start
my own B.S. and so I'm going to start my own B.S. and this is why we do pair programming impaired teaching.
So now you can see my screen you can see go Callie there and and crawl they go laying Reddit site so
go see what you can do to get that to work and positive video go do that when you're all done now y'all
come on back and I'm positive video and I'm going to take a swing at using go Callie never used it before
in my life and you'll see that after you do your solution so positive video go dears when you're done
come on back on opposite end you can see my solution which I'm gonna do right now.
So the first thing you'd want to do is drop that into the validator or a robot start texting validator
and here I have it going and just test it and it says yep you're allowed to do that next thing go the
go Lane Callie you know Web page go to docs and what we kind of what I learned from Daniel what we've
learned from Daniel was go down take a look at the examples there's actually a Reddit example and so
a good starting point is just to see if get this run so I copied including all of red I just want the
code so I'm gonna grab that code and bring it over to my editor and then paste it into my editor and
then I could do a quick read through of the code and when I do that I see that it's like an old read
it and so I'm going to see what I'm going to do is see if when I go to going read it here if I can bring
up the old read it and.
And right there I've got that I'm going to change it from WW W to old and see if there's an old read
it that comes up and an old read it did come up and it looks a mite easier to crawl and so I'm going
to add this in as a hint to your hands on exercise Yeah take a look at
the old read it and so noticing the difference there and so I want to crawl the old read it and then
also as I look through the code there's going to be some place where it's asking for OS ARGs and so
on going this is command line argumentation and so I'm going to try pasting in this old read it old
read it where did it go old read it you are Al right there as the you are all that I want to crawl in
my argument and so here's the code here's my terminal and I'm going to put in go run main dot go and
paste in the URL of the old code and see if I get any type of result and so now it's starting to crawl
and get some results out which looks promising so we'll let this run for a second and maybe fast forward
or edit pass this
and there it crawled for a bit and then brought some things out and I could kind of look through here
it's quite a bit of text to see what came out but that's the first step in my solution is just seeing
if I can get that example to work the next thing that I would do is I would go through here and I would
try to understand the code and so to understand the code I'm going to need to go to the documentation
and so Callie's documentation if you go to go talk and you search for Carlie you could find the documentation
here you have go calling you have Cawley and one of the things that you'll notice in the code I would
start going between the example that works here is the example that works one in you know in the code
we're creating a item struct and getting different items and then we're going to have a slice of those
items and these will be the different stories but one of the first lines is to create a new collector
and so I want to understand what this collector part is and I remember that from Daniel's code and so
I'd come in and I'd take a look at what the new collector is it gives me a pointer to collector when
I have a pointer to collector I have all of these methods available right there and and so I get a new
collector see and then I'm starting to use some of those methods like on each email on each email limit
on request and so I'd want to go through and take a look at each of those and and see what each of those
do.
And then also I have it here.
Right.
It's a visit only domains old Reddit dot com.
There's a few options that got set in there and so new collector and I have options an unlimited number
of collector options.
I'd also want to understand collector options and to understand collector option I could click click
what it did right there click right on the you know link for this item it takes me to it but then I
could collect on collector option it tells me what to collect your option is.
And so I'd go through all of the code like that and I don't want to take the time to do it here because
it's all already been demonstrated and explained.
And we're running at about seven minutes on this video but you could go through and start to explore
all of that in that fashion to see see what it has to give to you.
Maybe I'll do some of it so that the new collector collector options when I point click on new collector
go back to collect your options type collector options is a function and gives you a pointer to a collector
and a pointer to a collector has all of this information here.
So it starts to get in kind of deep but we could see here we have Colley allowed domains and Callie
async so I might look for where is allowed domain show up and allowed domains is a function here.
It's a collector option.
Right.
And then that allowed domains function gives me back a collector option and and so when allowed domains
Callie allowed domains gives me back a collector option.
Oh and then Callie async is going to give me back a collector option.
So if I look for caller async right.
This gives me back a collector option.
And what and what a new collector takes is a backup here at the top.
New collector takes a bunch of different collector options.
Right.
So new collector takes in a bunch of different collector options and so anything that gives me back
a collector option is something that I could pass in there.
So I could do a command C to copy that command after fine command V to search and I could start to look
through what is returning a different collector option and a collector option sets an option on a collector
type collector option underlying type as a funk that has a pointer to a collector.
And so if I when I clicked on that is kind of taking me into you know more and more depth but to use
the code what I need to know is that new collector takes into anything that returns a collector option
or anything that is of any value of type.
Collector option.
And so when I search for values of type collector option I could start to see.
Right.
Allow your RL revisit allowed domains async in the naming of this makes sense because this isn't this
is like options for collecting and the options that we're using here are allowed domains in async.
And so it's kind of a different way to think about that.
Do you have anything you want to say Add to that.
Yeah it's a good way to.
So when you create a structure you use a struct little to create a struct you can pass and all the options
but this doesn't work.
If you're creating a strict but a rule that has private values it's well that need to be set.
So this collector option thing is actually fairly common amongst bigger projects to have a way to kind
of preset public arguments on a struct that also has private arguments that need to be set by the new
function nice.
So it's a new collector or it will set some private private fields in the collector as well.
And then collector options is a nice way to easily set those public options to yeah.
So we've got our new collector with some options.
And once we have our collected then we go into on each team Al and we already saw that in Daniel's video.
And so that's where we start to look for the different class names and read it and we use our inspector
tools to do that.
And so in here launch Inspector tools and get this little icon right there and then I could start to
look at each of these stories and try to figure out which how do I grab just that story right there.
And looking at what the tag is and so they've already figured this out that it's a top matter.
And then for a top matter it's going to bring out the source title story you are all different items
like that through there.
So this is actually a little bit more involved than I think could be done in 12 minutes.
Takes a little bit of time but nice to look at the example.
Anything more you want to say about this.
No.
All right.
It's a little bit of hard hands on exercise for me to demonstrate a solution in just 12 minutes because
it does take some time to do that but that's my start at my solution for creating crawler using Callie.