All right welcome to hands on Exercise number three for this hands on exercise go through these steps
right here basically you're gonna count up each of the words like you saw Daniel do and to do that look
at in the code just you know here you've got title just look at title because old read it if we go and
look at old red it just has these titles here so get each of these titles and it's a string of text
and so you're going to want to split that string of text into words you want to collect all of those
words you want to use a map to count them and make sure you go to lower so you could also do the two
lower ones and then once you've done that maybe range over your map and get a struct and with that struck
to have 2 fields word and count and then create a slice of that type of struct and then range of your
map and put an entry in that slice for each word so then you could use sort slice from the source package
at sort or sorts.
And it's sort of a sort package to to make sure that it all runs well so pauses video goes take a swing
about when you're all done on positive video and then come on back and I'm going to show you my solution
which I'm going to do right now.
So one thing to share is that there's a difference between teaching as a profession and being a professional
developer and so on a professional developer you're actually in the arena and you're creating an applications
and you're swinging and using code every day in that way as a teacher.
You know there's a set curriculum which we go through if we know those concepts we teach that which
is where I find myself and my skill set.
And so this is just a little bit of vulnerability and I feel vulnerable sharing this and I feel a little
bit humble because I'd like to be able to practice and fight like somebody who's in their arena everyday
but academia is not the arena academia is a lot of other things and there's a lot of skill sets that
go with it but it's not being in the trenches being a professional developer every day.
And so when it comes to teaching coding I'm really good at the intro classes that's kind of where my
career I've spent my time but in actually taking that and dynamically putting that into an application
that's a strength I hope to develop and grow.
And I've been working on that last bit of time started a Web company with Daniel and a few others so
I could have more time to code but ended up doing all the other stuff and not getting any coding because
I wanted more of that real world experience.
But then there's so many other things to do I didn't get that.
And then also you know that all that all that to just preface that I wish I was as fluid as you as somebody
who's in the arena with this but in my life I haven't had that focus with my career and my time and
everything.
So this isn't going to be a slick and as fluid as with Daniel maybe you already know all that but here
I'm going to take a swing at it and enter code right.
We're going to focus on title that's where the title comes out and we have stories where we're getting
a slice of items and so the item is all that stuff.
And if we look to see where stories are being used right I could see stories are being appended so we're
collecting all of our stories there and inside stories as my title and then down here we're printing
them all out.
Well instead of printing them I've got all those stories and all those stories.
It's a struct It's a slice of home so I need a range over this slice.
And so if I'm going to range over a slice I'm going to use the range loop and when I range over a slice
I'm going to get back my index and my values I'm going to do for i v call an equal range and I'm going
to range over my slice of items called stories some ranging over stories and and so that's my first
step.
And I get my index of my value and so I'm not going to need my index I don't think I'm going to put
that away and I'm going to call this one a story.
So I range over stories and I get back a story so now I have my story and inside my story there is the
title.
And so with the title it has all the words in there and so I'm going to want to make that all to lower
want to split that and get all the words out and then and then that's going to when I split it if I
go in I look at the documentation go doc and look up split.
So that's in the strings package.
I'm doing great.
Just way right.
We go to this we've got a split and we get we need that and we get back a slice of string.
So we're gonna get back a slice of string.
So I'm going to go for a splitting that up and for each of those.
But then when I split.
Each to each of those See I just made myself nervous.
Now I get a slice of string gives me all of my words and I'm going to collect those into a map.
And when I split up all of my words I'm going to need to range over that slice and then put them into
a map.
So where each of these.
Each time we loop we get a story for each story.
This is what I want to do I get back a slice of string and that slice of string is going to be equal
to strings not split.
And we're going to do story and that's our separator right there.
And so that will give us back our slice of strings.
Right.
And we also want to split the title on that and then I also want to make that strings to lower strings
to lower.
There we go.
And so I've got my title a range of stories I get my my story and with my story title it's thrown in
there I'm going to figure that out here in a second with my story title I'm going to make that strings
to lower and I'm gonna put this here and strings to lower just around this and then my split needs to
be around that which means I don't need this last one.
There you go.
And now I get a slice of strings and so that slice of strings is going to be my words actually.
So I'm going to call this words.
So they're my words.
And now with all of my words from that I want to range over that.
And so the words is is also going to be a slice gives me back a slice so a slice of string I like that
slice a string.
So now I'm going to range over that so for index value.
Colon equals range.
I know I need to change those and I'm going to range over this and I'm going to call this a word and
I'm not going to use my index there.
And so for each word I'm going to add that to a map.
So I need my map.
So I'm going to have a map that's going to be equal to a map and the key will be a string and the value
is going to be an end and I'm going to just go ahead and create that right there initiate it initialize
it.
And so for my map here I want to add in the word.
If it's not there it will create the entry and then I'm going to increment that.
So now I've got my my word getting putting to my map and it's being counted.
So I'm just going to go through my logic here arrange over all of my stories I get a story for each
story and take the title I'm going to make it to lower and then I'm going to split it.
And then that's going to give me a slice of words and I'm going to range over that slice of words.
And it's going to give me I guess I like the idea of that being called words.
Right.
And then I'm going to get a word and then for each word I'm going to drop that into my map.
So that's like step one for me.
And then the next step is okay I've got my map full of all of my words I now need to have a structure
so I could sort that and that structure is going to be type word counts word count.
And it will be a struct and I'm going to have two fields it'll be the word which will be a string and
it will be count which will be an end and then I'm going to need to range over my map.
So maps have a key and value and call an equal range over my map.
And as I range over my map I then want to have a slice of words so slice of words.
And that's going to be slice of word count slice a word count and that's gonna be a slice of word count
and not double word word word word random word and then now that that is set up as I range over my map
I'm going to add to that slice so I'm going to do append
again do X WC X WC is equal to append
X WC and what I'm going to append to it is going to be I'm ranging over my map and I'm giving out my
key and my value and so my key my value are actually the word and it's that count.
And so I'm just looking to see if I used word up there.
So maybe I'll just go at WC and I think I kind of like that and then X WC kind of makes sense and so
I'm gonna pin to that.
I'm going to now create I've got my type word counts it's going to be a word count and we're using would
you call this an anonymous composite literal not assigning it to anything right was a literal I've got
my type and then curly braces and put in the values and I need my word that works and I need my account
so it makes me a little bit.
And so there I've got my word and I've got my count and and I'm appending that to my slice and now I
just need a sort that.
So to sort good OK dawg and go to sort
and salt is going to have sought slice
and got sought slice here which takes in any any type a slice of any type.
And then I need a function of less function deal and there's an example there if I want to take a gander
at it and I'm just looking to see the the less funk is right there and it's return you know which is
less than what.
And so I need to do that to sort I need salt dot salt slice and the slice is going to be x w c and then
the type is going to be func and it's gonna be I j.
And and grab the door.
Somebody just walked in it returns a bool and here's the code for the function.
I'm gonna say that it brings in that package and then for that function I need x w c and actually we
see the slice at this index position is going to be less than x w see this at that index position.
So I'm just gonna compare that now to the documentation.
I mean you return that return and we have this dot that that slice and that that was using that and
minus a slice of word count.
So I need to have my X WC slice dot and it's going to be the count and x w C. J.
Dot count it.
There's no red lines no red lines as a positive thing.
Yep.
So in this case the only error is this will be sending count order and you want decent increment orders.
So first you're the greater than Yep c.
So if if if you're callback returns true EIS goes before J Yeah and I like this example of a callback
where you know what sort slice is asking for a callback I've explained before as a function you pass
in as an argument and then sort we'll use that in the way sorts going to use that as it's going to run
this function the code I gave it.
And it will get a value back.
True or false and based on that it will do what it does it's using that function.
All right.
So it's calling back to the function I'm past and.
Is that a good way to explain it.
Hmm.
And and now that I've got everything sorted I could range over my ex WC and so w sees a slice a word
count and I don't need my index but I will get my value and colon equals range X WC and font print lying
and I'm going to print out my value dot word and also maybe then value dot count would make sense with
the county's and let's run it and see what we get.
All right.
So this is at 0 3 solution and to run it I could just bring up this previous thing and it's running
at 0 3 and we'll see what our word count is
so it's my hope in this process why this runs that you know collaborating many minds make stronger better
solutions we each bring something to the table when we pair program and also when we pair teach and
it's my hope that in that synergy of strengths each of us having different strengths that it will create
a more robust course where you get to see areas where each of us are stronger in areas where each of
us learn and complement each other and and then that's useful to you as I go through stuff and I'm like
wow that's totally new to me you know or raise questions come out by hopeful of hopeful hope I'm hopeful
that's useful to you.
All right.
So here are word counts why I tell you stuttered I haven't stuttered in forever
go three thirty eight not surprising go Lang is ninety three how right at the top of the list how do
I do the package library your hood it's interesting to look at those words all right so that's my solution
for hands on Exercise number three I hope it was helpful.