So in this section of the course, we're going to start working with Sessions, and our goal will be
to make session management in session usage as painless as possible for the end user.
So before we do that, let's have a look at this page homeport jet and what we can do right now.
This page looks like this.
So there it is rendered.
It's just the logo in the center with celebrities and jet templates.
Let's put a menu underneath this that will link to all of the things we're going to be building for
the remainder of this course, and it will give us a very easy way to test functionality as we progress
through the course.
So let's get started.
Let's go back to our editor, and first of all, I'll get rid of this bit right here.
Jet templates and just put the title there and up here at the top where it says browser title.
Right now, it says celebrities are celebrities.
Let's just change that to welcome.
OK?
It doesn't really matter, but it makes it look nicer.
And right now, this one div class deflects this has a height of 100 V8, so it takes up the whole browser
window.
Let's just delete that style entirely, and let's add the class say Mty Dash five to push it down a
little bit.
Let's see what that looks like.
So I'll go back and refresh this page, and that is good.
OK, so now let's add some links underneath this.
So let's go back to our editor and right after this, after this div, after this second to last closing
div, I'll put a horizontal rule in and then I'll put a paragraph, tag things to try
and close the paragraph tag.
And I'll put a division here with a class of straight out of bootstrap list, dash and group.
And I'll close that div and I'll put some entries in here.
So first of all, a f equals and we'll go to a non-existent path.
Go Dash page because this is something we've already done.
And it's class will be list Dash Group, Dash Item List, Dash Group, Dash Item, Dash action against
to bootstrap and say render a go template and close that I'm going to duplicate the line and change
it.
Change this to jet.
So render a jet template and that will go to Jet.
Dash page and I'll duplicate that again.
And this is the one we're interested in in this section sessions and we'll say.
Try Sessions.
OK, let's see what that looks like.
Let's go back and refresh this.
All right.
So now I have three links and we can add more.
We can add our cash when we get to that and everything else we're going to build in this course.
OK, so let's go back and make those links active.
At least the first two.
So back to visual studio code, we want to have a go page and a check page.
So let's go to Route's rootstock, go in our Miami package and I'll just duplicate this twice and change
the first one to go to page.
And then we'll go to a handler that doesn't exist yet called Code Page like that.
And this one will be Gitesh Page and that will go to Jette page.
OK, so now let's go back to our handlers inside the handlers folder handlers dugout, and I'll just
duplicate this and modify it.
So I'll copy this and paste it and paste it again.
This one is going to be go page and this one is going to be jet page.
And I want this one to not use the default rendering page function.
Instead, we'll make that go page.
OK.
And that means we get rid of this extra parameter and we'll have this render home what we already have
a home page to temple, which we're not using, so we can use that one that works fine.
And for this one again, I don't want to use page because that will use the default renderer.
We'll change that to jet page, and that does have the two data parameters.
We'll leave them both additional and we'll make that render, say, jet dash template.
So let's go create jet dash template inside our views directory.
So a new file.
Jet Dash template dot jet.
We can just modify the home page just to make sure that it actually works.
So we'll open home jet.
Select all and copy clothes that open jet template jet pasted in there and change this to, in the title,
say, jet template.
And we'll just get rid of this stuff.
We just added all of that and say.
This page is rendered using the jet template engine.
OK, so everything went well, I should be able to say make restart.
It'll stop my application, start my application.
And now when I go back and reload this page, this one should work.
It should render a go template.
And it does go templates.
And this one should work rendering a jet template.
And it does.
This page is rendered using the jet template engine, and this one should give me a 404 page not found
in error.
And it did for a four page not found.
Perfect.
OK, so that just gets us started.
So now we have a place to actually start playing with sessions when we're ready to do that.
So in the next lecture, let's go install a session package.