So let's get started with Sessions, and obviously we want to manage sessions as much as possible,
at least the creation of them and so forth in the Celebrity House package and not in the My App package,
the whole point here is to build celebrities such that someone can just say celebrities knew with some
command line utility, give their project a name and they're ready to start going.
They'll have access to the sessions to database, to all that sort of thing.
So of course, we're going to put it in celebrities.
Now there are lots of different ways to manage sessions and go, but I'm going to use and I go to my
web browser.
I'm going to use this package, which I've used in a couple of my courses, and I like it a lot.
It's Alex Edwards, SC SE session management for GO.
And if you scroll down, you can see that it's pretty easy to install it.
There's the command, so let's copy that and go back to celebrities, you know, in our visual studio
code.
Open terminal and paste that and go get GitHub dot com slash Alex Edwards slash x version two.
And if there's a later version, I encourage you to stick with version two for this course, and I've
created after the fact, it'll just make things much easier for you.
And somehow the dollar sign in there.
So let's get rid of that dollar sign.
Try that again.
There it goes.
Now it's been added to my gold moth file, and I can do things with it.
And let's go back and look at the page for it again.
So basic use here we are, package main.
We import that.
We initialize the new session manager and we set some parameters on it like manage our session manager.
Lifetime equals 24 hours.
Well, that's pretty straightforward.
We can probably do that without much difficulty.
Let's open up celebrities don't go and scroll to the top and figure out where we're going to implement
sessions.
Well, to start with, we want our front end to have access to sessions without doing a lot of programming,
so we probably should add that type right here.
Insularity.
So I'll call the method or the field session, and it will be a type pointer to us dot session manager.
And hopefully you'll find it right there.
Let's make sure it imports version two.
It does.
OK, so now whenever we have this set up, people will have access to the session right from the celebrities
type, and that's perfect.
Now the other thing is, if we go back here and look again at this documentation session, manager has
this field lifetime, but it turns out it has a lot more fields, things you might actually want to
set up.
So I'm going to come back in here and I'm going to add something to my config type.
OK, so this is our application config, which is not exporting and it's not available outside of celebrities,
so you can't access it directly from the other application, my app.
But this is the sort of thing that's going to be useful for us in this hilarious package.
So first of all, I'll put in a type called cookie or a member called Cookie, and I'll call the type
cookie config, which doesn't exist yet, but we'll make it in event in a moment.
Cookie config.
So that'll throw an error.
That's fine for now.
And I'm also going to put in session type, which will be a string.
OK, now what is cookie config?
Well, let's go create it.
So I'll go over to type, start and go, and I'll put it in there.
So I'll type.
Try it again.
Type cookie config right there.
It will be a struct, and it's only going to have a very few members.
So it's going to have the name, what do I want to call my cookie?
And that'll be a string.
It will have lifetime.
And that also will be a string.
And does it persist between browser closes, for example, string?
And is it secure?
Are we going to insist that cookies be encrypted and that'll be a string?
And there are all strings for reason that you'll see momentarily.
And finally, what domain is the cookie associated with?
And that also will be a string.
OK, so I'll save this file format it.
And now if I go back to celerity go, the error goes away, says I'm not using these two, but we'll
be doing that very shortly.
And let's go down to the part where we begin populating the values in celebrities.
So, for example, this config right here?
Well, let's populate our cookie config.
OK, so let's add a cookie and that's a type cookie config, and we'll just populate the things we want
in there.
So net, well, we're going to get that from our dot on file.
That will be OS get on.
And if you look in the data on file in the My App application or project, you'll see that there's one
called cookie name, the cookie name.
That's one thing.
And we also want the lifetime and that comes from OS.
Don't get on cookie lifetime.
And we also have persist
and that comes from OS.
Don't get on cookie.
Persists
with an s at the end.
OK, so that reads that information into my configuration.
And after that, we may as well, since we're at it right now, put in session type, which we just
added to the config type and that will be OS.
Don't get on.
And we're looking for session underscore type.
OK, so now we have that information read into our config, and that's great.
So let's go down here.
So what we want to do next is right here is we want to somehow create a session.
And just like I put render in its own package, I'm also going to put a session in its own package within
celebrities.
So I'll go to my explorer and create a new folder at the root level of this little project called session.
And inside of that, we'll have a new file called Session Go.
OK.
So I'll give it a package declaration, which is obviously session, and I'll create a type in here
called session.
And it's exported because it is a capital letter is the first letter.
It's just a struct and it has a few fields cookie lifetime that will be a strict cookie persist
and that will be a string
cookie name.
And that will be a string.
Cookie Domain, and that will be a string.
Session type.
And that will be a string, and that's enough for right now, so let's save that, OK?
And now I'm going to make a function within this and exported function funk, and we'll have the pointer
to see pointer to session the session.
We just the type we just defined and I'll call this in it session and this will initialize our session.
It takes no parameters, but it returns a pointer to export session manager right there.
OK.
So let's make this.
We'll create two variables verb, persist and secure, both will be bullet and I better spell persister
persist that much better.
So now we make a few determinations.
Number one, how long should sessions last?
And of course, that's from the configuration, and we're going to pass that to the session type when
we initialize this package.
But we need that to be in the form of an integer and we're getting it as a string because we're reading
it from the dart on file and everything from the dart on file comes in as a string.
So let's create a variable called minutes and potentially an error.
And that's a sign the value of stricken from the from the standard library dart is too high and we're
going to use C Dot Cookie Lifetime right there.
Now we'll check for an error.
We're not returning an error, but if we do have an error, we'll just set minutes to something that
makes sense.
So if error is not equal to nil, then minutes equals sixty one hour.
OK, so now we have minutes and now should cookies persist?
And of course, that's pretty straightforward.
If strings dart to lower because I don't care how they type it in the dart on file and they convert
it to lower C dot cookie persist, which I see I spelled wrong.
I'm going to go fix that right now.
So that's under.
Persist, that's better persist if strings to lower seeded cookies persist is equal to true, they will
make.
Persist equal to truth else, persist equal to false, and I keep misspelling persist.
That's better.
So now we have persists into next.
Must cookies be secure?
And again, that's pretty straightforward.
If strings start to lower, see Dot.
Cookie Persiste equals to true, then we can just say secure equals true.
How does that make any sense?
Strings to lower?
We actually should have this as secure.
So let's add a title to this cookie secure and that will be a string.
OK, so this should actually be cookie secure here.
And where are we going to get that from?
Let's go back to our own file in our other project and look for the word secure.
Should we use a secure equals false and cookie secure?
That's better.
Cookie secure equals false.
So we do have a cookie secure.
And let's go back to our other project and see how we get cookie secure in there.
So back to celebrities and we have cookie lifetime persist.
Let's try secure thus better.
OST don't get on
cookie secure.
All right.
I overlooked that one.
That's better.
Now let's go back to session.
That makes more sense.
So we have a means of populating that value.
OK, so does the cookie have to be secure?
What's next?
Well, now we can create the session, create session, and we'll just use the syntax straight out of
the X package from Alex Edwards.
Session is a sign the value of X new.
So that creates a new session variable.
Now we'll set its values and we want to set its lifetime, and that will be equal to time dot duration.
And we're going to take the into minutes.
So that takes it to a time trial duration times Typekit minute right there.
So that gives it its lifetime session, the cookie.
And this is why we spent all that time getting our cookie values that persist equals persist.
Session cookie name equals.
Seed cookie name that's already a string, so that works just fine, we didn't have to do any work for
that one session cookie that's secure equals secure.
Now I have secure here and there, secure up there, good, and it defaults to faults that should be
fine.
OK, which means I can probably get rid of this too.
That's redundant code because if you don't give persist a value, it will be false by default.
That's better.
So that's cookie secure.
Now, the domain session cookie domain equals C Dot.
Cookie, to me and here I am, cookie name.
I should be.
Cookie name sloppy today.
So there's that one.
And now this one is just one.
We're going to set a default value for and not let anyone play with it.
Session dot cookie cookie dough.
Same site.
And we'll make that one of the default from the HGTV package.
HGTV Dot same site LAX mode.
OK.
And that's sufficient for our purposes.
So now the next thing we have to do and this is just planning for the future.
By default, we can use just ex-new and have all sessions managed by cookies, and that's fine and it
works really well.
And if you're even if you're deploying it to a production server, if you're enforcing HTTP connections
to the site and you're encrypting all the cookies, then you'll have no problems whatsoever.
But there are multiple different stores available to us.
If we go back to the package, asks Alex Edwards and scroll on down, for example.
He supports storing and badger.
That one's a bit out of date, but it is there and we could have updated if we wanted to, but we could
store to store, to Mongo, to my school, Postgres, all of these things.
OK, so let's go back over to here and put a switch statement here.
And this is why we have that session type set.
So we'll say which session store.
So we'll say switch
strings to lower once again, so I can never trust people to type things correctly in their files.
See the session type and we'll just put the cases we want to handle.
So for right now, we'll put case.
We'll just put Redis in there because we're going to implement a register before too long.
But we're not going to do anything with it.
So we ignore that one and we'll have a default, which will be cookie.
So we'll have Redis later on.
We'll also have these ones case.
Minus que el.
Or Maria Deeb.
And we'll do something with the right with the MySchool store or case postgres, which is sometimes
Typekit post.
Que el.
We'll do something with that.
For right now, we're just going to worry about the default, which is cookies.
OK, so the last thing we have to do here is to return the session return session.
So there should be no errors at this point.
Looks good.
Let's go back to celerity.
Don't go.
And now let's actually create that session so we can do it simply.
Is this?
Says scc, which is just a variable I'm creating for locally.
Session Dot session.
And that should import it from my package, and it does, and we'll populate its values.
So we want cookie lifetime right there, and that will become c-can Fakt Cookie Lifetime.
We also want Cookie persiste Cookie Persist, which is C dot config dot cookie dot persist.
And I spelled it right there.
Good.
We want cookie name, which is C dot config dot cookie dot name
and we want session type.
And that's going to be seeked config dot session type, which we set up just a few minutes ago.
And that's enough for now.
So that creates our session a variable.
Now we need to do something with it.
OK.
So of course, what we're going to do is say, see the session right there, which we added at the start
of this lecture.
That's going to be equal to from the sess variable we just created in a session.
And that should give us a session.
Now we can actually work with that session.
Yet we have to add a little bit of middleware and you can see that right here on the web page for this.
So we need to have a session store.
We need to have a means of loading and working with this session data.
So it's pretty straightforward to do that.
Here's loading and saving sessions.
If I click on that, it takes me down to here and you can see most applications will use the load and
save middleware.
That's exactly what we're going to do.
OK.
This lecture is getting fairly long, so I'll stop it right now.
But in the next lecture, we'll add some middleware to celebrities, which will be added by default
to the routes that we hand to the application, and that will allow us to load and save sessions at
will.