So let's keep working on sessions, and before we go any further, I did leave one thing out in the
last lesson and I'm sure you noticed it.
It's right here in Celerity Moscow.
It's at Line 77 or thereabouts in my code, and it's where I set the C config value.
When we added this cookie and cookie config struct, I left out the domain.
So let's add that domain, and that's OK.
Don't get on cookie with two O's domain underscore domain.
OK.
So we added that there.
Otherwise, when we declare our sessional variable sesh here on Line 92, the actual domain is never
going to get set.
So let's add that cookie domain and that is c the config dot cookie dot domain there.
Now, when we call it in its session, we'll have the cookie domain now would have worked without it.
Probably it would just grab the default domain of what it's running on, but I like to set these things
explicitly so that's taken care of.
So the next thing we need to worry about is adding that save and load middleware.
Now we actually have some middleware in our roots file right now.
And as you can see right here, we're using middleware that comes with it, she router.
But we actually want to add our own.
So I'll create a new file at the root level of my celebrity house project called Middleware Dot Go.
And of course, that has package main
package to alert us.
That's better.
And all we're going to do here is declare a very simple function with a receiver c pointer to celebrities
and we'll call it session load and it's middleware, so we will give it one parameter next each http
dot handler and it returns and HTP dot handler.
And this is as simple as calling returned, which we better spell right.
And we're going to return C Dot session because that's now available in our sliotars variable.
Dot load and save.
And we just handed the parameter next, and that's it.
And that takes care of loading and saving our session on every request.
So that is pretty straightforward.
Now we go back to our roots and we say, use that.
So right here, Max, don't use and we want to use C Dot session load and there should be no further
changes required.
All right.
So in the next lesson, we'll just see if we're getting that cookie set on our requests.