All right, so we have our middleware set up, we have our session initiated.
Let's make sure everything is wired up correctly.
So I'm looking at celebrities, my celebrities package and I'm looking at the middleware Dogville file.
And what I'm going to do, first of all, is just make sure this middleware is getting cold.
So inside of that, before the return statement, I'm going to take advantage of my info log see Dot
Info Log Dot print line.
I'll just say session load call, because we're not actually going to get a cookie created until we
put something in this session or try to read something from the session.
But this will tell me the middleware is firing anyway.
So let's switch over to our My AMP project and I'll open a terminal window and I'll make sure nothing
is running.
Make stop.
It's not, and I'll call make start.
So there it's running now.
Now we'll go to my favorite web browser and I'll just go to local host Port 4000 and then we'll go check
the log file.
So there it came up.
Let's go look at our log file.
And it said session loads load called perfect.
So it's actually running.
So now we can actually do something with sessions.
So let's create a new page in the Views folder in the Miami project or create a new file, which I'll
call Sessions plural jack.
OK.
And to make things a little simpler, I'll just open up this jet template.
Copy everything out of that.
Paste it into Sessions jet and just say we'll will say this value came from the session, which is a
good start.
And of course, we'll put some value there in a bit.
OK, and we'll change this up here.
Two sessions.
Oops.
The C.J. There Sessions.
OK, so that's all we're going to do for this right now.
Now let's go to our handlers and let's create a new handler.
I'll just copy this one to make it faster, and I'll call this session test and it will render the template
sessions, plural.
OK.
And what we're going to do in here, first of all, is just set up a route and make sure this is all
working properly.
So let's go to our roots and duplicate the the jet page route right here and make that session, which
I think that's what I called it in my home page.
Let's make sure home jet.
So they're session or sessions.
It was sessions plural simple close that go back to roots at an -- and we'll call the handler session
test.
OK.
So let's now just restart our application, make restart just to make sure everything's wired up properly.
And then we'll worry about adding session in a bit, adding additional data in a bit.
So let's go back to Firefox Reload this page just to make sure everything is current, and this should
take me to my Sessions page.
And there it is.
This value came from the session.
Now I want to add some data to the jet template that is stored in the session, and then we'll read
it from the session right in the same handler and we'll see if it actually displays properly.
So let's go back to our code and let's go to the session test handler and let's try putting something
in the session, whatever it may be.
So we'll say my data is equal to just some text file and then I'll call H Dot app dot session dot put.
And you can see that requires a few parameters, the first one is the context, and we have that is
just out of context.
And then the key part and then the value, which is my data and this has to be an assignment operator.
All right.
So now we've put something in the session.
We're not reading it yet, but we're actually doing something with it.
OK, so let's try restarting our application.
Make restart.
And let's go back to our web browser, and before I do anything else, I want to open my terminal window.
I'm going to open a new browser tab and I'm in Firefox, so I'm going to go to my Firefox preferences.
And of course, they're in a different place in Chrome, but I'm sure you can find them in Firefox.
I'm going to go to a privacy and security, then I'm going to go to manage data and I'm going to look
for local host.
I may have already cleared this out.
Local host, it has one cookie, so let's remove that cookie OK and save the changes.
Remove.
OK.
And I think I just did a make restart, but let's make sure I did.
Now back to Firefox and I'll go to my Celerity Sessions page.
I will open my developer's tools and I'll make it really wide so I can see everything and I'm going
to look at storage.
OK?
And what do we have for cookies?
Nothing right now.
So let's reload this page and now I have a cookie, as you can see right here.
So there's my sessional cookie being set up just the way that it should be.
So of course, we also want to read data from the session, then then pass it to this template so we
can say this value came from the session and have it say, Ooh here, and we'll take care of that in
the next lecture.