So let's try passing some data to our session, and because we're using jet templates, this is remarkably
easy.
So I'm looking at handlers Dot go in the My App project, and first thing I want to do is get these
backwards.
I want this to be better.
I want that to be the data and I want the context to be full.
OK.
So now that we've got information in the session, as silly as it may seem, we're just testing things
here.
Let's say my value is assigned the value of each Dot app, dot session, dot get string.
And we're going to look for the key food.
OK, now this returns.
What does it return?
It returns a string.
Now, of course, we have to give it the context.
So our context, our context.
I knew that.
So now we have my value.
So let's add that to the data we're going to pass to to jet now.
Jet actually takes two kinds of data variables that we see here and then context data.
We're going to ignore that for right now, but we might come back to it later.
In the meantime, let's store this value my value inside a data structure that we can pass as the first,
second, third fourth parameter to the jet page value.
OK.
So we do that like this first, which is a variable I'm just creating right now and we make a jetport
VAR map, which is really simple.
And now we just say VARs Dot set, and we're going to give it a key to look it up with.
And we'll call it food.
And the value will be my value, my value with that.
OK, now this is purely an exercise to make sure things work, but we declare a variable store bar in
a string.
We put that in the session here on Line Thirty eight.
Then we immediately grab it out of this session, storing the result in my value and we create a VAR
map and we put the value, my value with the key food here, which means we have to pass that data.
So we'll pass verbs right there.
Now we can go back to our session, Georgette Page Sessions Dot Jet, and all we have to do is, say,
in double curly braces food.
So if I restart my application, make restart.
And go back to my Web browser and click on Try Sessions.
There is a value displayed right there, so sessions work exactly as they should.
Perfect.
So now let's go write some tests for our session package inside this letter test project, and we'll
take care of that in the next lecture.