So let's write a test for our new session package in the Celebrity House project.
So the first thing I'll do is I will create a new file in the session folder called set up underscore
test start to go.
Now, technically, we don't need this right now, but we're going to need it before too long, so we
may as well do it at the moment.
So it's packaged session and I'll create a funk test me as we've done before, and this takes one parameter
and a pointer to testing Typekit.
OK, now this is going to be dead simple at the moment.
The only thing I'm going to do is type of exit and end run to run our tests.
Try that again or asked exit, import, run.
That's better.
And hopefully, that input imported the OST package.
For me, it did.
Perfect.
So now let's write the actual test.
We'll be modifying this one later on to set up things like a Redis pool when we use a Redis cache for
our session.
But at the moment, we can just write a very simple test.
So let's free to create a new file called Session underscore Tesco and again package session.
And we'll write one test and it's going to be named func and I'm going to call mine test session underscore
in its session, because that's the thing we want to test in this in this package.
And of course, that takes a parameter T pointer to testing Dotti, and it didn't do the import for
me testing dot t.
That's better.
So how do we test our init session?
Well, let's go look at it.
Session don't go in its session and that takes no parameters, but it returns in a session manager.
And of course, it depends upon this receiver having some values, so we'll have to set up a receiver
or the value that will be used for the receiver.
So I'll call mine doesn't matter what I call it, C is fine.
C is assigned the value of and is going to be a reference to.
So an ampersand session and we'll just populate the things we want in there.
So we want cookie like time and I'll make that one.
It doesn't matter for the test and we also want cookie persist.
And I'll set that to true as a string because these are all string values and we'll set cookie name.
We'll make that celerity house
and we'll also set up Cookie Domain, which I'll make local host as long as there's some value in there.
And the session type, I'll make Cookie.
And that's sufficient for our purposes right now, so there is a variable.
Now let's create another variable ver sim a pointer to assess succession manager.
OK, now we're going to use this during the course of our test.
Now will assign a new variable called says, and we'll give it the value of C Dot in its session.
OK, so now I have two things a pointer to SCA session manager right here and I have this variable,
which should be an ex session manager.
OK, so now I want to figure out how I can make sure that I've got some reasonable return value from
that call to in its session.
So I'll create a variable, which I'm going to call says Kind, OK, access kind with a capital K and
that's going to be have the type from the Reflect package dot com right there.
So that should in part reflect for me.
And it did OK, and I'll declare another variable, which is the type versus type on that and that's
reflect type.
Now I'll create a variable called RV for a value, and that will come from reflect dot value of right
there, and I'm going to hand it the CSC variable, I declared right back on line 22, the one we're
getting back for a minute session.
And this is what I'm going to use for my test, at least to start with.
OK, so what I'll do right now is, say for RV Makinde, I'm going to loop through all the kinds in
here is equal to reflect Dot Peter or Pointer or RV.
Makinde again is equal to reflect dot interface.
Better still reflect right reflect interface.
And I'll just print some information out here so we can see what kinds of things we're getting back.
So we'll say from the format package format dot print line.
And this is in the for loop, so I'll just put for loop there, so I know what's going on and I'll print
out RV Makinde and RV type and RV itself just to see what's going on.
OK?
And then I'll assign the value that I get from RV, RV Makinde to that variable set kind.
Susskind is now equal to RV account.
And not surprisingly, Seth type is equal to RV type.
Now, eventually, I want to get out of this.
I'll say RV is equal to RV element.
And once we're through this for loop, here's where we can do some tests.
First of all, I can do a simple test to make sure that what I go back is RV is valid.
So if not, RV don't.
And there's a method built right into this called valid is valid.
If it's not valid, then I have an error T1 error and my message will be invalid type or kind.
And then I'll put it put kind in a colon, make that a semicolon so it's more readable and I'll print
out the kind.
Perfect kind type, ERVEBO type.
So there's one thing we can test now, we actually haven't actually used eSIM or such kind or such type.
So we have to do something with those as well.
So let's try this.
If this kind is not equal to and here's where I can get the kind of the variable that I declared a little
while ago reflect the value of right there.
Essam Typekit, then that's a failing test, so I'll say tort error, wrong, kind returned.
Testing cookies session, this will be testing other kinds of sessions later expected.
And here I'll put reflect that value of some unkind and God.
And here we have Seth kind.
So there's one thing taking care of now.
Let's copy this whole thing
and paste it in here and change this to Seth type.
Try that again.
Just type
and change this to type wrong type returned expected.
This would be type and this becomes less common sense type.
All right.
So we should be able to run these tests now or this test.
Let's try it.
Open a terminal window CD session and go Test Dash V for verbose dot.
And there it is.
It passed.
OK, so that was pretty straightforward.
Let's move on.