So now that we have a test for a session package, let's just check our coverage.
So I'm still in the Celebrity House project and I'll open a terminal window and I'm at the correct directory.
I'm at the root level of the celebrity house directory and all I have to do is type make cover because
we're using that make file and I have a failure and the failure is render test.
Don't go line 42.
I know exactly what that is.
So Line 42 is failing there.
It's failing because to make it fail.
A few lectures ago, I had a home to hear.
Let's change that back to home so that that'll actually pass this time.
So clear the terminal window make cover.
And everything passed, and we have two files being checked, rendered Argo, which is a seventy nine
point three percent and as you can see, it's pretty good coverage.
Most of the things that fail here are not covered.
Here are actually cases that I personally do not care about because I am not a purist and I don't insist
upon 100 percent test coverage.
I know that if there's a problem with any of these, I'm going to get the appropriate error returned.
So those don't bother me.
If they bother you, just jump through the hoops necessary to create the conditions where you'll get
an error here in here and here in here.
And that's entirely up to you.
I'm not going to do that.
So let's check session eighty eight point two percent.
Not bad.
And the only cases that are not covered are if someone does not put a value in the dot own file, which
we're facing up in, up here when we create our session struct in our setup, not test file.
So you could just leave that empty and write another test, it's entirely up to you, but I'm really
happy with this coverage.
Perfect.
So let's move on, and I think it's time to now start worrying about how we're going to integrate a
database into our application.
And in this course, we're going to take care of two databases Postgres, my favorite open source and
go to database and either my Escuela or MariaDB, which use exactly the same driver.
So we'll get started on that in the next section.