You have the theory of branches.
Why.
Well first kind of talked about why they're useful.
It's the idea of kind of like work on this bring it in work on this bringing in more branches as opposed
to less smaller changes as opposed to larger changes to branch merging and yeah we could even demonstrate
why just look what's working and master is bad.
You have a I make a change to tax and push it then you make a change without pull you make a change
in trying to push.
You can see the conflict that occurs.
Sure.
All right.
So now we're going to start exploring why branches are useful and this previous video that we just did
was cloning a public project.
Right.
Does Speedie media working.
Yeah.
And then we fought it and and now what we're gonna do is we're gonna both create changes to the same
repo without branches and we'll see how that could create some difficulties.
And so I'm going to start out and I'm going to go to my terminal and I'm inside right now going project
and inside there I've got that test t t and I'm gonna open that up and my editor.
So the Nano test text text text t text not text D.
And that's in here and then I'm going to add some change.
And so I just added that from Todd right.
Like that's what I've just added control X save it.
And.
And then well before I save it Daniel is gonna open it and he's also going to add something you could
see what mine looks like now.
Now we're gonna switch to Daniel's computer and he's going to open it and change the projects go for
it.
Okay.
I just real fast reclined under the goes to a loved one instead of B Ah the great.
That's awesome.
And I want the collaborator.
So I now I'm now set up as the collaborator or as as my account or Lord knows at which is a collaborator.
And so I can open up a text editor and
I can open that text file open that text file you see his doesn't have my changes yet I haven't pushed
him I haven't even saved him on my machine yet.
So go for it.
You're at your chain.
So I can say oh I want to fix that.
That was a mistake.
It should just be some text not some t text.
So if I save that and possibly add some additional stuff some more text and put your name after it.
We know that one's from me just so go and say it.
So it's safe now.
And so I've saved my life you push now and so hit it and push it I can get stats here get add that file
specifically.
That's another option.
Option is you can name the files you're adding but then you have to list all of them.
So it's no green it's modified it could get Mitt and fixed type O added
so if I get status again it's still it's still on my machine.
I've got that commit but it's not yet pushed yet.
So if I get push this change because it talks to get pushes that I can go now.
I can go here fresh the paid 21 seconds.
Oh my.
Midway through I can see some text at the T.
And it got right here and now I'm back in my file and I'm gonna save mine.
So I'm gonna file name to write as tech start to 60s and now minds save.
And if we look at my my file right you could see my file some t text and add some change from Todd.
There's nothing about Daniel's effects fix taking away that some t text and his lines not there obviously
just on my machine.
So I'm going to get add a dash a get commit dash and my boss is a blowhard no pride not a good command
message
adds a new line to text file and then get push and when I push it's going to say rejected failed to
push some raps to get updates rejected because remote teams work that you do not have locally this is
usually caused by another repository pushing to the same ref you may want to first integrate the remote
changes get pull before pushing again see know about passports and get push for details so what do you
recommend we do at this point follow those directions so it's good to get pulled do the get pulled is
the first step and so automatic merge failed fix conflicts and then commit the result so we have emerged
conflict text so so when you get pull sometimes get is able to figure it out.
So for example if I just deleted that T without adding more lines get would probably have figured it
out because I changed the line that he that his changes didn't effect and he changed lines that might
in effect it would've just been able to automatically merge it but because I added some things and he
added some lines at the bottom of the file get wasn't able to figure that out automatically.
So it tells him there's a there's a conflict in text 2016 and if he doesn't get status it will show
him that it's well it says both modified text at T T.
So now if he opens text out t t he can see the conflict.
So with that text so so you can see a get adds conflicts in this rather odd manner it has a bunch of
less than science and then what you're Kurt and then what it's called on your own machine.
So in this case head which usually means where you're currently working and then it's got some equal
signs in the energy and the bottom it's got a bunch of greater than signs and a commit number.
So this was years so so stuff here was so.
That's your comment.
No.
OK.
And then the head head is almost always what you've done yourself.
Yeah so to fix this I actually just start editing this file and save it right.
So get rid of that I bring this up I say get rid of that and then I come down here and I get rid of
this and and then I come down here and I get rid of that
and I'm like that's what we want the file to look like.
So I control X and then I hit y to save it and I hit enter and I do get status updates you get stat
it still says it's book both modified seeds you get seed you get add on that.
You add that file name or dash a.
Now if you get status it will say.
This is changes to be committed so you just get commit without a dash in without.
Okay.
Tell me why.
So when you get with this is creating a merge commit and then the merge commit has a default message
already.
So you can add the dash M and put it in the custom message for this merge commit.
But the default message is usually good for merge conflict fixing document.
So it will actually open your editor still but it's got the default message already so you can just
ex the editor.
So in this case it's a vim so I believe it's and you will exit you call and Q Yeah.
So now if you get yes now if you get statuses you can see that it gets that it shows it's been committed
and you push.
So that was kind of a laborious process where you have emerge conflict you have to open the file manually
fix it then you have to.
The hardest part.
Get out of them.
Yes.
You went them.
And then you push it.
So so back over at my machine now if I refresh this page I can now see this merge Chase merged page
4 file and add branches helps us avoid those conflicts and idea well we'll talk about the idea of branches
you want to do more branches than last and smaller commits as opposed to larger commands when you're
working with people that way you see what everybody is doing more frequently.
Correct yeah.
And less conflicts and less conflicts.
All right we'll do that next video.