So just to anchor you in the course outline we just got finished with working with merge requests.
You could see what we've done here so far.
We did a little introduction to Daniel and get we did understanding SS H encryption.
We did creating our github repo and we also showed how to work in windows when we were doing that.
And you know getting get bash terminal running on Windows we saw adding a collaborator to get how we
saw cloning a public project and cloning and forking kind of saw both of those.
And then we looked a little bit about if everybody is working on Master how those could lead that could
lead to merge conflicts and how you deal with merge conflicts and then branches don't eliminate merge
conflicts but they help more people work together on the same project and it helps segment kind of what
is happening in where you can kind of see where people are working and what they're working on but merge
conflicts aren't eliminated by branches.
And so once they are pushed to the end of the branch that's that's not happening while you're working
and interrupting your work say Say that again goes away in the merge conflict when you're using branches
though merge conflicts are eliminated but they are all pushed to the end of the branch lifetime instead
of while you're working.
So if you're just doing that you're all working on master every time you commit there's potential for
merge conflict at that point.
I got it.
Whereas if you're using branches it's only when you're done with the branch and you're merging the branch
back into the map where you merge the branches together at the end of your work you've you've made all
of your things you're going to make you've made all your changes you're done thinking about new stuff.
Now you change you can switch your train of thought to.
OK now what's the conflicts.
And just for all of us code heads out there all of us engineers branches and get doesn't eliminate the
need for communication between humans.
It's still also vitally important to communicate with your team and let people know what you're working
on.
So you could try to eliminate those conflicts as much as possible.
And so remember that.
So right now if I look to see what project I'm in I'm in the GO line project and I could see that the
route I've got my hidden get folder tells me this is gets tracking everything.
And so one command I have here is get branch and this will show me my branches.
And so I currently only have the branch master.
And now if I do get branch also has a dash a variant.
Let's hear it.
So get branch dash a shows.
All branches that you're get knows about both on your own machine and wherever your remote host is in
this case.
So I'm going to just keep track commands used in video here and we will do get branch showed the branch
and and get branch related to that is dash which shows all of your branches.
Yes.
So it's getting so get branch defaults to only showing branches that you are that your device has used
before.
So in this case master whereas get branch dash a is for all branch is that you know about which is step
on your device and the stuff that's on the the wherever you're cloning from in this case GitHub.
All branches to that
show.
Branches out there and and now the next thing I want to do is create my own branch.
So the way I've learned to do this is get check out dash B and checkout is how you check out a different
branch and then we can give it a name and I'll call this you know dog dog branch.
That's it.
And now switch to new branch dog.
You can see the command.
If I do get branch right there it shows me my two and if I do get branch dash.
It shows me the remote branch also which does not know about dog yet because you have not pushed dog.
So get up does not know about it so you don't see a remote origin slash dog.
You only see local dog and now you can also see the star next to the dog and that dog is green.
So I'm on the dog branch.
I could create a file here and I'm going to do that with nano and canine teeth.
And I love dogs.
What can I say.
Control X and save it and enter and I could do it get status and I see I have that.
And so now what I do at this point.
So now you can use to your get ad and commit like you normally do.
You add dash yes I'll get commit commit dash and commit to Ms.
Dash and adds canine file and declaration of feeling towards dogs and and now if I wanted to I could
do another thing I could.
No.
I don't know Labrador texting likes like to fetch balls lads like to fetch balls.
Yes.
Enter and get add dash Ash dash a comet dash to end it.
I got it.
Yeah that's him and about labs and then get status and nothing to commit.
Working to clean.
So I've got those.
So where do I take it from here.
So from here is now.
Now you need to tell get hub about the bridge.
So if you just do a get push it will give you an error which actually tells you what you need to do
to fix it actually.
So you can see it now set is great.
Current branch dog has no upstream branch so basically it's saying You've got dog.
He doesn't know what you should be pushing dog to and it gives you a suggestion get push dash dash set
upstream origin dog which creates the dog branch on github and sets and pushes and sets it so it will
always do that from now on.
So I've got the branch dog on my local computer but the branch dog is not on get.
And so when I tried to push it's not pushing the master origin master origin is right.
Yes it's not pushing towards a master cause I'm not on branch master so it's like where do you want
to push.
And so if I wanted to push this branch up to get I would go ahead and enter this command and then press
enter.
Is that something I want to do.
Yes in this case this command with the state kind of thing is get push like you normally do and then
the origin dog basically says you're pushing to origin your dog branch and then the set upstream says
Save this as a default so that get pushed on the dog branch.
Now on always goes origin dog.
So I push this
in so now if you go to get hub you can now see the branch so just go back to the right and two branches
two branches and branches active branches your branches default branch.
My dog.
And so those are on there and and then I'm accepting emerge requests if I want to merge this into Master
we could see how to do that in the next video.
Keep the video short yeah.
All right.
So that's creating a branch and adding some files to the branch and committing those files and then
pushing that branch up to a new branch on your origin your remote repository.
Get hub and we'll see how to in the next video How to how to merge those merge that branch into master
and then also how to get rid of the branch when you're done so that's coming up.