So one of the cool things about get out of here on Daniel's computer you could see that if you go up
Well I'll let you show it.
Yeah.
So get up actually has a bunch of stuff that gives you over here on this insights tab.
Lots of.
But the one I find most helpful most often is the network area.
So this network area shows all commits all branches all forks from this repo that have happened.
And so you can see here's the original comment.
The for storage book.
Here's where both Todd and I made a both made a commit in the merge commit and now down here you can
see the dog branch and it's even labeled dog dog branches at this commit currently where its master
is this commit and you can also see the forked the forked repo down here with its own commit and so
you can that you can actually see the lines as they merge back together and split apart and just kind
of visually track what's going on with your branches and that's moving left to right or the right is
the future so as we continue to add stuff you'll see it growing out to the right.
Correct yes.
And you can drag it around too to actually see stuff to go back and forth.
So one thing to add is that before you create a branch it's important to know what branch you're on
because you get to create a branch off of any branch.
It can be a master branch of a dog fight fires on dog and one to create another branch I could create
a branch right off of dog so I can demonstrate that here.
So I get pull to pull everything I can see it sees oh there's now a new branch.
And if I get it branch I just see master but if I get branch dash a I can see remote origin dog and
I can get check out dog.
No no dash B dash B is for creating a branch.
Get check out just branch it by itself.
Just goes to that branch.
Also no I do not need to put remotes origin dog I just put the actual branch name dog and so now switch
to a new branch dog and if I get branch now I'm now on dog.
And from here I can get I can get check out dash B
detailed detailed dog and now I'm on new branch detailed dog get branch dog
which currently that's still the same as dog but if I then make some changes like I open up this canine
96 t say put capital ii there for example I love your attention at all.
Get met proper grammar is important which I don't know how to spell grammar.
Yeah it's a G
now I push this I will say it will get I almost that ver just know this command I just don't I almost
always just do the get push and then copy paste it it's not a command we're memorizing given that it
tells you what you're supposed to do to fix it like a so now if I go back to this network tab and I
refresh
I can now see.
Dog is there in detail dog is a separate is off dog doesn't do the little interesting little if something
else is committed to dog it will put it'll push this down so you see that dog is still standing let's
add a file to your detail dog and see that switch see what happened so that it's back at dog so if I
go if I get checked out back to dog and I create a new fire so note this canine guy takes yes that works
I still because detail dog is where I got fixed not dog I can now create a new file
of smart
I can get add all commit and I like poodles push whereas Mangum it's up on the fly yes
so now if I refresh the page here now naked see they pulled the tail dog off into its own line again
the nice well we've got some confusing stuff to clean up here yeah and the main thing one of the main
things you want to take away from this is that when you create a new branch you create that branch off
of whatever branch you're currently on and it's also always good to do a get pull and I put that in
red here in the video above before creating a branch do a get pull you know so get your current state
of the remote repository with a get pull so before you create a branch you get pull so everything's
current then create your branch what ever branch your arm and you create a branch creating branch off
of that and then when you're ready to check branch out from master to just get check out branch name
which you could see right here get check out branch name.
Ready for the next video or shall we say getting more on this one.
That's it.
All right.
See the next one.