Now that we've created some different branches we've got some different code on those different branches
or different files different text.
We want to look at how do we merge those and bring those branches back into master and then get rid
of those branches.
So that's what we're gonna do in this video and Daniel is going to show us how to do it.
So there's two main ways to get to merge your branches back into either their origin branch or into
master which is the ultimate origin branch.
The first way is same as with before.
You can make a pull request to forget at least.
So you've got the dog and you had detailed dog and gives us a nice little shortcut to just go straight
to them or you can just make a generic app make a pull request.
I want to go from the dog into master.
Now we have to think about detail dog came off of dog.
Before we do that and kind of like so merge detail dog and the dog first.
Like do you think about that.
You can.
And especially since dog gotten update that detail dog is missing.
But it's not necessarily all required yoy.
The main thing I would think about is don't merge one branch into another branch that's completely independent
from it.
So if I make a cat branch off of master I don't want to merge dog into cat because they are complete.
They don't come.
They're not.
So you can do it however you want.
So let's start with dog and see what happens.
We're gonna use the dog in the master dog in the master so we can see the changes that the changes are
in green there.
So there is keen on the dog tax got added and Labrador tech's got added and poodle techs got added.
So we're gonna add those three files.
Let's do it.
It's just creates a merger pull request the poor questions message.
If there's only one commit the pull requests messages defaults to that commit.
Otherwise it's the branch name is the default case multiple committees.
So there's three comments here so it's the branch name.
So add dog data
and again we didn't provide a comment.
But you want to make sure you have good descriptions and comments so that when you're submitting these
particularly if you're submitting them to us we know what's changed and what's going on.
So now since I'm a collaborator I can just merge it directly from here which allows me to make a message
on the merge commit if I want to or whatever.
And so now this this pull request is merged.
If I go to code it can now see I'm one branch master and I can see all the different dog but the original
dog branch still exists.
OK.
It's marked as merged but I can go back to that branch still and keep working on it.
And detail dog hasn't been merged so let's go ahead and merge now and we'll see those changes.
Let's just go through that once more you want mean you do it on my machine.
So.
So the other that we could do it the other way of doing mergers though.
Sure let's do so if you are a collaborator.
You don't actually have to go through.
You can use the actual just get way of merging into the way the command line with the command line.
So you can so always want to make sure you pull all your changes.
So I am on it.
What branch my on I'm on dog still.
So get check out back to master.
And here's something interesting I pulled while I was on dog and then I flipped over to master and now
it says your branch is behind origin master by four minutes when you get pull it updates all the branches
but does not update your local branch to the remote branch except the one you were on so it knows that
the remote master has four more commits but my master is not updated yet because I was on dog when I
pulled so I need to pull again on master in order to chain update my master to the remote master now
that I've got my master is up to date I can now do the merge so if I get merge detailed dog so not Mark
not Mirko merge.
So get merge takes and then a branch name takes everything in that branch emerges into your current
branch.
So I'm moving detail dog into M..
So at this merge time this is when emerge conflict may occur either during the pull request or here
manually with the Get merge detail dog.
This is when a merge conflict cannot happen right.
If there is one not a big deal then you just manually go in and resolve it.
So are you saying human eyes on this please.
We need a human to figure out these differences.
So in this case there was no conflicts.
Also it just merged.
And now I can just get push this merged code which will take however long and now if I go back to hub
and I go to branches detail dog does not say merged because it has merged if there is a merge.
If there is a pull request to do it but if you look at this list here you can see that detail dog has
three commits or there's three commits on master detail dog doesn't have and there are zero commits
one detail dog that master does not have so say that again when you see that.
So so this is 3 0.
There are three commits on Master that detail dog that's right.
Yeah and there are zero commits on detail dog that master design.
Okay so the three comments are from dog right.
Yeah yeah the merge merge commits or ever or so on Master.
Interesting.
And so that's that's merging our two branches onto master one way.
Doing it on github doorway doing it on the terminal.
And when you do it on the terminal you want to make sure that you are on the branch you want to merge
into.
So we switched over to master and then pulled so that we got master current with the remote and and
then once we did that we were able to merge the branch that we wanted into master so we're on Master
Master its current with the remote and then we do get it merge and then the branch name get merging
and the branch name that's it.
All right.
So the next video will show how to delete branches.