All right.
So now we're going to see how to delete branches and annual shows how do I see it.
So once you've got branches merge you probably want to clean them up so you get branch.
You can see detailed dog and dog are still there even though they've been merged into master.
So do eat a branch.
It's got branch dash D for delete in the name of the branch that do eat a branch dog.
However this only deletes it on your own machine.
So if I get branch dash a remote origin still has the dog and pushing does not affect this at all if
I push says everything's already up to date.
If I pull everything still up to date get branch dash a still shows get hub still has dog.
So if you go to your repo and you hit the branches on GitHub you can go into.
You can see the dog branch and you can delete it.
There is delete it on github.
Now if I can get pull and already update still but and if I get branch dash a it still sees dog now
the reason for this is just that get is caching that it's it's it's that it saw that there was a branch
called dog at one point in time so it still keeps that around even though it's not actually there anymore.
So what you need to do to do that is get remote rune origin.
This was yes.
So you get remote prune origin.
This tells get to good to check origin and prune out any branches that we've got cached that origin
no longer has.
So you can see it says pruned origin dog and if you get branch dash egg and see it no longer has dog
tags so and you can do this in the or other order too.
I can delete detail dog
and if I get remote prune Orange says detail dog is gone.
Get branch dash a It Gets gone here.
But I still have my local copy so I need to eat my local copy as well detailed
branch.
Now I'm all cleaned up.
We just have mastered now we've got master local and then we have our remote origin master origin HEAD.
SO head is just basically the default where we're currently at.
So remote origin is that currently which is at Master head is that master that's pointing it's almost
like an alias for origin master the madam or master.
Yes.
Okay great.
That was awesome.
I really liked seeing the leading branches so yeah.
Todd still has his copies of those two branches as or you never got detailed dog so you don't even.
Yeah.
Let's take a look and let's clean me up so get branch books get branch DSA DSA and I am on dogs I need
to do get check out master and and then get branch Dash and I use my arrow keys to cycle through commands
they're previously done commands and then I'm gonna do a get branch dash D and get rid of dog shape
poll first see what happens when you pull if you it doesn't work matter too much.
One thing to note though is if you do a branch delete where it does not know that it's been merged because
you haven't pulled yet for example get we'll give you a warning so.
So if you tried to delete dog before pulling so your computer doesn't know that dogs emerged yet get
will warn you and give you the command to force it to be deleted anyway.
Which I believe is just capital the avoid I remember.
So now I've gotten rid of dog and I want to do my get remote remote print origin to see if anything
can be cleaned up and I got rid of a remote origin dog so I'm all good to go to.
That's the leading branches the guy thing you want to add to that.
That's right.
Tweet branches.
Good stuff.