OK.
So now we're going to do a little workflow summary so as workflow summary is a bit of a review and you're
going to kind of see everything we've just learned.
Integrated together.
And I'm gonna do that.
And so going to my terminal.
Like the first thing I want to do is just do a get pull and make sure that everything is current then
tells me I'm already up to date.
I could see the working project that I'm in right there.
And if I do get branch it's just going to show me my local branches.
But if I do get branch dash a it's gonna show me all of my branches and let's say I have an idea f or
something I want to do I want to add a new file so I'm going to go work on a different branch and so
I'm gonna do a get check out dash B I'm going to create a new branch by checking it out.
That's how you do it and then add the branch name.
And this one is going to be I don't know what you're doing dogs.
Maybe we should switch to birds.
So this is we're going to add birds to our thing and so now if I do might get branch dash eight shows
me.
There it is.
Get branch s eight shows me I'm on the bird branch and I could create a new file here so I'm going to
now parakeet that T T.
And they sure don't know much about birds.
I heard a really interesting that you show me that YouTube video of the bird of YouTube who's singing
the Imperial March from Star Wars is awesome.
Check it out.
You haven't seen it.
And.
And then I could do it get status and I could do.
I could see I've got a new file.
Could you get add dash a get comment if I wanted to on it get add I could have added the file name and
adds parakeet file which describes one trait parakeets.
So having meaningful command messages it's important so trying to model that too.
And now if I do get status and now if I do get push it's going to ask me Hey do you want to send this
up to get a job and I'm like OK.
Yes sure.
If I didn't want to.
Like if I'm working in a community with other developers I want to push my branches up to the remote
so that whoever's watching this project they all have eyes on who's doing what.
And so the people who are the collaborators on the project use the get up phrase who are watching the
game project they could see what the different branches are that are being worked on and and have an
idea of who's doing what.
Right.
And so some teams maybe would even have it would they have a practice of pre fixing a branch with the
developer's name you know that oh this developers working on this branch because otherwise you have
to do a little digging to figure out whose branch came from her.
So the most common way actually is to prefix it with an issue number so you can create issues which
are basically bug request bug reports or feature requests.
And the most common is to prefix your branch name with the net with the number of the issue on Github.
So it's associates at the branches associated and get hub actually knows about this and will actually
stick like links in the issue like this there's a branch for this issue over here.
That's super cool.
All right.
So now that I'm going to push this up I'm going to do the command that was offered to me here by.
So I push that up and and then maybe I'll just get everything current again with the get pull but get
pull see if that brings anything down but if I go to get hub now I could look here and go to site click
on that it refreshes everything I could go to two branches and we've got birds as as the new branch
and master and.
And now if I wanted to merge this I could do a new poll request right here from get hub and in here
it automatically gives the name and I'd leave some comment I think I think we should include info about
birds or whatever and create pottery class and then since I'm a collaborator that pull requests I go
back to my project go Lang and then go look at the poll requests that all requests right here I click
on it and I could merge this poll request I think we should create that adds parakeet file if I want
to see the files changed I could go right there I could look at the different commits that have been
submitted in this poll request and then go back to the conversation I'd say this looks good or look
looks good to me LG T.M. and a comment and then merge request merge pull requests and confirm merge
and then I'm going to come back to my terminal and I'm going to do it get pull.
Get everything current.
And it tells me here from get hub.
And if I do get branch dash a tells me I'm on birds.
But I wanted to get check out.
And just I want to move to master not create a branch.
I'm just checking out M. not adding the dash B.
And now if I look at my branches I'm a master.
I want to get pull again what did I.
Yeah.
Just pointing out and show it tells you specifically you were Master your local master is behind the
origin master.
So you probably want to get pull.
Yes some men do get pull.
Get that car in again and.
And when I look at my branches that I'm there and then I'm gonna do to delete a branch I could come
over here back here and delete the branch from up here.
And and that's under branches.
And then delete birds.
And then I could do a get pull once more and then look at my branches and I could get to remove this
branch I could do get branch Dash.
D birds and get an origin go and now look at my branches and I've got masters and remote origin master
which is great.
So that was getting everything going and summarize that workflow right here.
So we create a branch get check out DSP branch name you could see your branches see all branches get
branch a you can work on a branch branch by get get check out branch name the switch to branch which
you use a name which newly created branches it automatically puts you in to call to check out still
see stars of the branch and stage files and then get stars and commit files and check out master and
you could merge from the terminal we did it from the get hub and you could push to your remote repo
you could delete your branch and then you could prune your origin.
So that's pretty good stuff.
Anything to add to that.
No.
The nice thing that I think one of the things that was also covered this video is prefixes.
Branches with with an issue number from get hub is a useful practice right.
Yeah.
So that was awesome at it all right.
That's a little workflow.
Get hub summary.