All right.
Welcome to the hands on exercises ninja Level 1.
We call these hands on exercises ninja levels because it's fun and we can't use.
I was a little concerned about using jet level because jet I level maybe Disney might have an issue
with that.
So we're calling a ninja level one.
And by the way just because I mentioned Disney I just want to say hey to all of my Disney jet engineers
at the Jet I Engineering Academy which is something Disney has not a lot of people know about.
Totally cool the Jedi Engineering Academy.
How sweet is that.
So you might google it or look into it and they look for guest speakers so if you're somebody who's
in the L.A. area maybe they have other locations and you want to speak at the Jet I engineering academy
that's like an awesome thing to put on your résumé.
Total tangent sorry.
Try to save personal anecdotes to the end.
These are hands on exercises are going to help you learn more efficiently and effectively which means
you're going to learn faster and you're going to remember it longer.
You can't.
Well maybe you can.
I can't I can't just watch the videos and you know retain like I have to actually get my hands dirty
and go out there and work with it and try it out myself and so that's what these hands on exercises
are designed for.
That's one of the things that I think distinguishes the courses that I create we're creating from other
classes because a lot of these online classes is just some voice over screen recording and you're like
impressed by what that person does anything.
Wow.
You know you understand everything why you watch it all but then you get to the end.
You don't really know anything.
So the hands on exercises is really a difference.
And so that's from 20 years in academia over 20 years 20 22.
Coming up on 23 years now working at the university and college level doing the work is really kind
of having persistence having grit adding those drops to the bucket persistently patiently.
You're bound to succeed doing the work that's doing these hands on exercises.
That's what really helps you learn these skills.
So we've put together some awesome hands on exercises here for you to help you solidify and cement everything
we are going through with get and I'm a little bit sleep deprived because I was up editing the videos
last night and they're looking great really happy at how they're turning out but so we're gonna go through
these hands on exercises and I really encourage you to do them and to have a good time while you're
doing them because if you're not having a good time what's the point.
What's the point.
I've been listening to.
I'll save that personal anecdote for the end of this video.
All right.
A couple of housekeeping items.
There's two computers Daniel and I each have a computer and so sometimes you see my screen sometimes
you see Daniel's screen you probably maybe already figured that out but I realized we hadn't spoken
to that when I was editing the videos last night.
And so I just wanted to make sure that you realize hey sometimes you're seeing his machine sometimes
you're seeing my machine.
And then also we've created some structure to get hub repo.
And if you look at the get hub repo here I have created 0 0 1 learning yet so you probably already saw
that since you're seeing the finished repo as if you went through some time machine.
I wish we could go through that in the court.
No because then I'd be older and I wouldn't have lived it but 0 0 1 learning gets all the code we've
done up to this point.
Inside there you'll see those dog bird folders that we were creating.
And then if you wish to see the repo as it was as we're going through it you can click the commits the
the the commit do it show them and you can see here's all the commits and you can go back to any given
commit and you can.
And you can see what the repo looked like right after this occurred.
This is amazing stuff.
It's truly amazing.
Linus Torvalds is a genius.
Hey I'm going to shut this window because yard people just started running yard equipment outside.
Hold on.
Sorry for getting you off my chair.
All right.
And then the hands on exercises are going to be in 0 0 2.
You can see there's about humble and purpose.
So if that doesn't pique your interest you know these are going to be pretty interesting hands on exercises
in a Comp Sci course where it's about humble and purpose.
So we're going to integrate a little humanity with a little bit of our coding and then finally the last
thing I want to do under housekeeping is just share a little bit about the methodology sounds so rigorous
and official the way in which we are kind of thinking about building this course and so part of the
way we're building this course is that I tweeted out to all the people who follow me on Twitter and
I asked.
And whereas that like creating a project based web dev go long course need web dev project I need a
web dev project to create any ideas you need something built reply below or DME.
And so we asked people you know what do you want to see in this course.
What what would you like to have built.
And there was a ton of responses.
And one of the responses that came back I'm not sure how many times but people wanted to see how to
contribute to open source projects.
And so that's kind of why that that influenced our thinking to include this get stuff right at the beginning.
And so I just wanted to speak speak to that sort of let you know where we're getting ideas some of the
ideas for what we're including in this course.
All right.
So it's an introduction to this section hands on exercises.
Ninja Level 1.
And the next video we will do the first hands on exercise and then we'll give you the solution to that.
So we're going to give you the problem.
You can pause the video.
Go do the problem and then you'll positive video and you could see our solution.
And so that's we're going to do the next video analogies provide that personal anecdote.
So you just saw here for the coding jump ahead.
I know sometimes I get a you know you just push start and the mouse starts.
So here's a personal anecdote.
I've been listening to a lot of Anthony Tony Robbins recently.
He has this great book unshakeable.
He spent seven years researching and he's connected to some of the most powerful people on the planet.
So he spent seven years talking with people like Ray Dalio and Warren Buffett and some of the heaviest
hitters the luminaries of investing.
And they built all that research into a book.
Two books and the short book is called unshakable so I've been listening to his book and it's a great
book.
It's really good.
So I don't know what else I want to say about that.
I think I was talking about voices and he's he you could hear it in his voice he talks a lot.
All right.
So that's a personal anecdote.
And we will see you in the next.
Hands on exercise.
Do you have any housekeeping or anything you want to add.
No.
See you in the next video.