So here's a hands on exercise number one.
And so I'm going to introduce this hands on exercise.
Then you're going to pause the video you're going to pause the video and you're going to go and do the
hands on exercise and then when you're all done you're gonna come back and unplugged the video and you'll
see our solution.
So for those first hands on exercise we're gonna do an introduction and an introduction to in classes
as a common practice.
Everybody introduces themselves and so we wanted to have an introduction in here.
We're not asking for you know well you could see here we'll go and get hub and you can go to about and
we have a little template here.
So you're welcome to include whatever information you want in the introduction but I just provided like
yea started coding coding strings comma separated list and anything you want to share about yourself.
So pretty simple pretty innocuous but also kind of interesting to maybe see who else is in the class.
And we're gonna do this in a way where we are identified through our Twitter user name because that's
unique.
So we can explain the rest out.
And second I just want to say one more little bit about the introduction and respect this format here
because later in the course or maybe later in the future course we could take this data and if it's
unstructured format we can use it as an example to pass through a whole bunch of files and be able to
pull out that information and put it into some other storage structure and then maybe use that to connect
it to an interface web interface or a Web site or something like that that might be interesting.
And so anyhow there's a little template that you can fill out and for this for this hands on an exercise
you're going to introduce yourself feel free to provide as much information about this right here.
Fill these out if you want or not.
It's totally optional or you can make it up and.
And to do that you're gonna fork this repos or fork.
The goal line project repo that's our our project here.
So that's kind of what we did in the exercises.
And then on branch master go into the folder 0 0 2 hands on exercises 0 1 about and so that is 0 0 2
hands on exercises 0 1 about and make a copy of the 0 0 template about me text.
And so here's 0 0 a template about me taxi or copy that file then rename your copy to your get hub user
named T X T.
And in the file to the extent that you feel comfortable introduce and share about yourself stage this
file commit this file provide a descriptive comment message push this commit to your fork create a pull
request to branch master on this repo right.
And so I already explained this the structure of the file and then the second note as if for some reason
the template is no longer there simply you could recreate it or just provide a description herself.
So for some reason you can't find that.
Just do a work.
That's the hands on exercise.
Sorry I'm a little bit long winded pauses video go do that.
Hands on exercise I think that's kind of fun getting close to the camera and then when you're all done.
Come on back now y'all and we'll show you our solution what you're gonna do right now.
So hopefully you've already paused the video and gone and done your hands on exercise let's do it.
Who wants to go first you or me.
Doesn't matter.
Shambo.
Rock paper scissors.
Oh I'm going first.
Lucky me.
Or do I get it.
No you won.
You get to choose.
I'll go first.
Oh you're gonna go first.
Awesome.
So on the page I'm a collaborator.
But doesn't matter.
I can fork it anyway.
So fork it
which takes a little bit as GitHub copies everything over.
It's not that long.
Right.
I've got my copy of it.
I can clone this grass stage setup so I can keep it.
The sage copy openness.
I will go back and make this just in my home folder here that serves me out windows backslash is
clone the project and now I can't
open Faulkner up
to 1 it's.
So did location.
So you started coding do a file say about this.
Yeah.
Yes.
So it doesn't overwrite just so we don't forget.
I know you're probably just working out in a different order so you get hub user name and then what
is it and then not text.
That's it.
Yep.
Perfect so you're coding coding strings.
Anything else you want to share of code you're sorry coding.
I started coding fairly young.
It's actually been started way say somewhere thereabouts.
I like how your conservative
coding strengths.
More.
More structured programming and so going with its types over more flexible stuff like Javascript so
so a structured programming go laying
anything else you are share about yourself.
Uh I enjoy learning new programming things and I would add in super great dude.
And what are the individuals with the highest integrity I've ever met.
And super values and principle based like this guy's a rock.
He's unshakable.
Like if I had a briefcase with a billion dollars and I had to leave it with somebody and entrust them
with it.
I'd give it to Daniel.
He might not take it.
He'd be like I know what all this cash is for.
But I know I'd be safe here.
You would misappropriate it.
So a really good guy like I messed up a little bit man.
So you're a good guy.
Yeah.
There we go.
We got the description.
Yeah.
3 three things shared so I get that it's I am not in the correct folder which is why I always do get
said is first to make sure I get and oh get.
Commit and it s first excerpts.
Is
thinking when
I can push
it now on my repo.
Good project.
It's got my thing here.
The last comment was mine is my committee and so I can make a pull request it's just a nice shortcut
there.
So from always going project Manchester to master I think I messed up there.
I think it was was close to branch.
No no no it's just right off master.
No grand master master so the master to master create a pull request.
I have added my file for the first yet.
And on
exercise.
Uh.
Request
and that's it.
That's all that's needed for this particular
nice well done.
And then we switch back.
Did you merge it already.
I have not merged it.
Let's see that.
So coming back to in goes club and going project as a collaborator I am capable of merging my own request.
So it's got some nice default stuff for me as the merger or as a collaborator so I can average this
sweet now.
It's the ladies comment on goes to love and going project is this merger request.
Is the merge is the merge commit.
If I look back at commits I can see the actual comment I made on my repo.
Nice great.
Well done.
That's a hands on exercise.
No one.