All right so now I'm going to show you my solution to that first hands on exercise.
And I'm in a dummy account here.
I don't even know if I have SS H set up.
So this is not my goes to 11 account.
This is just some other account I created for this exercise and and to do this first thing I'm going
to check is I'm going to go into my settings and then in settings we can go to SS H and there's no SS
H key setup so I'm going to bring up my terminal command spacebar brings up spotlight in Mac where you
could start typing.
You probably already know that.
Like I said try to find a way between teaching to basic and giving enough information and then I'm going
to s dash L.A. and switch to my home account and then CDM into dot SS H and and then let's dash L.A.
take a look what's in there and I have temp job and that was the example that we created so I'm going
to cat that cat tab pub and then copy this one and so I'm just going to use a different one than I already
have my other get hub which is my eye the RSA pub and I don't think we'd make a difference what I sometimes
do what I call voodoo computing which is based more upon superstition because nobody knows everything
we're always operating on the edge of the unknown in computer science like you come up to the threshold
like I don't know anything beyond that point right.
And and so likes you know like logically if I think it through though it doesn't matter.
This is the public key it will then send me a message which I can decrypt at this right.
Doesn't matter wouldn't matter.
I'm still going to go with Vita computing.
And so this is Todd Mach example and add SS H key to computing that's funny and and so now I have an
SS H and then I'm going to go to goes to eleven and I have a broken screen by the way.
I don't know.
Let me it once.
Yeah right.
Like can you see that like the left side and bottom of my screen is just completely fragmented broken
monitor so I'm going to pick the recording yeah because it comes straight off the video card.
So I'm looking for goes to Levin we're going to do it this way it goes to love and get hub and there
I am and then I'm gonna find the repo that I want repositories and we're looking for go long project
there it is and I'm gonna start just because I like like and yeah and I'm gonna watch it.
Not watching watching and now I'm going to fork it no clone or wait let me think it through.
Let's go for yes I want to clone it once it's under my name I don't want to clone it when it's under
it goes to eleven and so now it's here at temp top and cloud we're gonna ignore this temp Todd McCloud
go line project and now I'm going to clone or download with my SS H so I'm going to copy that and if
it was HP yes it's a clone with HP yes but I want SS H so I'm getting that and I'm going to go to my
terminal bring that back up and go back to my root directory and then LSI dash L.A. see what's in there
and in documents I have my going project which is the one from goes to eleven so I'm going to put this
just right under my user account different area and going project isn't there so you could see it going
projects not there.
So now I'm gonna do get clone and get that.
So now it's bringing it down.
And now if I do my L S I could see going project is there.
So this is the one connected to the dummy account so I'm going to C.D. into that going project and then
take a look at what's in there and then C.D. into the hands on exercise and take a look what's in there
and then seeds into about and take a look what's in there and I didn't make it into about I didn't do
my C.D..
There you go take a look what's in there and then I'm going to copy templates I'm going to copy template
I'm going to copy that to this current location and it's going to be goes to eleven and I'm going to
adjust my terminal here so it's all in one line and not breaking it's gonna be goes to eleven Dot T
X T right.
So copy this to the same location call it goes to eleven and now if I do it unless I should see I have
goes to eleven and so now I want to edit that so I'm going to use nano to do that here and you're started
coding I actually started coding in nineteen eighty four with basic might have been nineteen eighty
three is Junior High is an incredible opportunity to learn that and I threw it all away and then pick
coding up again it's like one semester of coding in junior high and then I didn't come back to coding
until 2001 so I'm going to do it two thousand added in their cuttings strengths I like having fun and
teaching I'd say and having a good time and you know bringing some personality to it and and also a
humanities you know so like a totally different philosophy on like what are my strengths when it comes
to coding but thinking about all of those things and then if you look at my coding strengths go laying
and each shemale and CSX you know this is kind of like the core of what I teach at the college in the
university so that's kind of it and then V.S. code right.
Like just create a course on that and let's leave it at that.
Anything you want to share about yourself I think for that I'm going to go to YouTube.
Todd McCloud and I have this personal YouTube channel there's the Learn to code YouTube channel.
Here's my personal YouTube channel I'm just going to hit my volume so any audio play doesn't come up
and let's grab that you url and you can go to town on where I go go to my terminal there we go you can
go to tell him that and then also I'll add in a lot of people don't know this about me Amazon.com T.
Scott McCloud Yeah I think I've mentioned this already when we're talking about something but I just
think I read up through that
make sure that brings about you know and we'll drop that in there.
All right I'm going to exit.
I'm going to save it and I'm going to hit enter and now I'm going to just take a look.
That's what's in there and then get status see it my statuses get add dash dash all you can also do
dash a Daniels way I might start switching to that and then ads.
Let's do hands on exercise it's really easy to identify for whoever is accepting merge requested hands
on exercise ninja 0 1 No 0 1 4 goes to eleven about that's pretty clear and so I've stage it and I'm
going to do a get get add get command get status and yeah I'm just gonna go get push see what it tells
me.
So I just pushed it it's my repo and air failed to push some rest to this.
So let's read this enumerating objects Delta compression repressing writing remote resolving Delta's
completed to get that remote Master Master permission denied failed to push and rafts to get hub dot
com temp and cloud going project get what are your ideas on this your SDH key you're it's trying to
use your I.D. RSA is the default s this H key OK so so to fix that let's try this I'm going to go back
to my SS H and inside the SS HCV into my SS H we'll see if this works because in here I have those and
so I'm going to rename those rights I'm going to ream rename now and to IDR RSA bridge and I'm going
to rename this one to Venus he and no thank you.
In the ivy RSA pub to I.D. RSA
courage which was original and then I'm to rename temp to Ivy underscore our essay.
I'm gonna rename temp pub to Ivy underscore our say pub yes yes.
And now we're going to take a look and we got RSA Ridge and RSA pub ridge and then we have IDR city
pub and I.D. RSA.
Now let's try this again.
So we'll come back over to this one and you can launch multiple tabs and terminal.
I did that with command T.
There's a third one but we're going to come back to this one here and try that push again
Gene.
His love hacky solutions and now that that is up there.
If I come back to my profile and I look at my repositories I've got the going project here and in hands
on exercises I should have under about there's goes to eleven.
Now I'm going to log out of this account.
We need to merge it.
Thank you.
So create merge request is that's for the project.
Yeah but Newport request and you pull requests and this new poll request I'm going to go goes to eleven
so it's going to see the arrow here it's going from this to that's it goes goes to eleven going project
master temp Todd McCloud Girling project master that's why I want to merge and here's what I'm adding
it's that text I had so I'm going to create a pull request and a hands on exercise for Ninja 0 ninja
0 1 No one goes to Levin this is the about me for Todd cloud on get at goes to eleven and create poor
class
and checking the branches no conflicts with base.
And now we're ready there's something to log out and sign in and I'm back into my account so I'm gonna
go to my repositories and then going project and I have pull requests one.
And right here I'm gonna click on it.
And I could see temp Todd McCloud the user.
This is that about me for Todd McCloud and get her back goes to love and hands on exercise ninja 0 1
number 0 1 4 goes to Levin about this branch has no conflicts I could merge the power request or I could
come up here and I could see files changed and here is the file it adds this file goes to Levin it adds
all that code so that all looks gotta come back conversation and I could write a little message.
Welcome to class goes to eleven.
Great job on this assignment.
I was like myself.
Positive messages and I could comment and then I could merge this.
So my comic got out of there and I could emerge as pull requests and confirm merge sweep.
So that's my solution.
A hands on exercise number one.
Let's just make sure that I did everything so I added this little bit.
You'll emerge from the master on your 4 from the master on your fork which we just did to master on
the repo from which you fought so forth.
This repo on branch master go into the folder to about template about neat text copy that renamed it
stage command push create a pull request.
So that's my solution.
The hands on exercise number one.