Welcome to hands on Exercise number two in this hands on exercise you'll emerge from the branch right.
You're going to create a branch you're gonna merge from on your fork you're gonna create a branch off
of master and you're going to merge from that branch off of master to master on the repo from which
you fought so at your fork of this repo.
Do the following.
Create a branch titled My humble switch to the branch in the folder 0 2 hands on exercises 0 2 humble
create a file called Your get hub user name dash humble the text in the file share what being humble
means to you.
Stage I know it's an interesting question and stage this file commit this file provide a descriptive
commit message push this file to your fork create a pull request to branch master on this repo right.
So that's that's what you're going to do it's just going to be creating a pull request from a fork other
than master off of or from a branch other than master off of your fork and just to give you a little
example of what that question means to be humble and let's be humble mean to you I've included goes
to Levin humble text already so you could take a look at that and you could read you know what that
what my response was to that question and so go ahead and pause this video.
Do your hands on exercise and when you're all done.
Come on back now y'all and we'll show you our solution to this.
Hands on exercise which we're gonna do right now you want to go first.
Sure.
All right you got one in there.
Yeah.
Let me show you.
This is what do you have an answer that question or do you want me to share what I said somewhere.
All right go for it let's see it.
Yeah yeah.
So I'm in my my repo my fork and I don't actually need to be on on there on the web on it but I just
want to make sure I am in case I need to make another pull request and so I go I can open up the.
Here is the fold the folder go up and over to humble and here is the one solution already.
And so I can create new new file
dash humbles that description or Florida's humble but yeah but I uh I guess yeah it's fine either way
but that's the way I wrote it
awesome.
I love the smooth flow my my trackpad ran out of space so I just had blood flow
to me being humble means driving.
There's my answer.
Now status it.
Oh
that's a warning on Windows has a different way of doing new lines than Linux and Mac.
So it's just a warning that github will correct this.
The Linux version as it commits.
Yeah ignorable CRL F stands for carriage return like feed and carriage return comes from the days of
typewriters where you had this carriage which would go back and forth which move the paper so the keys
would type on it.
So a carriage return was when it got over here I went King all the way back and fed the line.
So Windows does carriage return line feet at the end and on PASOK systems Linux and Mac they just do
line feed is that right.
Yeah.
The symbols which kids symbolize the symbols which symbolize the end of the line for Windows CRL half
carriage return lying feet and for Mac it posits Unix like
so had I commit and push to my repository except I made a mistake.
The goal of this exercise was not to put it master.
So there is a solution to this still I can create my branch of this point.
So now I mean this in my branch and it can push from here.
It's going to repeat the error message again for the first time pushing it so I can push now.
There's nothing on that branch yet right.
Just push the branch.
So but but this but this branch got pulled off a master with my command that I beat on nails dragged
down on it.
So so now both my master and my branch here both have that file selected and I did push to master so
both have that but I am now on this branch set up with that file.
Now you can emerge from that branch.
Yes.
So.
Interesting you see that.
So my mistake.
Most things in get you can fix until you've pushed once you've pushed.
There are still ways to force changes to happen but it's not.
It's really really difficult to edit it and just undo stuff.
Once you here she had a gun once you shot a gun that you shot that gun.
Exactly.
So.
So before you've pushed you can do at and you can edit your local get and undo a comment but until this
was you pushed all you can do is they could commit that does the opposite of what you've already done
and you still have that your history so that I can make a pull request and I want to go from my branch
humble to muster that adds the file create a pull request here and did my
that
means you know I think it was
I wanted to
I think this is a really cool example for your humble exercise you're like hey I made a mistake let's
fix it.
It's very humble of you and now you're going to accept it.
So and then as as me I am allowed to accept my own request.
So as we.
Awesome nice solution.