So here's the solution to my hands on exercise for hands on Exercise number two this is me giving a
solution for the second one and we get into a little bit of get complexity here and we're going to explain
that to you and give you the resources to understand it and to also do it.
We're going to do and get is something with a lot of depth and it can get complex and this course isn't
a course on get completely.
It's just kind of wanting to take things a little bit farther so that people have the skills to be able
to contribute to an open source project.
And that was one of the things students requested.
So we want to include it and just move things forward if you take my classes with using get so all of
that said here's the situation.
So we have the original get Hub Repository that's under goes to eleven and it's the go project.
And so here's that repository and then I had a dummy account where I fought that project so I created
a fork over here and off of this fork this fork is a snapshot.
It grabs the code from the original repo.
When I fork off of it I get the code at one point in time at a certain point in time.
And then this code here I clone it down to my computer right.
So here's the original repo goes to Levin going project.
I fork it under a different github account.
It could just be a different person I'm using a dummy account to represent a different person.
So I fork it and then I clone it down to my local machine.
All right.
So we kind of have three things here.
We have the original repo under goes to eleven going project.
We have a fork under some other get hub user account.
Right.
And then we have a clone on a local machine.
We've got three things going on.
And then Daniel who also is a different user as has fought this project.
He's made a change he's made a merge request to the original goes to 11 repo and that code has been
accepted and that goes to 11 repos moved forward from this point where it was it has now moved forward
my fork has not moved forward I forked from this point back here where the code was at this point right.
And then I cloned it to my machine.
So I do not have the code that's been merged into the original repository under goes to eleven.
Does that all make sense.
And if you go and you look at my repo so here I'm inside the go lane project and this is not under goes
to eleven right which is the one that everybody's forking.
This is under that other user account so some other individuals forked it I'm using a double dummy account
to represent that individuals.
That's this project.
And if I look at that I could see what's in here at 0 0 1 learning get a 0 0 2 hands on exercises and
I need to see into that and then if I look in there I have zero to humble and if I look in their right
I do not have Daniel's code but if I go to goes to eleven so let's go take a look at goes to eleven
so it goes to 11 get hub if I go to goes to 11 and I look at the repositories and I go into the go Lang
project right and I look at hands on exercises 0 2 and I go into humble his is in here.
Mine mine doesn't have that mine doesn't have that mine only has goes to eleven humble goes to eleven
humble it doesn't have authorities so you might think oh great let me just pull let me first do get
status if it tells me a thing your branch is up to date with Origin Master let me do a get pull right
so I do get Paul and I already have to date because guess what.
Right here's goes to 11 going project I forked off at that one point time I cloned it and then goes
to Levin Go line project move forward right here's my fork here's my clone of my fork on my machine
when I'm out my clone on my machine I say hey are we up to date.
It looks to my fork and says yep you're up to date with this fork.
So how do I get my fork to re kind of get the code that is on the original one the easiest solution
at this point in time is to go to stack overflow and if you go to Google and you just Google like Google
I'm and type in Google Stack Overflow Stack Overflow overflow update get hub fork repository and if
you search for that.
How do I update get hub fork repository and you come into here here are all the instructions that you
need to follow and so part of this the first thing they're working well gate is just understanding these
concepts like how are things related you've got the goes to eleven going project you've got a fork over
here you've got a clone down your local machine this and move forward your fork has a move forward your
clone is talking to your fork right.
So now we understand those concepts as like the first important step the next thing is to understand
this code and because I've been doing a whole lot of talking because Daniel is better get than me we're
going to have Daniel just kind of explain this code and then we're going to do it and this is like bonus
right for you going through these hands on exercises you get this extra step.
So let's let's go for Daniel you and tell us a little bit about this code or maybe you tell it and I'll
do it and we'll just step through it let's do that.
Yeah yeah.
So so yeah.
This code represents a remotes.
So when you clone your your clone has one remote it calls it origin and that's where you clone from
in which case this case it's your fork you up my fork here and then I'm like clone here.
So whenever you say origin in any whenever we get says Origin in any way shape or form prove it represents
your fork right there.
So.
So that's your connection you get remote or get remote origin is your fork.
So origins like another way it's the origin it's the source from which everybody is you know from from
this right replan get hub anybody could connect to that Origin and pull it down.
If I gave you permission to write so origins the source from which all things come it's still an origin
right.
Yes that's the replan gap.
Yes.
So if you type in and get remote on your terminal it'll actually tell you all your remotes they get
knows about your device get remote to list origin you've only got one remote origin.
You can also do you get remote show origin to get more details about about origin which includes telling
you what the URL at origin is from.
And so here we have get get dot com temp Todd McCloud.
That's the user name it's not goes to Levin going project get and push.
So this is where it fetches from.
This is where it pushes to head branch master K go on.
So.
So what's the detail there.
So including you can see the URL is not goes to eleven killing project it's just the temp top McLeod
going project.
So what you need to update your fork get hub does not update the fork automatically.
In fact it doesn't have any way of doing it at all.
What you have to do is do it yourself on your own machine.
So way to do that is to add a new remote to the original goes to eleven repo to you to your local court
clone.
OK so we are looking at remotes.
The only one right now is this one when we get the details of the remote right.
Show origin.
It says Hey this is kind of like what I'm doing.
I'm fetching from the temp account a temp account and I'm also pushing to the temp account.
So our idea is we're going to get remote add an upstream origin or the streams.
See you get remote and give it whatever name you want in this case upstream makes is a good is a good
name for it because it's it's further up on your stream from the origin from your origin.
This name can be any.
It could be anything it's just whatever you want to call the stream.
So and then and then you rel is the clone euro for wherever you're going to call it.
So I'm going to go.
Goes to eleven I'm going to go to the repositories for this guy Todd McCloud seems like he's a pretty
good dude likes picture it looks peaceful and we're gonna go to clown with each G.P.S. and copy that
right.
Yeah they're either HP s or SSA.
You guys set up on a stage so as well use it.
Thank you.
And then I'm going to pace that up so get remote add upstream.
So now you drop that n.
Yep.
And now if you run get remote it'll show it'll tell you you've got two remotes.
Origin in upstream nice ASO so if you show origin it's got that origin still is temp Todd McLeod and
if you show upstream it'll have the you will have the details about about what upstream is which is
the goes to heaven going project as toy sweet.
And then what's the next step in the process.
The next step is your local machine now who's got that remote but doesn't know anything about what's
in that remote it knows upstream exists but it doesn't know anything about it.
So you to use get fetch upstream to tell it to actually go to that you are real and and take a look
at what actually exists.
What branches are there what comets are there you need to know about it.
So just to document this we did give them out and we did get a remote show origin to get those details.
And then from here we grab give remote add upstream with your l and I'm just going to do this little
trick here to get that on the text.
And we did.
Is that the same as I can get remote at upstream.
Yep.
With SS H your alts already have that one in here.
So I just wanna make sure we document the steps we're going through and then the next one is get batch
upstream right.
Yeah.
So I'm gonna do.
Get that upstream.
So I'm going and fetching this other remote origin.
It's the name it's called upstream.
So now your clone knows that there's a branch called upstream master.
Can you see that says new new branch upstream MASTER.
THANKS.
CAN I DO MY get branch dash and they'll show me some stuff.
Yes.
Yeah.
Nice.
So that you can see you've got remotes origin master you get remotes upstream master.
You guys just playing master they're all they're all there call and then the next step here at Stack
Overflow tells us to do what.
So make sure you're on the branch that you want to be updating in this case almost always master.
So make sure you're you're in the right branch.
We got to get checkout master just to ensure that make sure you're on the right branch.
So that's the next step.
You are already you could confirm that.
Confirm with get branch shake yep and also make sure that you are that you get pulled to make sure that
you're up to date with your own work.
Get Paul in this case it already is.
So now you're on the latest version of master and you get fetched upstream so you know about the latest
thing that upstream has for Master.
So now you can actually pull from upstream into yours into your clone and there's two ways doing it.
You can use get rebates upstream master or get merge upstream master
so that's two different ways of doing it.
Get rebase is the fancy or way it basically.
It basically takes all the commits for your entire repo both at your local clone and upstream and just
reapplying them in order.
It's a time machine.
The problem is if you've got people who fought off of you or clone you it can cause some issues because
you're modifying history.
The other option is get merge upstream master and what.
And this doesn't modify history.
This just creates a new comet that it's a it's a merge commit from the upstream master.
Which point kind of says OK all these committees over here are in the repo after this point.
So since nobody's probably forked my temp dummy account I'm going to do the get rebase upstream master
and I just added some notes here.
Yeah there's two ways to pull from forked repo so you could just check the way I've described this if
you'd add anything to it.
Get rebase upstream master is one way the other way is get merge upstream master and and this way modifies
history but because issues people have fought my fork.
Right.
And this doesn't modify history so this would be safer.
People have fought to save for.
If people have fought your fork Yeah.
So.
So basically if you're if you're alone rebase is fine and it makes for a nicer looking get history about
merges you want you would prefer to use merge if you got anyone else is on your repo too.
So if you're working with someone as a collaborator or they fork over someone else's fault off you the
merge is safer.
But in this case it goes to heaven Tampa's alone.
So the rebase is fine.
Now I'm going to rebase and first rewinding head replay your work on top of that.
Fast forward master upstream master.
Now is that it or do we have anything else that should be.
So so now I've got a lower dose humble there.
Yep.
And that's awesome.
So that brought all that down.
Yep.
So now this is on your clone but your fork on GitHub has not yet been updated so you have to push to
solve that.
And sometimes when you do this push it can cut it might have problems.
So sometimes you need to put in the dash f origin master which is that's what's listed on the stack
overflow thing.
In this case it wasn't needed.
The rebase was simple enough that there wasn't any heavy changes and so it worked.
But sometimes sometimes when it's replaying history it has to change one of your comments a little bit.
And so you have to force the push to tell it to overwrite the original comment on the
so you shouldn't need to use the the force push more than once though it's just if you've if you changed
history with rebase you might have to tell it before work.
Hey.
History changed for years a forced Bush.
Yeah.
So that's a little bit of an involved process that took a little bit of time to explain.
And I like to keep these videos short.
So in the next video I'll show you my solution now that I'm up to up to date with goes to Levin I've
got all the code and kind of got everything current with my fork and my clone and my in the next video
I'll show you my solution to the second.
Hands on exercise so one note if you want to do this again you don't have to add the remote upstream
remote again that's saved.
You just have to do the fetch and the fetch step on.
I think we'll probably see that when I do the 3rd hands on exercise.
Okay all right good.
See you in the next video I'll do my solution.