So here's my solution to the second hands on exercise and to do this I'm going to create a branch and
then create a file and on that branch and so that branch will be down here on my machine and in my clone
of my fork which is off of you know go laying going it goes to eleven going project and so and then
I'm going to merge that over to go Lang goes to eleven off of that branch and so I'm gonna go into my
repo I'm just going to take a look see where I'm at and I'm in zero to humble you could see go laying
project 0 2 hands on exercise of zero to humble which is where I want to be.
I already have a file there which I put up and so just for convenience if you want to read my answer
you can pause the video and then take a look at that answer right there for humble.
I'm gonna put up a second file.
I'm going to call.
But first I have to create a branch so I'm going to get check out dash B and give it a name and this
will be you know M.C. second you know whatever I want to branch being that can you get branch dash a.
And take a look at all those and confirm I'm on M.C. second.
And so now I could take a look at what's in there and I'm going to create a new file and this new file
B goes to eleven and humble to don t x t spittle it goes to eleven eleven goes to eleven humbled to
Dot T X T and in here I'm gonna reflect instead of on humbling and reflect on integrity and integrity
is never take that which wasn't freely given and there I think that's enough and it's a good principle
to reflect upon and I'm going to hit enter so now I can do it get status and I may get status I have
this new file so I could do a get add dash a and get commit dash M and hands on project ninja 0 1 number
number 0 2 second goes to eleven file and and so now I have all that and I could do a get push so this
is going to push it up from my clone on my computer it's gonna push it up to my fork what I fought from
goes to lemons can push up to my fork on GitHub they're pushed out on up and it's saying get push setup
string origin and second so I need to do that so it adds the branch up on github does say that correctly.
So this is more of a telling your system that M.C. second is coming off of origin as opposed to upstream
so you what you want make sure empty seconds pushing too origin you don't want to put an empty deck
and you push upstream because you you're not allowed to write upstream Oh good.
So it's setting it to origin goes to my fork right.
Yeah.
And now that I have all that I could come in to get hub and get hub come in there and here's my top
temp Tom McCloud going project and.
And now if I look at my branches I have two branches and so I have M.S. second right here and I could
do a new poll request when you click that and hands on project where do I want it to go.
I'm gonna go from temp Todd McCloud going project M.S. second 2 goes to Levon go long project master
and the second file for goes to eleven or ninja oh on number two and create pas request
and now the poor request has been made.
So if I log out or do you have it on yours and want to do it.
I got access so I couldn't just go back to
this to you.
Then
back to the original project.
I can see the pull requests.
I can see it.
There it is.
See files change shoes.
Looks good
Burj
and then over on my machine that tells me it's now been merged this poll request has been merge.
That's pretty good.
Pretty good.
I liked that.
Did we get everything for that.
I created a branch and I didn't call my humble I just called it whatever.
And and then I created a file and in the file share it being humble stage commit push create a pull
request to master on this repo.
So that's my solution.
A hands on exercise number two.
You got anything else you want add.
Nope that's it.