Here is hands on Exercise number three.
And so in this exercise you're going to emerge from the master branch on your fork.
So here's your fork.
Here's goes to eleven go Lang project and then down here you have your clone you have master on your
fork you're going to then you know push that back up to your fork from your clone from your computer
the cloning computer push it up to your fork you'll be on Mars you're gonna emerge from that master
to master on repo from which you fought and so at your fork of this repo in the folder.
Hands on exercise 0 3 do the following create a branch titled by purpose switch to the branch create
a file called Your get hub username desk purpose dot text to share what you believe gives purpose and
meaning to human life.
That answer might be the number forty two stages file commit this file provide a descriptive commit
message and by the way I don't mean to make a joke which it's an insider joke and if you don't know
it yet let me bring you inside.
So in Hitchhiker's Guide To The Galaxy they said a computer to figure out what the purpose and meaning
of life is.
And after decades and decades and decades that computer return the answer in the answer was forty two.
So just a little tech and tech law there.
So stage this file commit this file merge this branch to the brute to the master branch on your fork.
Right.
So you're going to merge it to master on your fork.
So on your clone and then you're going to push that up to year you're your fork from your computer where
it's cloned from your fork.
You're going to push that merged master up to your fort and then from there on GitHub you're going to
make a pull request over it goes it goes to eleven.
So go ahead.
So create a pull request from branch master on your fork to branch master on this repo.
Go ahead and pause this video and I could do that.
Hands on exercise and when you're all done.
Now y'all come on back and we'll show you our hands on exercise which we're gonna do right now.
And are you going to have to reboot.
So Daniel is going to start out on this.
Are you going to have to do the rebase deal because you don't have my latest file.
Yeah I want to hammer through that.
I've got to I've also got the problem too.
I've got the.
When I was on branch Mass.
When I was on Master I made those two comments and I don't really want those to be in my history at
all.
So I'm.
So my solution was probably just to do the recoding or the reef just to rework it.
OK so.
So another way you could do it just delete it on your local machine and then re fork and re clone.
Yep.
So first I would go to the hub and go on my fork.
Go to Settings go at the very bottom in the danger zone delete my fork.
They require you to confirm by putting in the name the full name of the repo.
That is your username name slash the repo name.
I understand it's and you also need to put in your password.
Well edit this out.
Your repositories been deleted and it's on there.
It does not exist anymore.
Now I go back to those two.
Then
googling project and I can rework
in the meantime I can go back here to my clone and I can delete it.
Which require mean which requires me to make sure my command line is not in the folder.
So now I've got a read I've been reformed I'm up to date and I can re clone with SS H.
So it goes to Levin going project used to lead everything on your machine you deleted everything on
your get hub from your fork and then you said let's fork it again let's clone it again.
So now if I go going project 0 0 2 0 2 humble and I look in here I can see I've got to go through I've
been humble to so if you don't have anything that you want to have kept.
If you don't have anything in your fork that's separate from the origin.
This is probably an easier way to pull your fork up to date or at least step it simpler at least.
So now you can go back in
here did
all right.
So now you're ready do hands on Exercise number three yet.
And for this hands on exercise you're gonna create a branch called my purpose for this to get check
out dash B my purpose.
You gonna switch to that branch make sure you're on it you're automatically on it and now you're going
to Sheriff Lee you believe gives purpose and meaning to life in a file and that file B or your user
name dash purpose dot t t create a file your user name on GitHub dash purpose that T.
And then in that file share what you believe gives purpose and meaning to life could be forty two years
want to be generous and keep it simple or you get philosophical and share a little bit with us
there's the file so I can get at it.
At this commit am.
You need it.
Yeah.
Yeah exercise is a level 1 exercise.
That's a good way to do that.
That's nice.
Get status.
I'm still in a branch my purpose but I've committed so I will push my branch to merge.
So I'm pushing my branch to my fork.
No I can't.
I can.
I.
Which is kind of an optional thing.
I can merge to master straight into your machine and never let my fork know the branch ever existed.
Yeah but.
Or I can push it.
Got it kind of.
Either way you can't do the pull request method to merge on your own fork.
If you were if you'd ever pushed so so I could push it or I could get check out back to master once
a master I can get.
I'll always want to make sure you pull first before you do any kind of merging just to make sure you're
up to date.
And now I can get merge.
Purpose.
Purchase
anyhow.
I've merged that thing and I can get push it
which takes a little bit of time.
Here I've got the added ninja level 1 exercise 3 commit and a shortcut for making Polocrosse is there
will be a short shortcut button there if you're in a forked repo that has that's ready to make people
request.
So from my going project master to go to heaven going project master make my request description up
above is plenty good balance.
Good.
Yeah.
The title I don't think you mean that comment.
Sweep under and they will accept it on the.
Goes to Levin three and goes fucking going project now be accepted.
It is done.
Well done.
Anything you want to add.
Just just another re re essay restating if you don't have anything in your fork that's worth that you've
changed that you want to keep.
Simplest way to update to the newest version is just delete your fork and rework and you delete it both
locally on your machine and on your get hub account.
Get all that stuff out of there and then you go back to the one you want to fork and you re fork it
right.