So now I'm going to give you my solution for hands on exercise.
Number three and I'm going back to my repo.
I have this dummy account Todd temp Todd McLeod going project.
So there's the original project which is goes to 11 go laying project.
Then I fork that under My Account temp Todd McCloud a different account and then I cloned it down to
my machine.
So on GitHub where I forked it you could see the temp Todd McCloud going project right there.
And right now in 0 2 hands on exercises 0 3 I only have this starter file which was already there.
I don't have Daniel's file.
We're going to look at Daniel's screen now and if you see here on Daniel's screen 0 0 2 hands on exercise
0 3 purpose he's got the goes to eleven purpose text started file but he doesn't and he also has the
lower dose purpose text file that's like a mouthful and and so I need to get that on mine and you've
already pushed that from your fork and your clone from your clone you committed it and you pushed it
to your fork and then from your fork you did pull requests in from goes to Levin as a collaborator you
merge that pull requests from your other account correct.
Yes.
And so now we're seeing that it goes to eleven going project.
And so I need to rebase my fork right.
So here's goes to 11 going project and then here's my temp GitHub file with a fork.
I need to rebase this fork because right here you could see I don't have Daniel's file and if I look
here on the terminal.
So I was looking at GitHub.
Now I'm going to look at the clone down to my term and my my computer.
If I look here on the terminal if I look at print working directory I mean going project 0 0 2 hands
on exercises 0 to humble so I'm gonna see these up out of that go into 0 3 and then do it.
L s L.A. see everything that's in there.
I don't have Daniel's files so I want to rebase my fork with what I fought from and to do that we have
that Stack Overflow article where it's get remote add upstream I've already done this.
So if I do get branch dash a I see all of my branches where I have master I've M.S. second and then
I have upstream master right here so I've already created this upstream that could be any name.
So now what I want to do is just get fetch upstream.
I want to make sure that I am on master anything.
I say that all correctly.
Yes.
Yeah.
So the first thing I'm going to do I'm just kind of a little bit the question that just arose for me
which is why I ask that is it's asking me to fetch the upstream before I'm a master.
I mean I just need to make sure rebase but these can be done in either order.
Correct.
That's correct.
OK so my mind just hiccup there for a second.
Like what am I doing that right.
So I'm going to do a get fetch upstream and hopefully this is all making a little bit of sense to you
or starting to familiarize you're starting familiarized with that and so get fetch upstream.
I find it helpful to also read through just to see what's happening here and you could see from get
hub dot com goes to Levin going project and if you remember in our notes we also added in some notes
here about get remote and get remote show origin.
And so that might be interesting get remote show origin if we look at that just to kind of refresh your
memory.
What we see there these are both from temp Todd McCloud.
We can also get remote show upstream and it is upstream just upstream.
Correct.
I don't have the master.
And then here you can see it's from goes to eleven and so that's kind of cool to see.
So I've done my get fetch and now I need to do my get checkout master.
So I want to make sure I'm a master so you can see how I get branches I'm actually on AMC seconds I'm
going to do get checkout master and then you can see I'm now on Master I've got the little Asterix there
plus the color coding of green and so with that I'm ready to get rebase upstream master you want to
pull first though just make sure you're up to date before you do rebasing emerging and once again you're
seeing the benefit of pair programming already up to date and then get re rebase upstream master get
rebase upstream master is all it good you go first rewinding had replay your work on top of it fast
forward master to upstream master and now if I take a look at where I'm at and I look at what's in there
I have or loaders or lower dose how do you say that we're all lured boost or a lord I've known that
oh this is a time to twister or Florida's his file and if I refresh here I'm not going to see I'm going
to do that the keyboard shortcut commands shift arcs I can't actually see the refresh thing and so if
I wanted to get this up to my temp Todd McLeod going project I have to do it get status and on branch
is ahead of master by form Kimmitt get pushed to publish your local commands get push
and now if I come back here and refresh I should see that so again go Lang goes to eleven going project
my fork temp Todd McCloud has a fork over here with going project and then my clone down here so I just
went from my clone up to my get hub temp Todd McCloud going project which is the fork so all that just
to get ready to do the third hands on exercise and the third hands on exercise is in 0 3 Create a branch
switch to the branch create a file purpose stage commit merge this to master on your fork and then create
a pull request from master on your forks I'm going to create this on a branch on my fork and emergent
to master on my fork and then merge it to goes to eleven from which I originally fought so to do that
I am now in print working directory 0 3 I'm going to nano and this file needs to be go well this is
going to be temp Todd McCloud because it's kind of where it's coming from.
Purpose t x t and I'm going to add in here live for others relationships are everything when you put
yourself second to the team you feel could choose pro social behavior
behavior not anti social behavior you were built to be a social animal have family and kids.
Your life will be great.
Nothing's giving my life more meaning than living for others.
True story.
All right so I have that file now I could do get.
But I didn't do it on a branch.
Get check out the Ashby and this branch name is going to be my purpose.
I did the same thing you did.
And now that I'm here both my branch and master has that file.
Except you never committed to master.
So let's see what we got here.
Is my purpose and get status and it's over here so now I could commit this interesting.
So if you have not state if you have not committed this to a particular branch yet your files will kind
of float with you as you check out between different branches.
Get check out will throw an error though if you if you modify a file that exists and it's different
between the branch and the original.
Like if you modified goes to eleven outright t it's been changed on your branch compared to Aster it'll
it'll tell you hey you've got.
I'm not sure how to change this but it is a new file site.
Where do you want to keep track that it's in it's indeterminate state.
It can just put it can just keep it with you as you move to the next file.
It takes a while to wrap your head around this entire thing gets very smart usually and will usually
just tell you okay can't do this here's why.
So Reed Reed gets error messages through usually good.
So now I'm going to add the file so get add and then get commit dash M and adds ninja level 0 1.
Exercise number 0 3 temp.
Todd McCloud purpose.
Text File temp Todd McCloud.
I guess we're all ultimately a little bit temporary aren't we.
We do not have ah ah life is a variable is for a defined period of time and now that I have that I could
do to get stats again and I'm on branch.
My purpose and so switched to the branch created a file stages file commit this file on emerge.
This branch to master branch on your fork provided descriptive comment message.
So now I'm going to merge this and so to do that get checkout master and then get merged branch to get
merge and I'm looking for my purpose.
I'm looking for my purpose in snagging merge that to my master and if I do get branch dash a I could
see that idea get status.
I could see that I'm ahead of some of my clone now I'm gonna push to temp Todd McCloud repo so I'm going
to do a get push for a master to get hub and now up here on my get hub temp Todd McCloud I hit refresh
command shift ah and you could see Tim Todd McCloud purpose and the next thing I want to do is do a
poor request and my poor request is temp Todd McCloud Galang compare master with goes to eleven going
project base master and if I look I've got temp Todd McCloud purpose and this is what it is I'm going
to create pull requests and that's a good description and thanks for this class having fun learning
a lot it's awesome and I mean that I am having fun I am learning a lot.
It is awesome.
I'm going to create my pull request and thank you Daniel for joining me on this.
It's fun and.
And so now that's there.
And if we switch over to Daniel's computer he can look at the poll requests and he could pull that poll
request and merge that
suite.
And then on my computer you can see that my poll request has been merged.
And that's the whole process.
Do you have anything to add to it.
No.
You do not actually need to update your repo in order to do to but to do the poll request in this case
it was a file that was not touched by anyone else at all.
It was a new file entirely.
And so he could.
Todd could have just made the file and done all this work without having to do the rebase and updating
his thing gets pretty good at merging files if need be and this case is a completely new file.
So the commit get would've been smart enough to just kind of merge it in as required but the updating
to the latest version will prevent will mean that you're taking on the burden of merging any conflicts
which makes it more likely that whoever is looking at the poll requests can see no conflicts.
That's a lot easier of a yes it's approved.
If there's conflicts the person who's looking at the poll requests usually isn't the one who wants to
figure out what's wrong.
They'll send it back to you and say fix us.
So there are conflicts.
All right.
That's a hands on exercise number three.
My solution.
See you in the next video where we have one more hands on exercise number four.