So this is hands on Exercise number four.
It's the last hands on exercise in the set and are the last of our get hands on exercises for this hands
on exercises.
Clean up your repository on your local machine delete your branches and so delete your branches.
And here's the code to do that.
Just as a reminder to get branch dash D branch name and once we accept your poll request which might
take who knows maybe a few months and truly hopefully.
Honestly I hope some people in the class volunteer to be collaborators so on the repo we could add you
as a collaborator and then and then you know you can help bring in these assignments but once that's
done you can delete your branch on your fork on github and then prune locally and and tell us a little
bit.
Daniel why.
Why they aren't able to delete their branch on GitHub before we've accepted or merged in their request.
Because if you delete it on github then the request doesn't know where to pull from to do the merge
so you need to make sure that E.
You need to make sure that the poor request is gone through or been rejected before the branch delete
it because otherwise I'm not actually sure how GitHub would respond exactly but I'm I'm pretty sure
that if you just delete the branch the pull request will then be cancelled as well because it doesn't
know where to pull it.
Maybe that's an experiment for us to run at some point.
You're kind of curious.
All right.
So go do this.
Hands on exercise.
Pause a video.
Go do it when you're all done.
Come on back and we'll show you our solution.
What you're gonna do right now so make sure you've already paused this video.
Gone gone and done it all right.
OK you're ready.
Here we go.
You want to go first for me.
Sure I've got I've got less to do because I get branch.
I can see I've got the mask for my purpose.
I don't have the.
The other one.
The humble one because I had to eat it my entire fork and read and report it including tweak my local
branches so I don't actually have the extra branch.
So for me it's just a we.
My purpose.
I can see many branches just half that.
All right great.
And for me get branch I've got master my second my purpose I am going to get branch DST see second and
get branch SD.
My purpose in deleting my purpose.
And now if I do get branch I just have master and if I want to see all my branches I've got master origin
HEAD origin master origin EMC second origin upstream master and since my pull requests have already
been accepted and merged in skin to get status here and I'm all up to date but just because of voodoo
computing I'm gonna do a get pull and make sure but now I'll go back to my going project.
This is on.
Oh yeah.
This is goes to eleven I need my my repositories and I want to go to going project forked from goes
to 11:00 so temp Todd McCloud going project and if I go look at my branches here I've M.S. second and
I'll get rid of this one because I don't need it and so again if I do get branch dash a I still have
M.S. second here so this is where I need to prune it and I could go back and grab this prune code I
don't know it off the top of my head and I wrote it down here somewhere gimme Jimmy f prune.
There you go.
Get remote prune origin we'll use the power of technology to find that and and now pruned my second
I've got upstream match their origin master origin HEAD AND MASTER so I'm all clean.
All right.
So that's our solution for this hands on exercise and that didn't take very long.
No.
So once you pull requests have been accepted.
If you don't need your fork at all anymore you are safe to eat your fork repo.
In this case if you want to keep it that's fine too.
But there's little point in keeping a fork of open source repo.
After all the changes you want to make have been made yet so as you're working through the course you
might want to keep your fork because then you'll have all of the code as it was at the time when you
started the course or from whence you last rebase to your fork and and then you could push your code
and keep it.
And then any of those branches that you like that you wanted to send over to goes to eleven add in.
So for instance as you're going through the course if I'm just looking for directory structure and I
think this will be the best place to show directory structure.
So here's going project 0 2 purpose and so maybe your your like you know you wanted to add some code
for other people to share.
You might create a new folder and say a student code and then maybe create a new folder.
And here would be you know it goes to eleven or whatever year get name whatever you get name was and
so other students who wanted to post some code of different variations with descriptions that could
be beneficial to other students so that might be something you might then say hey I want to send this
over to the goalie goes to eleven goal line project so other students could see it that that makes sense.
Yeah.
Similar uncertain but you know so you can use the fork to do that and branches as you're going through
the class.
Do you want to try that thing where we have just kind of like as a curious thing where we you create
a branch you add a file you submit a merge request and then you delete all of that on your side.
We see what the merge request looks like from goes to 11 or you want me to do it on my sign.
I can do it.
Let's do it projects.
Sure I date I am missing your changes fine so I just want to see what happened to it.
If I create a branch so as to
much better.
So yeah I like it.
Check out the Ashby.
Get your
money.
Yeah.
Just where
maybe that is an opening in a different location close it all down.
Yes I remember now.
This is this is the goes to love and based going project and I want all that slow climb.
All right so here is here it is.
If I just create a new file here.
This is for X here and
X beer instead.
Text
read this
it's
now if I go back year
experiment I want to take a pull request with a
gay experiment to get going.
Project let's create over past
request it's being created.
Now if I go back to mine
I go to branches delete this branch
deleted it.
If I come to this one for quite zero it's got no import request that the Clinton supporter put this
you can see it's got this angry red square so it automatically closes it if you delete it because the
code was on your other repo and so it's gone now right.
All right um except that was a good experiment.
That's logical.
Yes.
All right.
Hope you've enjoyed this about get.
Hope it's been helpful to you.
Yeah I've certainly enjoyed it.
And we look forward to seeing you in the next section where or looking at going into go modules.
We may be we'll switch that up if we talk and we decide something better come next but I'm thinking
go modules is good Max week.
Yeah.
All right.
You have anything else you want to say at last about get life or otherwise.
Forty two forty two.
All right.
See in the next section.