So in the last section, we created some data models and implemented authentication and wrote some tests,
and that was really helpful.
And this is all code that will make it much easier for users of the celebrity's package to build a web
application.
But of course, one of the things we want to do is we want to have some kind of command line application
that allows users to with one command in their terminal to do things like implement our authentication
code.
So by default, when you install a LERZ application, it won't have authentication and won't have any
of the things will be adding in the coming lectures.
But we want people to be able to type something like maybe the command line program is called celebrities
and they just type celebrities make off.
And that will create the necessary authentication logic by copying files into the project they're working
on.
And of course, one of the things they're going to have to have is database tables.
And the way that's handled in Laravel, for example, is with PHP artisan artisan make migration and
we want something like that.
We want to be able to create database migrations.
So let's get started with the very first steps of building our command line application.
And of course, we're not going to do that in my app.
We're going to do it over here in the Celebrity House project.
So open your celebrity's project, and the very first thing I'll do is I'll create a folder at the root
level of that project called.
And this is kind of a convention CMT for command and inside of the command folder or create another
folder.
And I'm going to call mine Seelye for command line interface and inside of the Seelye folder.
Let's create a new file called Mean Don't Go.
This will be the main entry point to our command line application.
So obviously, since it's in the main folder or it's a main package, I'm going to call it package,
and we'll just start with some really simple things.
First of all, create a variable because I know I'm going to be using code in the packages above this
one.
I'll call my variable cell for celebrities.
And it's a type celebrity's better spell, right?
Not celebrities.
And hopefully it will find it for me.
It looks like it didn't, but that's all right.
I'll just imported manually.
So import and I'll do it this way because I'm going to have more imports later on.
GitHub dot com slash t solar celebrities.
And of course, that needs to be in quotation marks, and hopefully that will find it for me.
And here this should be an upper case.
All right.
That's correct.
So we have that import.
Now another thing I'm going to want to do in this project.
This is a command line terminal application, but it's nice to give color as a kind of feedback in any
command line application.
So I'm going to open my terminal and I'm going to go and get a really simple package.
Go get from GitHub dot com slash f a T r h slash color.
And the reason I'm going to get that, it's pretty straightforward.
When you're writing code for terminals that's supposed to change the color of the output.
It's different on Windows and Linux, and it's significantly different.
The codes to escape to start a color are different in this package just makes it really dead simple
for us to use that.
So let's just get an application going here.
I've imported that.
I'm not using it yet, but I will before too long and I'll put a Constance in here just so I know what
version this is.
Concert version and I'll make that equal to one point zero point zero, which is pretentious.
We're not at one point yet, but this is good enough for our purposes.
And of course, this needs a main function.
So functioning, and we'll make this really, really simple to start with.
OK.
We want to get arguments, command line arguments, so I'll just create a few variables.
We're not going to ever have more than three.
So ergo one hour to an hour three.
And I'll also create a variable called error.
Those come from a function called validate input.
We want to validate what the user has to say.
OK, now that a function doesn't exist yet, but don't worry about that, it will before too long.
And we're also going to refer to another function that doesn't exist yet.
So I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
If that validate input function returns us an error.
Then I'm going to call another function exit gracefully.
I could just, you know, die.
That's not a very polite thing to do.
So error here past an error to that.
Now let's go create these functions that don't exist yet.
OK, so I'll create one called func and it's named validate input.
It takes no arguments, but a returns string string, a string and potentially an error.
OK, so let's create the three strings we might be returning verb one or two or three of type string.
So let's try to get our command line arguments.
So I'm going to write a simple if statement.
If the length of OS were from the standard library, the operating system package ARGS is the function
I'm looking for or the value I'm looking for, if that's greater than one.
Then we have at least one, and I didn't do the import for me, so let's try that again.
OS stop args.
That's better if it's greater than one.
Then I have more than one command line argument or at least one command line argument.
Because when you read the arguments from the command line, if, for example, my application is called
celebrities, my command line up application is called celebrities.
And if I type, say, celebrities speech space help, then I actually have to command line arguments.
The first one is the name of the program and I'm executing, which is hilarious in my case.
And the second one would be help.
So I'm checking to see if there are any command line arguments.
So if that happens, then I know I have at least one.
So I can say heard one is equal to 0s words at position one because position zero is the name of my
command line argument.
Now, immediately after that, I'm going to have another if statement if the length of I don't need
that parentheses, if the length of OS starts again.
Now, if it's greater than or equal to three than, I have at least one more.
OK, so I can just in here say, ah, two is equal to OST earns position two, which I should be the
third thing on the line.
Celebrities make migration, for example.
OK.
And I will do one more check if the length of OS starts position or start args is greater than or equal
to four.
Then our three is now equal to OS arms position.
Three.
Now, if it's not true, I can say else and down here, I want to give some kind of feedback to the
user.
OK, so I can say, here's where I want to use that color package.
We just imported it color, which is from the fatty package red.
Let's see if it finds it.
There it is.
It found color red and this just prints text in red.
And I'll simply say error command required like that.
OK.
And at that point, I'm also going to show them some help and we'll write that function in just a minute.
OK?
And we'll return nothing and nothing and nothing and errors.
Dot new write a new error.
My error will be command required.
Marshall help doesn't exist yet.
Let's finish this function first.
OK, down here, if we got past all of that, then I'm going to return hard one or two or three.
And no.
Now, art one, two or three might be empty strings.
OK, but I'm returning something art one wouldn't be.
But this and this might be empty strings.
So now let's just write that show help function, and we'll make it pretty simple right below this,
and we'll move these things around before too long.
Write a new function called Show Help and it takes no parameters, and it doesn't actually return anything
either.
It just prints to the console here will again use that color package color dot yellow in this case,
and if you don't like that color, pick your own.
And I'll just put in tactics the help file that I want to show the user.
So I'll just say right up here because I want this to be not spaced over available commands and we'll
add to this as time goes on.
And down here, I'll just say help.
And I'll put a few spaces in there and say.
Show the help.
Come on.
Show the help commands.
We can fix it later if we don't like it.
And I have another one called version, and I'll just line these up nicely and say, print application
version, OK?
Now, the last thing we need to worry about here is the second, the last thing we need to worry about
here is this exit gracefully command.
So we may as well write that one right now.
I'm going to close this terminal and down here below this.
All right.
Funk exit gracefully.
And that will take an error.
The are of type error, and I'm also we're not going to use this right now have one called message and
that will be one or more strings.
OK, so we think there's a very added function and an exit gracefully.
All I really want to do is say, declare a variable message.
Make that equal to nothing an empty string.
And I'll say if the length of MSG, which is our very attic, which is a parameter, the very adequate
and we can have one or more strings there, then I'll say if the length of message is greater than zero,
then message is equal to whatever message was passed there.
MSG index here.
OK.
So although we're allowing more than one string to be passed, what we're really doing is making MSG
an optional parameter.
Because the fact that it has dot dot dot in front of the strings says accept one or zero or more strings
as many as you want and will only ever pass one.
So.
Typekit there should be if.
And we'll also say if error is not equal to nil and error is something we received as a parameter to
this function.
OK, we'll print out color in red this time because it's an error and we'll put error.
Present be followed by a carriage return and the air.
And now, if the length of message, the string we declared right up there in line 50 53, if it's greater
than zero, then print out so color dog yellow.
Print a message.
Otherwise we'll print colored green finished.
And we exit OS x it OS exit
status code zero.
OK, so if we go back up to the top, we have one hour to an hour three but not being used.
And of course, we have to do something with those.
So let's just do this.
Let's say switch.
Argument, what's our first argument, OK?
And our case will be held
until we're going to do here is say.
Show help.
And our second case will be version.
And here will just say color, the yellow application version, plus the version.
And for now, just so we can run this program, let's type default,
and we'll just say Long Line
are two or three.
OK, so at this point, I should be able to do something with this now importing things and declaring
things that I'm not using.
But let's not worry about that right now.
Let's try running this.
And if you open the make file for this particular project, you might recall this from some time ago.
We have something called Build Seelye and that builds the command line tool celebrities and copies it
to my app.
So we'll build on.
Our output will be to the My App directory, which is beside the Solaris house directory in my case,
and if it's not in your case, you're probably going to want to change this path.
I'm going to call the the binary that I'm building celebrities and I'm going to compile everything in
dot slash cmd slash Cee-Lo.
So let's see if that works.
Opened my terminal, I make sure I'm in the correct folder, I am, I'm in the celebrity directory,
so I should be able to say make build underscore.
SEAL up.
And there is built now as I switch over to my other project, my app, and open the terminal and go
up to the top and type wallets to allow us to make sure it's there.
There it is, celebrities, let's Typekit slash celebrities.
And it says air available a command required available commands and a printer to help file.
And that's it.
OK, and then it prints out the air again.
Well, that's fine.
We can clean that up later.
But it seems to work.
Now, a word of caution here.
Back in the other one, naturally, if you're in windows and you're not using the the Linux subsystem
or something like that, you're going to have to call this celerity dot EMC.
OK.
And when you go to run it in the other window, other package, of course, you're going to run.
Celebrities don't exit.
But in my case, I'm on a Mac.
And if you're on a Mac or Linux, my approach will work fine for you.
OK, so we have the very beginning of our command line application in place.
And what I want to work on next is actually implementing migrations.
We could use a standalone tool like Sota, which I've used in other courses, or we could use a standalone
tool like Go Dash, Migrate, but we're actually going to take advantage of a package that allows us
to quit the migration logic right in our code and then we can implement it in our own command line application.
I think that'll be a fun exercise, so we'll get started on that in the next lecture.