So we're getting closer.
Let's fix the down migration, so it behaves the way it's supposed to, and let's copy over the data
models and we'll get started with that right here in my off.
Don't go file in the celebrities project inside the CMT slush seal up.
So between lectures, I went and made sure that the school to delete everything works the way that it's
supposed to.
By modifying it to this, so I'm going to copy the city here and go back to my I.D. and just replace
this with this.
So drop table if users exist, Cascade Drop Table, then a semicolon, then drop table.
If exist, tokens cascade and then finally drop table if exists.
Remember tokens?
OK, so we'll try that in a minute.
First of all, let's try copying over our data models.
And of course, we're going to have to create some sample data files, the user's table or the user's
model and the token model and put them somewhere in our template file system and copy them over.
But we'll get to that in a minute.
First of all, let's go.
Error equals and this is really easy.
Copy file from template and we're going to copy from and I'm going to assume it's going to be in the
templates file system.
So templates slash and we'll create a directory called data.
And then I'll put one in there called user go dot text.
And the only reason I'm putting text at the end is so my editor visual studio code doesn't continually
tell me, Hey, you've got this file in the data package and it's in the wrong folder, which it probably
would, and I'm not going to bother checking to see if it does or not.
This will do the trick.
And we want to copy it to sell down route paths.
We want to append slash and data slash user talk go and we'll check for an error.
And we actually do need to modify that copy file from template to make sure that file doesn't already
exist because we don't want to allow people to overwrite things.
So if error is not equal to no, then we'll return.
Not, we won't return.
We'll simply call things it gracefully and handed the error.
Now I'll copy this whole thing and paste it here and change this to token.
Don't go to text and change this to token.
Don't go.
Now let's go.
Look at this copy file from template function right here, and I have this to do message that says check
to ensure file does not already exist and we can do that pretty easily.
OK.
What we'll do is just create another file right here.
Another function right here called Func File exists, and that'll return true if the file exists and
false if it doesn't.
So file to check will be the full path into a file in the form of a string, and it returns to William
and go.
This is pretty easy if we don't care about the first return value.
We do care about the error is.
Post don't stop.
And that requires one Patnaik file to check, and we'll put a semicolon and then we'll put OS dot is
not exist error.
And then in curly brackets, return false.
Return true.
That's pretty simple.
So up here in my to do now, all I have to do is replace that with if file exists and handed target
file, which is the full path named the file I want to create and will say return errors dot new and
we'll just say target file plus already exists and that will be the early return.
OK, so that takes care of that.
Or at least it should.
We'll find out before too long.
So back to our stock go.
Now we're trying to copy from templates data.
Use your go to text.
And that doesn't exist.
So let's go to the CMD Seelye folder, then the Templates folder.
Then we'll create in the Templates folder a new directory called data, and we'll create two files in
there a new file.
And the first one is called User Don't go to text.
And another new file token don't go text.
Now I'll switch over to my My App project and I'll open the token Darko File, which is inside the data
directory.
Select All and copy.
Switch back here.
Make sure I'm looking at token doggo text.
I am paste today.
Now we'll go to user Agoda and switch back here to the other project and open user account and select
all and copy and switch back to celebrities and paste it into the user.
Not go too far.
OK.
So this should actually work.
And what I'm going to do, first of all, is build the binary make build Seelye from the root directory
of the Celebrities project, and that should build and copy the binary over to my my app.
And it looks like it did.
So we'll go to my app and the first thing I'll do.
And you might want to move them out of the folder, but I have many copies of these.
So I'm going to delete token logo and user account.
OK, so I'll delete those.
Actually, I'll delete them, do we move the trash and then I'll make sure that my migration's folder
is empty?
It is.
I have errors now because I'm referring to two models that don't exist anymore.
But hopefully this command will make that go away.
So let's check our database.
Make sure there's no tables in there.
And if I look at celebrities and refresh this, no tables at all perfect.
So I'm ready to run the test.
So dot slash tossed from the root level of my salary test or my my app project and my command is going
to be let's just hit, enter and see what the commands are.
We didn't put make off in there yet, but it's make off, make off.
And hopefully this will create the two migrations.
Run them and copy those files.
Token go and user don't go to the correct directory.
Let's find it.
So it finished and over here, it looks like I have user Darko.
Let's make it short, let's make sure it's actually user not go.
It is.
And we have token Darko, which is token perfect.
And let's go look at our database.
Refresh this near all my tables, perfect.
Now let's try just to make sure we got the down migration right?
Dot slash celebrities migrate down.
Migrations complete.
Let's go back and look at our database and refresh this, and they're gone.
And now we should be able to say migrate up the they should come back.
And refresh, and they're back, that looks pretty good.
So let's try now thinking about the other things we might want to copy over for our authentication package
because if you think it through, we have a middleware folder.
Has nothing in it.
And what use is an authentication framework or an authentication system that doesn't have middleware
that allows you to check to see if somebody is authenticated or not?
So maybe we should write some simple authentication middleware and put that in our Read-Only file system
in the command line application and copy that over as part of make off as well.
We'll get started on doing that in the next lecture.