So this time around, we want to create some middleware that will be installed automatically in the
project when someone types celebrities make off.
And before we do that, let's just update this help file.
So this is in helpers.
Don't go in the CMT Seelye folder of the Celebrity House project, and I'll just put make off and write
the help file for it.
And that will say something like Oh creates and runs migrations for users table.
I'll just put authentication tables, authentication tables and creates.
It creates models and middleware, and you can say whatever you want, but that's in my help file now.
So let me go back now to our My App project and get started writing some simple middleware.
OK, I'm going to write the application middleware here in my app first because it's easier to do it
that way.
So I'll create a new file in middleware and I will call this one off, Darko.
And of course, its package is middleware.
Middleware right there, and it's very simple.
So we'll create a functional standard middleware, and this is dead simple.
I'll give it the receiver of M a pointer to middleware, which doesn't exist yet, but we'll take care
of that before too long and we'll make this an off middleware and it takes a handler.
An issue to be handler alcohol next, which almost everybody does when they're writing middleware and
go and it returns and dog handler.
OK, so I'm going to return an HDP dot handle, funk handle or funk right there.
And that will be a an inline function funk WHDH response record because I need access to that and our
pointer to HTTP request.
And I'll say, if not and here I'll be getting some errors from my compiler or from the IDC because
I'm referring to things that don't exist on the M receiver yet, but we'll take care of that in a moment.
AMD after session Dot exists.
And I'm looking for context
inside of that, I'm looking for user ID, which we use for authentication.
So if that exists in this session that doesn't exist in the session, then we'll just run deep error
and we'll handle it.
The response writer and dot status text will be for everyone.
We're going to return HGTV Dot status unauthorized?
No, not accepted.
That's the opposite of what we want.
Unauthorized.
That's better.
OK, so that's our middleware, so we better create this type middleware.
So I'll just create a new file in here called Middleware Darko in my little EWR package middleware.
I'm a carrier type called middleware, and it's going to be a struct and it's going to have as its members,
not surprisingly, app because we're going to want a reference to our celebrities type celebrities,
not celebrities.
And we'll also have models, data dump models because we might need those.
OK.
So hopefully the imports for me, it did.
Perfect.
So in order to use this course, we're going to have to make a change to in.
It's hilarious.
And this should be old hat for you now.
It's pretty much the same thing we did before.
So say right here after I named the app my name or my app, what I'm going to do here is just create
a variable called my middleware, and that will be assigned the value of a reference to from the middleware
package middleware.
And hopefully it's this one.
Yep, middleware, Typekit middleware.
And I'll populate app with.
So that's what I called it.
So.
So we have this and not doing anything with it yet.
So let's go down here now and in our application.
Let's add another type in here and I'll type it in.
Then Go added left after the fact.
Middleware like I already added it, middleware will be my middleware.
That's great.
And it sure seems not to be working.
Field middleware instruct little unknown.
I didn't think I had it, so I took a look at application and what I middleware here, and that will
be a type a pointer to middleware middleware.
Now, if I go back to any celebrities, that error should be gone, but I'm not quite done.
I have one more thing to do here after I have my models created.
I need to add that to my middleware as well because I might need them there.
So I'll just say I support middleware that models and that's going to be equal to app models.
OK, so that should take care of all of the errors in our off dart go file the middleware.
And it did.
But of course, this is only authentication, web based authentication.
We also need API based authentication, so that's easy enough.
We'll create another file in middleware called off dash token.
That's a great name.
Go.
And of course, it's in package middleware
and it's very similar to the previous one.
So we'll have a func with a receiver of AM, a pointer to middleware, and we'll call this one off token.
And it takes next as a parameter of type AGP dot handler and it returns HTP dot handler.
And again, we're going to wrap inside of this.
We're going to have a return, which is itself an HGTV, dot handler, funk and Lawler funk right there.
And we'll inline the function w HGTV out response writer and a pointer to response rare and a pointer
to our was a pointer to endpoint request.
And it's very simple once again.
So we don't care about the return value, but we do care about checking for an error when we call EM
Dart models DOT token tokens right there.
Don't authenticate token, and all that requires is that our our pointer to an HTP request, which we
called error.
So if error is not equal to nil, then I'm going to create a variable called payload, which is a struct
VAR payload struct right here.
And it's going to have an error as one field, which is a Boolean and in JSON, which is.
Be sending back in a moment, I'll call it error, and it's going to have another field called message,
which is a string.
And in Jason, I'll call that message and then I'll set the values for that payload error.
It's going to be equal to true and payload dot message will be equal to invalid authentication credentials,
credentials that like I spelled out, right?
And now I don't care about the response, but I'll call from my receiver and I will go to app and I'll
simply say, right, Jason.
Now that doesn't exist because we haven't worked with Jason at all.
But just bear with me for a minute will finish writing this command.
Then we'll go and write Jason to celebrities itself.
OK, so that's going to take a response writer as an argument, a status which is HTP status unauthorized
and the payload.
OK, now let's make this error go away.
So we need to go back to celebrities and I'm going to create a new file at the root level of celebrities.
And I'll just click right click down here and say New file, and we'll be adding to this in a in a few
lectures.
I'm going to call it response utils.
Don't go.
These are utilities I can call whenever I need to give some kind of response package to Alatas.
And the one we want right now is called right, Jason.
So it's just a function with the receiver of C pointer to celebrities.
So that'll make the error go away once we're finished here.
And this is right, Jason.
Like that and it takes a pitot response writer.
It requires a status issue to be status, which is in it, some kind of data, whatever you want to
convert into Jason.
And we don't know what it's going to be.
So we'll just call it an interface, which is the only way you can do it and go until generic show up.
And optionally, we might have some headers, which will be a very attic reference to type H2 e dot
header case.
I need to add custom headers to this because I don't know what's going to be calling this, and it returns
an error, potentially.
This is a really simple, would you say, declare a variable out check for an error?
And what we're going to do is, say Jason from the Jason package and I'll say mercial in debt just because
it's very readable in production.
I would just use Marshall, but I'm in development right now and I can change this after the fact.
And I'm going to marshall data with no prefix, but I'm going to indent things using one tab and that
will give me nicely formatted JSON.
So we'll say if error is not equal to nil will return the error in case we can't go any further.
Otherwise, we'll check for headers to see if they've been included because you can have zero or more
headers as the final parameter in this function call.
If the length of headers which I have to spell right is greater than zero, then we'll just say four
key and value are assigned the value of or assigned values by ranging through headers.
Zero.
OK.
We're only going to be looking for one header and we'll call on W.
Our response writer header index key is equal to value and that should assign a header to the request
or to the response.
And we also need to tell it that Jason is coming back.
So Dot Header Dot set up and we're going to set a content content type two application slash JSON.
And finally, W Dot, Right, had her status, which we received as a parameter to the call to this
function.
And now we don't care about the first return value.
We do care about the error.
Those come from W Dot right out.
And once again, we have an error check which will paste here and we'll say return nil.
OK, so that's now available to us.
So when I switch back here, I still can't see it because I have to open my terminal and say Go mode
vendor.
And eventually this should catch up to me.
So here we are.
And it'll take a little while for that thing to go away, except that there is actually an error there,
which is probably why it's showing up that way.
And I misspelled Jason.
So it's right, Jason, like that, so that takes care of our middleware are two kinds of middleware
we want to install automatically.
And this lecture is getting a bit long, so we'll take care of installing those in the next lecture.