So we have our middleware written, and now, of course, we need to update our command line tool to
install that middleware when someone types make off.
So we have our off token middleware here and we have our off middleware here in my app and we have a
warning, OK, I can do that.
He wants me to use this constant instead of hard coding for a one which is fine, we can do that.
So now let's switch back to our celebrities project, and I'm looking at off.
Don't go.
And we're at this point here where we want to now the very end of this before the return statement copy
over middleware.
And not surprisingly, it's pretty much the same as what we've done here.
And again, we're going to have to create those templates.
But let's get this going first.
We're going to copy copy file from template inside of the Templates directory, which is our Read-Only
embedded file system.
And we'll make this middleware and we'll copy over auth don't go text to in the application in my app.
Middleware often go.
And of course, we can copy this and scroll up a bit and paste it here and make this auth dash token
go and make this our Dash token go.
So now, of course, we need to come over to our Templates directory and create a new folder called
middleware.
And inside of the middleware folder, we'll create a new file called Auth Go.
And another one of Dash Token Go text.
So we're looking at off Dash token.
So let's switch over to my app and find off a token here.
Select and copy and paste it in here, and then we'll open off, go to text and switch back to my app
and get off and go to text.
I think I might get those backwards.
Let's make sure I often do that off token.
Yeah, I got them backwards.
So we'll copy off token.
Good thing.
I noticed that and paste this into off dash token.
Don't go.
That's better.
And now we'll open off doggo
and go back here and open, often go to text and paste it in.
So that actually should work.
So if you think it through, we should be able to go back to our original Darcy line.
Go back to our map project.
Delete the models related to authentication from the data directory.
Delete the middleware from the middleware directory, but leave middleware.
Don't go.
That'll be part of the actual empty application and delete all the database tables run.
Make auth and everything should be recreated from scratch, which should be pretty straightforward if
we didn't make any mistakes and we'll try that in the next lecture.