So we're just about ready to try the new make out functionality.
And before we do that, I did have one typographical error, which I'm sure you noticed over here in
the middleware folder inside of the Templates folder in CMD Seelye.
I have t.x t at the end of this instead of dark text.
So let's fix that.
Otherwise, we're just going to have a an error.
So that becomes dark text.
OK, now let's go down to our terminal and let's make build, underscore Seelye to build the new binary
and copy it where it has to go.
And that's done.
And now let's switch over to my app, and let's make sure we get rid of the things that we don't want
here.
So I don't want models.
No, I do want models.
Don't go.
I don't want token, don't go or user don't go in the data directory and you might want to just move
those somewhere.
But I have lots of copies, so I'm going to delete those moved to trash.
I want to make sure my middleware folder is almost empty.
It doesn't have both token or off go.
So let's delete those and I'm going to get errors because I, my other code, is referring to things
that no longer exist.
But that's OK in my migrations.
I want to make sure there's nothing in here, so delete those.
And now I want to go to my database and make sure that my tables are all gone.
So back to post Taco and I mean, toss in the celebrity stalker salacious, select all of these tables
and delete them.
Cascaded delete.
And they're gone.
So at this point, I should be able to Typekit slash celebrities in the makeup project make off.
And it finished.
OK, so let's make sure everything is there, we have our this should be the same because I didn't change,
so user don't go, that's fine in the data directory token.
Don't go, that's fine in the data directory and in my middleware, I now have off token.
Let's make sure it's the right one.
It is, and I have off.
Don't go.
And that's correct, too.
OK.
Is there anything else we should add there?
Because if you think it through when they actually run, make off, we're not telling them anything.
We're not telling them what we did and we're not telling them things like, for example, you probably
want to go to your models dog go folder and add these two lines right here because we don't want to
do that programmatically.
We probably could, but the chance of messing up somebody's existing code is too high, and I'd rather
just tell the users, you know, this is kind of your responsibility.
If you want to have access to the users and tokens in the model struct, just go add them, add them
there and of course, add them down here as well.
So let's go back to our celebrities project and let's find that often go, which isn't the middleware
in this case, is the commander installs the authentication tables and all of those things.
Let's just put some messages here.
I'll put color yellow just so it's visible, and I'll put a, you know, as a string a couple of spaces,
then a hyphen, then users tokens and remember tokens, migrations created and executed.
Just let them know that we've built the necessary tables in the database and executed and on duplicate
that.
And I'll also I'll change this message to.
User and token models created.
I don't duplicate that and change this one to off middleware created.
Then I'll just give them a blank line colored yellow and a blank line, and I'll duplicate that one
more time and I'll put the reminder here.
Don't forget to add user and token models in data slash models.
Don't go.
And to add appropriate middleware to your roots, and I'll put an exclamation there.
That's just a little friendlier.
OK.
So that seems to work pretty well.
Now, obviously, there's more we can do with our command line tool.
For example, we can automate creating an empty or a stub model file or a stub middleware file or a
stub handler.
So let's get started on doing those things in the next couple of lectures.