So let's improve our Seelye even more by implementing a make handler function that allows us to create
with one command a simple handler, just a stub handler for our end users.
So I'm looking at may not go in the celebrity project inside the CMD Seelye folder.
And if we scroll down here, we already have a function here that says make that calls to make.
So we have a switch statement with the case of make and provided they have an argument, all the appropriate
arguments it calls do make.
So let's open to make.
And right now we have migration and we have off.
So let's add a new case case, and I'll call this one obviously, handler.
In this case, we need to make sure that we haven't earned three, that's not an empty string because
we can't say celebrities make handler and stop because we wouldn't know what to call the handler.
So we'll do a simple check here.
If ERG three is equal to an empty string, then we'll exit gracefully, exit gracefully and we'll handed
errors.
New, you must give the handler a name, and that's simple enough.
And let's give ourselves some room here.
Now, assuming we have that, what we're going to do, of course, is build a file name for the new
handler, copy some template file into that file.
And right now, that's pretty straightforward.
So we'll just say filing or filing for the handler will be sold on route path because it needs to be
the full path named the file we're going to create plus and handlers go in the handlers directory plus
and I'll just take whatever name they gave me and convert it to lowercase using the strings package
strings dot to lower.
And it would be R3, and then we need to append don't go to the end.
So that will be the full path named to the file we're going to create.
And of course, we want to make sure the file doesn't already exist.
We don't want to overwrite an existing one.
So if file exists, that function, we wrote just a few lecturer ago file name, then exit gracefully
with errors dot new and we'll just say file name plus already exists.
And that stops at this point.
So we're not overwriting somebody else's data.
Now, one of the things we can't do is simply copy a template unchanged over to the My App directory
because no matter what we put in that template, it's going to have the wrong name for whatever handler
we're trying to create.
So instead, let's create a data variable and check for an error, and we'll read the contents of that
template, which we haven't made yet, but we'll make it shortly into data.
OK, so we'll go to template EFS and we want to read a file right there.
In the file we want to read is templates, and we have to create this directory handlers and we'll call
it handler dot dot and go dot text.
OK.
So that will read the contents of that file into data, and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then exit gracefully with error and we'll have to create that file in
a minute.
Now I'm going to create a new variable called Handler, and this will be the final version of that handler,
and it's assigned to the value of casting data to a string.
So now it's a string, so now I can do something with it.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to put some text in that template file that I can replace with
whatever I want to call this particular handler.
OK?
So it's as simple as handler is now equal to strings.
Don't replace all replace.
All right there.
And we want to search in the string handler.
We want to look for and I'll call it, dollar sign handler name like that dollar sign because there's
no way that's going to exist anywhere else in the template.
And I want to replace it with using staircase.
Staircase right there, two camel like a camel case.
And what I'm changing, of course, is are three, so that will take whatever they type for a name for
their handler, convert it to camel case, which is the norm for naming handlers and replace every occurrence
of dollar sign handler name dollar sign with the correct name for this particular handler.
OK.
And at that point, I'm just going to write the file.
So error equals IOU tool dot right file.
And I want to write the contents.
I want to write to file name, which I have a capital in for and I want to cast to a slice of bytes.
The string variable handler, which has the contents that I want it to be and will give it sensible
permissions.
Zero six four four should do the trick and again will copy this.
Paste it in here.
And that should do it for that.
So let's go back to our templates directory and create a new directory called handlers, and inside
of that will create a new file called Handler and Coco Text.
So we'll just type it out is a regal photo package handlers, which would have to be and then we'll
import the one thing we'll need, but I'll put it like this in case they want to put more imports in
quickly.
We want net h GDP and down here, I'll say dollar sign put a space there handler name.
Dollar sign comment goes here.
Try it again here, and I'll create a funk with a receiver of h.
A pointer to the type of handlers with dollar sign.
And I'm a copy that I'm going to miss Typekit otherwise.
And I'm doing the autocomplete.
For me, that's nice.
And that takes as old handlers do the response, writer, HTP response writer and are is a pointer to
FTP Typekit request.
And we'll just leave it empty like that.
So that should do the trick.
Now let's go back to our main doco and update our helpful right there.
His show help.
So let's find that and we'll just add on another line make handler name and say creates a stub handler
in the handlers directory.
Now, that's not a whole lot of functionality, but it does make life easier for people that are working
with our product, and we may as well since we're here anyway, let's say make model name.
We're going to do that next creates a new model in the model's directory.
OK, so that's pretty straightforward, and we can try it out so we can say make build, underscore
Seelye.
And we have a problem here, staircase no required module provides this, where is that?
And that is my fault.
I never imported this module and this is something that I really should have noticed before I did it.
But to convert something to camel case, the easiest way in the world is to import this package.
So let's try that.
Go get and paste that in there.
And let's go back to make don't go.
And I did the auto import for me and fixed it, so let's try that again.
My apologies.
So let's just go have a look at this.
I'll open my web browser and we'll paste that.
You were all in the location bar.
And as you can see, this is a dead simple package.
We could implement this functionality ourself, but it just allows us to change things to snake a snake
with ignore, so on and so forth.
And the one we used was to cameras.
I apologize for that.
So now let's try building that again.
Make Build Seelye.
And let's go back to our other project, my app.
And from here, I should be able to go into the terminal.
Clear the screen and Typekit celebrities make handler and I'll just call it test handler.
There it is.
So enough, I look in my handler's directory.
I have one called test handler all lowercase as it should be.
And if they open it up, it's actually named test handler in camel case, as it should be.
OK.
Very straightforward.
Now, in the next lecture, we'll do a similar thing for models.