So we have make Handler working pretty well and is pretty simple, but it will make life easier for
people using the celebrity's package and this time around.
I'm back in Mexico in the CMT Seelye folder of the Celebrity House project, and this time around I
want to work on allowing us to make models case model so someone types celebrities make model and it
will actually make a model for them.
Now, the convention we've used so far is that database table names would be plural, but model names
are singular.
So, for example, the database for users the table in the database is called users plural, and the
one for tokens is called tokens plural.
But the actual models in the data folder are called user and token, and we'll follow that same convention
where we make models.
Now, of course, making a word plural is actually not as simple as you might think, because sometimes
it's easy.
Sometimes it's ISIS, sometimes it's s.
But fortunately, there's a little package, a really straightforward one found here at GitHub dot com
slash g e r t d slash go dash plurals.
And this is a part of a nice JavaScript package that solves that problem for us.
So we're going to use that.
So we'll go back to my I.D. Make sure I'm in the celebrities project.
I am an open terminal window and type go get.
And then that's the URL.
So it will go and get that for us, and that will just make our lives a lot easier.
So I'll close my terminal and I'll get started.
So the first thing we want to do, of course, is pretty much the same thing we did when we created
a handler.
And that is to make sure that Argument three is there, that they're giving the model a name because
we can't actually read minds.
So I'll paste that in here and say, you must give the model a name.
And assuming we get that again, we want to do this sort of thing that we did before, and that is to
create a data variable and look for an error.
And actually, we can just copy this whole thing.
There's no point in reinventing the wheel.
We'll just copy this and paste it here and change this from templates handlers handler.
Don't go to text to template data and we'll call it model.
Don't go.
OK.
So once we've read that again, we'll create a temporary variable string variable, which I'll call
model.
And that will be the data bytes, which is a slice of bytes cast to a string.
And then I'm going to plurals that I'm going to get a plural version of this.
So I'll just call plumber.
That's my variable name.
Not a real word, but it'll work for my purposes, and I'm going to call the Plurals Package.
We just installed plural lies and found it.
That's good, and I want a new client.
And this is right in the documentation for that page, but it's danceable.
So I'll create a variable, which I'm going to call modeling, and that will be equal to R3.
And I'll create another variable, which I'll call table name or table name is we need both of these
things.
And again, that's earned three.
And then I'll just work on them.
I'll make them what they need to be.
So the first thing I'll check is to see, did they type in a pluralist name already?
So if plural, which is that client I just created for the plural plurals package?
Is it plural?
Is plural and I handed out three or three.
If it is plural, then modeling.
Model name is equal to plural, singular.
Three.
And table name is equal to strings to lower.
We want it all to be lowercase tabling
otherwise.
In the case where what they typed as ERG three is not plural, then tabling
is equal to strings to lower plural, plural part three.
And this will give us our two variables are variables model, name and table name.
In the format that we need them to be now, let's keep going.
Let's build a filing filing.
This is where we're going to write the final file.
It goes to sell dot root path
plus slashing data slash plus.
Strings to lower name plus dot.
That's what we'll write the final version of this, OK?
And now of course, we need to work on the final version of the data that we're writing to that file,
and we're doing that with the string model, OK, that we declared right up there in Line 77.
That's going to be equal to.
And again, we're going to do a search and replace, but we're going to search for two things strings
don't replace all.
And we're working with model and we're going to look for the string that'll be in our template model
name.
Dollar sign modeling, dollar sign.
And we're going to replace every occurrence of that using the staircase package we installed last time
around.
And we want it to count.
And again, it's going to be model name.
OK.
So that's the first thing we want to replace.
And of course, that's the name of the model.
Now I'll duplicate this whole line, and this time I'm looking for table nine door sign table name.
I get that right.
Tamboli and Amit.
Yep, and here I'm going to use just table name.
And of course, that's the function that returns the name of the table.
And I have an extra parentheses there.
OK, so we have that the next step is just a copy data to file.
So I can say error equals copy data to file and I'm going to use a slice of bytes and I'm going to hand
it model that string we just worked on.
And we're writing into filing and we'll check for air, you know, just copy this error checking code
right here because it's exactly the same and paste it in there.
OK, so that's a good start.
Now, of course, we need to actually put a file named the one we're reading here.
Templates data model, don't go to text.
So let's open that up.
Could a new file and we're going to call it Model Dot Go Dot T s t.
Now, just to save some time on the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a file called Model
Dot Gokey.
Because what we're putting in here, there's nothing new.
It's exactly the sort of thing we've done already, but we'll go through it quickly anyway.
So I'll paste in the contents of that file at the very top.
Of course, it's packaged data.
We have our standard imports and here is where we're going to give the model its actual length.
So that's why we went to all that trouble of using camel case and plurals and so forth.
And we're going to say that the stub model has only three fields I've created and updated that.
Then we have our table function, and that's where we substitute model name here and table name here,
and everything else is pretty standard.
We put in a starter, get all a get by ID, an update record or update method, delete method and insert
method.
And then down here just to show them how they can use builder.
I put an example of how you can use uppers sequel builder.
OK.
That's a good starting point, and they can modify it to their heart's content.
So at this point, I should be able to open my terminal window.
Make sure I have everything right.
I'll type, make build, underscore Sealord.
And then I should be able to switch to my My App project, which should have the new build of celebrities
in there.
And if I look in my data directory, I don't have anything called test.
So let's just try this out.
Dot slash celebrities make model and I call it test, and it said it finished.
And if we look up here in our data model, we have a test.
Don't go.
It does look like there's an error.
And of course, it's the FMT package.
Apparently, I have that left in there.
There's no problem.
If I delete that, does it fix it?
We have an error down here.
Get Insert I.D..
And of course, that's an uppercase D like that.
So let's go fix those two things in our test model back over here.
So the first thing up here is get rid of the format package and then look for get insert.
There it is, and this will be fixed on the copy.
I posted the course website for you, but I had to fix it right here and that should take care of it.
OK.
So if I rebuild this now, make build seal.
And switch back to my app and close this test, go and delete Tesco and run it again, this time it
should work.
Make model test.
So it made a model, let's go look at it.
There's Tesco and the model name is Test Singular Perfect.
The table it's returning is tests plural perfect?
Everything looks good here.
OK.
And that will make life much easier for our end users.
All right, let's move on.