So we have to make model working almost perfectly.
There's one thing I left out, I did not include logic to make sure that the model we're trying to create
already exists or doesn't already exist.
And we did a very similar thing here, and I'm looking at make Dot go in the celebrity's project in
CMD Seelye.
This if file exists.
OK, so let's copy that.
And we do that right after we define the file name variable.
And let's go back down to the model case, and here we have the file name variable, so we can just
paste that right in there and that'll take care of it.
Now, this time around, I want to make another thing easier for us.
If you recall, right now we're only implementing cookie based sessions.
And the big drawback with those is that when you restart the application, all the sessions are lost
and there's probably a way around that.
But typically, I never use cookie based sessions in production.
So let's go back to our web browser and let's have a look at.
Alex Edwards SXSW This is the session manager we're using.
And if you scroll on down, you'll see that it has supports for various kinds of database stores and
other stores.
For example, here's one for post-career store where your entire session is stored in the database and
there's another one from my school.
Let's use those.
Let's go back to our code, and let's go to the main menu or the main dog file.
And let's go to our show help.
And let's add another command in here.
First of all, this is incorrect.
This one, we're not creating a new model in the model's directory.
We're creating the data directory.
Now let's implement make session and we'll put four.
This creates a table in the database as a session store.
OK.
And now we'll go back up to where we're doing our make command.
And I think that's here in Makoko, it is.
Let's create another case here.
So we have one for model.
Let's now create one down here for session case session.
And what I'm going to do is, as I've done with other ones, I'm going to put this off in its own file
just to keep things pretty clear.
So I'll make a reference to a function that doesn't exist yet.
Do Session Table and that will return potentially an error, as you can see.
So do the check.
If there is not equal to nil, then exit gracefully with the error.
OK, now let's create this do session table function because that's all we're doing is creating a database
table.
So we'll create a new file in the CMD Clia folder called.
Session, don't go.
OK.
And it's package main
and we'll create a function do session two, which takes no parameters, potentially returns an error.
So we'll say return nil.
Just to make sure all the errors go away.
And if I go back to make Doc go to session table, I do have an error here, so only copy that name.
I probably have a typo over in session doggo do session two.
That's OK.
So that makes the errors go away.
Now we need to figure out what kind of database they're using, because if we go back here and look
at the in the web browser, let's look for example at the MySchool store and the Postgres store, and
I've opened each one on a new tab.
So let's look at the MySchool store.
What that says is you have to run this sequel, and that's all we're going to do here is run some sequel,
create a migration, run the migration.
So this is the one for my host.
You will.
And as you can see, this is the syntax, and this is the one for Postgres and their different syntax.
So we'll have to figure out what database they're using.
So let's go back to our code and figure out what database are using.
And we already have that information.
It's in our cell variable.
So DBE type is assigned the value of cell dot db dot data type.
So that tells me a third MySQL or Postgres.
Of course, they might have typed MySQL or MariaDB, or they might have type Postgres or Postgres Q.
Well, so let's just make sure that is correct.
If DBE type equals minus Q, well, let's just assume they're going to go with MySchool.
If it's equal to Maria DB, then DB type equals, I call it minus two all OK.
In the same way, if DB Typekit equals.
Postgres que el and debe Typekit is equal to just post-cruise, so we know what to use because we're
going to build a file name here shortly.
OK, now let's create an outmigration, a file and this will be the full path to where the migration
will live.
And that will be equal to spelled out root paths plus slash migrations, plural slash plus some file
name, which we'll get to in a minute.
Plus the Dot Plus DB Type Plus Update Sequel Dot Up Dot sequel.
OK, now let's define file name, which I probably should have done first, but it doesn't matter.
We're going to get it done.
So filing?
Will it be equal to it?
We've done this for migrations before.
Format Esperanto.
We're going to have a format stream that consists of a percent D for an integer and then an underscore
and then create sessions table.
And our substitution is timed right now.
There don't Unix timestamp or Unix microbots at Unix Micro.
So the cases are based me and we'll duplicate this.
I make this down file and this becomes down.
So our migrations will be named.
Whatever the current Unix micro timestamp is underscore, create sessions table update as you will and
dot down to rescue.
Exactly like we did before.
So now that we have these ready to go, we're going to call the signing a value to error.
Copy file from template.
We'll have to make the template in a minute, OK, and it will be templates, slash migrations slash.
And then our Deb type, which is why we went to the trouble of getting into the right format TV type
plus underscore session, don't screw up.
OK.
And then all.
So that will give me my up file, but we have to check for an error.
So we'll just do our standard if error is not equal to nil.
Then we're going to.
Exit gracefully with the air, and our downfall is really simple, air is a sign the value of air is
equal to those who already have an air variable.
We're going to copy data to file and we want to copy a slice of bytes.
And all that's going to consist of is drop table sessions,
and we're going to write to downfall.
And again, we'll copy our error check pasted here and now we run those migrations.
Error equals do migrate and we hand it up.
There's nothing for the second parameter.
And we do urge it.
And that's it for that one.
Now we have to create our two templates, so we'll create two and they're both going to be in the migrations
folder in our file system or embedded file system, so migrations will create a new file.
And the first one is going to be called Postgres underscore session, not sequel.
And the second one is going to be called and we bring this up to make sure you get the name right.
It'll be minus you will underscore session that sequel.
My ask you will underscore session that sequel.
OK, so we're looking at my school.
So let's go get the appropriate school for that right from Alex Edwards site.
So back to the Michael store.
So we'll copy this.
Paste it in here and I will switch to post-cruise underscore session at school.
Our template and go to the post-credits store one.
Copy that and paste it in here.
OK, so we should be able at this point to say make build underscore seal on.
Switched to my app, open a terminal window, clear the screen and typed celebrities, which was type
help to make sure help file still looks good and it does.
We want make session so clear the screen that celebrities make session.
And it says Postgres underscore session dot sequel in templates migrations.
That file does not exist.
Session Postgres underscore session.
Let's see what we have here.
So we have in templates.
In-migration post-cruise underscore session dot, Scott.
Well, I have a typo here somewhere.
Let's go back and see what we have.
Ah, get rid of that slash before the templates.
So that was my problem right here in line.
Twenty six do something terrible.
I had a slash before that.
And of course, this is an embedded file system, so we don't need to slash.
Actually, we wouldn't want to slash in that form anyway, ever, but let's try it again.
Make build CeeLo.
Switch back over.
And we should have the new binary there, so it should just be able to hit the up arrow and press return.
Finished.
OK.
There's the session migrations, so this one is the down one, and that looks good.
Drop table sessions and it looks like this one ran without an error.
Let's make sure let's go to our postcard client.
And go back up to celebrities and refresh and we have a Sessions table.
Perfect.
OK, so we have a sessions table now, but we still can't use it because we haven't installed the necessary
session store package and we haven't done the necessary code changes to the celebrity's project.
But we'll take care of that in the next lecture.