So we've managed to modify our command line application to generate the appropriate table for sessions
in the database.
And as you can see right here, we have it live in our Docker database.
So there's the sessions table and now we need to modify our package or our projects so that we can actually
use database sessions.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to go to session, don't go in the celebrities package
inside the session, and I'm going to add a type here because we need to have access to the database
pool in order to write to the sessions table and read from it.
So I'll add a type or a field in here.
Deep pool of type point or two SQL Dash or DV.
OK.
And that should do the import for me.
And it did.
So let's save this to format it.
And the next thing we want to do is we need to go to celerity.
Don't go the main file or the entry point for our Solaris horse package, and I'm going to go all the
way down to a modal line, one hundred and eighteen in my code right here.
And here's where I need to actually populate the DB pool field.
So deep pool should be available to me now, and it is and is simply seed on DB pool because we already
have that at this point in our program.
So that's done.
And the next thing to do is to go to the in its session function, which is right below this.
So I'll just command click on it.
And that takes me over to Session Doggo where we were just a moment ago and down here.
Where my case is Postgres or PostgreSQL at this point, I'm just going to set my session store, so
I'll say session, which is a variable we have available to us and we've been setting all of its values
right up here.
Don't store.
That's going to be equal to Postgres Store Dot new and we had it said cool, and that should take care
of it.
But of course, we need to tell our application in my app that we're going to use a Postgres store for
our sessions.
So we'll go back to our Maya project should we collect an error there.
What is the error?
And the air says could not important.
So I guess I need to import that.
So let's go get this.
I thought I had already done that, but apparently not.
No problem.
Go get that.
And it goes and gets it for us.
So that's been added to my session or to my go to Ahmad file and the errors are gone.
So now let's go over to our Maya project and let's open our own file and let's find this type or the
section on sessions.
And we're going to use session type equals Postgres.
So now if I open my terminal.
And say, make start assuming I have my appropriate Docker images running, it should run, and it did.
So let's try it out.
Let's go to our web browser and I'm already on my local host.
Let me reload that and let's try logging in as a user.
So I'll log in as we hear dot com with password, password and log in.
Another error upper no more rows in this result set is to be expected.
But if we go back here to the main screen, the problem is that I've emptied my database so many times
that I don't have a user in there anymore.
So let's go back and look at our code and open our roots file and find out what that path is to create
a user.
So right here.
Create user slash create user gives me me out here icon with password.
So I'll just go back to my application and I'll just put slash create user like that.
Create Dash user.
Now I've created myself, so now I can go back in here and log in as a user and put in me here dot com
with the password password.
Log in.
Now I'm logged in, so log out shows up.
Now, if I go back and actually stop my application and we'll look in the database in a minute, but
if I go back in here and go to my terminal and say Make stop, if we were using cookies sessions, which
I was a moment ago, then the logged in user would go away as soon as I started the application back
up.
Let's try and make a start and refresh that screen.
And if all went well, I should still be logged in.
So I should still see log out here, so I'll reload the page and we are.
And if we go, look in our database over here and open our sessions table, I actually have values in
there and that's the session for my one user.
That worked really well and that will make things much simpler.
Now, obviously, as you can see back in our sessions, dark go in the celebrity's package.
We're also going to support my Esquivel and MariaDB, so we may as well go get that.
So I'll just put in for this case session.
Dot Store equals minus goodwill store, which I'll probably have to go get York-New with the Cedar Divi
Pool.
And if I go to the top.
Yes, it's not important.
It's showing up here because I have it in another package, but I need to import it for this one.
So if my terminal and type go get and paste that in and that will go and get it for me.
And that area should go away, and it does.
And of course, we're also going to at some point in the not too distant future support Rita Sessions
as well.
So we'll support Rita's My or MariaDB Postgres and of course, the default of Cookie.
So that was relatively painless.
And now we have a means of persisting sessions between application restarts.
So let's move on.