So the last thing I want to do in this section before we move on to validation is to support make off
for people who are using MariaDB or my ask you out.
So I'm back in the Celebrity House package I'm looking at mean doggo.
And of course, right here in the first switch statement in the main function, we want the case where
it's make.
So we're going to we're going to do make.
So I'll come and click on that.
And of course, I want to make Auth, which takes me to the function do off.
And all I really have to do here, if you look at it, is we're building the file name for the create
off tables, but we're reading it from here on line 17 copy file from template templates, migration
auth underscore tables dot db type.
OK, so let's create a new file in our Templates folder under migrations and we'll call it off underscore
tables.
Dot Mostue out the sequel, so create a new file
auth underscore tables.
Dot my scroll dot sequel, and if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a file
you can download that gives you the necessary sequel.
So I already have that copy to my clipboard, so I'm just going to paste it in, and there we go.
It's very straightforward.
There's nothing surprising here.
It's a simple, simple file that creates all of the necessary tables and relations for authentication.
All right, let's move on to the next section and figure out how we're going to implement data validation.