So let's get started working on implementing migrations in the Seelye tool, and we're going to do some
work in the command line interface and we're going to do some work right up in the celebrities package
itself.
And we're going to start with the celebrities package.
So over in my celebrity's project, at the root level, the application right beside celebrities start,
go or create a new file.
And I'm going to call it migration's dot com.
OK, now we'll give it this package name, which is hilarious.
And what we're going to do in here is write some functions that will run an up migration.
In other words, it will load some file, presumably in the Migrations folder in the Maya project,
and it will execute the sequel it finds inside of there and will also read it migrate down function
that reverses that and we can do it by steps.
And if something goes wrong, we can force the migration and we're going to be doing that using code
from this package over here on GitHub.
So let me go to my web browser.
It's called going dash, migrate, slash, migrate, and there's a link to this in the course resources
for this lecture, but it's pretty straightforward.
I mean, one of the things you can see down here is that it's actually intended to be used as a command
line application.
In other words, you build a binary called migrate like it says right here and you indicate where the
source file is, what the database is and what you want to do migrate up.
And in this case, he wants to go two steps.
But the part I'm interested in is down here.
Use it in your go project, and that's what I want to do.
I'd rather not have to command line utilities for my end users.
I want them to do everything using the command line utility.
We're building.
So let's get started.
So I'll go back to my code
and I'll open my terminal window.
And the first thing I'm going to do is import the necessary packages so I will go and get from my terminal
window GitHub dot com slash golang dash migrate slash migrate slash and I'm going to get version four.
And as I said before, if there's a later version out at the time, you take this course, stick with
version four.
The difference between version four and version five, according to semantic versioning, usually means
there are breaking changes.
So stick with the one I'm using in this course, which is version four.
And after you're done, if you want upgraded to version five or whatever.
That's the time to do it.
Otherwise, you're going to run into problems.
So I'll go get that.
And it gets it.
Now I'm going to go get.
The same URL, but I'm going to do it for specific databases, so I know I'm going to want to be able
to have database slashed my ask you up.
And this is support for MariaDB and my ask you.
So we'll look get that package.
And I'll hit the up arrow and get the one for post-cruise.
They may have come down with the first import, but I'm really not an optimist.
And finally, I want to support file, so slash file.
And it's not database file, it's slash source file, they're.
So those are now all in my government, and they're available to me.
So let's get started in my Migration's Go file, which is at the root level of this hilarious project.
I'm going to, first of all, write a function that has the receivers C pointer to celebrities.
And this is a simple one.
I'm going to say migrate up and it's going to take one argument DSN, which is a string, and that will
be the data source name and a word of caution.
Going migrate actually uses a different minus or postgres driver than I do, so we'll have to rebuild
the DSN back in our in our command line application, but that's not difficult.
So this is going to return potentially an error.
And what we're going to do is create a variable and I'm going to call it four, migrate and check for
an error.
And we're going to call from the migrate package.
And I might have to put it in manually.
They seem to have to do that way too much.
Now there it is.
Migrate got new and we're going to migrate into string argument file colon slash slash.
And then I'll close my quotes and append to that C dot route path, which is the root path of the application
using celebrities plus slash and the folder where we're going to put our migrations is migrations,
plural.
Like that and it requires a second argument, which is the DSN, and we receive that as a parameter
in the call to this function.
So we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil,
then we'll just return the error.
Now we're going to call defer import clothes.
We're going to close this file after we're done with it.
OK, so after this application, after this function exits AM, we'll call its close function.
Now we'll again check for an error if error equals.
And this is m the variable, we got back on Line six and we're going to call a method on it called up
and we'll check for an error.
It's not equal to nil.
And what I'm going to do here is just say Log Dot Print Line, which I'll delete eventually, probably
error running migration
in the error.
And I'll return the air because we can't go any further.
Otherwise we return nil, so assuming that we have a migration to run and we will by the time we call
this function, this should attempt to run the migration and look there in the migrations folder and
say, Are there any migrations here that have not yet run?
If so, run them.
OK, so up is pretty straightforward.
But of course, you also have to run down migrations, and I'll write a function right now with a receiver
of C pointer to celebrities, and I'm going to call this one migrate down all, run all the down migrations.
DSN again, our connection string, which is a string, and again, it returns an error, potentially.
So just like we did before, we're going to have this, I'll copy this embarrassment and the error and
the defer because I'm going to need them all and I'll paste it here.
So we tell it where to find the migrations we create, the variable em, we defer clothes.
And not surprisingly, it's pretty much the same thing we did before, but we're running down migrations.
If error is assigned, the value of import down this time and error is not equal to nil, return the
error, otherwise return nil.
OK.
But you can see it's pretty straightforward logic.
It's not difficult at all.
Now we're going to have another one, which I'll call steps and that will run in migrations.
And when end, which is an integer, if it's positive, it'll run up migrations and when it's negative,
it'll run down migrations.
OK.
So we want to run one migration backwards, for example, this is the function will be, call it, so
func receiver of C pointer to celebrities and I'll call it steps.
And these have to have capital letters as their first name, or we're not going to be able to call them
in it.
And the DSN string and it returns potentially in error.
And just the same as before.
I need to get all of this.
So a copy it and I'll paste it in there.
And I will run if error is a sign, the value of important steps.
And of course, we pass it how many steps we want to go in and if there is not equal to nil, then we
return the error, otherwise return.
Now, sometimes when you're running migrations, you might have an error in the migration file itself.
And when you do that, one of the really irritating things about this particular package migrate going
migrate is that it actually causes some grief.
It marks something is dirty in the database and we need a way of addressing that.
So what I'm going to do is create a simple function called with a receiver of C pointer to celebrities,
and I'm going to call it migrate force, which fortunately is available to us.
And again, it takes the DSM the string and it returns, potentially an error.
So we're going to again need to open our migration's folder, so we'll copy all of this and paste it
in here.
And this time we're going to say if error is assigned the value of EMD up force and we're going to force
it to get rid of the last one, so minus one, and that will fix any problems we have, at least in
the vast majority of cases.
It's worked for me so far and we'll return the error if there's an error.
Otherwise, we return nil.
OK, so these are our functions.
We're not doing anything with them yet because we have some work to do in our command line application
before we can ever call them, but at least they're set up.
Now we haven't tested anything yet, and we will write tests for this.
But let's see if we can get things working first, and then we'll write some tests after the fact just
to make sure we cover all of the cases.
Let's move on.