So last time we worked on this, file migrations don't go at the top level of the celebrities package,
and I said we were done and we're not quite done because these functions like here end up.
They're actually using the database.
So we have to do some additional imports that I left out last time.
And I do that quite often.
So we need to import them even though they're not explicitly being used.
So we'll start with a blank identifier and we're going to have to import GitHub dot com slash go dash
school dash driver slash MySQL.
We're going to want that one, for sure.
And we're also going to want another blank identifier and GitHub dot com slash.
Golang migrate slash migrate slash v4 slash database slash MySQL.
And I will duplicate that one and change this one to post-cruise, which is the one who will be using
shortly.
And then I'll duplicate that again and change this to source in this to file file.
And that should be it for that.
And the only other change I'm going to make is here on Line 21, and this is not critical, but I like
to be consistent.
I want to make that an assignment operator.
So it creates a new era variable for these four lines of code.
OK, so now let's get started working on back in our Seelye.
I'll go to main doggo.
And what I want to do is add a command make and that will make various things.
And the first thing we're going to make is a migration.
So we'll add a case here case.
OK.
And when we call make.
We're going to require argument to to have some value.
So let's put it in our checking here, if earned two is equal to an empty string.
What it will be if it's not specified, which is, say, exit gracefully.
And we'll hand it errors, Don New, and the error will be make requires
a sub command and then I'll listen.
We're going to have migration, which is the one I'm going to be working with right now.
But ultimately we're also going to have model and handler to make it even easier for people to write
code.
OK, so exit gracefully will stop the application, so we don't have to worry about anything else in
that if statement.
Otherwise, we're going to look for an error.
We're going to make that equal to a function that doesn't exist yet, but we'll start work on it shortly.
We're going to call it do make.
And it will take two arguments argument two, which has to be there an argument three which might be
empty.
OK.
And we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then exit gracefully and we'll just pass it the error.
OK, so we don't have a do make function, so we probably should go make one of those.
So what I'm going to do is in the Seelye folder just to make things a little cleaner or create a new
file called Makgoba.
And it will be package main and we'll have a function called Do Make, which will take two arguments
or two and three both of type string and potentially it returns an error.
So let's put return nil here just so everything will compile, and we won't have any errors showing
up.
And I want to go back to mean, don't go, that error should be gone and it is good.
So what are we going to do in this make function?
Well, again, we're going to switch on argument too.
So for right now, we'll say switch or two and we'll have one case.
Case will be migration.
OK, and here's what we're going to make our migration.
Now, the very first thing we need to know because we're going to support both MySQL and we're going
to support Postgres, is what database is this person using?
So what's their default database in the dart on file?
OK.
And we can get that, of course, by declaring a variable DB type and assigning that the value of from
that celebrity's variable we have at the very top of our file.
And we're going to look for is DB slash DB Typekit or database type.
And we'll also, since we're running immigration, we're going to ask people to give the migration a
name, some kind of name, just so we have an identifier that makes it easy to understand which migration
is which.
So we'll check for our imagery if our three is equal to an empty string.
Then we want again to exit gracefully and.
We're going to give it a new error.
Errors don't know now, and we'll say that the errors you must give the migration any.
But if we get past that, then we're ready to start building a migration now.
Now, typically, migrations are named using a convention and the name is, say, the current Unix micro
time, followed by an underscore followed by whatever name the person gave their migration.
OK, so let's build a name.
So we'll give our migration a file name, assign the value of we use format as printouts, and our format
string will just be an integer, followed by an underscore followed by a string.
And our substitutions for those will be from the time package we'll call now.
And we want unique micro.
That's our first substitution.
And the second thing is just earned three whatever they decided to call their migration.
So this is the base for the two files that we're going to create.
We're going to create an up migration and a down migration.
So let's get the full path up file.
The up migration is going to be assigned the value of the root path of our application because we're
giving the full path to this so settled up route path plus the migrations folder.
Plus, file name, which we just built, plus a dog, and then we want the DV type minus two L or Postgres
plus up Estuvo.
So that's our upfront and our downfall will be almost exactly the same thing, but it will be down school
and we'll have to, of course, use the variable don't file.
So now we have the full path named the files I want to create.
So the next thing I would do at this point, and we're going to leave the code broken and pick it up
in the next lecture, the next thing I want to do is I want to create some templates for migrations,
things that I can copy in there that are something more than just an empty file because I want to give
my end users something to start with.
So we'll create a migration template for an app migration and a migration template for a down migration,
and we'll do it for Postgres to start with because that's our default database.
And later on, we'll do it from my school as well.
OK.
So we're going to create a function, something like copy files from template, and we'll create an
embedded file system that has templates we want to work with and there'll be migrations and models and
handlers and all sorts of things.
And then we can use those two functions or that function copy files from template anywhere.
We need to get started on that in the next election.