So we left this function do make in the make don't go file for a command line application.
We left it kind of in the middle of things broken our code won't compile right now, so let's finish
this part off.
And what I want to do next is to take those two full path names to an up file and a down file, which
are an up migration and a down migration, respectively.
I want to create some functions that allow us to copy starter migrations to make it easy for end users.
So to make that happen.
I'm going to call a function that doesn't exist yet, and I'll write it right here.
So I'm going to look for an error and that will be assigned the value returned by copy file from template
and that will take two parameters.
And the first one is where does the file exist?
And it's going to exist in an embedded file system called templates right at the same level as Dot.
And inside of that there'll be a folder called migrations, and inside of that there'll be a file called
migration dot and then whatever the DB type is.
So I ask you over Postgres, followed by upstart SQL, and we want to copy it to this path name up file.
And of course, that's the path to the migrations folder in my app.
In our case?
Now, of course, that that function doesn't exist yet, but we're going to write it in a minute.
So first of all, let's just say if error is not equal to nil,
then we'll exit gracefully with the error.
OK, then I'll copy this whole thing and do precisely the same sort of thing for the down migration.
So this becomes an equal operator.
And this becomes down the scale and this becomes downfall.
OK, so now let's go create this copy file from template, which I think I better spell, right?
That's better.
And here as well, look, I'll create that and we'll do it in its own file once again.
So in CMD in the Seelye folder will create a new file, which I will call copy Desch files.
Don't go.
So let's keep that it's packaged declaration package main.
And the first thing I'll do is create an embedded file system.
So I'm going to put things in a folder called templates.
So I'll go create in the Seelye directory a new folder called templates, and we'll take advantage of
that embedded file system functionality that came out a couple of versions of Go ago.
So to make that happen, we put in a special comment.
Go Colon embed.
And we're going to embed templates that folder we just created and we'll create a variable, a variable
called template EF-S for file system of type embed dot fs managed the import form.
That's good.
So we've imported that.
Now let's use it.
Funk copy file from Template, which takes two arguments Template path will be the first one, which
is a string and target file, which is also a string, and it potentially returns an error.
So first of all, we need need to make sure that the target file, the one we're trying to create does
not already exist, so let's put a comment there.
Check to ensure file does not already exist.
We'll come back to that and I'll put it to you in front of it.
So I don't forget to do
so.
We'll do that in a minute.
Now, let's read some file from our embedded file system.
Some data and error are assigned the value of from template f's.
I spelled it wrong, which is why that's not working.
And let's make this template for us.
That's better template.
Don't read file first, don't read file.
And we want to read template path and we'll check for error.
If error is not equal to nil, then our template doesn't exist.
So exit gracefully in the error.
Otherwise, we have some data.
So now what we want to do is to copy the data to a file, and we'll be doing that a lot with the various
templates we'll be building during the remainder of this course.
So what I'm going to do is read another.
Yet another function will refer to yet another function that doesn't exist yet.
So let's check for an error in equals copy data to file.
OK.
And we'll make that in a minute, and we're going to pass that two parameters data and the target file.
And again, we'll check for an error.
Copy paste.
And if we get past all that, then we've copied our file return.
Nil.
OK, now let's create that function func copy data to file and that takes two parameters data which
is nothing more than a slice of bytes.
And it also takes to string what are we copying it to and potentially returns an error.
All we do is say error is assigned the value of from the IOU till package.
We want right file and we want to write to.
That's where we're writing it to what we're writing into into that file is the data a slice of bytes
and we'll give it sensible permissions.
Zero six four four.
If error is not equal to nil, return the error, otherwise return nil.
OK, now go embed templates.
Templates, command Seelye.
It's there.
Hopefully, that error will go away shortly.
So the error I'm getting here, it says go embed templates and it says cannot embed directory template
because it's no embeddable files that will go away momentarily.
So let's create a new directory inside of our templates a new folder called migrations.
And inside of that, let's create some standard templates we can use.
Now, if you recall, back here in Make Dog Go, we're trying to create a file called migration or read
a file called migration dot db type postgres.
In our case, dart up SQL and one down dust you out.
So let's create some files inside of migrations or create a new file called and it has to match exactly
what I have here, and I do make function.
Migration dot postgres dot up school and we'll create another one.
Any file migration that post grows, don't screw up.
Now let's go back to migrations.
Postgres up, and I've already copied to my clipboard the contents of a file you can download from the
course resources for this lecture, and it's called Migration PostgreSQL Update sequel.
And it's nothing more than Common's and sequel, a starting point for people that are working on a migration.
And it gives them a simple create table in the Postgres syntax, and it gives the instructions on how
to use the trigger to auto update.
The updated app for the table might be creating, and of course, they can use this as a starting point.
Delete it, put their own sequel in there, whatever they want to do in the same way.
I have some down starter code here, and as you might expect to reverse that migration, all we're going
to do is drop that table, whatever it is.
So we'll leave it up to the end user to make sure that the sequel is correct, but this gives them a
starting point.
OK, now back in copy files ago go.
Presumably, that error will go away soon once it realizes that there is some embeddable stuff there.
But we now have we go back to the beginning of this main doggo.
If someone types celerity US space make and calls, of course, do make, so we go over to do make.
And then the one case we're trapping for right now is migration.
So here we get our database type and we make sure there is an argument three where they give their migration
a name.
We build the first part of the file name.
Then we construct the complete path to where we want these migrations to live and we copy file from
template.
So we're copying it.
The contents of this file, which is in our embedded file system templates, and then we copy the one
for the down migration.
At that point, it should be done.
OK, so this is a good starting point.
In the next lecture, we'll give it a try and see if it actually works.