So we appear to have written the code necessary to generate empty up and down migrations.
They only consist of comments.
Let's give it a try and see if it works.
So I'm still in this hilarious project and I've opened a terminal and I'm at the root level of my project
right beside Celebrity Moscow so I can take.
I can type, make, build, underscore Seelye.
And that should build the new version of our executable and put it over here in our My App project.
And it's there.
So let's try it out.
So I'm at the root level of my application, so I'm in the My App folder and I'll type dot slash celebrities
make migration and I'll just call it test.
I'm not going to do anything with it yet.
I just want to make sure it actually works.
And it doesn't, and it doesn't for a very specific reason.
If you read that error message closely, it says error open templates, slash migrations, slash migration
dot.
So far, so good.
But then we have another dot and update sequel.
In other words, what should be there?
The word postgres, in my case, it doesn't exist.
And if you think it through, this makes perfect sense.
Let's go back to our Celebrity House project and let's look at our celebrities main.
Don't go file right here.
Online 14, I've declared a variable cell of type celebrities start celebrities, and that's what holds
things like the root path that I absolutely need and data type, which is either Postgres or MySQL.
And although I declare that variable, at no point do I do anything with it.
I never populate its values.
So let's fix that and we can fix it really easily in the main function.
After I validate the input and make sure there's at least one thing after make what's called a function
that once again does not yet exist.
And I call it set up and I'll put that file, I'll put the function.
I'm going to call setup in its own file.
So in CMD Seelye, I'll create a new file called Helpers Dot gov.
I don't have to, but I like to keep things more or less organized.
So helper stucco has package me and we're going to have one function here called setup that takes no
arguments and returns nothing.
And what we want to do here is, in effect, a subset of the sort of things we do when a celebrity's
application starts up.
In other words, we want to load the dot on file and populate some values in the celebrity's variable,
so we can do that really easily.
We'll check for an error and I'll call from the package go dot on which I have access to Dot on and
I'm going to call load just like I do when I start up the application, the web app, and I'll check
for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll exit gracefully with the error.
But assuming I've done that, then I can do certain things.
So we have that variable cell, which is a package level variable.
We can we can work with that.
So let's try one thing.
We need to get the root directory, the root path to our web application, and we can do that really
easily by declaring a variable name path and checking for an error and calling OS Scott get working
directory.
OK.
And of course, this assumes that you're running the celerity command from a directory that has a dot
on file, and if not, we get an error message right there from Line 12, and it really doesn't matter
where that celerity binary exists.
If you, for example, put it in some folder that's accessible from your path as long as you execute
that command from the directory where the dot on file lives, then you'll be fine.
So we'll check for an error, and I'll just copy and paste this
right here.
And now that I have access to the root path for the application, I can say things like it's spelled
out.
Root path is equal to path, and I can also now load that database type that I need.
So DBE type debug data type is equal to OS.
Don't get on.
We just read it from the environment and it's called database underscore type.
And that's all I really need to do, I think.
Let's rebuild the application.
Make Build Selah in this hilarious project from the root directory.
And let's switch over to my app and let's try everything that command again.
So I hit the up arrow dot slash Solaris House, Make Migration Test, and if I look at my migrations
folder right now, this should be nothing in it and it's empty.
So let's run that.
And Iran.
That's good.
So let's look in the migration folder.
There are two migrations.
So let's try the up one.
It should be a commented out create table.
And it is.
And let's look at the down one.
And it's dropped some table perfect.
So now we have a means of generating migrations in the next lecture.
We'll actually try running migrations.