So we've managed to generate up and down migration successfully, and of course, they're fairly useless
until we can actually do something with them.
So what we want to work on this time around is actually running migrations up or down ones.
And of course, we're going to have to add a new case here in Maine.
Don't go in the Celebrity House project inside the CMT Seelye folder, and we're going to have to add
something like case migrate.
So we'll just put that in there and we won't do anything with it yet.
We'll come back to this now in order to run migrations.
If you recall, we worked on that migrations don't go file, which we may as well have a look at right
here in this hilarious project.
And of course, we want to be able to run an up migration, which means we're going to need to be able
to call this.
And that requires a parameter, which is the data source name the DSM in the form of a string.
And as I said a while ago, that data source name actually doesn't follow the same syntax as the one
we're using for our main Postgres driver, and I'm working on Postgres migrations right now.
So when we hit this case, somebody types celebrities migrate up.
For example, we need to call a function that will run some migrations, and that function is going
to have to have the DSM because it's going to call that appropriate function in migrations.
Don't go.
So let's go over to our help helper file and let's make a new function in here, one which I'll call
get decent.
And this is going to, of course, take no parameters, but it will return a string, a DSM in the correct
format.
So we'll get our database type because we don't know what type of database that person is running when
we call this function.
So DB Typekit, which is just a variable, I'm declaring right here and that comes from our cell variable
IV type celebrity sliotars and we're looking for DBA Dot data type.
So that should be either post-cruise or it should be MariaDB or MySchool.
But if it's post-cruise, we've actually changed it to PDX, if you remember, because that's the driver
we're using.
So we'll say if DB type is equal to X, then DB type is now equal to Postgres, which is the form we
need for the driver used by the Go Migrations package.
So we'll do a check here, if Debbie type is equal to post-cruise, which is the one I care about right
now.
Then we'll do something.
Otherwise, we'll build a different dataset.
So let's create a variable right here in the Postgres condition there, and we'll just call it the end
of type string.
And we're doing that for the same reason we did when we opened the connection to the Postgres database
a while ago because the connection string is different depending whether or not password is actually
set.
Now, in our case, if you're doing it like I am, then your password is set because you're doing everything
through Docker images and we set a password there.
But lots of people run a local installation of Postgres and the user is just Postgres and it has no
password.
So we have to track for both cases.
So we'll say if and at this point, we've already read everything from the DOT on into our environment
in that setup function, so we can check to see if OCR don't get on and we'll look for database pass
the database password.
If that's not equal to nothing, then we'll do something else.
We'll do something else.
So let's handle this first situation, OK, where the database password is not equal to an empty string
in this case, DSN is going to be equal to and will use the format as per Deb function.
And put things in the syntax or the correct syntax for our migration's package, and it has to begin
with Postgres colon slash slash.
And then we have a string followed by a colon, followed by another string, followed by an at sign
followed by another string and a colon and another string.
Then another string, followed by a question mark, followed by SSL mode equals another string.
And of course, we need to do the substitutions, so we'll hit a comma and I'll put these on the next
line so they're more readable.
Our first substitution is going to be OS.
Don't get on.
And we're looking for database underscore user.
And our second substitution is going to be the database password, which in this case is not an empty
string.
And our third substitution will be the host database host.
And after that comes support, not surprisingly.
And after that comes the name of the database.
And finally, we get the SSL mode.
So that is database SSL underscore mode, and I can bring this back up here and get rid of the karma
just to make it look pretty decent.
Now, if that's not the case and apparently didn't import format for me, so let me import that if empty,
that's better.
If that's not the case, we're going to have almost the same things.
So copy this and paste it here
and make the change.
And the only thing that really changes is everything before the outside, we get rid of this.
And then we get rid of database password, OK, and then down here after this it's statement inside
of the overlapping if statement.
If TBE Typekit equals Postgres, we'll just return DCEP.
Now, in the other situation, we can actually call because it's simpler for my ask, you will already
be.
We can simply return and pretend my que el colon slash slash, which the database migration's DSM requires.
And we can just call it hilarious.
Don don't build DSM.
And that should give it to us in the correct format.
And when we get around to trying MySchool, this should work fine and we can actually simplify this
even more because we don't need this health themed.
That's a useless code.
So let's save this.
All right.
Now I have a function that will actually return hopefully the DSM in the correct format for the migration's
driver.
So let's go back to mean dot, go to our initial switch statement and handle the migration part.
Now I'm going to assume that if someone types celebrities migrate, then they want to run their up migrations.
Otherwise they might be running, migrate down or migrate a number of steps or something like that.
So let's try this if are to, which is what would come after the word migrate.
If that's equal to nothing, then we'll assume they're going to run an out migration or two equals,
which has to be in quotation marks.
OK.
And at that point, I want to check for an error and run something called do migrate, which doesn't
exist yet, and we'll hand it earned two and three, which might be up to.
And we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil, then we'll say exit gracefully and we'll
hand it there.
And I'm also at this point going to say message that string we haven't done anything with yet, but
it's used by exit gracefully.
We'll add a message, migrations complete, and of course, you can put whatever you want there.
Now it looks like I haven't actually defined message here.
So back up in Think Maine, I'll just create a variable called message the message of type string.
OK.
And at the very end of this, after all of these things have executed, we can just say things it gracefully
with no air in hand message.
And of course, we'll have to remember to populate it for all of these cases.
But we'll get to that when we start running it.
So now, of course, we have this do migrate function and we need to build that yet because it doesn't
exist.
So just to keep things clean.
I'll come over here at peace in the Seelye folder and I'll create a new file.
Well, let's call it migrate dgo.
And this will handle all of our logic for managing migrations.
So Package may not see our main.
That's better.
And we'll declare a function do migrate, and it accepts two arguments are two and three, which I have
to put an hour in there, both of type string, and it potentially returns in error.
So DSN, at this point we can just call get DSL and now we have our connection string.
If we did everything right and now we want to run the migration command and of course, what we want
to run first is the UP migration command.
So we'll switch on our two and our first case will be up through monitoring the up migrations.
And at this point, it becomes as simple as checking for an error and calling from celebrities migrate
up and handing it to us.
And if error is not equal to nil, so we'll return the error.
Now, if that actually worked, then we're done with that case.
OK, but let's put the other cases in here, since we're doing it anyway.
We might also be running case down, running migrations down.
And not surprisingly, this is pretty much the same thing.
But in this case, you might want to run one migration down, or you might want to run all of the migrations
down.
In other words, to reverse all of the migrations that have currently run.
So, you know, in essence, to reset your database to nothing.
So let's say if our three is equal to all, I want to run all the migrations in reverse, then we'll
call error.
And that's a sign the value of cell migrate down all.
And we had it DCEP.
And again, we checked for an error.
So I'll just copy this because I'm going to be using a couple of times and I'll paste it right here.
So that's the case where they want to run all the migrations.
Otherwise, we can assume they just want to run the most recent migration back down and that becomes
error.
So Dot and we want this time to go steps and we'll hand it minus one, just run the most recent migration
backwards.
And we had it this hour and pacing our air check, and that handles that one.
Now another common use case, and it comes after this is case reset.
I want to I want to reset my database, run all the down migrations, then run all the up migrations.
And in that case, we just do this.
We're going to run, migrate down all just like we do right here.
And then we want to migrate up, we want to run them all over again, so I'll just paste it in like
this.
Move that back over changes to an assignment operator and change this just to migrate up.
And that should take care of the reset.
OK, now the last case, if something went wrong.
OK.
And we're going to be doing this regularly default.
And of course, that belongs inside that early bracket.
So let's try that again, default at this point to show out.
OK.
And down here, we'll say return nil, so now we have a command we can call do migrate.
So let's go back to Mongo.
And that era is going away and everything, I think at this point should work as expected.
But let's come down here as well and make this default show help.
And now we can get rid of our end to end this logging of our two and our three as I was just to make
it compile.
And that means I need to get rid of lug up here.
OK.
So let's save it.
I don't see any errors.
Anywhere in the next lecture will try running a migration.