So we've written all the code that should execute migrations.
Let's give it a try.
So I'm still in this alert house project and I have a terminal window open, so I'll make sure I'm at
the root level of my celebrity house project.
I am.
So now I can run, make, build, underscore seal art and that will build a new version of the command
line executable and copy it to this project.
My app.
So I have a new version of silver here.
So let's just look at how things are before we try anything.
Right now, I have nothing in my migrations folder and I'm connected to my database and make sure you
have your Docker images running before you do the next step or nothing will work.
And I'm looking at my celebrity's database in the Docker image, and right now I just have three tables
the ones that we created last time around.
So I'm going to generate a migration dot slash celebrities and it's make migration and it requires a
name, but just leave the name out and see what happens.
Error you must give your migration a name perfect.
So happy apparel, and I'll call this one test and that should.
And it did create an app migration.
So let's open that and of course, is not going to do anything if we try to run this until we uncomment
this bit.
So one comment that I'll leave these ones here commented, But I'll uncomment this.
I don't have to because I already have this trigger, but it should create or replace it.
And finally, I'll create the trigger.
So these lines, from 10 to 16 create or replace the function trigger set timestamp.
And this one assigns a trigger to this table using this function.
OK.
So we also want to, of course, uncomment are down migration.
So I'll uncomment that
perfect.
Now I should be able to come down here.
Clear the screen and type dot slash celebrities migrate up.
And it says it ran.
Let's go look at the database and make sure that it did.
So back to my database client.
I'll refresh it and look, it created some table.
Let's make sure it has the right columns.
So the structure of that is ID of integer, which is a sequence some field, which is a marker 255 and
are two time stamps.
Perfect.
So now we'll go back to the top level of this database, and you notice it also created this schema
migration's table, which if it doesn't exist the first time the tool is run, it creates that for us.
And that's what keeps track of which migrations have been run and which ones have not, and so on and
so forth.
Let's try running the down migration.
Migrate down.
And it says it finished.
So let's go back and look, refresh this and it's gone.
But it did leave the schema migrations table, which it should, of course.
OK, so that all seems to work pretty well.
Now, of course, there's one thing I need to do if I go back here and just type in the terminal in
my Maya project dot slash celebrities and hit return, it prints out the help, but it actually doesn't
put our migrate commands or anything else in there.
So let's go fix that.
Let's go back to our celebrities project, and let's find out where that show help exists.
So right now, show help.
There it is.
Command.
Click on that or control.
Click if you're in windows to see where that function exists.
So it exists in my mind, I'd go, Oh, I'm going to get it out of there.
I don't want it to be there.
So cut that out of there.
And instead, I'll put it in my helper smile.
I think that's a better place for it.
So I'll put it right at the bottom of that file.
And now let's updating.
And of course, we need to update color use color.
So see if it'll do the auto import for me.
Colored yellow?
Perfect.
That should fix the import, and I'll just delete the extraneous code.
And back in Maine, let's make sure that color is not being used anywhere else.
It so that's fine.
OK, so back to my helper stuck up.
Let's update our help file.
First of all, I'll put a blank line in there because it just looks bad.
So we're now going to add the command, migration and space over.
I'm not going to use tabs because they often don't work when you're working with console, but it's
up to you.
And I'll say migrate runs all of the migrations that have not been run previously
and I'll say migrate down
runs, reverses the most previous.
Our most recent, most recent migration, and we can try to migrate reset, which we haven't tried yet,
but we'll do it before too long.
This one runs all down migrations in reverse order and then all up migrations.
OK.
And we also should say make the migration name and we better space this over, or it will be very attractive.
And here will say creates two new up and down migrations in the migrations
folder.
I think that's it for now.
So we'll save this and I'll just rebuild the seal I.
Then I'll switch to my app.
Clear the terminal console and just run celebrities.
And we still have that Air Command required twice, but I can live with that for now, we'll clean that
up later on.
The help file at least seems to be useful, and let's try that slash celebrity's version application
version 1.0 point 0.0.
Oh, perfect.
So this seems to work really well.
Now let's take advantage of the code we've written and actually create a new command make off.
And what that would will do is copy all of the necessary files from our command line, from our read
only file system in our command command line application over to the appropriate location in the My
App application, and it will also create and run migrations to create these tables, the ones that
we did by hand right over here.
So remember, tokens, tokens and users will automatically create all of that.
Now that might take a couple of steps, but we'll get started on it in the next lecture.