So now that we're more or less sure the migrations work as they should.
Let's get started on making a new command for our celebrities come online application and it will be
make off and that will do everything necessary to in one step with one command set up the necessary
database tables, create the necessary models and everything else we need to do to make sure that authentication
is created very easily for end users.
So right now, I'm in this alert house package and I'm looking at Mango, and obviously we're going
to have to have a command down here that says make off.
Now we already have make render that takes us to do mix.
So let's go look at that.
Do make, says one case migration.
So let's add a second case here.
OK.
And it would be right here.
Case.
And rather than putting all of the logic right in this switch statement, because there's going to be
a fair bit for make off.
Let's create a new function called do off.
So we'll create a reference to a function that doesn't exist, do off, and it has no parameters and
we'll check for an error.
We'll do the same thing we do everywhere else, so we'll copy and paste that right there.
Now let's go make this dual function or at least get started with it.
And because it's going to be a fairly lengthy bit of code, I'll put it in its own file.
So in CMD Seelye, we'll create a new file, which I will call off ego.
And of course, that has package made and we need a function called due off and it returns potentially
an error.
So I'll put return nil here, and let's just think about the kinds of things we're going to need to
do here in this function.
Well, first of all, before we can have any authentication taking place, we're going to have to have
our migrations.
And then we're going to have to after we've done that, you know, will create the migrations.
We'll need to run the migrations and then we'll need to copy some files over and there might be more.
But this isn't a first term.
Well, we already know how to make migrations.
We had our DV type because we need to know what kind of database the person is using, and we get that
from seld DV data type.
So that gives us our data type, and then we need to create a file name, a based file name for our
migrations, just like before.
So that would be equal to from the format package.
Sprint F and our format string.
And that's going to consist of the Unix time, which is return is it isn't and then create users or
create off tables or tables like that because there's more than one table being created.
And we substitute, of course, time dot now
dot Unix Micro.
So that gives us our base file name.
Now we'll create our up file full path to the up.
We're going to create and that will be equal to sell dot root path
plus slash migrations plus file name plus.
And then we'll put up Dot sequel at the end and we'll duplicate that.
I will make this one downfall.
I make this down.
OK.
Looks like there's an error there somewhere.
Let's just make sure there's no error.
I'll just put a long dot print line and use the variables variables I'm not using.
So give me type of file and downfall.
Yeah, there is no error.
OK, so that'll go away in a minute.
But I'll leave that that here, just so we don't have any errors while I'm writing the rest of the code.
So now we need to copy the upper up migration and we can do that using that function copy file from
template.
And just handed the name of the template we want, which doesn't exist yet, so we'll have to copy it
in there in a minute.
Templates it'll be our file system that we're using.
Slashed migrations, and we'll call that one stay off tables, dot plus de B-type, because I have to
have one for my school, one for post-cruise dot sequel.
And that will be up for OK.
And we'll check for an error
if error is not equal to nil, we'll just exit gracefully with the error.
And now we need to create a down migration.
OK, so that when I can actually just write the code for it right here because it's very simple.
So I'll check for an error.
And of course, I don't use the assignment operator because I already have an error.
And we'll say copy data to file, and the data will be a slice of bytes and I'll I have to put in here
is drop table.
If exists, users cascade and that will delete the user's table and everything else, that depends upon
it because we're cascading it and we hand it down.
File.
Yeah.
And again, we check for an error.
So copy
and paste and the next step is to actually run the migrations.
So to make that happen, I might be able just to call do my great right here and hand it the necessary
arguments.
And of course, the arguments I want to hand out are pretty straightforward.
I want to run up and nothing.
And that does return an error.
So error equals you migrate.
And again, copy this and paste it there.
And let's just look at this and think of what we're doing right now.
So we're creating our migrations, and I'm pretty sure this is right because that's exactly the syntax
we use before we do have to make the create off tables template that we're referring to down here.
But this should work.
All right.
Then we'll get our migration, our template and put one in for Postgres and then later on one for my
school.
Then we copy that data over and make the necessary up migration.
Then we copy the this string of bytes over to down migration, and then we run the migrations that should
work.
So let's create a file in templates.
Migrations create a new file that's inside the CMG Seelye folder, and I want to call this one off.
Underscore tables dot postgres dot SQL.
OK, now I've already copied to my clipboard the contents of the school file we use to make those tables
so just pasted in here.
OK.
And that should be the one appropriate for Postgres, and we have our IDE.
Firstly, my name and make sure I got the right one here.
I want to go all the way down to tokens and make sure I have token in there.
Yeah.
This is the right one because I added my token character.
OK, so if that SQL is right, then in theory this should work.
OK.
We haven't done the copy files over a part yet, but we can test this.
So what we'll do in the next lecture is delete the three tables that are in our database or all the
tables from our database.
Make sure the migrations folder is empty.
Rebuild the Seelye and then run it and see if we get the necessary tables created, which will be a
good first step.