So let's try it or make off command, and of course, it's not complete yet, but it should at least
create the necessary tables.
But before we go too much further here in Austin, go inside the CMD Seelye folder of the celebrities
project probably want to put a slash after migration's.
Otherwise, we're not going to have valid path names and I will probably create files, but not where
we expect and not with the name we expect.
OK, so that's out of the way.
Now I'll build my seelye, so I open my terminal window and make sure I'm at the root level of my celebrity
house project.
I am, and I will say, make build underscore C.R and hopefully that will complete without an error.
It did.
Now I'll switch over to my My App project, and I'll clear the screen here.
I'll delete any migrations that are in there right now.
So those are now gone.
And now I'm going to go back to my database client, make sure I'm connected to my Solaris house, Docker.
I am just going to select all of these tables launched.
You know, I'll do it as a sequel query and might not be using the same database function as I am.
So I will say drop tables, table users cascade and execute that and hopefully delete them.
Let's find out about go back to celebrities, refresh those and apparently didn't get rid of remember
tokens.
So I'll delete that one and I'll get rid of these two as well.
I don't know what happened there, but anyway, it doesn't matter.
They are now gone, so I emptied my database.
So there are no tables in there at all.
There's nothing in my migrations folder.
So let's try running dot slash celebrities, make off and see if we get it right.
So it has my printing to the log file, as it did before, and there are my authentication tables and
hopefully those migrations ran, so I'll go back to my database client and refresh this there.
There I have my tokens, my users and I remember tokens.
OK, now just before we go any further, let's try this make migrate down.
And of course, I have to put dot celebrities in front of that dot slash celebrities and see if it deletes
those tables the way that I think it's going to.
So it's run.
Let's go back and have a look at our database client and see what tables are left.
And it didn't delete any of them.
I wonder why.
Let's look at our down migration drop table.
If exists, users cascade.
So obviously that one which I did for memory isn't the one that I want.
Well, this so we can actually manually delete those tables and fix this down migration, and we'll
take care of that and start copying files in the next lecture.