So this time around, we want to add additional services to monitor, and I think the easiest one to
start with is actually monitoring HTP s.
So in our handler's package, we already have underperformed checks.
We have at the very top constants.
HTTP is equal to one htp s equals to two.
That's the one I want to monitor.
So if we think about this logically in these scheduled check part, we look at the test services for
host.
That's the one that we actually want to look at.
So let's go down to that method.
And here we only have one case we want to add a second case to look for HDB secure Web server connections.
So to make that happen, there's a few steps we probably should take care of to begin with.
So right now, just make sure your application is not running.
So stop it and let's go over to our database client, whatever database client you're using to connect
and look at the services table right now.
There's only one entry in there.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to delete first of all, I'm going to go to hosts and I'm going
to delete this house just by deleting that record and saying save changes.
So currently we're monitoring no hosts.
And because we have four Q relationships, we're not monitoring any host services.
And I'm going to go back to services and I'm going to add a new service here.
I'm actually going to add two women will do them now and get them out of the way.
And I'm going to add HTP s and I'll make it active and I'll make its font faez f a dash server, same
as we had before, and I'll put a default date in there.
Twenty twenty one zero three oh ten twenty twenty one zero three dash ten and I'll hit return and then
I'll add another one SSL and I'll make that active as well and I'll make that effort.
Ashlock just to give it a lock icon and I'll put the same date in there.
Twenty twenty one zero three ten twenty twenty one zero three ten.
And I'll hit return and I'll save the changes.
Now this next step is important.
If like me you have numbers that are not two and three here, go change https to two and SSL to three
because those keys must exactly match what we have back in our idy at the very top.
This, this and this.
This one is two and this one is three.
So those need to match and in my case they do.
Now I'm also going to go back to my database and just to clean things up a little bit, I'll completely
truncate this this event's table because I have some stuff in there that doesn't really match any host
right now, so I'll just truncate it.
So delete all those records.
OK, now let's start writing some code and what we need to do here to begin with is to go back to our
idea and I'll find that method again, because I'll be going back there shortly, OK?
I need to open my database.
What we're going to do is we're going to read a host here.
So let me go to my repository and go to DB Repo and find host Postgres Culgoa.
Our hosts underscore postgrads Keywell don't go.
And I want to find the very first method where I insert a host and it's called insert host.
In my case, it's right at the top of the file.
But find the insert host method and scroll down to the part where we say add hosts services and set
to inactive.
And I want to modify that because when I add a host, I don't want to just copy and paste this to more
times and insert one for it to add one for Eighty-three.
Actually want to just look at the services table, find all of the services and add a service to a host
and set it to an active same as we were before.
So this is really not that difficult.
I'm going to write a new query and I'll just use a variable I've already have used above called query
and it's a simple query, select ID from services.
OK, so that's my new query.
I'm going to go get all of the IDs for all of the services in the service table and I'll create a new
variable which I'll call service rows and potentially an error that's assigned the value of IMDB query
context and had it the context and send out a query check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll just say log print line error and I'll return zero.
And the air, OK, and now, of course, I need to defer my service, Rose.
Up close, so we don't get a memory leak and I would just loop through all of the service post for service
Rose Dot next.
I'll create a variable VA service ID of type Int and I will scan into that newly created variable service
rose.
Scan into a reference to service ID.
So now I have the ID and I should check for an error.
I'll just copy and paste this.
Now that I have that, I can actually go down here and grab this all of this, cut it out of there,
paste it into here and modify it as necessary.
So here I am inserting host service or host ID and service ID and I have a hard coded one.
So I'll just change that to dollar sign too, which means I have to update this to Dollar Sign three
and this dollar sign for and my second argument after new I.D. will actually be service I.D..
So now when I execute this, it will actually automatically add all of the services for that particular
host.
So we'll have three and they'll all be set to inactive, which is exactly what I want.
The other thing I want to do is I'm going to finally get hosted by ID and in my case, it's the very
next method.
And I'm just going to add something here that's purely cosmetic.
So when I get it services, I'm simply going to add a little bit here that will give me the services
in a good order.
I'll say order by.
Escort service name that will list the services in alphabetical order.
OK, so that is a good start.
Let's start our application, make sure everything works as it should, and I will go back to my Web
browser.
Create a new window and I'll go to localhost 4000 and I'll have to log in admin at example dot com and
my password is password.
And we should have no hosts, but once we get in here and we don't no services, no hosts, so let's
go to the hosts tab at a new host and I'll have the same when I was using before.
So local host, local host.
The URL is htp colon slash slash localhost colon 80 80.
My IP address I'm not using but I'll put it in anyway.
And again, I'm in New Brunswick, Canada, and my operating system that I'm monitoring is Mac OS X
and I'll make it active.
So when I save this someday we should fix this button.
But that's not critical.
So I'm going ignore right now because these both do the same thing, save and continue.
Now I should have some services listed here that are all inactive and I have all three of them now.
This one works and I can turn it on and we'll actually work.
But this one doesn't currently do anything and we do have some things we want to add there.
So let's look at one other change we're going to have to make right now when I have three services.
If I say active, that's saved it and I go over to the pending table.
You'll see that it lists all of the ones, even if they're not active and that's not right, so we could
modify the query that only will pull out the active services, but then we'd have to modify the query
again to list all of the services here.
So all I'm going to do is I'm going to go back to my idee and I will find the host page, which is post
jet or hosted chat, and I'll just modify the way that I'm displaying the information in all of those
tabs.
So I'll scroll up to.
Healthy is the first one I'm just going to modify this if status equals healthy and.
Active equals one, and I'll just copy that, so that way we'll loop through all the services for the
only show me the ones that are active on those appropriate tabs and the same thing here.
Paiste and the same thing for problem.
Paced and finally for pending.
Paiste, So if I have no typographical errors, I should be able to come back here, reload this page,
look at the pending tab and only see my one active service.
OK, so back under managed services, all three are there.
All right, so that gets us going.
We now have a means of getting all the necessary services associated with any host that we add in.
The next lecture will actually start monitoring HTTPS services in our case because we're running a local
the local host that doesn't have an SSL certificate.
It will always return an error.
But that's OK.
We just want to make sure we can monitor more than one service.