So now we want to set up the actual monitoring for HTP services, but before we do that, I did have
a typo in the last lecture and this is in the host jet file when I was copy and pasting this little
bit right here and active equals one, I accidentally put that inside the quotation marks.
So this belongs over here.
So fix that and you may have noticed that and fixed it anyway.
But we all make typographical errors.
So let's go over to our perform checks dot go file.
And the part we're looking at, of course, is this test service for hosts.
And we have this switch statement which checks for the case of HTP and obviously we want another case.
So I can just copy this and paste it right here and make this https, which is a constant.
And as you know, that concept is set to do so.
This is calling a method, a test htp for host.
And obviously we want to put an S in there and then actually go and create this method.
So I'll go down to test HTP for host and this is really easy and simply copy this method because it's
virtually the same.
I could modify this method to handle both cases, but I'll just keep it simple.
Rename it to test http s for host and there's very little else to change here.
Basically I need to change this part where I'm looking for HTP s and changing it to HTP and move the
S, so that was easy.
And then down here.
Is there anything else to change.
No.
That should literally do it.
So I think at this point all we have to do is stop our application, start our application.
And go back to our Web browser and try going to the overview page, see what it looks like right now.
We have one healthy service and we're only monitoring one service.
So let's go to localhost and go to managed services and turn on HTP s.
And that should, with no change, no other changes in the code, appear under the pending tab.
And it does.
And I'll actually just check click check now because I don't want to wait the default three minutes
for that service and we should get an error and there it is.
So if we go to error problems.
Everything works as expected.
OK, that was the easy one, the next one, and we'll do this in the next lecture or two, is to monitor
SSL certificates.
And what I want to check there is a very simple thing.
How many days are left until our SSL certificate expires?
And if it's less than some predefined number, give a warning if it's less than some smaller number
than give a problem and we'll we'll take care of that in the next lecture or two.