So far, we have two host services were actually performing checks on, one is HTP, the unencrypted
Web server connection, and the other one is the encrypted Web server connection.
And we want to add a third case.
So I'll do the same thing I did last time and we'll get started here.
I will copy and paste that changed that to SSL certificate, which is a constant with the idea of three,
which matches the appropriate entry in the services table in the database.
And I don't want to test TDB for host.
I want to test SSL for host, which doesn't exist yet, but that's no problem.
We'll go created.
So I'll copy the name.
Go down here and I'll put it just after the one we made a few minutes ago.
Func paste the name.
It takes one one parameter URL which is a string and it returns a string kind of string.
OK, so we've got that created.
It's not returning anything right now, so we still have an error.
But this begs the question, how precisely does one test an SSL certificate from go?
Well, it turns out this is a problem I ran into a few years ago, and I'm going to show you a GitHub
repository.
And the link to this repository is right in the course resources for this lecture.
This is a plug in.
I wrote free server monitoring system called Nagios or possibly Nagios.
I'm not sure how to pronounce it and I don't use that system anymore.
But at the time, Nagios didn't support checking HTTP to Connexions or SSL certificates, at least not
that I could find.
So I wrote my own little plugin for it and I wrote it and go.
And as you can see, it's been a few years since this was worked on it all.
The last time I did was added a check for individual pages and this does more than test SSL certificates,
but let's see how it works.
So I'm going to copy the GitHub link and I'll go to my terminal window, make sure I'm on my desktop.
I am, and I'll clone that.
And it's been a while since I've looked at this, so I'm not actually sure how it works, but I'll change
into its directory.
Now, let's go look at the reedman I left for myself.
So here's how you build it.
So I'll copy this.
And paste that in here, and that should build it, there's my executable and how does one execute it?
So you specify the binary name, the hostname and dash cert, so I should be able to go check HDB to
host, which I'll just check Google dot com.
And I just want the certificate details.
And this should give me something back in the format that Nagios expects to find it and I can't remember
what that is, but we're about to find out.
OK, Google dot com Port 443 expiring in sixty two days, so that looks like it will do exactly what
I want.
Now let's see how the code works.
OK, so it looks like I have a main go file.
Of course.
Let's look at that.
So there are the imports.
There's a function scan host that does something that looks like that's what I'm going to have to use.
But we'll check in a minute.
We get some flags, we pass them.
We do some validation.
And here, scanning an SSL certificate for expiry date, and that uses the certificate utils, so we
probably need that.
Let's go back to the top and see what's in certificate utils.
So there's a test file and there's a go file.
OK, I'm just going to copy all of this, select all copy and go back to my EDEK because I know I need
that package and I'll just put it in as a package.
So under my internal I'll create a new directory, which I will call certificate utils.
And inside of that, I'll put a new go file called Certificate utils Dongo.
And I will select all and paste over top of this and see if it gives me any errors.
No, looks good.
OK, so I have that important.
Let's go back to perform checks, stock, go and see exactly what I do when I scan a an SSL certificate.
So I go back to the mango.
And get down to that statement.
There it is.
OK, so it looks like I need to scan for an expiry date, I'll copy all of this stuff and I'll copy
this call to scan host to and I'll paste that in there.
OK, and we don't have a host pointer that must be the euro, but what format that you will need to
be in?
Let's find out.
So we're getting a euro.
And we need it without the HDP or HDP.
OK, so we need to just as we did up here, we need to get rid of let me get rid of that long line.
We need to sanitize the Eurail coming in.
We need to strip off the prefix.
So if string's has prefix you IRL and I'm looking for HDP Collins.
Then I want to change your URL to be equal to string's don't replace and I'm going to replace you url
HGP Colon's with nothing everywhere and then I'll copy this.
And paste it because you are all might have been entered as HTP.
All right, that should sanitize the part where we're actually getting the euro.
Now, before I call scan host, I need to put some information in here.
Let me create my message and new status variables, both of which are type string.
OK, now let's go back and see what that scan House looks like.
So scan host.
Where's that?
That is right on line 19.
So let's go go look at that.
Copy this whole function.
And I'll paste it right before the function I'm writing right now, OK?
Any other changes there?
No.
We'll go back and look at the actual code and see what all this does in a little bit.
But first of all, let me get something in there so we have something to work with.
So after we scan the host down here.
We have this big four statement, I don't care about the Irish channel, so ignore that.
We scan the host and let's just paste that in.
OK, so scan host takes are you Earl?
It takes the certificate details channel, which we created up here, and it takes the errors channel,
which we're ignoring.
OK, and I could probably get rid of that, but I'll leave it there for right now.
Then we go through all of the entries in that channel.
And it has a length of a maximum of one thing at a time, so we'll never, never do more than one certificate
at a time.
Perfect.
OK, so after we do that, we check to see does it expire soon?
If it does, I'm not going to create the variable message.
I'm going to assign this to it.
And that will give me my message.
We don't care about the errors channel and we don't care about the messages thing because that's very
specific to Nagios in the second case.
We want to do this, so in this case, a certificate is expiring in less than seven days.
Let's set our status right here.
Our new status will be equal to problem, because if your certificates expire in less than seven days,
then that's a bit of a problem.
Let's go back and look at the original again.
Critical and warning, perfect.
OK, so this one would be new status.
Equals warning.
And the last thing would be status, what was the status, their status, OK, so new status.
Try that again.
New status.
Equals healthy.
OK, and message, we don't want to create a new variable, we want to change it to that one.
So this should build all of our messages appropriately, which means we just need to return things.
And what order do we return them in?
Message and status, so we'll just return.
Message and new status.
Now, in theory.
That should work.
Now, let's go back at Certificate Utils, because I wrote this a while ago.
Let's see what it's importing because there were changes and go 16, go one point one six IOU till.
OK, let's see where we're using that.
I owe util right here, OK, that needs to be changed to Ossy read file.
I'll just do it this way so my imports get fixed automatically.
OK, that's just the change for go on 16, the IOU till package has been deprecated.
So we'll use the OS package, which is what you're supposed to use from now on.
OK, let's give this a try and see how it works.
So I'll clear this run.
And we'll go back and add a new host.
So let's go to Vigilante.
Let's look at our hosts.
We have one.
Wahad had a new host and let's use GitHub.
And P.S. now it's just GitHub, dotcom hub, dotcom http s Coingate, GitHub, dot com.
Don't know its IP address, don't know anything else.
So I'll just leave all that empty save and continue and look at managed services and let's turn all
three on because I don't think we have actually checked remote hosts at all.
So if everything went well there should be three entries under pending and there aren't.
So let's check HTP because we've never done it with anything other than a localhost.
So let's make sure that it works.
OK, that's good, let's try.
OK, that worked.
Now let's try our SSL certificate and see what we get back GitHub dotcom expiring in four hundred and
twenty five days and that should show up under healthy.
And it does so there.
Now we have a means of checking SSL certificates.
Now there's a few things you'd want to change before you actually run this in production.
For example, testing in SSL certificate every three minutes seems kind of pointless.
So you probably want to change that to once every 30 days or something like that.
It's not hurting anything, checking it every three minutes, but it's unnecessary network traffic.
But otherwise this seems to be working fairly well.
So now we have a means of adding as many hosts as we want to our system, and we have a means of actually
displaying the status of three services for any number of hosts.
And I think we've done fairly well and we're pushing things through Web sockets exactly as we should.
There's a few other things we could add, none of which are critical because you've already learned
the concepts, for example, the events page.
This is not updated in real time and there's a few other cosmetic things.
But by and large, we have covered everything I want to cover in this section of the course.
So next we'll go on to testing.
How does one write tests for Web sockets?
And I'll also do a test for one or two handlers as well.
Just to give you a bit of a refresher for that, if it's been a while since you've written them.
All right.
We'll move on in the next section.