All right.
So now we're down to hands on exercises and this is Ninja level to Ninja level to number two.
There we go.
Ninja Level 2 and I'm super excited for these hands on exercises.
It is 4 0 7 on Friday we've got four hands on exercises for you here and I think they're going to be
really cool and really fun.
And our goal is to get through these forehands on exercises introducing them to you and then also showing
you the solution to them before 5 o'clock because that's when like you know we're done.
So we've been here doing this for quite a bit today.
Yeah.
Been a good time and there's been a lot of intricate detail in the module stuff but now I think in using
it you're going to find that you're very conversant with it and that it's actually not you know the
theory there's a lot theory there but in practice it's pretty simple.
So for this first hands up Yeah I mean you want to add just motivational inspirational do good to others
be kind have good integrity and then for this hands on exercise we want you to create a go module import
Ah I see I quote use glass from our C I O forward slash quote run your program look at your go module
what version of RL CIO quote are you using.
Do you have any indirect dependencies and then list out all your dependencies to see if you have any
indirect ones I put the command there for you and then just look at your go some.
So pauses video go do that hands on exercise when you're all done.
Now y'all come on back on pause the video and we'll show you our solution which we're gonna do right
now.
Do you want to do it or do you want me to do it.
I think you better do.
Given I just lost connection again Oh you lost connection again.
OK so for this one my first thought would be to like I need to be in some other space and I don't need
this to be on github.
I'm just kind of thinking through my process so I don't need to create a repo because I'm just going
to get rid of this at the same time I don't want to do it in this folder right here.
That always kind of freaks me out when I bring this is our screen recording software I'm like whoa.
Inception reality within reality.
I don't want to do it in here.
Where do you have go module so I'm just gonna go to you know my terminal and go back to my home folder
and then just make it door and call it temp exercise 0 1 and and then I'm going to open up that so I
could do code dot and it opened up that your Holder opened up my home folder don't allow don't allow.
I think that's going to keep coming back up in a close that I want to switch into my directory so seedy
into I get excited and I go too fast and forget steps and now I'm going to do code dot and that's going
to open up my my editor and I'm switching from a go land which I loved but at our school people are
moving to the free option so here I go to B.S. codes and still learn B.S. code and so inside here I'm
going to create a folder and click on that and they'll just be.
Actually I don't need a folder I could just do my code right here and I need main go.
And this is package Main and func main and I want to use for this I want to use from our CIO quote use
glass and so I need to go find our CIO quote and here's the import some import that's going to grab
that and drop this and as an import and save this and when it saved it just went away.
So I'm not using anything from there.
And I also need my go module file.
So in this route I'm in that route right there from my thing I'm going to go mod a net and then I need
some sort of namespace.
And since this is just a throw away my namespace is going to be Mickey Mouse for it slash Donald Duck
forward slash
he could just do this to Daphne.
There you go.
And so that's my new go modules in that namespace.
And and now I'm going to import that package and not save it.
And from quote I'm gonna use glass and I just want to print that front up front line.
Quote glass and then I'm gonna save it and it brought all that in and I'm gonna run it go round and
go and I can eat glass and it doesn't hurt me.
That's not true.
I don't it would hurt me and I don't eat it but it is a funny function in that quote in that package.
And so now if I look at my go mod I could see that I'm requiring version one point five point two are
a C I O quote If I look at my go sum I could kind of come in here and see.
I could see those hashes not I kind of but I can't for reals for reals.
I could see those different hashes in there and if I want to look at my indirect dependencies as well
as my direct dependencies go list dash em all and I could see both my indirect and direct dependency
so there's my direct dependency.
Here's indirect dependency and here's an indirect dependency.
And then here is my namespace.
That's the word that comes to me would use that word.
Then I'd go module and module name for that thing.
So that's hands on exercise no one would see if I got it all run your program look it go mod you have
any indirect dependencies.
Yes.
And look it goes on so as my solution for hands on exercise number one.