Here for hands on Exercise number two.
We want you to working with the same code the built in hands on exercise number one.
So let me add that in there working with the same code that you've built and hands on exercise number
one.
Go get version 3 1.0 of our C dot I O four tax code does your code still run what is the folder structure
of that version on GitHub run these commands just to look it up and so pause this video go do this hands
on exercise positive you're going to do it when you're all done now y'all come on back on pause video
and we'll show you our solution which we're gonna do right now and since it's on my computer I guess
I'll be the one typing.
So we want to go get version 3 of our C I quote so I could open this up and I could take a look at what's
there it brings me here package quote I'm looking through it I don't see anything about versions here
I know I'm going to click this and go to get what's it called get yeah I'm got to get and and then.
But is there any way in here that I'd be able to see versions only if they added a sort of read me down
here or something right.
Yeah I don't think go down it doesn't really support it Yeah I don't think so I'm going to open up get
an inside get I can go down to releases and it releases I have these different versions so here's one
point five two which is what I have been using and I could see that right here one point five two and
so we look at one point five to browse those files and if I look at I came in here because I wanted
to look at I wanted to look at the folder structure so it's just here's what the folder structure looks
and one point five two and if I go back to releases and I look at version three and then Woops I gotta
click the little cache thing there click on that Click browse files here's what the folder structure
looks like we're now in folder V.
All right so version three as go mad go some and quote go.
And here at this root we have go mod quote go quote Tesco.
That's kind of interesting because we talked about adding the forward slash v three which if I want
to bring in a certain version so I'm going to go get a C I O for it slash quote forward slash v three
fact correct.
I get all that right.
I'm going to go get that.
And now if I go look at my go mod my good go mod now says Here is our CIO quote version 3 and I also
have this one there.
So I've got version 3 and that one.
And if I want to use that and we're going to come back to this folder structure discussion here in one
second but like this before we're like oh that's not necessary tab B correspond to folder and get hub
so we're gonna discuss that in a second.
But now I just want to change how I use this.
So I'm going to import version 3 so I'm going to do a forward slash there and do a v 3 and and then
quote glass let me just save all that and version 3 quote glass it's giving me a glass and not declared
by package quote so I'm going to look at version 3 there and version 3.
Well you need to go to the folder class.
I can eat glass and it doesn't hurt me because it's looking in there for version 3 the folder Mallow
concurrency glass V Three is the name but there we go.
Class V Three Class V Three.
And then I'm going to save that and then when I run it go run me and go all still runs and if I do my
go list dash M All I could see I have version 3 and version one of quote and if I do my go tidy doing
it lets the command go tidy go go my tidy.
There you go but you might go mod tidy and then list that all again I got rid of version one point five
two so cleaned it up because I'm using his version three now.
So now let's talk about that folder.
So it's actually compatibility backwards compatibility so that's why they did it this way here.
Yeah.
So version go version 1 9 7 1 10 3 and go and then go 1 11 with modules on is all are all capable of
detecting a following the slash v 3 and knowing this means the rid of the base repo as opposed to a
folder but if you're running go 1 9 6 and before or go 1 tend to end before it didn't know that.
And so since they have since go always tries to keep two versions up to date working when they first
added in Go Models and go 111 they had to make sure go 1 10 was still capable of running most of the
code so they added in.
So this these 3 folder was kind of a compatibility hook almost so that if you're using go 1 10 without
modules it's able to know our CIO slash quote slash v 3 means in that folder so that the import path
actually map to a folder path on get.
Yep but it's not required though because with go modules it's able to figure that out either way.
So given that modules is now fully working on all versions of go that are currently supported that's
not really required.
So best practice in the future is if you have major versions don't drop it meant to be three V for v
five because in your is going to have all the code sitting next to new code that's going to confuse
you the recommended way is actually to go for a whole branch just to create like a V to branch or something
that way you still have your v 1 code around and you can push like bug fix updates back to that old
stuff if you want to but then you're working on your new V V to branch with your new stuff so that branch
with that branch you've got M..
Right.
And this is version one.
And then we say oh version two Here's version to branch.
Right.
Yep.
And then do we eventually bring version two back in.
No.
So Virgin 2 just runs for it and we no longer even look at Master if you if you make it you got like
a bug fix or version for Master.
Someone's using master for whatever it is someone's still using version one they find some like security
for.
You decide to go patch it it's on a separate it's on master branch it you can make that bug fix separate
from your version to branch and so anyone who's still using version one can still get security updates
so master branch was version one doing branch off to version 2 and and then everything is running on
Version 2 but if we need to update the old version one we can.
Yeah.
And and in that so that would.
This has the same code as this when they first start out and we do that date here but then also merge
it back to master.
We would not merge version two back to back.
But just that one comment with the O if you want to fix oh if you if you want in Version 2.
In that case you probably Version 2 would presumably have a lot of code differences so it may not be
the same patch for why Virgin 2 may have different code so it may or may not necessarily be the same.
I thought the Master is always master so there's other ways of doing it.
The other option is instead of creating a version to branch you create a version one brand.
I like that.
I mean that's not going to make a lot more sense to my head already either one year like that was just
off to the side and everything still coming back to master which is now version 2.
Yeah OK I like that right.
So so enjoy it.
So yeah a major.
So the go going modules entry in the in the get hub we keep her going go says basically a major branch
for you have a branch for every major version or major sub directory so a folder like they've got there
just kind of in general so you can still update your old major versions if you find the need to.
All right.
So we'll put a link to this here and that is major branch update that go Monfils included v three at
the end of.
Yes so that's that's all the same stuff yeah.
Oh cool.
All right.
A little bit more about branches.
That's our solution for hands on exercise number two.