Here's hands on Exercise number three and sorry about that noise in the background.
You can hear that we're running short on time but we want to get these done for hands on Exercise number
three from version three point one I know of our CIA quote use the function glass from Version 2.0 1.0
of our CIO quote use the function.
OK and so this hands on exercises just so that you can practice using functions from different major
branches or different major versions.
So go ahead and pause this video.
Go do this hands on exercise when you're all done.
Come on back now y'all and we'll show you our solution.
We're going to do right now.
So in the previous.
Hands on exercise we were already using version o three point one point zero.
And so I've got that three right here and I'm using glass three and now I need to do a version two point
one point oh and there is a command up here where we can list all of the versions of package and I'm
just looking for that command in our list yet.
I don't think that's to our short list it was but we'll find it here in just one second.
It was something like go list dash and dash version.
It's in the module.
Erica remember it was on it.
No
and this is a package name.
Yeah
check it out.
OK.
So we just found that code it's go list dash M versions and then the package name so I'm going to use
that code here.
Go list dash versions.
Let's have flag.
Yes versions and then the package name which is or C I O quote.
And so here are the versions of those packages and the ones that I need for this hands on exercise are
two point one zero.
So I've got version 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 0 because I can also do forward slash v 2 and I could also do need
to be lowercase city and pretty sure I could also do v 2 and I can also do the three.
So there are versions and I would need to point 0 point 1 so I'm going to come back to my code and add
my import and I'll be Version 2 and 0.
Better yet gonna go get go get control C.
Go get R A C dot dot I O Ford slash quote forward slash V to at B to dot was a e to dot 1.0.
Is that right.
No.
I think it's 2 to 1 but it's also the latest version c do we even need to add sine because it's also
it's also the latest version for me to read too.
Oh all right I got that next step right here
2 0 1.
Sorry if that caused you confusion on years hopefully you figured it out and I'm going to try with that
because that should be the same as later.
Yep.
And so now if I go look at my mod I should have 2 0 1.
Yes.
And there's my import.
And so I could grab that and just add this import in here.
Or it just easier to duplicate this line go.
And now I'm ready to duplicate this line and I need to use from quote and I need an alias.
This quote V2 alias that and this will be quote V2 since they have the same package name and the function
that I'm going to use is what popped up village to
go now to run it and see what happens and my still on a temp exercise 0 1 yet.
Now let's go run main and the program is too slow.
Must have a loop and then I'm going to go list dash them all and then go to I.T. just go mod tidy and
I don't think that's going to change anything.
2 3 1 2 3 1 yet saw the same.
All right.
So that's our solution for this.
Hands on exercise the next hands on exercise is gonna be awesome.