All right.
For this next hands on exercise you're gonna create one repo.
Create a package add it go modules to it and then create another repo and get and or doesn't need to
be on.
Get the second one doesn't need second one doesn't need to be but the first one does go get it and then
your second one is you're going to use the package you created in the first one.
And so you know create create and create a new create a new go module new project with a go module new
project with a go module.
This can be on your computer or on.
Also if you want so if you want it on github there it is and you're going to add your go module.
That's obvious and then the first one from your get hub report number one quotes.
Use the function faves.
Let's just not do it on get out.
That's gonna be too much.
A great new project.
This is does not need to be on
this community computer and does not need to be on github.
Use function faves string and add I get tagged version 1 0 run your code and we're going to take this
out and we aren't going to have a tag.
Well well it doesn't matter right.
Yeah yeah.
Guess we're seeing that in the previous one.
All right.
So there's your hands on exercise clauses video to do that.
Hands on exercise when you're all done.
Come on back and you'll see our solution.
I'm gonna pass this laptop to Daniel.
We've got like seven minutes to do it.
I think we can do it.
Can we hold yours.
Let's do the laptop swap because his is a I don't know what's going on that but I think it's having
it mostly just issues with the Google Drive.
It's it's got everything else seems to be working.
The hardest thing about this is going to be you're now on Mac.
You're gonna be like Where are the keys for the most part.
Yeah.
So I'll do it man.
It's my get hub and everything.
Yeah maybe I'll pass it to you for your second one.
All right.
So I'm going to create and you get every post so I'm gonna go to get hub and create a new Reaper and
this report is gonna be called what's it called the repository.
And it's going to be called quote and create repository and then I'm going to clone this with S AS H.
So copy all that and come back here and I'm gonna CB and then get clone there and so cloned and then
l SLA and C.D. and quotes and LSD stash L.A. and I get mod and net and then I'm going to need my Go
Go modern that I'm going to need my.
Let's close the door.
The other doors open and go modern.
And I'm gonna need.
Get hub dot com forward slash goes to eleven goes to eleven I'm not got Wow pair programming is awesome
and and then I'm going to add in this one is called quotes.
So that looks good.
So now I do my all SLA and I've got that there and I'm gonna open this so I can close this one.
I got this one and here I'm gonna do code and I open that and I'm going to create a new file and this
is going to be I guess this could be called anything and and then I'm gonna have a package quotes in
here and I'm gonna have a funk and it's gonna be called favorites.
Is that the name of a famous faves.
And I wanted to be exported right.
Yeah.
So it needs to be that it can return a slice of string otherwise it won't be available to people.
If it was an export it's I need to update our assignment to have faves exported and faves.
And now I'm going to create a slice.
So I'm going to have my slice of quotes will be equal to and I'll use a composite literal strings.
And then I'm gonna put some quotes in here and I'm just gonna go find some quotes.
So Rumi quotes Rumi as a poet.
Here are a couple of Rumi quotes.
They look pretty good.
And I'm gonna grab those and I want to quickly sort of karma quotes and commas.
Oh we're running out of time okay.
So this is gotta be fast.
And so I'm going to do that and I need to quickly add.
Well I've posted multiple cursor selection so we'll go to keyboard.
Where's my help.
Interactive keyboard shortcut reference and multiple cursor and multiple cursor is insert cursor is
was that option click.
I don't know the Mac symbols first option option click
on Big Baby come on baby
I'll put quotes and then we'll go down here and we'll get rid of that and we'll put quotes here and
here and here and here and here and here and here and you're here let's be quotes comma and and then
I just think we need something over this and I'll be a quote comma and so that should be OK.
And now I'm going to return that
and so I'm returning my slice of strings and it's giving me a don't don't return the variable access.
I'll just return the whole thing.
Thank you Erica.
All right.
So that's quotes and this is a little bit of a bigger hands on project.
So the first one I got.
This created GitHub repo your repo added go module add a function add to get tag version want that that
minor version 1 so I'm gonna do get tagged so you must have a permit to tag.
OK so get add Shay get commit ads fave quotes and not get tag and it's going to be version quotes around
tag doesn't not required zero dot one zero.
Right.
And then get push and we're gonna come look at this repo and let's see if it's up there.
And so far so good.
And releases
Oh man was my internet.
Yeah I just lost everything all Internet myself.
Come on.
There aren't any releases here because you do not push the tech.
Oh Kit push dash hashtags right.
Yes.
There we go good reminder
now we've got a release.
And so now I'm going to use this right there.
Copy that and I'm gonna go create yet one more directory and I already have one which is print working
directory.
I'm here.
I'm gonna come up a level and less and I'm gonna see into what is the one I just did before this temp
exercise when Tip exercise 1.
Thank you.
And and then I'm gonna open that one so we'll close this one.
How much time we got two minutes.
One minute.
We got one minute and it's too much pressure starting.
All right.
Now we have all the time in the world.
But that is kind of fun having the pressure.
So now we're going to code dot dot and open that up.
And in here I can change all of this.
I want to use my code and so I'm going to import that from
here and then I'm going with HP yes.
Thank you.
I'm gonna use quotes uh for index value call an equal range.
Quotes
dot faves and I'm gonna find out print line and we'll do print index and the value of the quote to your
area there is beats function faves.
There you go and you must put quotes
and I think that all looks good.
We look at our go mine.
I've got that one.
If I do my go my tiny that's now being cleaned up.
And I'm going to do.
Go on me and go
do that.
Let's see if we got anything else.
We need to do it use the uh the correct version to if you look at the Go mod and go some.
You can see the go mine that is actually using the 0 the version number is correct.
With these 0 1 0.
That's super cool and
just curious as you could see that.
All right.
That's hands on Exercise number four.
I hope you enjoyed it.
I totally enjoyed it.