That's a really powerful skill that we just acquired like understanding dependency management package
management having package management.
That's not going to go ghost on you.
Right.
Like with NPM.
You were like I don't know that code used to be there.
The guy turned off his computer it's gone.
And like half of the universe stops working for an hour.
Because they have the module Mir which is a proxy and that proxy is storing everything and by the way
if you don't want stuff stored there you've got to go private variable which you could set for modules
that you create and then use go modules instead of your go path the old way the workspace then package
source folder right in the name spacing under source.
We learned about name spacing you now use modules instead of that and with modules anywhere on your
computer you just say hey this is a module and you set the namespace.
You set the namespace so that namespace is whatever you want it to be.
I use that goofy you to Mickey Mouse Donald Duck and Daphne or whatever it was or you know it's best
to connect it was something on the web so that we're if you want other people to access your code so
that when your code is up there you know it's stored or just so that you know where it's stored.
If it's private write your modules connected at this storage location so domain and then whatever else.
And so we learn that and we also learn how to create a module that could be access and used by you or
anybody and and connecting that to get hub and then pushing it up there and adding a version so that
you can now increment your versions and we learned about versioning major minor in Patch.
And so how you add those numbers and where and when you would major breaks backwards compatibility minor
does not you know it's backwards compatible and patches backwards compatible.
What else do we learn in that some some good stuff how to eat how to upgrade from you can have multiple
versions of a packet of a module at the same time so incremental upgrades
and what else.
Anything else.
In the end all the various tag the tag stuff text that's the useful even if you're not intending it
to be used by others just as kind of a this is a you would tag a version that you consider working so
you may have like three commits before you put it another tag because your code was not fully functional
during those other two minutes in the middle and then the third version.
Third mate Nico it's all functional out attack.
There is now version one point two.
All right Suzanne good stuff.
I hope you enjoyed that and we're gonna sit back and reflect over the weekend on what to teach you next.
I know that curl is something that is potentially on our horizon as well as some of the items down here
context package continuous integration build pipeline.
I don't know if that's going to fit into this.
What we're doing.
You know just a note there to talk about documentation and that's not so much going to fit in but interfaces
and middleware and testing and benchmarking and then also creating some sort of monolithic application
but this entire process up to this point has kind of surprised me it took longer than I thought.
So this might end up being a course in and of itself pretty close just like some damn fundamental skills
and we might do the monolith course in another one because in the past my courses have all been really
long and so I'm trying to break those up into the six to eight hour range so we'll edit this all up
and we'll see where we are at.
And and then we might have a second course instead of making this one monolithic course after that.
All right.
You have anything you want to say or add before we 442 we did pretty good we got 18 minutes left before
we head out for the weekend.
Anything else you want to add any personal anecdotes.
So it's just personal anecdotes from this point for now.
No.
Let me see if I have any personal anecdotes so I was thinking of.
I had one idea for software in the middle of night last night and in business there is this thing called
the Hawthorne effect I think that's what it's called Hawthorne effect Yeah.
Ricky and they study type of reactive in which individuals modify an aspect to their behavior in response
to the awareness that being observed and so they study back in the day people on the factory floor it
scientists come in academics and they said we're gonna study how you all are working and how the level
light in the factory affects your performance.
And so they turned up the light they made it really bright and productivity went up and they said that's
interesting.
And then they turned down the light and they made it darker than it was normally.
And productivity went up even higher and they're confused.
And then what they realized was the light had nothing to do with it.
Well they're as bright or dim.
And what mattered was whether or not the individuals were being observed.
And so with the Hawthorne effect and also with this idea of reflection.
So if we reflect upon who we are and what we're doing at work I had an idea for like some software that
would allow employees to sort of like get hub log what they do every day.
And so that would track there'd be a system that would track kind of like before you went to lunch.
Here's what I did from 8:00 to noon.
And then after you came back you know before he left for the day.
Here's what I did from 1 to 5 met and made these contacts I have these leads here are the phone numbers
the emails had a conversation with this person to a log all of your activity.
So it's basically like get hub but for people who are in sales or people who are you know I don't know
what else is there engineering and sales
you know whatever your position is you'd be logging your activity for the day and then you could run
a email against all of that to try to find efficiencies.
And also most importantly I could try to bring cohesion to the organization.
So the organization would know what it knows more effectively know what it knows.
And because you'd see who's doing what.
But then also people would feel like whatever they're doing there they're not having a quarterly evaluation
and not having an annual or every in academia I get evaluated every three years that's it.
Right.
It's like every four hours somebody might be looking their people up above in the machine learning to
be looking at what they've done over the last four hours.
And so with that sense of OK I got to be on point.
It could lead to increased productivity might just make everybody stressed out at work.
You know the guy who's studied efficiency see I'm actually going to google that.
The big guy who's studied efficiency
Frank Buck is crazy idea that Google would bring that up.
Frank Buck American author and pioneer time motion study right father and central figure I don't know
what Cheaper By The Dozen is but he was an efficiency expert.
I wonder if there's the shovel story in here.
So time efficient see shovels story.
Let's see.
Frederick Winslow Taylor.
That's it.
So wasn't this guy is Frederick Winslow Taylor.
So this guy Frederick Winslow Taylor studied how can people be more efficient.
And he would time them with a stopwatch and he just stressed everybody out and and and so he did this
with all of his kids and and and I think this is true.
Kids suicide.
All these kids killed themselves.
They're like this is too intense.
There were a decade after that.
I don't.
So that might just be that might be what do they call those cultural myths.
We're really onto a personal anecdote.
What do they call those cultural myths there.
There is a movie you probably know.
What is it cultural Miss.
I don't know.
So anyhow maybe it's just one of those cultural myths and it's not actually true.
All right.
A little bit of a personal anecdote and just some interesting information about efficiency but that
was the idea that came to me last night for some software could be interesting might be a light bill.
See you in the next video.