So in this section of the course, what we're going to build is a very simple chat application built
using go is the back end and WebSocket to to actually send the messages back and forth.
So on the left hand side of the screen, you can see there is no user currently logged in.
And there's one person online, Bernie and Bernie is over here on the right hand side.
But if Fred joins you, notice how it automatically populated Fred down here and it pushed it over here.
And that's done using Web sockets.
And the Web sockets package we're going to use is guerrilla web sockets.
And it's a very easy one to use.
So this is a very simple way to get our feet wet with WebSocket.
Now, this is not a fully functional Web application.
There is, for example, no database behind the users and so forth, and there's no login page, and
that's OK.
The second project, what we're doing in this course is a fully functional Web application with all
the nuts and bolts and all the pieces we need to to actually do something a little more sophisticated
than a simple chat.
But this is a perfect way of getting our feet wet.
So if I send a message from Fred to Bernie, hello, Bernie.
It appears and if I change the name here from Fred to Frederick, it changes it down here and it instantly
pushes it over here.
And this shows you just how fast and interactive you can make your Web applications by using Web sockets.
So let's get started.