So let's get around to actually sending messages, so when someone has a username in here and they have
typed in a message, it should appear here prepend ID with their username and everyone should see that.
And this is not terribly difficult.
So the first thing I want to do is when someone types a message and presses enter or return, that should
work.
But I probably should put a button here, too.
So let's go do that right now.
I'll go back to my home jet or find the places where I'm entering them.
And right here I will put in an hour and then I'll put in a trough equals JavaScript void just so nothing
happens.
But if I don't have something in the tag, this part class equals button button outline secondary button
outlines secondary.
I think that's how it goes.
Gundry
send message and I'll give this an ID.
If I didn't have the RF tag then this part would not work properly.
So we'll give this idea of send button.
OK, so I created that send button and down here in my JavaScript I need to create a function and I
know it doesn't, doesn't need to be my ADD event listeners, so I'll put it down below that and my
function will be called send message function, send message.
All right.
So what do I want.
Send a message to do.
Well, let's create some JSON data.
We know we're sending this through our sockets, so it has to be sent in the form of Jado of Jason data,
Jason.
And we'll give it some action, Jason.
Jason, data action and I'm going to call this one broadcast because it's something kind of broadcast
to all users broadcast and I need to give a username so I'll know who the message is from Jason Data.
Username is equal to document
get element by ID and the ID is username and I want the value from that and like using my username and
the message will be, I'll just duplicate this line to make it a little easier.
The data message will be document element, get element by ID, message value.
OK, and we're going to put a check in here to make sure that both of these have been populated before
we try to send the message, but we're not going to do it in this function.
And finally, we'll say socket dot send.
Jason Stringfellow, Jason Data, and that will send their data and now we want to reset this message
thing to empty so they don't have to delete it themselves.
So we'll just copy this part.
And pasted in there.
And say equals nothing.
So that's our message function.
Now, I want to be able to have this person click the button, which we defined right here to send it.
OK, so I can just I could just put the JavaScript there, but I'm going to do a listener instead.
And I also want people just to be able to hit enter because a lot of people that touch type don't like
taking their hand off the keypad or where they are on the keyboard in order to hit the return key or
to scroll down and click on the button.
That's it.
So we're going to have two ways of sending this.
So let's handle the first case right now, let's say when someone is actually going to press the return
key.
So back in my document at event listener, at the very bottom of it, I'm going to put another listener
in there and I'll say document get element by ID message, which is the place where you type messages
at event listener and the event listener.
I'm going to use this key down.
So when someone presses the keys, this this listener will fire function event and if event dot code
equals exactly enter.
In other words, they have pressed the enter key then.
I will say, if not socket, in other words, if they're not connected, I'll just say console log,
no connection,
and we could do some other error handling in their display and alert, whatever it may be.
But for right now, I'm just going to say logged the log file and I'll return false so we don't go anywhere
else.
But if we get past that, then we want to say event prevent default.
Don't try to submit a form which some browsers might try to do.
And it's not going to hurt anything to stop this and eventually stop propagation again.
Same idea to handle every possible browser I can think of and finally send the message.
OK, so this part should we should be able to reload the page at least and not see any JavaScript errors.
Let's make sure we didn't get anything wrong.
I'll clear the screen, reload the page.
And the only error I have is there's no Fabi control.
Everything is great.
OK, so at least that part seems to work now.
We need to handle a situation where we actually get this part, get the send a message.
So let's see if make sure that that's actually going to fire Trevor test no JavaScript errors, but
it did clear it out.
Perfect.
So that's exactly what I wanted to do.
So now we need to go back to our handlers and we need to trap for the action broadcast.
So let's do that.
Let's go to our handlers.
Let's find the part where we're handling our actions right here and let's do a new one case broadcast.
And what do we want to do in the case broadcast?
Well, it's actually pretty simple.
All we really need to do is to, first of all, set up a response action.
And I'm going to make that broadcast again.
This is the one we're sending back to the clients and we want to response to that message equal to.
And what I'm going to do here is actually format a string pre pending the user's name.
So format s, print F and I'll put percent s actually I'll put Strohm percent s strong to build their
name and then another string and little put in there is a username that's the first placeholder.
So that'll be between the strong tags and E message which will be right here at the end.
And I just broadcast that broadcast to all response.
OK, so now we've handled the case where we get this broadcast at the server, but we also need to handle
the case where we get the broadcast message on the client and that is actually handled right here.
Right now we have one case list users, so let's give it another case, case broadcast.
And what do I want to do in here?
Well, if you recall, back up here, we have this ID output equals chat box.
So let's get a reference to this chat box.
That's where we're going to be putting the messages and I'll get it right here.
Let O equal document get limited by ID.
And it's called CheckBox was Checkbook's.
Where is it?
Output, not chatterbox.
OK, so that's where we're going to put our output, so now I have a reference to it so I can use it
anywhere I want in the application.
So down here under broadcast, what do I want to do?
All I want to do is append the HTML to whatever's in there already.
So odah html.
Equals Odon Interreg tml plus, and then I want to put something in here, so what I want to put in
here is dated message
and return and then break so that in theory should work.
Let's stop our application.
And let's go back to this window and hit return and go back to Crumm and hit return and logging in as
Wilma.
OK, so Wilma's logged in now.
We'll go back to Firefox and log in as Betty and we have Wilma and Betty and I will try sending a message.
This is a message from Betty.
Now, this button doesn't work because we haven't hooked it up yet, but this one does.
And I get a message showing up down here.
And hopefully when I go over to Chrome, I get a message here as well.
So now we can send messages.
That's pretty straightforward.
But I'd also like to put a couple of checks in.
I'd like to make sure that this and this are populated before you hit return here or before you click
the button here.
I want to make sure that error checking is in there, and that's pretty easy.
So let's go back to our JavaScript code on the home page and we have the function send message so we
could put a check in here, but we could also just come up here and put another listener in.
So we named that button send button.
So let's put a listener on send button.
So I'll do that inside my document ready, which is starts right here at that event.
Listener And it ends right here.
So right after this document and get it by idee Senba add event listener click function.
So first of all let's do some checks.
So I'm going to put other two other selectors up here just to save myself some typing.
So I'll put this one as user field and that's going to be a user name and I'll have another one message
field which will be message just to say some typing.
And down here I'm going to do some checks if and I'll have two conditions.
User field, dot value, not value.
So if either of those are empty, we'll just say alert, fill out user and message and you can put whatever
you want in there and we'll just say return false.
Let's just see if that works, because I think there might be a typo in there.
No, that was good.
OK, so that gives us one condition, Phillip, user and message otherwise else send a message.
OK, so that works quite well.
So we're putting a An event listener on the button.
But what about on send a message.
Well let's just see.
So send a message when we put the listener on this, we can just for right now copy this and find the.
Listener for.
Send message.
There it is, send button and that's message.
OK, and take this and put it down here, and that should work.
So let's try this, let's reload this and just try sending a message that didn't work and let's click
in here and send a message that didn't work as well.
Perfect.
So that gives us our basic chat functionality.
And it seems to me that this is relatively straightforward.
There's more JavaScript on the client side than there is go code because the gorilla websocket package
is so robust, but the JavaScript itself is not that complex.
So our chat functionality is actually starting to look pretty good.
We still have some a few things I want to do just to make sure it's a little more robust and we'll take
care of those in the next few lecture's.