Let's just take a few minutes to clean things up, because we have a little bit of messy JavaScript
code on our home page, so I'm going to go to the bottom here and see what I might do to clean things
up.
So you notice here I defined a user field on a message field variable to point to the elements username
and message.
But I think down here somewhere I have let's see, get element by ID.
There it is.
This one.
Well, instead of having user input here, I've already defined a reference to it up above.
So let's just say get rid of that and call it user field.
So that one's OK.
And the same thing here.
I don't need to do document get a little bit of B element body message.
I already have a message field so that's good.
And look here I have send message taking place here and then I have it taking place again here.
You probably noticed that.
Let's get rid of that.
And if I have any other ones there, send button username and message, that's fine.
Except here I don't need to do that.
I can just say user field and here I can say message field.
No sense in doing look, ups, if I've already got a reference to it, and that should be fine here,
except I can say message field.
All right, let's save that and stop our application and start our application and make sure everything
still works the way we expect it to.
And then we'll make a couple of other improvements.
So I'll reload this page by hitting return their log on as NENO works.
This is from Dino.
Send the message.
Good second message this time I'll press return to send it.
That worked well.
And back over here if I connect again and go on as Fred Weir is Dino and that should show up here and
it does.
OK, so that's a little cleaner.
Now there's a few other things I'd like to take care of.
One is I don't like this alert.
It really irritates me.
It just doesn't look good to me.
So instead, I want to use this package which I've used in other courses and I use all the time in production,
and it's called Nottie and it gives really nice alerts at the top of the page.
So let's get a copy of that from CD and Jazz and I'll look for Nottie.
And there it is.
So click on it and we will get the note he minge, yes, that's what I want.
So copy script tag, and I'll go put that script right at the beginning of my JavaScript here and format
a little better and I need to get also the success Nottie Minsk's.
Let's copy that link tag and put that at the top of our page in the head right about here.
And format that, OK, so now I have Nottie and let's see how it works, let's go back and look at the
documentation.
How do I actually use this?
Simplest of cases is right here.
So let's copy that one and we'll just make an alert down here.
We'll just create a new function
function error and it'll take a string, which I'll call MSJ.
And inside of that will do it.
No, the alert and we want a type is going to be an error.
So let's get rid of all this and put in error.
Text will be the message and everything else I can leave alone.
I'll just take the defaults for that.
So now we have an error message.
I'll call it error message.
OK, so we'll copy that.
And everywhere I have an alert.
Let's just go to the top and search for alert.
OK, now instead I'll say.
Error message, filla username.
And message.
OK, and look for the next alert.
We'll change that to their message, capitalize that and put a name at the end and an exclamation point,
why not?
And that's not the alert, OK, so that should actually be a little bit better.
Let's go back here, try reloading this page by hitting written up here and just try sending a message,
fill out username, a message that's much better, OK?
And it goes away less intrusive than the error alert that we saw before.
OK, so that was just a little clean up.
And the last couple of things I want to do for this chat project is we've never trap for a situation
where the server goes away and if the server goes away, maybe it's been rebooted.
Maybe you just lost an Internet connection for a few minutes or a few seconds.
But really, we have no way of indicating to the user that something has gone awry.
And we want to, first of all, let them know that they've lost their connection to the server.
And secondly, we want to reconnect as automatically and give them some indication that they've reconnected.
And we'll take care of that in the next lecture.