So one thing we haven't dealt with yet is the situation where, for whatever reason, our WebSocket
connection goes away and we have no way of notifying the user that there is an issue and no way of determining
by looking at this Web page, whether I'm online or not.
Right now, I'm on the server and I'm on as Fred and I can send messages.
Hello, is Bernie there?
And it works.
But what if for whatever reason, I go over to my application, which is running and I stop it and I
try to send in another message.
This is a test while nothing happens and I have no indication as a user that there's an issue.
Now I look at the JavaScript console and it says connection is closed, but it doesn't actually tell
me anything here.
More importantly, it would be extremely helpful if I could just reconnect automatically when the server
comes back.
It could just be temporary and network problems where I lost my connection to the server and it should
actually reconnect automatically.
Now, there are a lot of ways of doing this and a lot of JavaScript libraries we can import to use this.
There's a one here that I'm going to show you right now by Joel Wallies, which I'm probably mispronouncing
but forgive me, called Reconnecting WebSocket.
And it's quite old.
It hasn't been updated in years, but it is stable call code.
And I've used it many, many times without any difficulty whatsoever.
So let's get a copy of that, download it and put it onto our server.
So I'm going to download this as a zip file.
And I'll just save it.
And we'll go back to my desktop, find this file, extract it.
And inside, I have this reconnecting websocket mindgames, so I'm going to drag that to my desktop,
then I'm going to go to my go projects, find my W.S. folder.
And inside of this, we don't right now have a means of serving static files.
But I'm going to do that very shortly.
So I'll create a new folder called Statik and I will put that file I just downloaded and extracted in
there.
Then I'll go back to my source code, open my rights file, which is right here, and let's serve this
static content and it's really easy to do that in go.
I'll just create a new variable called file server and all assign that the value of PDF file server
with a directory of cars to dear.
From the level of my application, the folder called static, and I will put a trailing slash there
and the next line just tells us how to serve that muxtape get from static
HGP dot strip prefix.
And the prefix I want to strip is static and passive.
That file server I just created.
OK, so now inside my static folder, I should have this reconnecting websocket, which I'll add to
get and let's open our homecourt jet file and at the very bottom where we're importing our JavaScript,
let's import that file script that are spelled out right source equals slash static slash reconnecting
websocket mindgames and there it is.
So now we've imported it and we're not using it yet.
So how do we actually use it?
Let's go back and look at the documentation.
The documentation for this is dead simple, its API compatible.
So when you have this, you can just cast it to that or change it to that.
So instead of having a new websocket, we can have a new recruit reconnecting WebSocket.
So let's do that.
Where do we create our W.S.?
Right here.
Reconnecting WebSocket.
Now, there's a few other things we can put in there for parameters and you can read the documentation
yourself.
It's all right here, but I'm going to put them in myself right now.
I'm going to pass Noel as the second argument.
And the third argument will be some options debug.
True, because I want to see any problems I have while I'm in development.
And of course, I'll set that default to when I go live and to reconnect interval.
Reconnect interval, which is in milliseconds, and I'll set it to 3000, which is 3000 milliseconds.
OK, so let's start our application up and try this again.
Go run command Webster, not go.
And in windows, of course, it's not start out go.
It's DOT, but this runs.
And now if I go back to my application and reload this page, I should be connected and I am reconnecting
websocket.
It got me there.
Perfect.
OK, I should be able to log in as Fred and I am now.
What happens if I go back to my application and I stop this?
I've just lost my connection, lost my connection and look at it trying to reconnect.
So we're still offline.
Let's reconnect by starting up my application again.
And now we're connected, perfect, so I should be able to say hello, world, and off it goes.
And we reconnected.
We kept our connection.
Life is good.
Now in the next lecture, I want to add one more thing, an indicator that shows the user whether or
not we're actively connected at the moment.
And we'll take care of that in the next lecture.