So this time around, we want to put some indication for the user as to whether or not they are currently
connected to the server.
So I think I'll put a little badge right here, one that is red and says not connected when we're offline
and one that is green and says connected when we're online.
And we'll change the content of that, change it from the red to the green or the green to the red,
depending upon whether or not we have an active connection.
And we'll just check our Web sockets.
And that's really easy to do.
And maybe I'll get rid of this HRR so things aren't too cluttered.
So let's go back to our homepage.
And I'm right here on the home file.
And just below the the hidden name equals action.
I'll get rid of this H.R. and I'll just put a div there.
It equals status.
That will be our status and it's just an empty div.
That's all that it is right now.
And I need to give it a class because I want it to go to the right.
I'll say class, I'll give it a little margin at the top mtu and I'll just float to the end, which
is how you do it in bootstrap five these days and it's empty right now when we start out.
So let's go down to our JavaScript and find the part where we connect.
I want to put this just before socket on open.
Here we are.
So I'm going to define a couple of things here.
I'll define a constant offline and that will be equal to some HTML and a better spell offline, correct?
Correctly and const online.
And again, that'll be some HTML.
And the e-mail here is going to be something really simple.
We'll use the built in badge classes in bootstrap span class equals badge and then we'll call it big
success.
Try that again.
Big, big success, which will make it green and I'll just put the word connected in there and close
my span.
Then I'll copy this and paste it in here and modify it and make it better.
Badge danger and we'll say not connected.
OK, so now we've got our two little variables that holder appropriate html.
Let's just grab grab an instance of the status div so let status div equal document get element by ID
and I call it status.
So now I have my correct HTML for online and offline and I have a reference to my status.
So when we're online, what we want to do here after we successfully connect so socket on open right
now we're writing to the console and I'll keep doing that.
I would remove that before I went live, but I'll just put status div dot in our HTML equals online.
OK, so let's just save that and go back and try reloading this page and see what happens.
And there I'm connected.
Perfect.
So that shows that I am connected.
Now what happens when I close my connection.
When I get an unclosed event, I can do the same thing here.
I'll just copy this once we close for whatever reason, we can make that offline.
OK, so let's reload this page.
We're online and I'll put Fred and I'll send a message to make sure that still works.
Test it does.
And I will go back here and stop my application.
OK, so didn't quite work, what did I get wrong?
I misspelled my dange should be big danger.
B g dash.
I think I got it.
So let's start that up again and try this one more time.
So I'll reload this page.
I'm online now, I'll go back and stop my application, stop.
And we're offline and I'll get started again and auto reconnect should change it back, and it does.
OK, so there we have some indication as to whether or not a user is online.
Is there anywhere else we should add this?
Well, probably.
On air, for whatever reason, now, that may not be appropriate for every situation, but there may
be cases where you do want to put it there in this application where we're just learning about how to
connect to WebSocket, how to use them, how to reconnect all those things.
I'm going to put it there, assuming that in every other case we've gone offline.
And if you're writing a more robust application, you may want to do something different there.
But this, I think, gives us a pretty useful and pretty functional chat application.
And it also demonstrates the vast majority of the cases where you're going to be able to use WebSocket
and how you're going to use those Web websites.
So the one thing that's bothering me right now is that this button is bleeding into that device and
I can fix that pretty easily.
I'll just find my div ID equals output and give it a class of chatterbox and say maybe three.
Just give it a margin talk and that looks a little bit better.
OK, so that's it for this application.
And what we're going to do in the next section of the course is we're going to write a somewhat more
sophisticated application and again, we're still going to be using Web sockets, but we're going to
use the Pusher library instead.
And what we'll build is a server monitoring tool that allows us to monitor the status of as many external
servers as we want and to use Web sockets to alert the user who's looking at the application and also
to notify otherwise sending email, sending text to whatever it may be.
So we'll get started on that in the next section.