OK, before we can actually start working with WebSocket, we need to set up a basic Web application
and fortunately go makes that really easy.
So I'm in goaland you could be in visual studio code or whatever idea you choose to use.
But I'm going to create a new project and I'm going to create a new Go Modules project, and I will
call it W.S. for Web sockets.
So let's create that.
And inside of that, I need to have a main function.
So I like to organize my code in a way that's kind of standard for people that work in Web applications
and go, I'm going to put my main package in a new directory at the root level of my application called
CMD, and inside of that will create a new directory called Web.
And inside of that I'll create a new go file, which I'll call Mango.
And I'm going to change the package name to Main because I like it better than I like Web and I'll create
a function here, my empty main function.
Now, what we're going to do in this main function is create some roots.
So we need to get some roots that we can listen to.
So path names to different pages on our Web site and we need to start a Web server.
So in order to create a route's file, we need to have something to root to.
And those are handlers.
So let's go create one handler for a homepage.
And when I create my handlers, you could just do it.
You write in your your main package if you wanted to.
But I like to plan for the future.
And quite often when I start a project that seems like it might be really small, suddenly in a few
months down the road or six months down the road, it has to have new functionality.
And at that point, I'm actually kicking myself saying, why didn't you just organize things in a slightly
more sensible fashion?
So I'm going to create a new package and I'll do that by creating a folder at the root level of my application
called Internal.
These will be internal packages that are not useful to anyone except me.
They're only used in this application.
And inside of that it'll create a new directory called headers.
And inside of that I'll create a new file, which I will call handlers dutko.
So this is going to have a package of handlers and I'll create a function func.
This will show the homepage func named home and like every handler, every handler, every Web handler
and go, it has to have two arguments.
A response writer, which I'll call w he should be response writer and then a pointer to a request,
which I'll call her, and it's a pointer to HTP request and I want this to display a page.
Now we could use the built in templating system that's part of the go standard library go templates
or go HTML templates if we wanted to.
But I want to make this a little easier to use.
And there are three things I'm going to import into my my application.
Three external packages, one for rooting or routing if you prefer, one for building and displaying
HTML templates, so for rendering pages and one for web sockets.
So let's go get those right now just to make our lives a little bit easier.
So the first thing I'll get is my HTML template package and I'm at the root level of my application.
Yeah.
And I will just say go get from GitHub dot com cloudy kit with a capital C and a capital K jet and V
six.
Now at the time I record this lecture version six of Cloudy Kit Jet, which is an e-mail template rendering
package.
It's the latest stable version.
You may be taking this in a few months after I record it and there may be a newer version and feel free
to use that if you want to.
But if you want to follow along and do exactly what I'm doing, then get version six.
So I'll go get that.
Now I need a routing package, a place that will allow me to direct traffic from my Web server, which
will get to momentarily to the appropriate handler.
And I'm going to use one that's dead simple.
Go get from GitHub dot com b, m, i, z, e, r, a and Y.
Pat Pat is dead simple and very fast and sufficient for our purposes to get an application up and running.
And the last thing we need is the actual WebSocket package.
So I'll go get from GitHub dot com gorilla websocket singular.
There's no s and it gets so if I look at my go mod file now I should have imported all three of those
and I have perfect.
So I want this homepage, I want it to render a jet template.
Well I need somewhere to store those templates.
They need to be files somewhere in the file system.
So I'm going to put them at the root level of my application in a directory called him up and we may
as well create an e-mail page right now.
So inside of that directory, I will create a new.
File, which I will call home Jet, because it's a jet template, and that's just going to be a basic
HTML file.
So I'm going to use a an extension I have built into my system called Emet and I will create it like
this HTML five and it creates an HTML template for me, empty one.
So I'll call this home and I'll just put H1.
This is the home page and save that.
Now I want to be able to render that.
So how do I do that using jet.
Well if you've never worked with it before, it's actually really, really easy.
It's actually much easier to use than the built in templating system.
That's part of the standard library.
So we want the home func or the home function to render that that homecourt jet file that I just created.
And we can do that really, really easily.
Using Jet, it's actually much easier than using the built in templating system.
That's part of the Go Standard Library.
I have no complaints about that package.
I use it all the time.
But for this course, I thought it might be fun to use Jet.
So how do we do that?
Well, we create a variable var, which I'll call views because it's going to be a variable that handles
my views and that is equal to jet dot new set and it requires a flutter.
So the loader is going to be equal to jet dot, new OS file system and all that wants is a path to my
director where my templates are stored.
So I'm actually going to add a second thing here just to make life a little bit easier.
And the second thing I'm going to add is jet lag in development mode.
And all that does is it it removes the requirement of stopping and restarting our application every
time I make a change to a jet template.
So you take that out before you go into production, obviously.
But this is something that's going to make my life a little bit easier.
OK, so now I have this views variable and I can use that to render templates.
And I could if I want to put all of the code right here in my home func to render the homepage.
But chances are I'm going to have more than one page in this application.
So what I'm going to do is create a new func called Render Page, and it's going to take three possible
arguments.
It's going to take or at least three.
It's going to take a response writer because I need something to write to and that will be my htp dot
response writer.
The second argument will be the name of the template that I want to render, which I'll call spell,
and it's just a string.
And the third argument will be whatever data I want to pass to that template.
And Jet has something called Vermaak as a type built into it, and this is going to potentially return
an error.
So I better add that.
OK, so three arguments to pass this one, the response rate is absolutely required.
Template is required because I need to know which template to render and data can be nil if it's empty.
And I don't want to pass any data to a template, which is what we're going to do right now.
I can leave that.
No, but let's render the template.
So how do I do that?
Well, view error.
I'm creating a variable and potentially an error called view view as the template itself.
And then I call my views variable that are defined up here.
And I said, get template.
And what I want to get is the name of the template template, the string that I passed right here.
So I check for my error.
If error is not equal to nil, just return the error.
I should just log it to logged up print line error and then return the error.
If there is no error now, I want to execute it.
So again, check for an error.
Error is equal to viewport execute and it requires the response, right.
What do you want to write to?
I want to write to my HGV response writer and then it also requires data, if there is any.
So I'll put in data and there's a third argument for context, which I'm going to ignore in this course,
because it's beyond the scope of the things I'm trying to do.
But yet templates allow you to pass data as a variable, as a jet via a map and also to pass data in
the context which I'm not going to do it all in this course.
But you can read about that if you want to.
And again, if there's an error, I'll just copy and paste this.
Otherwise return nil.
So now I have this render page, so I should be able to go up to my homepage and just say something
as simple as air is assigned the value of render page pass at the name of my template, which is a part
of my response writer, which is w pass it the name of the template line, name that Homburg Jet, and
I'm not going to pass any data and will check for an error.
So I'll post that in here.
I'll just print the error if there is one logged print line error, OK.
And will actually improve this in a little while.
But this is sufficient for our purposes right now.
So I now have a function home that will render my home page.
I have the render page function I can use for any handler that needs to render a page.
But I still don't have a means of getting from my request in the main function to the actual handlers,
we need to create some routes, so let's do that.
Over in my Web folder in CMD Web, I'll create a new file.
Which I'll call Rich.
And this is going to have a funk called Roots that returns and HDP dog handler and what I'm going to
do here is use that Pat Rohter that we installed a few moments ago.
So I'll create a variable, which I'll call mux, which is pretty common for multiplexed, is equal
to Pat Dott knew.
And now I'll create a root to the homepage, to the home page handler.
So mux it'll be a get request.
I'm going to nothing, just slash the top level of my web application and I want to go to htp dot handler
func and I want handlers dot com.
And that should do it now I just need to return my mux, return mux.
OK, so now we have a route to get to our handler --, but I still need to go back to my main application
and actually start something, because right now, if I run this application, nothing is going to happen.
We have no Web server starting.
It'll just I'll compile it.
It'll look at the main function, say that's empty and say, OK, well, I'll just quit.
There's nothing happening.
So let's do that.
Let's create a Web server.
First of all, I need to get my roots.
Roots is a sign the value of roots.
And let's just go create a Web server.
So I will, first of all, print out a message logged up print line, starting web server on port and
I'll put it on Port 880 and I'll ignore the error and go htp listen and serve two port eighty eighty
and hand it my roots.
Oops.
Call this mux there, that makes more sense.
So this should actually work, so let's give it a try.
So let's make sure we're in the right direction.
You need to be at the root level of your application.
Yeah.
And now we'll just compile and run everything in the command folder.
So go run ACMD Web start ogo.
Now, if you're running on Windows, you need to go dot.
You can't go Stargirl, but if you're on Linux or a Mac you can go start Ukko.
So it should run.
And it does.
Let's go to our Web browser and let's try going to localhost AT&amp;T and this is the homepage.
Perfect.
So now we have a home page set up and we have a Web server with a routing package and a handlers, and
it displays our e-mail template.
And that's all we need to do at this point.
So in the next lecture, we'll get started working with Web sockets in a little more detail.