So far, our Web application just does one thing, it listens for requests to the home page and renders
an HTML page, which isn't terribly exciting.
So we need to actually create some more handlers.
And the handler I want to create right now is not one that renders a Web page.
Instead, it's one that actually takes a connection, a regular HTP or HTTPS connection and upgrades
it to a WebSocket connection.
And in order to make that happen, I need to create a new variable.
I'm going to create it right here, right after my views variable and I'll call it var upgrade connection,
which seems like a meaningful name and that will be equal to a type.
And the type is WebSocket upgrader and that actually requires a few parameters.
It requires a red buffer, a right buffer and whether or not to check the origin, which is a security
thing.
So we'll put it in these Nereid buffer size.
I'll make that ten, twenty four, which is a good size.
Right.
But for size I'll make ten, twenty four and finally check Origin.
And that is going to be equal to a function, a function that just takes the request.
And returns a bull and the bull is going to return, is return true,
so that's a variable I can use to upgrade connections and let's use that variable and come down here
just after the home handler and create a new handler.
And this one will be called We can point our WebSocket End Point.
And it is a handler.
So it still requires the response operator and the pointer to the request.
Let's put those in there.
And what does this do?
Well, the very first thing it's going to do is to upgrade the connection.
So I'll create a new variable W.S. for my WebSocket connection, potentially an error, and I'll get
a call.
That variable I just created upgrade connection.
And that actually has a method on it called upgrade and upgrade requires your response rate or your
pointer to your request.
And the third third argument, I'm going to leave as no, but you can actually look at it and see what
it does.
I don't need to do that.
Try that again.
If there is not equal to nil, then what do I want to do?
If the error is not equal to nil, I'll just log the error for now.
OK, so upgrade actually takes three parameters.
And the first one is your response writer.
The second one is your request and the third one is your response header.
And we're not going to worry about the response header right now.
It's unimportant for our purposes in figuring out how websites work, but you can read about it at your
leisure if you choose to do so.
So I've created that was that variable.
I've upgraded the connection.
Let's just log something.
Log, print line and I'll just log client.
Try that again.
Client connected to Endpoint.
OK, let's try spelling endpoint.
Right.
So client is connected and I've loved this.
And what I want to do at this point is send back a response and I can just send back text if I want
to, but I like to structure my responses in a way that makes them easy to pass.
I like to use Jason, so let's define a new type just in front of this W.S. Endpoint type.
And I will call it was JSON response and it's a struct and I'll give it a few fields that I can actually
use.
So I'm going to put some in right now that we'll be using in a few minutes or the next few lectures.
But let's just define them.
All right.
Now, the ones that I know I'm going to be sending back.
So I'm going to send back something called action, which will be a string, and we'll define the JSON
response to be action lowercase.
And then I'll define another one, which I will call message.
And we'll just call that message for Arcachon response and we'll define another one called message type,
which you don't need to worry about right now.
But we'll be using it in a little while.
And finally.
Well, that's enough right now.
We can go with those.
OK, so let's format this, give a few comments.
W.S. JSON response
defines the response
sent back from WebSocket and this endpoint needs a name upgrades connection to WebSocket.
OK, so that's done so far.
Now I want to actually give a response back because I've defined this variable WSC and I have to do
something with it or I can't even compile this program.
So let's just go with really simple one.
VAR response is of type WSJ JSON response and I'll put in here response message that spell response.
Right.
And I'll just put in a very simple HTML, which I'll do this way, I'll wrap it with the back text so
I can use quotations if I need to at some point.
M small connected to server small m.
OK, now I want to send that response back to the client so we can do that really, really easily with
the Gorilla WebSocket package.
Would you say error is equal to W.S..
Right Jason.
Try that again.
Right message.
Right.
Message would actually send back just text.
I don't want to send back Jason so we'll read our response and it takes care of the martialing that
into Jason for us and sending it back.
And let's just check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, we'll just log that for right now.
OK, so that is all I need to worry about right now.
That gives me an endpoint.
So I need to actually set up a route to that endpoint.
So let's go over to here and let's just duplicate this route and we'll instead of going to Handler's
home, we'll go to Handler's WC endpoint and instead of a slash, we'll listen to WC.
So this will be the euro.
We call from our our Web page that we're sending to the end user.
So we need to go into that Web page and add some JavaScript that allows us to connect to the WC endpoint
and see if we connect.
And we'll take care of that in the next lecture.