So right now, we have an application with two routes, one that goes to the homepage and all that does
is it just takes the template home jet and writes that to the screen.
And the template looks like this.
It's just HTML and it renders this way in the Web browser.
This is the home page.
And of course, we're going to improve this over time.
And as you may have noticed, all this is is HTML, even though I'm passing homecourt jet through the
jet template engine to render HTML, I'm not actually taking advantage of Jet and that's OK.
We're going to take advantage of it later on in the course.
So it makes sense to set it up right now.
And the other route we have is our end point and that takes us here.
And all that does is take a standard connection from a Web browser and upgraded to a WebSocket connection
and send back a Jason response.
So our task right now is to go to our home dot jet and add some JavaScript that actually connects to
our endpoint.
And then we want to verify that we've actually got that connection.
So let's get started.
So I'm going to add a script tag just before the closing body tag.
And inside of that, I'm going to declare a variable and I'll call it socket because it's a WebSocket
connection.
And right now I'm going to set it to null so it has no value whatsoever.
So I've just declared it so that I can access that variable from other functions in the JavaScript for
this page.
So what I want to do is I want to wait until the document is loaded and then connect to my WebSocket.
So let's do that one at an event listener document.
At Event Listener and we'll look for dumb content loaded, in other words, when everything is loaded
in the page will execute this function and all I'm going to do is take that variable socket and make
it equal to.
What a new websocket.
And I'll pass it a path and I'll pass it Collins just like a Web page starts with HTP or https colon
slash slash WebSocket.
Use the WC for an unencrypted connection, which we're going to use and development.
But in production we would use for a secure connection.
But we're just in development right now, so this will work just fine.
And I'll connect to my local machine, which is one two seven zero zero one the Lookback address, which
is always the local machine.
And I'm going to go to port eighty eighty.
That's the port we're listening on and our path is W.S..
So once that's connected, what are we going to do?
Well, we can actually call some methods on our socket.
Our socket has a few things built in, so we'll call socket, which I better still right on open.
And inside of that, what do I want to do?
I'll make that do it this way equals.
It's a nicer syntax I like that syntax for.
Calling methods on objects, and I'll just say council log.
Successfully connected, that's all due for right now just to see if that works.
OK, so let's stop our application.
If it's running, let's run our application.
And let's go back to our webpage and I'll open my JavaScript terminal window and reload it and see what
happens successfully connected.
Absolutely perfect.
Let's go over and look at the log for our application client connected to End Point.
So there we've actually connected to our endpoint.
Now, that's enough JavaScript for this time around, but since we've got that's that home open anyway,
let's make that a little bit better.
I'm going to go to bootstrap and I'm going to use bootstrap five point zero point zero dash beta one,
which is the current release.
When I'm recording this, and to be honest with you, I would never use a beta version in production.
But we may as well get our feet wet with this right now because it won't be too long before we have
bootstrap five available to us.
Now, if you like foundation or something else, feel free to use that.
I'm just using bootstrap because it's extremely common.
A lot of people are familiar with it and it's easy to work with.
So let's get started.
I'm going to copy this success into my home jet right up here.
And format that so it looks a little bit better and I'll grab the JavaScript too, because I may as
well get that, I don't know if I'm going to use it or not, but it's not going to hurt to have it available
to us.
And again, I'll format that.
And since we've created that, we may as well go.
Div class equals container.
Div class equals row.
And div class equals call, and then I'll just take this H1 tag and put it in here.
And get rid of this.
All right, let's format that it's good and let's just reload the page and see if it actually got put
in properly, it did a little close to the top of the page.
So I'll put to class equals MTC three.
That'll move the margin down three.
And that looks a little bit better.
And I'll put a horizontal rule underneath that and I'll create a new row.
And this time I'm going to put in two columns, div class equals call MMD eight.
And down here, div class equals call me for.
And I'll put an H three in here that says chat and an H three in here for who's online and you can see
where I'm going with this.
So what's going to happen is we're going to create a chat application and there'll be some things up
here that you can type your message in to and specify username.
And then you'll have the actual chat showing up over here.
And then who's online will be the list of connected users.
And the goal here is that whenever somebody comes online, we'll use Web sockets to refresh the list
of users over here.
And whenever somebody posts a message, whether it's the user of this page or some other user will see
the chat reflected up here in real time.
And we're going to do all of that using what's WebSocket.
So this is just to get the layout started and get us moving along a little bit.
And that's enough for this time around.
In the next lecture, we'll move on with some more functionality with Web sites.