So right now, we have a couple of routes, one to our home, page one to our WebSocket upgrader, and
we've managed to connect to our WebSocket successfully.
So that's good.
And our homepage just looks like this right now.
We have a title at the top.
We have a column here and we have a column here.
And we need to actually be able to send some information to our handler more than just connect to it.
We need to be able to do something.
So in order to do that, of course, we have to have some information to send.
So let's create some things here that allow us to specify username and to create a message.
So over in our home jet file, let's create a couple of form elements.
And we're not actually creating a real form because we're not posting anywhere.
We're going to be using websites for everything, but we can still use form groups.
So let's create a div form group.
And inside of that, will have a label label for and will do the user name first for user name and we'll
just call it user name.
That's where the user can type in his or her name.
And then we'll have an input type equals text.
Name equals username, ID equals username and class equals form control.
And I like to also put autocomplete equals to off, even though it doesn't work sometimes with Google
Chrome for whatever reason, it's still I like to put it in there just to be, you know, correct.
And then we have a place for our message.
So copy and paste that and we'll make this message for message.
Name is message, ideas, message, and that's enough for that one.
So let's see what that looks like.
Reload, right.
We've got a place to type in a username.
And ideally, when someone types in their username and then gets out of this field, in other words,
this field loses its focus.
The username should show up over here.
And when they type in their message, it should show up down here.
So let's go look at this.
We don't have a place to put that message yet.
So let's put an HRR here and we'll put a div and I'll give this idea equals output and I'm going to
give it a class that will define in a moment and that'll just be Chatterbox and we'll put it down here
like this.
OK, so we have now a place to put our message, but let's give that a little bit of styling so I'll
create up here in my head style and I'll call it chat box.
And what will we do?
We'll give it an outline outline.
One picks solid silver.
We'll give it a min height of, say, one hundred and fifty picks or OK, one hundred and sixty picks
and a little bit of padding.
Padding zero point five m so let's save that chat box chat box.
This should work and there's a place for messages to show up.
OK, now let's go look at our handler for a minute in our handlers file.
I have already defined a type S Jason response.
This is the response that sent back from the WebSocket and we'll get that as a Jason file.
I also need a place to define the kind of information we're sending to this server.
So let's create a new type type W.S. Jason payload.
I'll just call a payload that's even better and it's a struct.
And what kind of information are we going to be sending while we're probably going to be sending an
action and that will be a string and we'll call it Jason action and that will define what we expect
the server to do.
So we might be sending it something like joint or something like message, whatever it may be.
But there may be multiple actions that we have to handle.
We definitely want to have a message and we'll call this message.
It's a string and we'll call it Jason message.
And the last thing I might need to use is the actual WebSocket connection itself.
I don't know if I need it now or not.
And I know that my website, WebSocket connection from guerrilla web sockets actually has a type predefined
and that's called WebSocket dot com.
So let's just create a new type to hold that just a wrapper for it type and I'll call it WebSocket connection
and it will be a struct and it only has one member and that will be of type pointer to WebSocket connection.
OK, so we have that type defined and it holds that, that's all that it is.
So down here I'm going to add in this payload.
I don't know if I'm ever going to use it, but I'm going to put it in there just to be safe.
So I'll call that Kirchen.
Now, not current, I'll just call it court and it will be a type WebSocket connection, and I'm going
to leave that out of the Jason.
I don't want that to show up.
OK, so we have an action.
We have a message.
We have a con.
We probably also need a username.
So let's put that in there.
Is there anything else they need to store in there?
Well, I don't think so at the moment.
There may be later on, but for right now, this is probably sufficient for our purposes.
OK, so that's enough for that struct.
Let's go back to our home jet and think about we have we have username, we have message.
We don't have action.
So let's put an action in their input type equals and I'll make this one hidden because nobody needs
to see it.
Name equals action and ID equals action.
OK, so now we have let's just make sure this all renders properly looks good.
Now we got to think about what we want to do in our JavaScript.
So if we scroll down there and have a look at it, all we're doing right now is defining one handler.
Sock it on open, do something.
Well, there are other things we need to take care of as well.
One is obviously on clothes.
If there's an unopened there's probably darn clothes and there is.
Try that again.
And right now, I'll just log to the console.
Connection closed, which we would never see, but I'm just putting that in as a placeholder.
We have other ones that we need to take care of as well or that we should take care of.
For example, what if there's an air socket on air is equal to and we can pass it the air.
And we need to do something consoled log, there was an error, which is just a placeholder, but that'll
suffice for right now.
And this is the one that the next one is the one that'll get called a lot socket on message.
And that would be equal to message, that's the variable we're going to pass to our function and we
what do we want to do here?
Well, first of all, we're going to get our message as Jason console the log.
Message.
OK, so we're just going to log whatever they get, whatever we get back from the server.
So what we need to do next is to actually create a message from the server and send it back.
Well, let's see what we're doing right now.
When we connect to our End Point.
We're writing our JSON response back.
So in theory, I should be able to write a message in the same way from a handler from West End Point
will pass this off to something else that decides what kind of action are we getting and what should
we do and send back a response.
So in order to make that happen, there's a little bit of code that needs to be written and we'll take
care of that in the next lecture.