So we've created some JavaScript on our homepage, our chat page, that allows us to handle specific
responses from the server, and we also have a means of sending certain kinds of information to the
server.
So now we need to work on our handlers a little bit.
And what we need to do is to think about how we're going to handle our requests from the client to start
with.
So right now, we have just one handler, one handler specifically for our WebSocket standpoint.
And what I want to do is after someone connects, I want to throw them off to a good routine that'll
run forever.
And if it stops, it'll start itself back up and that will actually determine what we do with a particular
request from the client.
So I'm going to call that listen for W.S., for example.
And when I get a request, when when I get a payload coming in and the payload will be in this format
right here, I'll determine what I do based upon the action and I'll hand that off to another girl routine
that listens to a specific channel and does different things depending on the content of the payload.
So we're going to have to go routine's.
The other thing we need to worry about, of course, is one thing I need to keep track of is who's in
the chat room, because I need to know who I send messages to.
And I also need to be able to display the list of connected users on that page where it says who's online.
So let's create a couple of new variables right up here on the top.
I'm going to create a channel and I'm going to create a place to hold all of the connected users.
So we'll create a new variable via channel for Web server WebSocket channel, and that will be equal
to make Channe W.S. Payload.
Right here.
So this is a channel that will only accept things of type W.S. payload.
The other thing I could create is a new clients variable for our clients.
These are the connected clients and that will be a map.
Make a map of type website WebSocket connection, because that's how I keep track of them.
Everybody has their own WebSocket connection with a string in there.
OK, so two new variables.
I'm not using them yet, but let's go do something with them when someone connects to the server with
a WebSocket connection.
I'll add them to that map right down here.
I'll create a new variable icon and I'll make that of type WebSocket connection.
And inside of that I'll just put Con W.S..
And then I'll add that to the map clients, which is my map con, which is the variable I just created
and I'll just put nothing in there, doesn't have to have anything in it right now.
So I'm not going to put anything, any value in there.
I just want to have an entry in the map.
And that's sufficient for our purposes right now.
We'll be using that later on and it won't be an empty string.
So I've now added that.
Use it to the map.
What's the next thing I want to do?
Well, I actually want to take this these people away from this endpoint and put them over into a go
routine.
So let's create a new good routine and I'll call this funk.
Listen for us.
And it's going to take one argument and the argument will be a connection, which is a pointer to a
WebSocket connection.
Try that again.
WebSocket connection that doesn't return anything.
And inside of that, I want to make sure that if this go routine stops for whatever reason, it comes
back.
So I'll just say defer, in other words, when this function stops executing.
Will execute this function and of course, it has to have parentheses at the end inside, we'll just
say if our which is just a variable uncrating equals recovered.
So if you panic for some reason and our is not equal to nil, then logged print line.
And I'll just say error.
And formatted as print f.
And I'll just put the area in their present V and R, so this will recover us if we die.
Now, what do I want to do inside of this function?
Well, I'm not sure yet, but I know I'm going to get a payload periodically.
So let's create a variable via payload payload and we'll just say for and we'll just execute this forever
and we'll say error is assigned conduct rejoice.
In other words, no, not remote address.
Read, Jason.
And what we're going to read is into payload.
If error is not equal to nil, don't do anything, do nothing, because there's just no payload else.
If there is no error, then payload Darkon is equal to my pointer to con.
And send this off to my question.
OK, so I've got this function, I'm not doing anything with it, but up here in W.S. End Point, after
I've done all of these things, I'll just start this go routine.
Go listen for W.S., which I see I spelled wrong, and I should probably fix that right now.
That's better, and I'm going to pass it on a reference to Con, so somebody connects, we start this
go routine and it runs forever.
If it dies, it starts itself back up.
And all that it does is it listens for a payload.
And if it gets the payload, it sends it off to that channel on the channel.
Doesn't it doesn't it doesn't do anything.
We're not actually listening to it.
So let's create a new function down here.
Funk, listen to us channel, which will have to start at some point, and we'll do that in our main
function and inside of this, what we want to do is to create a variable fire response, which will
be WSJ in response.
This is what we're going to send back to the user.
That's the type that I specified right up here.
And I want to listen.
So first of all, we'll say create a variable.
I'll just call it E for event.
And that reads from WC.
OK, and then for, again, an infinite for loop that should be inside of here, actually try that again.
But right now, let's just make it easier.
Let's just say response equals.
Got here and a response, that message equals some message.
So we've got that.
OK, and is we get something from here, let's say.
Some message and action was.
And I'll put a percent s here, I just need to do something with that variable to get rid of the error
and I'll put idot action.
And we'll change this to a format of best print F.
There, OK, so I've now anytime I get a value from the channel, I'm creating and I'm using my response
variable that had cleared up here and I'm populating it with some with some information.
The last thing I need to do is I need to actually broadcast this information to all of the users.
I don't want to do that inside this for loop.
So instead we'll create another function func, which I'll call broadcast to all.
And it's going to take the argument of response, which we're going to pass it from this go routine
up here, and that's a type Jason response.
So from here, what I want to do is broadcast this to everyone.
I need a list of all of the clients.
And of course, we already defined that.
We have our map clients so I can sit for client is assigned the value of range clients.
And all I'm going to do here is say broadcast.
This error is equal to client DOT.
Right, Jason.
And I'm going to pass it.
My response.
And I'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
What do I want to do?
I'll just say log, print, line, websocket error.
But this usually means that someone has just left the page and they don't exist here anymore.
And then I'll just not do anything with the error equal to client close close their connection and remove
them from the map.
Delete clients client.
OK, broadcast all is now a function I can call from up here broadcast to all and we're putting in response.
OK, so let's go through this whole thing.
Somebody connects to our webpage.
We display the web page using our home function wherever that is right here.
And once they display that page, we actually automatically call W.S. and point to connect.
And once they connect, we listen for W.S., we start this go routine.
So everything they send us from that point on for this connection will be passed off to listen for W.S.
and it starts itself up if it dies, which is no problem.
And then we have this infinite loop, which just goes forever.
And every time it gets a request with a payload, in other words, we get a JSON post or JSON file from
our JavaScript client, then we do something with that payload.
We pass it into our channel.
And down here this listen to us go go routine, which hasn't started yet, but we'll get to that in
a moment.
All it's going to do is say every time we get a A payload from the channel we stored in the variable
E and we populate some of the members in our response variable and we broadcast to all and broadcast
all says for every client that you know about, send them this response.
And if we can't actually do that, if we get an error, it means we've lost that client.
So we just log the error, we close that connection for that particular client and we remove them from
the map.
So the last thing we should need to do here is to start this go routine, which I'm going to do right
in our main Dongo file.
All I'm going to do is say log, print, line, starting channel listener.
And I'll start it, and that's in the handler's package, so let's put handlers in front of it.
And get rid of this there, that does the import for me, so I should be able to at this point stop
my application if it's not running and say go run command Web Stargirl.
And again, if you're in Windows, you put a dot there, not a Stargell and Alfio.
So it should start.
And I should be able to go to my Web browser, open this up, reload it, and we get a message.
Look at that.
We have a response and the message is all the way down here.
Look at this.
We have our response from the we have a method or a field inside of this file called data.
And it looks like that's where my information went.
Now, it's hard to read because I'm not actually parsing this is adjacent file.
But if we actually do that, if we go back to our homepage.
And find the part where we get that message and instead of logging the message, let's pass it.
I'll say J let J equal Jason pass.
And I can't pass the message because it's not Jason, I need to pass message data and then we'll log
our console log.
Now, I called message dot data because if you look at this object, everything that is our job, our
Jason file is actually in data right here.
OK, so let's reload this page.
I'll clear the console, see if we got it right.
And there it is.
Action message, message type, that's it, so that's exactly what we want.
So now we have a means of passing information basically to every connected user.
So what we'll do in the next lecture or two is we'll make this a little smarter and not just broadcast
got here.
Some message in action was will actually vary our response based upon the kind of action we have in
our and our request that's passed to the client.