OK, so it's time to improve our code a little bit, and what I want to do this time around is two things.
Well, probably one thing, this lecture, but we'll be doing two things over this lecture and maybe
the next next one.
And that is when someone enters a username like Fred, and then this input loses its focus by hitting
return to error tab to get to the next field, for example, that I take this username and I fire a
request through Web sockets off to my server saying, hey, a new user has entered the chat room.
Can you please populate that user's name over in the list here?
And I should be able to see everyone is currently connected to the chat room, everyone who's filled
this field out.
And the second thing I want to do, and I probably won't get that to that this lecture is to send a
message.
Someone typed some text in here, his return, and it should show up here and this should get cleared
and their username should be prepend into it.
All right, let's get started.
So the first thing I want to do is to put some kind of listener on this input, which I called username,
so that when this changes, I send a request off to the server.
OK, so let's go get started on that.
I'll go over to my homepage and that's right here home.
Yet at the very bottom inside of my ADD event, listener dom content loaded at the very bottom.
I'm going to put a new event listener in, so I'll say let user input, which is just a variable I'm
declaring equal to document get element by ID and and the one I'm looking for is username.
So now I have a reference to that, that Java, that form control and now I can add a listener to it,
user input, add event listener and I'm looking for the change.
And what I want to do inside this function is pretty straightforward.
What I need to do is to construct some Jason and send that through my websocket and that's pretty easy.
So we'll just say let JSON data equal to an empty JSON object and then we'll just populated with some
information.
So if you remember, back in our handlers at the very top, our payload is right here.
It has action, username, message and icon.
All I care about right now are these two.
My action is going to be some some word that I'm going to specify and the user name will be whatever
I type into that form input.
So let's just say JSON data and I want action to be equal to I'll just call it username and Jason data
username is going to be equal to this value, the value of that form control.
And then I need to send it off to the server.
And it's a simple one line command socket, which is my variable, my my variable that holds my WebSocket
connection.
Send and I need to send it as Jason, so I'll stratify it Jason Dot String Afie And what I'm stratifying
is just Jason data and that should do it.
OK, so this will actually send when somebody actually fills that form out, but I'm not doing anything
with it in the handlers right now.
In the handlers, you enter through this WSM point, you get sent off to this.
Listen, for W.S., it listens for a payload and when it gets it is just sending it into the channel.
But the channel listener and this is where we're doing our processing, our logic, all it's doing is
printing some stuff out.
Now, this should work.
I should be able to stop this and start my application to make sure everything is current.
Go back here, look at my JavaScript console.
I'll reload this page to make sure it's current, clear the screen and put Fred in there.
And it does.
It sends back got here, sent some message and action was username.
That's great.
So it's actually working, but I want to do more than that.
I actually want to send back a list of users with my username.
So let's go back up to our handler here and think about where we're going to do rather than this, which
is not here, down here rather than this.
I'm not going to comment this stuff out because it does nothing of value.
I'm going to switch.
I'm going to use switch on e try that again.
TKG on IDOT action.
And right now my first and only case is username.
In other words, someone entered the username.
And what I want to do here is I want to get a list of all users and send it back via broadcast.
I broadcast function so well.
The very first thing I need to bear in mind is that back up here when I have my initial WC endpoint,
I'm saying clients can't is equal to nothing.
Right?
So I need to actually put my username in there now while I can do that pretty easily, I can just say
clients and we're looking for Edcon is going to be equal to IDOT username.
So now I've updated my entry in the map to have the username.
So that's the very first thing I need to do.
The next thing I need to do is to get a list of all users and to do that I could write it right in here,
but I'm not going to I'm going to read a little function down here func and I will say get user list.
And it takes no parameters, but it returns a slice of string.
So all I have to do is to go through my list of users, build the string and send it back.
So for nothing and I'll call it X is a sign the value of range clients.
And I needed to declare a variable, so let me declare a variable user list via our user list.
Equals or is a slice of string and all I have to do is to say user list equals append user list and
I'm a pending X.
I'd better put a capital L there.
And the next I probably want to sort that, that would be the nice thing to do.
I don't want to give people a list, an unsorted list of users.
So that's pretty easy sort of strings.
And I'm sorting user list and then I just return the user list.
Now I have my user list or a means of getting my user list.
So up here, now that I've added myself to this map, I can just get my list of users.
So I'll just call it users is a sign the value of get user list.
And I want to send this back and I want to send it back to my client.
But do I have anywhere to put that?
Well, let's go back and look at our response payload.
Our response, Jason.
Response.
I have action.
I have message, I have message type, but I don't have anywhere to put a list of users.
So maybe we should add that I'll create a new entry in here called Connected.
That's the wrong one.
Connected users, and it's going to be a slice of strings and in Jason, I will call that connected
users.
All right, now I have somewhere to put it, let me just format this and go back down to our code here
and I can say response dot action because I need to give some action.
I'm going to send back to my users.
I will call that what seems like list users might be the appropriate term and a response dot connected
users is equal to users.
And then I just broadcast this broadcast to all response.
So that actually should do something of value, so let's stop our application, we're still not going
to see them on the screens.
I haven't written the JavaScript to handle the response, but I can actually make sure this all works
the way I think it's going to.
So I'll reload the page.
I will clear this console and I'll put Fred in there again and I get a response.
Connected users, Fred, so as getting back the way it should be.
So now I need to go back to my home dot jet and in the JavaScript section, I need to be able to handle
the response that I'm getting from the server.
So we have this code right here on message.
And what it's doing right now is just parsing that stuff out.
So I don't need that anymore.
So I'll just comment it out and instead let's decide what we're going to do.
Well, I'm actually do need that line.
I still need to get the JSON data, so I'll put that right here.
I now have my JSON data, which I'll call data.
And what I'm going to do now, which is a console log action, is just so I can see something in the
console and it's going to be DataDot Action.
And then I'll switch on this as Whitechurch Switch data action.
And my first case and only case right now is list users.
So I need somewhere to store this information, so before we go any further, let's just go back up
and look at our code here.
I have who's online, but I have nothing in there to actually list them.
So let's put a list.
Should put an unordered list and you will ID equals online users with nothing in it.
OK, so now I have a place to put something.
So what I'm going to do here is to say after I've got my case statement, I don't need that Colen case
list users.
Let's get our reference to that.
You well, we just created let us all equal document get element by ID and it was our online users.
So that gives me a reference to it.
And then I need to empty that while you ulda up first child.
You will remove child.
And the one I want to remove is you held up first child.
That's that's a one line, first child, first child that should get rid of everything in that list,
we're going to empty it because we're going to repopulate it with new information.
And that's as simple as this.
First of all, I need to make sure that there are some users in that list so I can say if DataDot connected
users
this year length, if that's greater than zero, do this.
Otherwise, I'll just get a JavaScript error if I try to do what I'm about to do next on an empty list.
So I'll just say data connected users.
For each to loose loop through it all function and my current one, I'll call item.
And I'm going to say let ally equal document, create element.
And I want to create an ally and then ally to pin child.
Document, create text node must have a typo in their text.
No, there it is.
Item.
One, two, three has too many to opening ones here.
And then append that to my up, you will not append child.
Hello, so all I'm doing there is I'm saying if I have a length of greater than zero in connected users
from data, if there's at least one user in there, do this loop through every entry in that list of
users, create an ally tag, populate the text of that like tag with the value that I'm getting from
my list of connected users and append it to you, Will.
And you will.
Is this one right here?
So that is all that I have to do there, I think.
Except, of course, because I'm going to switch statement, I should probably put a break in there.
OK, let's.
Go reload our Web page
action is empty string, OK, so it's connecting and sending something back and I'll put Fred in here.
Uncut reference you is not to find.
Where's that?
You know, type of let's reload the page.
Try it again, Fred and Fred winning twice.
OK, so I don't know why Fred Button twice.
That's not good.
But at least I know there's something of value going on there.
So let's try reloading it again.
Fred, Fred, Fred.
OK, so we're still getting to nothing.
It's not perfect, but at least we're getting a list right now.
So we're moving in the right direction.
So in the next lecture, we'll clean this part up and make sure that when we change our name, Frederick,
that worked.
See, there's something there's something setting a value in that map to start with.
And we need to actually find out where that is and resolve that.
And it shouldn't be terribly difficult.