So last time it looked like we had an error and it looked like we were getting our username displayed
twice and it wasn't actually an error in our code, or at least not exactly an error in our code, it
was more error in the way that I was doing things.
So I have just started the application.
As you can see right here, I've just started there's only one message being printed to the console.
That's because this client is already connected.
And if I put Fred in here, I get one Fred.
And if I put Frederich in here, I get one Frederich.
But if I reload the page without restarting the application, here's what happens.
Watch this log file.
So I'll just put a couple of blank spaces in here so you can see that there's nothing right here right
now.
When I reload the page, all of my users go away because I'm not actually listing my users, but I have
error.
Repeated field on failed WebSocket connection.
That's because when I reload the page, I actually got a different WebSocket connection.
So I put Fred in here.
Now I'm going to see Fred and Frederick because that Frederick is still in the map.
So because I didn't stop the application and start it, that's what caused the grief.
There was still one entry in that map.
So what I need to do is I need to have some means of determining whether or not a user leaves the page.
Unfortunately, that's pretty easy.
So I want to go back to my code and I'm going to go to homecourt jet.
And right here at the top, I'm going to put some code in my JavaScript.
And what I'm going to put here is something that will execute just before we leave the page window,
dot onload or on before unload.
So in other words, just before we leave the page, I click the link, I close the window.
Whatever it may be, I'm going to execute a function that's equal to a function.
And all I'm going to do here is say console dot log leaving, just so I know that it's actually executing.
And then I'll create an empty JSON data object.
And then I'll populate that with an action that we don't have yet, Jason, data action is going to
be equal to left.
In other words, somebody left and I'll send that along my socket sockets.
Send Jason String Afie, Jason, Dana.
OK, so that will actually send the command to the server, but in the handlers, I need to actually
check for that now.
So let's find the part where we have our actions, we have our actions right here.
We have username.
So let's create a new action case left.
So I need to send an action to the users that tells them that the user is left.
And the simplest way of doing that is actually just to remove the user from the list of users.
So let's make a response, response action.
And my action will be equal to list users.
And if we look at our home dot jet.
We have a case for list users.
It's our only case right now, so back to our handlers and then we need to actually fix our list of
users.
So that's our action and we want to send them a new list of users, but we don't want to send a user
that's not there anymore.
So let's delete from clients Edcon.
And of course, because this is being executed on the on before unload in homecourt jet, then we're
actually deleting the correct user and now we need to get our list of users so users is equal to get
user list and a response.
Users are connected users is equal to users.
And so we've got our users, we've got our user list, we have our action, all we need to do now is
to say broadcast to all.
Response and that should do it, and to make this really easy, I'm going to go back to our homepage
and I'll put a link right about.
Here, just before this, I'll just put a paragraph tag in there and say a draft equals ICDs, set to
go to GitHub, Dotcom, go to GitHub, and this will give me a means of making sure the user leaves
the page and watching the response on the other page.
So let's stop our application.
Start our application.
Go back to this page and rather than reloading it, I'm just going to return so there's nobody online
and I put Fred in here and Fred shows up.
Perfect.
Now, I'll go to a different browser entirely, Google Chrome, and I'll go to localhost eighty eighty
and I'll put Wilma in here and we see Fred and Wilma.
And if I go back to Firefox, I see Fred and Wilma.
Now, if Wilma goes to GitHub and that's who I am right now on Chrome.
She's gone to GitHub and over here she's removed from the list, and that solves that problem perfect.
So in the next lecture, we'll work on getting a message broadcast to all users so everyone can actually
chat for the very first time.