Before we get to sending messages, there's one other case I want to handle, and you may have noticed
that already.
So I've just started the server and as you can see in the log file, only one client is connected because
I started here and there's the connected message and I'll register as Fred as I have been right along.
Now I'm going to go to another browser and open a new window and go to localhost AT&amp;T.
And because the only thing I do when you first come to the page is connect to the server.
I don't get the news online.
That action has never been sent to me from the server to handle in JavaScript.
But if I go back to Fred, you'll see if I, for example, change my name or I send a message, I do
something that actually contacts the server.
It sends back an empty string for a user, someone who's hit the page but has not yet entered their
username.
And I probably don't want to do that.
I probably don't want to have that person show up or I want to have them show up as a lurker or something
like that.
So we should probably fix that.
And that's pretty easy.
All I have to do is go back to my code, find my handlers, go down to the part where I get the user
list and all I have to do is run a check in here.
If X is not equal to nothing, then append it, otherwise skip it.
And that should take care of that situation.
So let's make sure let's stop this started again and I'll go back to my Fred page and just hit that.
So now I should be connected and there's nothing there and I'll go back to my other page and hit that.
So now I have two clients connected, but no names in there.
And if I go back to Fred and put Fred in here, I just get Fred.
But if I go to this one and put in Bernie, I get Fred and Bernie and I get Fred and Bernie.
So that handles that one situation.
OK, now we'll finally get around to sending messages.