So we have a Web server running as part of our application, but so far it doesn't do anything very
exciting.
All it does is what we see right on the page in front of us.
It renders the text welcome to celebrities, to the web browser, and that's not very helpful.
So let's go back to our code, and I'm looking at the hilarious project right now, and what I'm going
to do is create some functionality to render pages and will support more than one kind of rendering
engine.
So let's get started so I could create the render functions I'm going to be working on shortly right
here at the top levels of my project, and it would work just fine.
What I'm going to do instead is make it more reusable by putting it into its own package.
So I'll create a new folder and I'll call it not surprisingly, render an inside of render or create
a new file, which I'll call render go and we'll give it a package name package render.
And what I'll do first is set up a couple of types.
The first one is going to be called render and it will be exported and it's a struct and it will have
a few fields.
First of all, it'll have a render for what rendering engine do we want to use?
And that will just be a string.
And it will also have the root path which we need, which will be a string.
In other words, where am I going to find the views?
And we'll also have, say, secure, which are set to bool.
Are we running in TDPs mode?
If so, that's true.
If not, it's false.
What port quarter are we going to be on, which is a string?
And I may not need these for a while, but I'm going to need them eventually.
And the server name, which will be a string, and that's enough for now.
So that's the first type I'm going to set up.
So let's save that and create the next thing we want, and I'm going to call this template data because
we're going to be passing data to our go templates and that will be a struct.
So first of all, things we might need to know is authenticated.
Is the current user authenticated and we will be using this, but not for a while yet.
It is authenticated, which is going to be a Boolean.
And then let's just say the kinds of things I might want to pass to a template, and we're going to
be fairly generic here because we're not sure what kind of data the users might want to send to the
particular views they're working with.
So we'll have an event map and that will just be map of string int.
So we look things up using a string and we find it in value, then a string map, which will be a map
of string string and maybe a float map because you need to pass a floating map or floating numbers to
your templates.
That'll be a map of string, and we'll just make it float 32 and then just generic data.
I don't know what it's going to be, but that's going to be in a map of type with an index of string,
and we'll just put interface in there so you can store whatever you want to in that particular map.
Later on, we're going to implement cross site request forgery protection.
So we'll have a CC rf token, which will just be a string.
And we'll also want things like the port, which will be a string, the ServerName, which will be a
string, whether or not we're running in a secure connection, which is just a ball.
That's enough for now.
So let's save that.
OK, so we have two types now.
Let's write a function that will render a page so bunk with a receiver of Save C star render to pointer
to the render variable type.
So that's the receiver.
We'll just call this page, so we'll be able to call render Typekit page and things we're going to want
to have there.
Well, w the response writer, we need that for sure, because we need something to write to.
We're probably going to be using the request at some point.
So our export request, when we deal with Sessions, for example, what's the name of the view we want
to render?
And that will be the actual file, the template that we're going to render information to.
Then we'll have variables.
What variables are we going to pass to our template and also data?
And those are both of type interface.
They can be anything.
OK?
And this will potentially return an error.
OK.
So let's put return nil in there.
So we don't have a compiler error.
And what I'm going to do here is decide what function this function calls based upon the value of renderer
in the render struct.
So we'll just implement a Switch statement.
So Switch and we could just go switch on C Dot renderer, but I'm not really an optimist when it comes
to this sort of thing.
So I'm going to convert it to lowercase strings, dot to lower, and I'll just wrap this whole thing
right like this
and give it its parentheses.
So we're only going to handle two forms of templates in this particular course.
Standard go templates.
And that's what we'll start with.
And then later on, we'll implement Jet.
So let's say for case go, if we're going to use go templates and we're going to do something.
OK?
And then we'll do one as well for Case Jet, which will do a bit later on.
And we're going to do something there and what we're going to do is have this function call another
function.
So let's make the first one here.
Func C pointer to to render and we'll call this go page and it will take a few parameters.
Our response writer.
Our request,
the view.
It should be a string.
And the data, which is interface, it can be anything and it potentially returns an error, and we'll
just say for now, return nil and then we can come up here in our switch statement and just say Return
Sego page.
And give you our view and data,
so we'll also have one for Jet, but we'll take care of that a bit later on.
So how are we going to undergo pages?
Well, it's pretty straightforward to start with.
We need to open the template.
We need to pass the template file.
So tempo and potentially in error are assigned the value of from the template package, which is part
of the standard library dot pass files.
And you'll notice that I'm getting the HTML template here, not this one, which is text template.
If you get that one, you're not going to have good results.
This is the one you want.
So we're going to pass files.
And what we want to pass, we need to build the string for that.
We know the root path, the path to the application and we know the name of the template.
So we could just call format dot, print f and give it our format string, which in our case will be
percent s slash views.
The name of the folder we know is going to exist, then the name of the template and I'm going to end
mine with Dot Page Dot template.
OK.
And the substitutions for those two placeholders are the right path, which I have as part of my renderer
see dot root path and the name of the template, which is view.
So that gets me my template and potentially an error.
So let's check for that error.
If error is not equal to nil, then just return the error.
Otherwise, we've got the template.
We've passed it.
So let's create a template.
Data variable TD for template data is assign the value of a reference to template data.
I thought.
And now we'll check to see if I received any any data as part of the call to this function.
So if data which is a parameter passed to this function, if it's not equal to nil, then T equals data
dot and we'll just cast it to a point or two template to the.
So now we have data, if any, so all we need to do is call check for an error template template, DOD
execute.
And we're going to execute it with a response writer and a reference to TD.
So once we execute, that life should be good.
But let's check for error.
If error is not equal to nil, then return the error.
OK, so now when we use this package, we have one more step to do before we can do that.
When we use that, we just call render Typekit page and then it decides what to do.
Based upon the value of the rendering engine.
Either Go or jet jet won't do anything right now, but we'll get to that before too long.
Or we can call this one directly.
And that's going to be great because it will allow end users to either use the convenience function
page or to call Go Page or jet page, which will exist before too long directly so they can support
multiple template formats or template engines right from the same application with no real effort on
their part.
So we have this part done.
But of course, we need to have some means of accessing this from our my app right now.
That doesn't exist.
So let's go back to celerity asked.
Go go to the top of the file, find our celerity struct type and add something in here.
And what I'm going to add is render and it has the type of pointer to render render.
So let's save this to format it.
Now, of course, we need to create a renderer to populate that particular field, so we need to create
a variable and store it in the render field of the celebrity struct type.
So I'm going to go to the very bottom of my file, and as I usually do, I'll put this off into its
own function so it will become easier to test.
So this will be a very simple function.
I'll call it func, and it will have the receiver of C pointer to celebrities and I'll call it create
render.
And it will take one variable.
Cell, which is a pointer to celebrities, and it will return a pointer to render render, which is
exactly what we need.
All we have to do here is say my renderer is assigned the value of rendered, render and populate its
various fields.
So first of all, we want is renderer Siddharth and Fig renderer.
So that's the first thing we need in there.
The second thing we need is a root path, root path.
Well, we know that one as well, that c dot repair.
And this shouldn't be C.
It should be so so I could grab it from C.
But I want to make sure that when I pass celebrities to this function, that I have the necessary values.
OK, so I'm just going to do it this way.
And let's put in the thought, which is seld config dot part.
That's probably enough to get us started.
OK.
So we'll come back and populate more of this as we need it, referring now let's just say return a reference
to my render.
So now I have to create and create renderer available to me.
It's currently not being used, so let's go back up and use it.
So let's find the repopulating this right here after we create the config, let's say C Dot Render is
equal to C to create renderer and will hand it.
See?
OK.
So that should give us a rendering engine, which means we can do something.
We can now create a handler and a root on my app in the Maya project that will actually render a single
page.
But the last thing we have to do before we can do this is open rootstock.
Go and get rid of this one.
We don't need that anymore.
Our dummy.
Welcome to celebrities text.
OK.
In the next lecture, we'll get this render a try and see what happens.
Save this to clean up the formats and all is good.
So let's move on.