So let's try out that render package we worked on in the last lecture, and right now I'm looking at
the My App project and on the course resources for this lecture, you'll find a few things you can download.
One that has some images and a zip file, and one that is a sample home page template.
And when I'm going to ask you to do is to download the images, unzip them and then put them, put the
contents of that zip file inside the public folder, so you should wind up with a folder called Echo.
And that's just the five icons for a for a web application, so we won't continue to get a file not
found error.
And the other one is an images folder that has a sample logo in there.
So download those and put them in your public directory and also download the HomeKit page Duct Temple
File and put that inside your views.
Now, I haven't put it in here yet, but I'm going to create a new file called HomeKit Page Dot Tempo.
And I've actually copied the contents of that file to my clipboard, so let me paste it in.
And there it is.
As you can see, it's a really simple HTML file.
It has this dot cc rf token here, but just leave that alone.
That'll be fine.
We'll be working with that later on.
So once you have those created, our goal in this lecture is to have the ability to serve that HomeKit
page tempo using the render functionality we worked on in the Celerity package last time around.
So the first thing we're going to need, of course, is a route's file and we have a root file insularity
Moscow.
But our actual application roots won't live there.
That just sets up some middleware.
Our actual application roots will live in this file, which I'm about to create, called not surprisingly,
roots don't go.
And again, this is in the My App package.
Now, of course, this needs a package declaration package main, and it will be remarkably similar
in format to what we have in the Solar House package.
So we'll create a function, but the receiver for this one is a pointer to the application type.
We created a little while ago, but it's still called roots, and it returns a pointer to checkmarks.
Now the first thing I'll do here is put a couple of comments in and I guess it didn't auto import chief
for me.
So let's try that again cheeked mooks.
That's.
So I put some comments in, and the first one is going to say middleware must come before any roots,
and then I'll put and roots here.
OK, now there's a reason for that.
The way that the chip router works is pretty straightforward, but it expects to find middleware before
it finds roots.
So we can't just be adding them wherever we want.
We should put our middleware at the top of our roots file and the actual roots at the bottom.
Now, of course, it might seem a little counterintuitive, but right now we're not returning anything
because we have nothing to return.
We actually appear not to have a root to return, no pointer to achieve, but not much to return.
But we actually do because this has a receiver of type pointer to application.
I can do something as simple as this return a dart app.
Dot roots, OK, because the roots that were initialized in the celebrity's application are available
as part of this pointer to an application.
The variable A. that we have as a receiver in this function now, we haven't actually added any routes
yet, but we could do that easily enough.
Let's create right here.
Let's return a handler that will take care of static assets.
The ICO files and the celebrities start JPEG file that you downloaded a little while ago.
So to do that, let's say static reads, and we do it the way we always do in go.
We create a variable.
I'll call my own file server because it's serving files.
That's a sign the value of HTP Dot file server right there.
And that requires one parameter, but it has to be in a specific format.
So we'll take each to http d.r and we'll say look for everything in dot slash public, the public folder
at the root level of this application.
And now we can create a root account dot roots right there.
Dot handle.
And we're going to look for everything in the public, followed by a star.
And then we strip the prefix http dot strict prefix, and we're going to strip it down to slash public
using file server.
So those two lines of code allow us to serve all of the content, the assets in the public folder of
our application by going to the root, whatever your server name is, slash.
Public slash the following, so that's pretty straightforward.
Now there's one more change we need to make in our tax package before we go too much further, and I'm
going to do it now, otherwise chances are I will forget.
So I'm going to switch to the securitized package and I'm going to go to the in it bit.
So that is in this us.
I'm looking for the listing and serve it, which is right here.
This secret routes, it worked great when we were testing a hard coded route in the routes file in the
silver tax package.
But this actually needs to be changed to see routes like that because that's the one we're accessing
in our aked app routes, in the other package, in our My App project.
So let's get that change done now before I forget.
OK.
So what we want to do next, of course, is we have these routes, this routes file.
We want to be able to add routes, something like this.
Let's say we're going to call a dart app, dart routes, not render routes and then say a get request
for the home page for our application.
And what I'd like to do next, of course, is put a handler here, maybe something called home, for
example, but the way that we have our application structured.
If you look at those folders, we created quite a few lectures ago now.
One of those folders is called handlers, which means my handlers are supposed to be in that folder
and in the go world.
If you're in your own folder, you are a package.
So we need to actually create a package for handlers.
Let's do that really quickly.
So inside the Hammers folder or create a new file, which I'll call handlers don't go.
And of course, it requires a package declaration package handlers.
So let's create a type so we can create an instance of this and use it in our application.
And I'll call it handlers and struct, and we'll give it one member for now app, which is a pointer
to celebrities, top celebrities.
OK, now that I have that, let's just really quickly put together a home function handler that we can
use.
So func and h pointer two handlers in this case, because we're in a package.
And I'll just call it home.
And because it's a handler, it requires two parameters a response writer, which I'll call W http response
writer and a pointer to a request, our Typekit request.
And here finally is where we're going to use that render package.
We built in this Alatas package, and it's really straightforward.
So we'll check for an error here is assigned the value of From H, which is our receiver Typekit app,
which is a member or field in that receiver Typekit render, which we now have access to.
And I want to render a page and the page I want a renter requires four parameters.
If you recall the response freighter, the request, the name of the template which is home, and two
pieces of data.
But I'll just pass meal for both of those kneeling, Neal.
OK.
If error is not equal to nil, then I'll just take advantage of the error logger in my celerity package.
So each app dot error logged on print line.
I'll just say error rendering and then whatever the error was.
OK, so now if we go back to our roots file, I can change this to aid handlers at home.
But of course, we still haven't initialized that handlers.
So let's go take care of that.
So let's go right from the start.
Got a main dog.
So we're looking for in it application.
And let's say, let's get rid of this debug line.
You don't need that anymore.
Let's create a new handler right here.
So I'll say my handlers can call it whatever I want, but that works.
My handlers assign the value of a reference to the handlers.
Package dog handlers node is populate its field, which is just apt, and that becomes self.
And then down here, we need to add the handlers type to our application.
So let's find that and add handlers.
And that's a pointer to handlers, dog handlers.
So back to our unit celebrities.
And here we can now, say handlers, is my handlers.
So the last thing we have to do, we have our handlers, we have our roots file, but at no point have
we told the celebrities back end to add our roots to its default roots, which just consist of middleware
right now.
And fortunately, that's pretty easy.
We just here, say app.
Typekit app.
And that's hilarious.
Dot roots is now equal to.
Popped up roots, because what we're doing in this function, Apport Roots, which is this one, is
we're taking the existing roots from our receiver and we're adding these roots to it.
So back here, we're effectively overriding the default roots, which we got from celebrities with the
roots from celebrities, plus our own roots.
All right.
So if we did everything right, I should be able to open my terminal window.
Make sure that this isn't running, make stop and say make start.
And switched to our Web browser and go to local host 4000.
And there it is, it rendered the template for us.
So the nice thing about this is although we've had to do a fair bit of work right now, by the time
someone actually installs a new celebrity application using the command line utility, we're going to
be building before too long.
They're not going to have to do any of this stuff that will already exist when they start in effect.
What they're going to have is this a very simple mean go file?
And this are ready to edit roots file, and we're going to make it as painless as possible for people
to render their content.
Now, of course, so far we're only rendering go templates.
And as I said a couple of times, what I want to focus on a great deal more in this course with respect
to rendering in any case, is working with jet templates.
And that's because go templates, as good as they are and they are quite good.
Many people find the syntax a little awkward.
For example, instead of saying if X equals y, you say if e q x y and some people find that syntax
a little bit awkward.
Jet templates will give the end user something much more familiar in most cases.
And also jet templates are quite a bit faster than GO templates.
It will support both in any case.
All right, so our next step is to extend or improve our rendering package, insularity us to support
jet templates, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.