Before we move on to working with jet templates in our render package, I just want to do a little bit
of cleanup.
A couple of lectures ago we created this function you see here in celebrities don't go in the celebrities
package and it's called Create Renderer, and I clearly was caffeine deprived, but I put this together
because this is far more complex than it actually needs to be.
First of all, we don't need to return anything here at all.
And secondly, we don't need a parameter here at all.
In fact, we have access to everything we need right from the receiver.
So we're not going to return anything here.
And these become CS.
And all we have to do here is say, see, dot rendered is equal to my render a reference to my render.
OK, and then back up here, of course, that means we need to simplify this code to nothing more than
this.
And get rid of that parameter.
And that is ever so much better.
OK.
So that which is a little bit of clean up.
And as I said, that was unnecessarily complicated code where it was passing parameters and changing
the receiver, and I could have done everything with the receiver.
I blame it on a distinct lack of caffeine.
So let's move on.