So far, our system only has support for GO templates, and we want to add support for additional templating
systems.
And in this course, we're just going to add one more.
The jet template system and this is found in the jet repository, GitHub dot com slash cloudy kit slash
jet.
And there is a link to this GitHub repo in the course resources for this lecture.
So let's go install it and then we'll play with it a little bit later on.
So installation, as usual, is pretty simple.
Let's go back to our Visual Studio code and make sure you're in the Celebrity House package and open
a terminal window and type.
Go get GitHub dot com or spell that right slash cloud kit with a Capital C and a capital K. SEAL or
you DIY K.R.I.T. slash jet slash D6.
And if there's a later version when you're taking this course, I strongly recommend you stick with
version six and then worry about upgrading it later on, and that'll make it much easier for you to
follow along.
So hit return.
It goes and gets it, and now it's added to my gold file.
And the very first thing I'll do is I will add a tape to my celebrity struct right here in Silver Costco
because we're going to need this.
So I'll put it right after render and I will add or call it jet views.
And it will be a reference to a pointer to jet, which we just imported.
Dot set right there, and I'll make sure it imported the right one.
No, I've got version three.
I want version six.
Clearly, I've been using this for a long time.
OK, so now we have a member in our celerity struct that we can use when we have to render things.
Now let's get down to the bottom of the new function, and the new function is right here.
So just before I create the renderer, I'm going to create it because we might need it VAR views and
that will be equal to Jet Dot new set.
I'm going to give it a few parameters jetport new OS file system loader and that will go to format.
Don't sprint f.
This is the argument for it and now my pattern I'm going to or my format pattern a placeholder for a
string.
SplashNews.
And not surprisingly, this is going to have a path as its substitution.
OK.
So this is where we'll find our jet templates and it'll just be at the root level of our application
slash views.
And the second thing I'm going to put it in there, it's optional, but it's great where you're in development
is jetport in development mode.
And that will just make our lives easier as a redevelopment.
OK.
And then after I create that, I'll simply populate see jet use equal to views.
So now we have a jet set, which is absolutely critical to load jet templates and work with them.
We have that added to the celebrity experience.
Now let's go to create renderer right here.
Now Create Renderer creates a renderer using render render.
And that is something we're going to have to modify a little bit.
So I'm on a command.
Click on that on Windows or Control, click on a Mac and jump right to it.
OK.
I'm going to add a field to the render type and it will be called jet views, and it's going to be a
type a pointer to Jet Dot set.
And let's make sure it imports the right one.
It did.
Good.
OK.
So that's available to us.
Now let's go back to celebrities.
Don't go back to the create renderer function, and I'm going to populate jet views with C dot jet views.
And all of this is just so we have a means of accessing that jet set.
We created a couple of minutes ago in our renderers and without that, we can't render jet templates
at all.
Now let's go back to the rendered Argo file and look at what we have right now when we render a page
we call Render Dot page.
And right now, we only have support for GO.
And in fact, we want to render jet templates.
So obviously what we're going to do here in the second case statement in our switch.
This we're going to return something like Dot Jet page, and it's going to take some parameters.
It will take the writer to write to.
So our response writer the request, so we know what to do when we write to the response writer.
The View we want to render variables and I'm calling them variables because of the way that jet handles
passing data templates and then data.
Now that function doesn't exist yet.
So let's go build it.
So I'll create a new function funk with the receiver of, and I'll call it, see a pointer to render.
And it's going to be called check page, and it will take his parameters.
H.
HTP Response Writer.
And that's what we're going to write to our which is a pointer to a request template name, which is
just a string that tells us what template to render some variables and some data, both of type interface,
so we can pass anything to those and it will return potentially in error.
So the first thing we'll do is create a variable ver and it's going to be VARs.
That's the name of the variable jetport vermouth and a jetport VAR map is a data structure that Jet
uses to pass the data to templates.
So we created an empty jet VAR map variable.
Then we check to see if variables, which was passed as a parameter to this function.
If it's equal to nil, then Veras is equal to make jet version, which will initialize and make it empty
because the variable itself effectively has no value online.
63.
But if it's not empty, if we receive some information in that version that variables data, then we
make VARs equal to variables and we cast it to a jetport, verma, because we already have data in there.
OK.
That way, variables is of the correct format or in the correct format before we try to do anything.
OK, now, just like we did when we were rendering a go page, we also want to deal with the situation
where we have some information in our template data.
So to assign the value of a reference to template data
and we'll just make it empty.
And then we check to see if data, which is the last parameter, passed this function.
If that's not equal to nil, then TD becomes data cas to a pointer.
Template two.
Now we have our template data in both forms.
Both the variables and the data parameters passed to this function have now been converted to the format
they need to be before we can render a jet template.
Now how do we load the template and render it?
Well, let's create a variable called T for template and we'll check for an error.
Those are assigned the value of C dot jet views
dot jet template.
And this will go and get the template for us, and the template name is just going to be the first part
of the name without the jet extension.
So let's add the jet extension to whatever name is passed to this function format as print off as print
f and our format string is just percent s dot jet and we substitute.
Template name.
And we checked for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And I'm on a log it here, long the print line.
The error and I'll return the error.
Otherwise, we execute it if error is equal to T, which has the method execute right from the jet package,
W Vase and TD.
And if the error is not equal to nil, then not surprisingly will log it again.
Logged up print line.
The error return the error.
Otherwise, return nil,
so let's give this a comment.
Jet page renders a template
using the jet templating engine.
OK.
And we probably should put one four go page here to
go Page renders a standard
go template.
So now we have these functions available to us.
And the next step, of course, is to create a jet template and try it out, and we'll get started on
that in the next lecture.