So let's try out the rendering a jet template, and we will actually use a jet template this time around.
We'll do that in the next lecture or the one after that, we'll just make sure that things work as expected.
So if you look in my I'm looking in the My App project, and if you look in my views folder, I have
a file I've created called test jet Typekit.
And all that's in it is a line of text.
This is from jet.
OK, so create one of those.
Then let's go to our roots file and let's try this out.
So before we do that, of course, I have to open my terminal window and type go mode vendor just to
get the latest version of celebrities in my vendor folder there.
That's done.
It will just create a test route right here.
A really simple one and will inline everything so we won't even create a handler this time around.
So a dot app dot roots don't get because we're just going to make a get request to slash jet and in-line
a function here.
Func Whv Typekit Response Writers is the first parameter and our a pointer to don't request is the second
parameter.
And we'll just call a Dot App Dot Render Jet page there, and that requires a few parameters.
W R and the name of my template is test jet without the extension.
And then Neil and Neil for the two days.
OK.
So let's give that a try.
So we'll open our terminal and type make start.
And go to my Web browser and let's go to HP Collins slash local host 4000 and we should get the go templates.
There it is.
And now let's put slash check after that.
And there it is.
This is from Jack.
So our render functionality using templates, both go templates and jet templates works as expected.
But the great thing about this, if you go back to our roots file, is that I can call Jet Page directly
or I could call go page directly, or I can just call page and go with the default one.
So that works really well.
So in the next lecture, we'll try creating a handler and creating some actual jet templates and play
with that for a bit.
And then we'll write some tests.