So let's get started working with jet templates, and right now I'm in the My App project and I'm looking
at the dart on file, and the very first thing I'm going to do is change my default renderer right here
at the very end of the file from go to jet.
OK, and then I'll delete Test Jetport Jet because I don't need that anymore, so I'll just delete that.
Yes.
Move it to the trash and I'll go to my roots file and I'll get rid of this as well.
That temporary route we wrote last time just to make sure that everything worked as expected.
OK, so now we're back as we were just before the previous lecture, except we've removed the handler,
the test handler and the roots file, and we've made that one change in the dart on file.
So now let's go to our Reviews folder, and let's get started with jet templates.
Right in here.
I'm going to create a new folder inside of The View's folder, and I'm going to call it layouts ella
y o ut's OK.
And inside of layouts, or create a new file called Base Dot Jet, and it will be our base layer.
So and if you look at the course resources for this lecture, you'll find the file.
You can download code based object, just download it and move it into this folder or copy and paste
its contents as I am right now, because there's no point in your watching me, right?
Basic jet template.
It's very straightforward.
This is a simple HTML file with some jet directors on it.
Now the next thing I want to do is I'm going to make my life a little bit easier by going here and choosing
extensions and searching for jet right there.
And you can see the second from the top right now as I search is the jet template engine.
Let's try that and see if it works.
I've actually never used it before.
We're about to find out.
So I'll install it.
There it is.
It's now installed.
Now, if I go back to base jet, that's much cleaner.
OK, now this is a base layout template, and as you might expect from a good template engine we can
actually do includes some yields and all that sort of thing, sort of like blade templates in the Laravel
world.
Now this is a really simple template.
It's a basic HTML file HTML five that imports bootstrap and that has some directives.
For example, here on Line eight, I have yield browser title and you'll notice that it has opening
and closing parentheses and you do need those.
OK, so this is something that I can override on any template that uses this layer.
Similarly, down here I have CSC.
If I want to have custom CSC on a per page basis, I have the basic content and a word of caution.
Don't ever name your content area content.
That's a reserved word in the template world.
So instead of call it page content and down here, I might have JavaScript on a per page basis.
So there is my basic base template for this project.
Now, inside of the View Views folder, I'm going to create a new file not in the layouts, but in in
the views folder.
And I'll call it HomeKit.
And let's make sure that this template uses the one we just built, so it extends and this is not a
standard go template directive, it's one specific to jet.
It extends in double quotes, dot slash layouts, slash they jet.
OK, so now it knows that it's going to use that base template and I'll have the block and I'll call
it system like that with the quotation, with the double parentheses around it or after it, I'll just
say and not put anything in there.
And down here, I'll say block.
And this one is page content.
I'll just leave it empty for now, and I'll fill it in in a minute and then I'll have block Jess.
And not surprisingly, and an I'm going to put it in here right now is I'll open up my home page at
10 p.m. and I'll copy this stuff right here.
OK, so I copy that.
Everything is in between the body text, and I'll go back to home jet and I'll paste it in there and
then I'll make sure I've got what I actually need in here.
So starting with a div container and it's ending with that and what's in my base jet?
I have a div container, so all I really need is the call that the innermost column.
So I'll get back to home jet and find the inner most, which is this right here?
And I'll delete these too, which means I can delete these two and I'll just bring this over to make
it format a little bit nicer.
OK?
And as you can see, this is now very, very easy to work with a page that extends the base layer.
Now let's go over to our handlers.
Now, let's change this.
Instead of saying, Well, you do have to change anything, I don't think I need to change a thing.
This should all work.
So let's say make stop in our terminal.
Make start.
And with no other changes, I should be able to reload that page, so let me go back to my browser and
go to the top here and get rid of slash jack because that URL doesn't exist anymore.
And Chris return.
And I have nothing.
So we have unresolved block browser title I something.
So back to my home, Joe, and we'll put the block browser title, block browser title.
And in there, I'll just say celebrities house doesn't matter content and save that now because I'm
in development mode.
When we set up our jetset at the very couple of lectures ago, I shouldn't have to restart my application.
And that's why I put that directive in there, because it makes things a little simpler.
So back to my web browser.
And there it is now, it says, go templates, let's make it sure it's actually that one because it's
not true anymore.
We'll go back to Visual Studio code and say Jet templates in Honda Jet.
Go reload that page.
And there it is.
So that works as expected.
All right now I'm going to stop developing new code for the next lecture or two, and we'll start writing
some tests because we have written any tests at all.
And that's generally frowned upon in pretty much any programming language.
But particularly when you're dealing with the go, people expect to see tests, particularly employers,
even employers who aren't entirely sure what a test is.
They look for those files, so we better write some and we'll get started on that in the next election.