Hello and welcome to Golang programming language course in the independent musician, we talked about
simple for loop, and in this session, we want to talk about the ideas, loops and control statements.
For Loop as Infinite Loop A For Loop is also used as infinite loop by removing all the three excursions
from the for loop.
When the user did not write conditional statement info loop, it means the conditional statement is
true and the loop goes into an infinite loop.
Now you can see the syntax.
Let's go to this code paragraph to illustrate how to use of an infinite loop.
In this case, we want to define an infinite loop and create a message.
So we write for without any expression, open and curly braces and put our statements in curly braces.
So we write FP, go through training language, reformat the cool, save the project and execute the
program.
So go to terminal and run the program by the comment.
Go round the back.
Is this man go?
Now we can see the output.
We could print and go programming language.
And this loop continues infinitely.
So precise control plus C buttons to terminate the execution of programming.
OK.
In order now to prolong the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content in
the next session.
Goodbye.