Hello and welcome to godowns programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about Braekhus statement, and in this session, we want to talk
about the others control statements.
Continuous statement, they continue in a statement and go programming language works somewhat like
a break, a statement.
Instead of forcing termination, a continuous statement force is the next iteration of the loop to take
place as keeping any code in between in case of the for loop continuous statement calls is the conditional
test and increment portions of the loop to the Executive.
Now you can see this syntax.
Let's go to escort Brian to illustrate how to use of continuous statements.
First, define a variable named X and initialized by zero value.
So we write that X by the Typekit equals zero.
Create a loop that works as a vie loop and define the condition, and progress will continue as long
as the value of X is less than eight.
Print value of X valuable indent and one unit two x value.
Now do the following.
So first, define the loop for by the condition x list and eight open and close curly braces and write
our statements here.
Now, in four blocks, we define and f block and said if x equal equals five value added to value to
X and continue the for loop.
So we write if X equals equals to five.
So let's get two iterations E X equals X plus two and continue this statement.
Go out of the if lots and display the value of X.
So we write f f value is per cent d and set the back stretch in and set the X value the end after each.
The iterate the east value, then one by one.
All right, x plus plus reformat the code, save the project and execute the program.
Now go to terminal and wrong go wrong.
The back.
Is this mean that go now we can see the output value is zero one two three four and value seven, and
we don't see values five and six.
The program runs at each time.
First print the value of the variable X and then adds one unit to Variable X until the value of the
X equals five.
In this case, the program into the F block and executes the comment inside the F Black and X two units
to each variable and jumps from two reputation in skips to value five and CS and the continuum for loop.
In order not to put a line in the time of decision, we will finish it and we will continue the content
in the next session.
Goodbye.