So now that we have most of the code changes done, insularity us and my app, it's time to update a
couple of things.
And the two things we need to update our first of all, these skeleton git repository when we create
a new application using celebrities new whatever your project name is.
It goes and grabs a gift repository, clones it and then makes changes to it using the Seelye automatically.
So we'll have to make changes to the skeleton get repository, which in my case just means updating
my app and pushing a version of that to my get repository.
The second thing we need to do is to make some minor changes to the command line application itself.
So we'll get started with that right now.
So first thing I want to do is look at my app.
Now there are some things that are not on the get repository that will be there automatically as soon
as I commit and push them.
For example, we have this config folder that has database dot.
Why?
And of course, that's used by our version of soda that we've encoded right into our project.
So we'll want to put an empty version of that up, and that's easy enough in the same way.
If we look in the handlers folder, we have this handlers underscore test go.
And I don't want to put all of these tests here because that was just for our purposes as we were making
sure that things work the way that they're supposed to.
Now you could, of course, just comment about certain tests and leave them as examples, and that would
be extremely helpful.
But typically, if you're going to write something like this for other people to use, you would actually
write some real documentation.
And I'm not going to do that, or at least I'm not going to do that while you watch me.
I'm not going to record a lecture with me writing documentation, but it's something you may wish to
do.
So what I'll do for our purposes is just leave the one test that I know will always be there, and that's
the home page test, and I'll just get rid of the rest of them.
So I'll select these and delete those.
OK?
And if there's anything else here that needs to be pushed to the git repository, it'll just happen.
OK.
So if we go back to our celebrities project now and we look in the CMT folder and then see a lie and
then the Templates folder, these are the files that are used when we automatically execute some command
that the end user enters.
We use these as files that we copy.
So the first one, of course, is inside these templates folder.
We have the data folder.
We didn't change anything with that, so that should be fun.
OK?
The handler's folder of handlers go that might have changed.
I'm not sure, and I'm not an optimist, and it's easy enough to come down here to handlers in the my
app.
Open up handlers don't go select all copy closes and then open up the template off handlers go down.
Delete what's in there and paste in the new version.
I know that's going to work now.
And yes, we did have some changes, so that's good.
That's good.
Handlers don't go.
Let's see what's in there, so we just have this right now that shouldn't change at all.
That's when you create a new stub handler.
So that's fine.
We didn't make any changes to males, so that should be fine.
What about middleware?
Well, again, there's three files here off.
Don't go off token.
Don't go and remember ICO.
I'm not an optimist, so I'll open up middleware in my app, open ASCO, select all copy and then open
off and go here the text file paste in the new version, just to be sure.
Next is a token.
Select All copy and open up of Dash token.
Go select all paste.
And finally, remember.
So let's remember.
Don't go right here.
Select All Copy.
And remember that no select paste and I should do it for those ones migrations.
Anything change in there?
I don't think so.
We'll find out if I've missed something when we actually try this views.
So we have log in the jet that might have changed as it did.
I believe let's go down to our views in my app.
Right here and open up, log in.
So that includes the logging with GitHub, logging with Google Play Music with those in there.
So I copy that.
Close all of those and open up.
Log in.
Select All Paste.
OK.
That should take care of that.
Next is the dot on the file, and that's definitely changed, so I'll open up the dot on file here in
my app.
Select Go and Copy.
And if I look at the template on which is called on site, it actually uses dollar sign and then in
curly braces and underscore name and is here on line two here for the red as prefix on line 29 and down
here in line thirty five.
Those three places, so I'll select all and paste.
Now I'll get rid of the things that don't belong in there so I can leave at the very bottom with these
three.
For Google, I get rid of this secret.
You don't want to put that in there by default, and I'll get rid of the key.
And I'll get rid of the secret for GitHub.
And get rid of the key.
That's fine.
And I should probably leave these empty as well, because some people may not use WebDAV.
Or SFP
or Mineo?
And the same thing for three.
You don't want to be putting this kind of information in a public repository at all, ever.
So those are gone.
The encryption key leave that empty.
You better spell settings, right, since I'm here anyway, but.
And, of course, this stuff I can leave empty as well, because not everyone will be using the database
at all.
Now, let's fix my app.
That should be Dollar Sun app.
Underscore name and close that and copy this, and we want it for us, prefix.
And we want it for cookie name.
OK, now let's say it's something that should be it for that one.
So the next one is go on, go on.
And of course, that has app name up here as well.
So let's open the other one, because that's definitely changed.
We'll find God in my app and I'll select everything from go one point one seven all the way down to
the bottom here.
Like that, you know, replace this from here.
All the way down to here.
So hopefully that will be correct.
We'll find out when we try it.
Now, I don't immediately see anything else that has to change here in the Templates folder.
So the next step is to go make whatever changes are required in our command line application and to
push our skeleton app up to our repository, which means deleting some things before we do that.
And let me try this out.
So we'll get started on that in the next election.