So the next step is to make some changes to our my app and make sure that's the skeleton app that's
committed to a git repository that our installer will use our command line application uses.
The very first thing you should do is make a backup of your entire my app folder and put it somewhere
where you're not going to lose it.
So make sure you do that because we're going to be deleting a fair bit of the things that we worked
on in the course so far because none of them are necessary for an empty celebrity's application.
So I've already backed mine up, so we'll get started.
So the first thing I'll do is look at my roots file, which is, of course, right here.
Roots don't go in my app and I'm going to delete everything except for the home root and the static
roots, of course.
OK, so I'll delete these.
And they're gone.
And this is basically all that I want to have in the default application, so I'll mount the routes
that are directly from celebrities.
I'll leave that and amount the API routes, which I have to open now and make sure that this is empty
because you don't need that at all.
So there's my first two changes now that I've deleted all of those routes.
I don't need the handlers that are associated with them either.
So let's find handlers and let's open up handlers don't go and see if there's anything there we want
to leave in.
Well, I want to leave in the home route.
No question.
It's all.
Delete this, everything after that.
All the way down to here.
And now we just have the home rule, so that's good.
Any imports break?
No, that's good.
So far, so good.
Now, handlers test, I've left one in there, the test for the home route.
Let's have a look at set up test to make sure there's nothing in there that needs to change.
There is, of course, we don't have this route anymore, so that's gone.
Perfect.
Mail didn't change middleware, do I want to delete anything out of here?
Yes, I do.
As a matter of fact, I also want to delete off handlers don't know anything that was installed when
you type the command from our Seelye that implements authentication.
Those need to be deleted.
So that includes in the data folder.
Remember, token token and user, those can get deleted.
And that means in models, we'll have to delete these three entries here where we return models in the
new command and we'll have to delete these entries up here in the type of models.
OK, so that's fine.
Those are gone.
Then we delete off handlers.
That can go when we go down a little bit further here to auth token and remember and ask, don't go
in middleware, those go.
We look at our mega migrations folder and simply make sure that's entirely empty.
That's gone.
In public, that's fine, those can stay.
Camps should be empty, and it's ignored by get anyway views.
We're going to get rid of celebrities, upload forgot, list us Logan, reset password protester and
upload those all go away.
We just leave the home jet and the associated base layout.
Dawn was not committed to get so it doesn't matter the celebrity binaries, not committed to get, so
it doesn't matter.
Dr. Campos.
Now, I don't see any changes that I really need to make in there, and that should be fine.
OK, go modest is fine.
And as far as I can see, that's all we need to worry about for this.
So my next step and I'm not going to bother making you watch me do this is just to commit this to a
git repository and tag it.
I'm going to tag mine version two because I'll be pushing it to the repository that I used in the first
half of this course.
So do that, and we can move on to the next step, which is updating which skeleton application we pulled
down from.
Get in our Seelye and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.