So I've pushed all the changes for my celebrity, I say application, the skeleton application up to
a repository named GitHub dot com slash t solar slash celebrity house Dash app and of course, your
repository name might be different.
And I have also pushed all of the changes for my celebrity project to its own repository, which is
GitHub dot com slash t solar slash Solaris house.
Now let's try things out, and not everything is going to work back in my I.D., I have opened up the
celebrity app in its own project window, as you can see here, and I've also, as you can see here,
opened up celebrities in its own project.
And there's a few changes I need to make to start with back in this one Celebrity House Dash app.
And that's the skeleton application.
There were a few things I didn't actually do in the last lecture, and none of them are terribly difficult
to fix, but we need to fix them.
So to start with, I emptied out the mail folder because there were two mail templates left over from
when I was testing things, and they don't need to be there in the skeleton application.
So I deleted those.
So the mail folder is empty.
I also, if you open up the database, don't worry, email file in the config folder.
I just removed all of the values next to these keys because not everyone's going to use the database
and we shouldn't be repopulating that with anything.
The third thing I did, and this was an oversight on my part is in the views folder in layouts based
on jet.
I remove that nav tag, the dropdown menu, the menu bar at the top of the screen because those links
all pointed to things that don't exist anymore.
So that's gone.
Now, the next one was over in the celebrities project.
Inside the CMG folder, inside the Templates folder, the dot on file.
Here, if you scroll down to the part, it's line sixty four in my my code, the encryption key.
Remember when I deleted that?
Well, we actually need to put this in here.
Dollar sign.
Brace bracket.
KFYI.
And the reason ends when I run the new command, which you find in New Dongo, I actually use that somewhere
in here.
There it is.
Line fifty seven actually generate a random 32 character string and replace that value right here with
that random character.
So that needs to be there.
Just an oversight on my part.
And the last thing to worry about is actually in the go dot mod text file.
When I did my copy and replace, I actually left this lying down here replacing GitHub dot com slash
whatever the path to your Solaris house folder is.
We don't want to replace that anymore in production.
And in fact, I'm actually also going to just to make things easier.
Delete this line up here where I require the Celerity Project version zero zero zero because that doesn't
exist.
So to make things work a little bit better, what I'll do is delete that line entirely.
Then I'll go back to the new Dot Go file and we close this new dot go.
And if we go down near the bottom here.
Where I do go on tidy right here, what I'm going to do is before I run, go on tidy, I'll actually
just copy all of this right here and paste it after that little message that I'm running, go Monty.
And instead, I will say, Go get it and I'll put in the past name to my celebrity house repository,
which in my case is GitHub dot com slash t solar slash celebrities.
And the reason I'm doing that is that this way I don't have to worry about what version is tagged up
there.
And of course, if you want to tag it and get a specific version, you can do that.
But this way, I'll always get the latest version of what's in the main branch of my repository, and
I'll never put anything in the main branch that hasn't been thoroughly tested, so this should solve
the problem.
And of course, that means I need to come down here and make this an equals operator instead of an assignment
operator.
And that should take care of it.
So in the next lecture, we'll actually try things out and generate a new application and see if things
work.