So I've pushed all of the changes to my skeleton app and to this celebrity application, both up to
the git repositories on GitHub, so make sure you do that.
And now I want to test things out.
So in the celebrities project, I'll open a terminal window and I'll build the new executable, and
all I have to do is type, make, build.
And that should build the executable into the folder named Dist.
So if I do with lastest, there it is.
What I do now is I'll copy that executable to my desktop and you can copy it wherever you want.
But I need to copy the actual file dist celebrities and of course, in windows that celebrities don't
see or something like that.
And I'll copy it to the desktop.
You can copy to whatever folder you want, but I know there's nothing up there on my desktop, so I
can do that.
Now I'll move to my desktop CD desktop and I'll create a new application, a new celerity application
by typing dot slash celebrities like that.
And of course, in windows, you just type to start.
And I'll say new, and I'll call this Test app, and that should create a new folder named Test app.
And it did.
OK, so now let's open that up.
So I'll go to the file menu and open up.
From my desktop, I want test up, so I open that folder and open it.
And I open it in a new window, and there it is.
Now let's open a terminal window and see if it works.
Oh, I should have to do at this point is say, make start.
So it's running, that's a good sign.
Let's go over to our Web browser and see if it works.
I'll open a new tab and go to local host 4000.
And it seems to work exactly as it should.
Now we haven't tried any of this new functionality, and we'll do that in the next few lectures.
But so far it seems like my celebrities command on application is doing exactly what it should.
All right, let's take a little bit of time and just test out some of the functionality and make sure
that everything works the way that it should.