So we know that our new application starts properly, and now we want to try a few things out, and
I'm not going to try every single thing, but I'll try a few just to make sure that things are working
as expected and leave the remainder as an exercise for you.
So to start with, let's make sure our application is not running.
Make stall perfect.
Now I want to test, say, make off and maybe the cash.
So to do that?
Of course, I have to set up my database first, so I'll go to config and then database start why email
and I'll put in the things that I find right here in Docker compose.
So by default, we're using post-cruise.
And there's the information, so let's fill that it dialect Postgres database Solara tops user Postgres
password, password host use, local host and port use five four three two.
Perfect.
Now let's do the same thing in our dart on file right here.
We'll find a database database.
Typekit Postgres host is a local host port is five four three two.
Database user is Postgres.
The password is password celerity.
US is the database name and we use disable.
OK, now I have that setup while we're at it.
Before we go any further, let's just set up a cache and we'll use Badger.
OK, and I won't bother setting anything else up at this point.
Let's try this out.
So first of all, I need to start Docker so Docker compose of the dashboard.
Now, word of caution.
It can take a couple of minutes for this to run the very first time you run a new Docker instance,
and I ran it just before this lecture, so mine should be going now.
So I should be able to take, make start and have this work.
And no, it hasn't started up yet, so I was a little ambitious.
There it is.
Now it's running.
So let's make sure it's still it is still up and running.
I just go to my web browser and reload this page.
Perfect.
So that's all running as it should be.
Now let's try this.
I have my latest build of celebrities in this folder, so let's try putting the server in maintenance
mode that slashed celebrities down.
And I go back to my Web browser and reload this, and it says Page not found, so we left something
out.
Let's see what that was.
I believe it was probably.
In the public folder.
Yeah.
I don't have the default server is under maintenance in there, so I'll have to copy that over and post
it up on the Skeleton Celebrity's application.
But that's simple enough.
At least it.
It did take it into maintenance mode.
So now I should be able to say dot slash Celerio, toss up and come back here and reload this, and
it should be live again.
That worked perfectly.
So let's see what else we have got.
Slash the Loretta's health.
Let's try this one.
Make off.
So that's flush.
Celebrities make off.
And that should hopefully create and run the migrations for the authentication tables and create the
models and middleware.
Let's see if that works.
OK, so it looks like it created it.
Let's make sure the necessary files are there.
So views, yeah, it put those views there, perfect.
And it has.
Under middleware, we should have our off middleware, and we do.
And then under models or data, it should have models don't go and I should have remember token and
user and it does perfect.
Well, that all seemed to work as expected.
So as I said, I'm not going to go through all of the necessary functionality for this.
I'm reasonably sure that most of it works and I will test it after this lecture is over.
And if I missed anything, I'll put it up there.
But the only thing I'm going to worry about right now is copying over a sample file in the public folder
that's displayed when maintenance mode is alive.
And all I have to do for that is put it up on my skeleton application's GitHub repository.
And that should take care of it.
So at the end of the day, we now have an application that allows us to develop data database functionality
very quickly.
Full authentication is in place.
We have API routes in and standard web routes.
We have support for various different file systems.
We have a generic file uploader that will upload to any file system that we support.
We have caching, we have sessions, we have a lot of the functionality that you need in order to develop
a sophisticated, modern web application.
And I think that's an excellent start.