Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in this session, we want to talk about
the protocol barter concept.
Political warfare.
Political boxers, usually referred as put it above, is a protocol developed by Google to allow serialization
and this realization of a structured data.
Google developed it with the goal to provide a better way compared to similar to make systems communicate.
So they focused on making it simpler, smaller, faster and more maintainable, then examined.
But as you will see, this protocol even surpassed Jason with better performance, better maintainability
and smaller size.
You define how you want your data to be structured once.
Then you can use a spatial generated source code to easily write and read your structured data to a
variety of data streams and using a variety of languages.
They are essentially a data format like Jason or Eastment, i.e. they can install structured data which
can be serialized and this serialized by the wide number of languages.
Let's understand these with a few examples.
Imagine you are storing data about books.
So as Sam, policemen were killed like this, you can see the scene syntax.
He could represent the same as transfer data using a small footprint with Jason.
Now you can see the syntax for Jason.
And if we were to represent these using political buffers, it would look like something like this.
Now at this school, the size of both the Jason and the political buffer seem to be quite similar.
But as your data increases, a lot of the size and complexity gets shaved off, which can lead to smaller
and more efficient payloads for your application.
How does it differ from Jason?
It is important to note that although Jason and Porter, both messages can be used interchangeably,
these technologies were designed with different goals.
Jason, which stands for JavaScript object notation is simply a message format that arose from a subset
of the JavaScript programming language.
Jason messages are exchanged in text format and no days they are completely independent and supported
by virtually all programming languages.
Portal both, on the other hand, is more than a message format.
It is also a set of rules and tools to define and exchange these messages.
Google, the creator of this protocol, has made it open source and provides tools to generate code
for the must use programming language around, like JavaScript, Java, Ruby, C-sharp, the Object,
C, Python, C++ and Go Land.
Besides their portal, Boff has more data ties than JSON like enumerators and methods, and it is also
heavily used on our PC's remote processor costs in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.