Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course in this session.
We want to talk about rest APIs concept.
What is API?
Application programming interface, or API, is a software interface that allows two applications to
interact with each other without any user intervention.
API is a collection of software functions and procedures.
In simple terms, API means a software code that can be accessed or executed.
API is defined as a code that held two different softwares to communicate and exchange data with each
other.
It offers products or services to communicate with other products and services without having to know
how they are implemented.
What it actually means is it exposes functionality without exposing internals.
If you're programming the language that supports running functions or methods, you would totally understand
what I am talking about.
In fact, it can be said that using different API, two different machines with different operating
systems can communicate with each other without any dependency.
An API could be a function, you wrote, or to function from a library or a method from a framework
or a sticky end point.
API voting.
Let's see how API works.
We use a simple daily life example to understand the concept of API.
Imagine you want to go to a restaurant in order your favorite food first welcomes to you, gives you
a menu card and you will provide personalize it order.
After some time, you will get your order from the waiter.
However, it is not that simple as it looks, as there is some process that happens in between here.
The waiter plays an important part, as you will.
Neither go to the kitchen to collect your order, nor will you tell the kitchen staff what you want
all this done by the waiter.
API answer does the same by taking your request and just like the vendor, tell the system what you
want and give a response back to you, a request is sent from client to server in the form of VIP or
as if Typekit or post or puth or delete request after death.
A response comes back from server in the form of a resource which can be anything like Estima example,
image or JSON.
But now JSON is the most popular format being used in web services.
Application programming interfaces consist of technical specification, pointing to data exchange option
between applications.
The applications communicate to a user interface following a process written application that needs
the functionality of the other application, calling the applications API and specifying how the functionality
should be provided.
Assuming the request is authorized, the target application and receiving the request returns the functionality.
Why would we need an API?
Here are some reason for using API application programming interface acronym API has two different softwares
to communicate and exchange data with each other.
It helps you to emit content from inside or application more efficiently.
APIs can access app.
The delivery of services and information is more flexible.
Content generated can be Pompey's automatically.
It allows the user or a company to customize the continent's services, which they use the most in software
needs to change over time and APIs health plan Typekit pay changes.
Features of API.
Here are some important features of API.
It offers a valuable service data function.
It helps you to plan a business model.
Simple, flexible.
Quickly adapted, managed and measured.
And offers good developer support in order not to prolong the time off decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.