Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course.
In the previous session, we could define select a student based name function for rest later.
And now it's time to implement another function that is supposed to fit on a student's from a student
table of person database.
So define the function name like select all students.
This function accept two parameters first and object from study participants.
Writer.
And second, a pointer off basically request.
So right
font
select.
All the students
set the parameters response.
Writer response
is Typekit draft response writer and set a pointer parameter as istituti request request.
Poynter Institute of Request.
Now we want to implement the body of the function.
This function is supposed to return the information of all student based on the end point.
Now first connect to the database, then call the query to call select all students.
So we define a variable like a students call him equals calling DevTools.
And from the DevTools in walking, select all a student function, go out, select all the students.
Now we have to send the return value of the select metal to the client we GS and the object from the
student list.
But you have to convert the object adjacent and send it to the client as JSON format that do this through
the JSON package.
So we write JSON
and calling neo encoder function in response as parameter for each new encoder and set response and
as parameter for eat.
This function returns a new encoder that writes writer and calling encode function instead of student
in this parameter for it and code, and set the students as arguments for it.
OK, reformat the code and save the project.
So we were able to implement the methods of sending all students from the database and sending it to
the client.
We arrest API.
OK, in order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish time.
We will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.