Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course.
In the previous session, we were able to implement the rest config function and could define foreign
opponents for calling rest API and indecision.
We want to continue the other concept.
For example, if you want to call the rest API related to calling all the students, we have do the
following we put this line inside the comment.
This end point is for calling all students first defined domain because we want to call the project
on our machine.
We used localhost as domain, so we write low column, fast column
support, A380
and CIT Pat Perfect's.
It's less rare.
This less API and CIT pat of calling all of Sudan's API in this case is established to students.
It's less the student, so we could create a rest API for calling all the students from database localhost.
Colin, 88, is less risk as much API as a student, and you also write these in phones for other apps,
for example, for select a student based name.
You can write local pass calling 880 is less packed or fix less API and pat for select.
The student based name is if a student is less name is less student slash name.
And for at AMU, the student to the database, we can write localhost column 880.
Just last rest is less API as part graphics and path for saving you.
The student ease as a student is last at this list.
The student is a class act and API for to update.
We can write localhost call and 880 Flash Paper Fixes, Rest API and path for after the student is as
good as student.
This last edit student, it's less.
It's OK now we should implement a method that is responsible for running the rest service on the server,
so create a method name like rest, start,
find rest.
Start this function.
Accept a string parameter as a main address, for example.
In this case, out addresses localhost, so set a parameter like endpoint
by the time stream
and return an error object as writer type of.
This function is supposed to calm the rest conflict method to calm the risk-benefit method.
You need the rotor as the input parameter, so we first create a new rotor defined a variable light
rotor calling equals calling new motor function from Mark's package marks the new rotor.
Now we could create a rotor, so calling this conflict function and set created water as argument for
it.
This config and set water as argument for it now, right return for the function so we can reason and
serve function from the TV package return.
They still don't listen and serve function.
This function accept two arguments.
First is important and second is the handler.
So we sit and point and rotor.
OK.
We were able to make configuration for the rest liar first create a rest config function that contains
forward and point, uh, first for select all the students.
OK, this parses API, especially students and API, a student for select a student based name, rest
API for added student and rest API for any student, and defined another function like resource that
is responsible for running the rest service on the server.
In order not to prolong the time of the session, we will finish you.
Then they will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.