Hello and welcome to the go and programming language course in the Pentagon's session, we talked about
this API's concept and indecision.
We want to talk about the others concept.
Types of APIs in terms of released policies, APIs can be private partner and public private API.
These are application software interfaces are designed for improving solutions and services within an
organization in house.
Developers or contractors may use these APIs to integrate as a company's I.T. system or applications.
Build new systems or customer facing apps leveraging existing systems, even if apps are publicly available.
The interface itself remains available only for those working directly with the API publisher.
The private estratégia allows a company to fully control the API usage partner API.
Partner opinions are only apparently prompt, but share with business partners who have signed an agreement
with the publisher.
The common use case for partner APIs is software integration between two parties, a company that grants
partners with access to data or tapping ability.
Benefits from extra revenue streams.
At the same time, it can monitor how the exposed digital assets are used in ensure whether to party
solutions using their APIs, provide decent user experience in Maine to incorporated identity in their
apps.
Public APIs.
Also known as developer facing or external, these APIs are available for any third party developers.
The public API program allows for increasing brand assurance and receiving an additional source of income
than properly executed.
These are two types of public APIs open in commercial ones.
The open API definition suggests that all features of such an API are public and can be used without
restrictive terms and conditions.
For instance, it's possible to build an application that utilize the API without explicit approval
from the API supplier or mandatory license fees.
The definition also states that the API description and any related they can mention must be openly
available, and the API can be freely used to create and test applications.
API use cases API can be classified according to the systems for which they are designed.
Database API Database API enable communication between and that application and a database management
system.
Developers work with the database by running queries to access data, changed tables and etc.
They did open seven.
Database API, for example, allows users to write unified queries for different databases.
Both proprietary and open source.
Another example is AWS Database API, which is an embedded into Oracle Rest Data Services, Operating
Systems APIs.
This group of APIs defines how applications use the resources and services of operating systems, every
OS has its sets of APIs.
For instance, Windows API or Linux API by Terminal users faces API and channeled into not API.
Apple provides API reference for Mac OS and iOS.
In its developer, Dutcher mentioned APIs for building applications for Apple's Mac OS desktop operating
system are included in Kirkwall set of developer tools.
Remote appearance.
Remote APIs define the standards of interaction for applications running on different machines.
In other words, one software product accesses resources located outside the device that requested,
which explains the name.
Since two remotely located applications are connected over communications networks, particularly the
internet, most remote APIs are written based on very standards.
VVIP, ap, ice.
This API class is the most common lib APIs, Pearl White, machine readable data in functionality transfer
between web based systems, which represent client server architecture.
These APIs mainly deliver Acworth from web applications and responses from server using Hypertext Transfer
Protocol, or HTP.
Developers can use web APIs to expand the functionality of their apps or sites.
Two types of APIs are first server side.
Server side Web API is a programmatic interface that consist of one or more publicly exposed and points
to a defined records response message system.
It is typically expressed in JSON or expand the client site.
A client site, what API is a programmatic interface helps to extend functionality within a web browser
or other Typekit client.
Examples of that API are like Google Maps.
APIs allow developers to emit Google Maps and web pages by using a German script or flashing interface.
YouTube API allows developers to integrate YouTube videos and functionality into websites or applications.
Twitter offers two APIs.
The rest API helps developers to access Twitter data, and the Search API provides methods for developers
to interact with tweets or search, and Amazon's API gives developers access to Amazon's product selection
in order not to prolong the time of decision.
We will finish it and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.