Hello and welcome to the Golang programming language course.
In the previous session, we talked about APIs and in decision, we want to talk about the others concept.
API specifications and protocols.
The goal of API specifications is to standardize data exchange between web services.
In this case, a standardization means that the ability of diverse systems written in different programming
languages and or running on different OSes or using different technologies to seamlessly communicate
with each other.
Remote parameter kon or our PC that APIs may add to a resource exchange principles based on a remote
procedure call.
This protocol is specifies the interaction between client server based applications.
One program, client requests, data or functionality from another program server located in another
computer on the network, and the server sends the required response on a PC is also known as a SOP
protein or function called one of two ways to implement a remote processor.
Colonies swap service, object access protocol or swap.
Swamp is a lightweight protocol for exchanging structured information in decentralized, distributed
environment, according to the definition by Microsoft that developed it.
Generally speaking, this a specification contains the syntax rules for requests and response messages
sent by web applications, APIs that comply with the principles of sweat in even some of the messaging
between systems through HTTP or Simple Mail Transfer Protocol or SMTP for transferring made extensible
markup language.
Or it is a simple and very flexible text format widely used for data storage and exchange over the internet
or other networks.
SML defines a set of rules for encoding documents in a format that both humans and machines can read.
The markup language is a collection of symbols that can be placed in the text to detonate and label
the parts of the text documents examined text that humans contain self descriptive tags of data objects,
which makes them is little readable.
Slap is mostly used with the enterprise web based software to ensure high security of transmitted data.
Stop APIs are preferred among providers of payment gateways.
Identity management and CRM solutions, as well as financial and telecommunications services.
PayPal's public API is one of the commonly known swap APIs.
It's also frequently used for legacy systems support.
Representational state transfer or arrest?
The term race was introduced by computer scientist Roy Fielding in a distortion in 2000.
Unlike SLAPP, which is the Port of Call, Ernest is a software architectural style with six constraints
for building applications that work over HTP, often lip.
The World Wide Web is the most common realization and application of the architectural style.
Rest is considered a simpler alternative to swap, which made developers find difficult to use because
it requires writing a lot of code, complete every text and falling to a similar structure for every
message sent in this course.
The one to Explorist technology auction In order not to prolong the time of decision, we will finish
sheet and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.