Hello and welcome to the Golden Age programming language course in the previous session.
We could define iconic method for connection to the database.
And in this session, we want to create another functions to perform craft operations.
First, the assault by writing the quiz related to the select statement, so create a function to select
all the students records and return as students, Eric.
So we write funk,
select all students and return tie.
Array of model got a student?
Now calling connect function for initializing my school driver, my name and datasource name, this
function returns a DBI object from a school package.
This gives us access to metals contained in the package to perform crud operations.
So define a variable like DB calling equals and invoking chronic function.
After creating a deep object, the Invoke query method that it executes a query that acts it is cruel
curious statement as string parameter and returns rolled and over objects.
So first, define two variables like roles and erode column equals the B dot query.
In this case, we want to see all the students in the student table.
So we should use select query statement.
So we write Select Query has a string parameter.
Select a star for the student.
Go to the next line check earner status, if at all.
Like the fat on the road, how we use the ether for clothing to create a DB object.
Ether DB don't close.
We create the least of a student strike to add to each new student that is read from the database,
from the student table and at the end of fetching data from the database, the student list is displayed
by the method return value.
So do you find it?
Very.
It is like a students column equals
model dots.
Students
now put the return value of the query inside a up to access each of the rows by the next function.
So we write for those dots next.
Next, fashion prepares the next results are all for reading with this method.
If returns to an success or false, if there is no mixed result draw or and it all happened while preparing
it, so create an object from a student.
This rock is student calling it cool modern art student.
And calling it method on Rove's resolve to it recalls one by one, the skin crawl is the Collins in
the car and throw into the values pointed at by destination.
The number of values in this nation must be the same as a number of the Collins in defined an enormous
debate and in scan function at all equals roles not scanned.
Is Student Ideas Pointer Anderson, Student Dot.
IED said a student named Ampersand Student dropped name and set a student age as pointer and her son,
Student Dot H scanned Converse columns read from the database into the following come and go types and
especial type provided by the astute package.
So check your status if they're not equals mean like dots, fatal error, dot arrow and continue.
I will be at each readers record that contains a student to the list of students by the app in function.
Students.
Equals app and function as students, as students
now will return as student and return values of function, return as students.
Now we could define the function and select all the students that fit all the students of a student
table in person database by the select the statement.
Now we want to create another select function.
In this case, we want to fit a student body condition.
Otherwise, we create a query by a very close for this sandpit.
We want to define the function that returns a student base, a student name, first define the function,
then select a student based name.
The packs it and is string as name and return a student based that name value.
So, right, find select a student
based name and set a name as a parameter by the time string named as string and return value is modeled
after students.
Now cutting clinic function for initializing my school driver, so define a variable like TV calling
equals panicked
after creating a deep object.
The invoked 20 year old method that it executes a query that is expected to return at most Marvel query
role method always returns and non mean value.
So defined roles variable and Colin quitted role method roles column equals VB don't query role.
In this case, we want to select a student in a student table by based on the given name, and we should
use Select Query Statement.
We are very close, and so writes the a query as a string parameter.
Select a star from.
A student and said very condition based name where.
Name instead of name value.
Put a question mark equals question mark.
And as a second parameter, we received the name value from the inside the method.
So we right name.
Use differ for closing the creator TBE object, the ether db dot low.
Now we create an object from a student who struck the student card and equals model dot.
A student.
And Corning is gunmetal on the rolls, results right record defined an incredible animal, skin functions
to be right, erode calling equal roles.
Thoughts can set a student i.d.s pointer, ampersand, student I.D. and a student name, anthracite
student name and age ampersand student Dot H.
S can collars columns read from the database into the coming do times and the spatial type white the
misspelled pages.
So first check entry status, if at all not equal.
Is Neil like don't at all dot her or now return a student as return value off function.
If the student is not available, the normal value will be returned with the seller name return per
student.
OK, now we could define a functioning select.
A student based name that reads her is student of a student table in person database by the cynic.
The statement based name value in order not to prolong the time of decision.
Will finish it, and we will continue the content in the next session.
Goodbye.