So this section of the course is all about improving our database migrations, and as you recall from
the first half of this course or the previous version of this course, we actually have migrations built
into our system right now in order to try those out and just to have a quick review.
Let's look at our Docker compose.
Why image, file and the section up here.
I'm using Postgres.
You might be using MariaDB or MySchool, but in any case, you have a section in here for your database.
And in order to try out our existing migration solution, we have to populate some information in the
dot on file.
If you don't already have this, you need to put it in.
So I'll put it here in my daughter on file.
My database type is Postgres.
My host is just local host, my port.
And let's review that to make sure I have it right.
My port here is five four three two.
The standard Postgres port, so five four three two.
And my user, we can see as Postgres right there in the Docker file Docker compose my password is just
password.
My database name is celebrities and I'm not using SSL.
So for Postgres, you use disable.
OK.
So the next time I start my application, it will connect to that Docker image with a Postgres database
running and we'll have access to the database.
OK, now let's open our terminal and make sure you're in the celebrity folder.
Not the My App folder.
And what I'll do is just build the celebrity executable.
Little program we use to generate handlers and migrations and migrations are what interests me right
now.
So I'll build that may build, underscore Cee-Lo.
And that should create a celebrity's executable.
If you're on a Mac or Linux, it'll be called celebrities.
And if you're on Windows, it's called Celebrity X.
So if I go back over to my other tab where I mean the My App folder, I actually have a celebrity's
file now.
So less celebrities.
There it is.
That's an executable.
And if I just run it by itself, Dot Slash Alatas, it gives me a halfa.
And the command I'm interested in here is make migration with a name and that creates two new up and
down migrations in the migrations folder.
So I Migrations folder is right here and it's currently empty.
So now if I type dot slash celebrities make migration and I'll just call it test.
I when I look inside the migration's folder, there should be two files there with some comment that
code.
So the up migration.
And there it is.
It shows a create table with a small comment that also won't run, but it just gives people an indication
as to how they should write migrations.
And the down migration is a comment that I drop table comment.
OK, now that's great.
But you might notice that this is pure sequel.
And of course, sequel for Maya Skull is just a little bit different than sequel for Postgres.
Not always, but enough that it becomes irritating.
So with the system, as it exists right now, when we generate a migration, we have to look and see
what kind of database the person is using and putting the correct template for.
Marcella has application, and it's a little awkward.
It works really well, but it can be a little bit awkward if you take an other.
Any other of my courses on Udemy?
You've probably noticed that I'm really fond of this package.
Let me go to my web browser.
The soda, seelye and soda is actually part of the Buffalo Dot Io project, a web framework written
for Go.
And it works really well.
So if we get down here to migrations, so the nice thing about soda migrations or PHE's migrations as
they call them, is that you write one migration file and it's basically database agnostic.
It works with my ask you, well, that works with MariaDB.
It works with Postgres.
Not every database, but enough for my purposes.
Postgres is my go to database, but I occasionally use mariadb or some other database.
So what I want to do in this section of the course is modify our code in this Alatas package and in
the SEELYE.
We might leave that to the end of the course, but we'll get there eventually to allow for SQL migrations,
which we already have, and also to allow for PhysX migrations.
So we'll get started on that in the next lecture.