So in order to implement pop migrations or soda migrations or phased migrations, whatever you want
to call them, we're going to do that by starting with this file migrations don't go in this hilarious
project and we already have migrate up, migrate down all all these functions that work really well
with this package.
Golang Migrate, Slash Migrate, and we're using version four.
And I could simply modify these to make them work with soda instead.
But what I'll do is actually write new methods that are specific to the package would need to impart.
Now the package, we're going to import one that gives us the migration functionality we're looking
for is found here on GitHub dot com slash go buffalo slash pork, and you have some helpful documentation
down here, OK?
The documentation here is really not helpful.
That tells me how to write migrations and so forth.
So we actually have to dig through the source code to figure out how to implement this.
But fortunately, it's not that difficult.
But the first step is actually to go back to our ideas, to open a terminal, to clear the screen.
Make sure I'm in the correct folder.
Celebrities us because we want to import this in the celebrity's project and type.
Go get and then paste in that URL, GitHub dot com slash go buffalo slash pup and that will go and get
it for us.
And there it is.
So now we can actually use this.
So the very first thing I'm going to work on here is I'll go to the top of the file and I'm going to
leave all of these methods here that use the Golang Migrate Slash Migrate package.
I'll leave them there as a reference, and I'll start by writing something.
I'm going to have to use a fair bit.
It's a function with this receiver of C pointer to celebrities, and I'm going to call this function
and it's not exported.
It's Pop Connect.
This is how we connect to the database.
OK.
And that's going to return a pointer to from the pop package.
We just installed pop dot connection and potentially a return error as well.
OK.
So we're going to call a method pop dot connect and we'll get back our transaction.
That's how they refer to it in their documentation, such as it is potentially an error when we call
Pop Dot Connect
and I'm going to use the key development.
If you take out my other courses, you're aware that the database why HTML file for pop or soda or fizz
or whatever you want to call it, it actually allows you to specify a particular kind of connection.
And I'm just going to default to development.
OK?
To make things as simple as I possibly can.
So I'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll return nil and the error.
Otherwise, I'll return my transaction and nil.
OK, now we'll be using this pop connect function as we write the various methods to create migrations,
to run migrations and all that sort of thing.
But this is enough to get us started.
So in the next lecture, we'll actually write the function that creates up and down pop migrations.
OK.