So the first function, apart from this non-expert and pop connect, the first function I want to write
for pop migrations will be the one that actually creates the migrations and up and a down migration.
So it's a function with receive, receive hundreds of celebrities and I'll call this one, create pop
migration.
OK, now this will create both the up and the down migrations.
Now, if you actually use the binary, this sort of binary that is distributed by the Go Buffalo project,
it actually creates empty migrations.
I don't want to do that.
I want to put some starter code in there just to make it easier to write a migration.
So I'll accept a few arguments or parameters.
And the first ones are called up and down and these will be slices of bytes.
So we'll be able to pass a slice of bytes that will consist of the contents of the up migration and
the same thing for the down migration.
We also need to name our migration, so migration name.
That'll be a string that we accept and the migration type because we don't want to limit the kinds of
migrations that people generate.
If they want to use SQL, they should be able to use signal.
So both of these are strings, and this will potentially return an error.
OK, well, let's declare a variable migration path.
Where are these things going to be stored and that will be equal to from a receiver sees of Typekit
pointer to Solaris has the right path.
In other words, the root path of wherever the application is and we'll add slash migrations because
that's where we store migrations.
Then we'll check for an error when we call from the pop up package dot migration create.
And that requires the migration path, which we just built a migration path.
It also requires the migration main, which we get as a parameter migration name, and it requires the
type.
Well, that's another parameter.
We received migration type and up and down the slice of bytes that we're going to use to populate those
with some content if there's an error return.
Otherwise, return null and that should actually do it.
So that was an easy enough one.
As you can see, these aren't terribly complex functions, but they will give us some additional functionality.
All right, in the next lecture, we'll write the function that will actually run migrations.