So this time around, we want to write a function that will actually run our pop migrations.
So far we have this non-oil exported pop connect function, which we haven't called yet, and we're
not going to call it in this file.
Probably we're almost certainly going to call it from the command line application.
But we need it at some point and we have this one that creates up and down migrations at the applications
root folder level in a folder called migrations.
Now we want one that runs them, so function.
See Pointer to celebrities.
That's the receiver and we'll call this one.
Say run pop migrations and it's going to require just a connection T.X of type pop dot correction.
Now, obviously, we're going to get that from this function up here, pop connect.
But we don't want to get it right in this, this actual file.
We want to do that in the Seelye.
We get to the Seelye, you'll see why.
And this potentially returns an error.
OK.
And again, we need the migration path.
So just copy this code and paste it right here.
So we need that.
Then we're going to run something called Pop Dot New File my grater.
So we're going to get a variable file migration, which I'll call form for.
Follow my reader and we're going to check for an error when we call Pop Dot New File Migratory and we
pass it migration path.
And our connection to the database T x and we check for Fonarow.
If error is not equal to nil, memories from the error return here and we're done.
We can't go any further.
But assuming we get past that now, we can actually run those migrations.
And that's as simple as calling or calling are passing a potential error into this variable R firmed
up.
We're going to run the up migrations.
OK?
And we checked for an error once again, so I'll copy and paste this code.
Right there was that worked, we just return now.
So pretty straightforward, actually.
So this is how we'll run any migrations that we generate using create port migration, how we run the
up migrations in any case.
So let's move on to the next one, which will be migrating down something you do a lot during development.