So far in our effort to implement pop migrations or sort of migrations or phased migrations or whatever
you want to call them, I think I'll just call them pop from now on.
We have a means of getting a transaction, which is a connection to the database, and we still haven't
called that, but we will.
Before too long.
We can create up and down migrations and we can run the up migrations by calling run port migrations.
And of course, we also need to be able to migrate down.
So let's create a function to do that for us, the folksy pointer to celebrities as usual.
And I'll just call this pop migrate down and all that's going to require these two parameters.
The first one is a tax, which is a pointer to pop connection.
OK.
And we also on steps how many steps do you want to run down?
Now I want this to be an optional parameter, so I don't want to have to pass one when I'm running just
one down migration.
So instead I'll make it very adequate and it will just be an integer and it will potentially return
in error.
OK, now in untapped languages like JavaScript and PHP and so forth, you can actually have default
values given to function parameters, but GO is rather strict about typing.
So we can't do that.
So one way of getting around that is actually to put a very high parameter as the last parameter in
your function and then just check to see if anything exists in that.
Because with very audit parameters, you're allowed zero or more entries.
So if we don't pass anything, then the function will still work.
But if we pass one value and one value only, then things will work just perfectly.
So let's work on this, and once again, I need my migration path, so I'll copy that and I'll paste
it right here, and then I'm going to default the number of steps I want to run to be equal to one.
So that's an integer.
And then I'll check to see if the parameter, the very idec parameter I received at the end of the function
signature, if the length of steps, if that's greater than zero and I'm only ever going to use one,
if I populate that, then step is now equal to steps at index zero.
OK.
So if I pass a two in the call to this function as the final parameter, then step will be equal to
two.
Otherwise, it defaults to one.
Now we need another file, my Grider.
So I'm going to copy this code from up here and paste it right here.
Give it a blank one.
Now I have a file my greater.
And as you might expect, running the down migrations is as simple as checking for an error when you
call FMCT down instead of up.
But this time it requires number of steps.
So I'll put my variable step in there.
And copy and paste my error, check, paste it in here and return nil.
If everything goes as expected now I can run, generate migration's, I can run the migrations and I
can run one or more down migrations.
So the next one, and I believe it's the last one I want to do is to reset everything entirely.
In other words, to run all the down migrations, then reset the database, then run all the migrations.
And that is a really straightforward function, and we'll get started on that in the next lecture.