So the last function we need to implement inside this file migration SCO is the one that resets migrations.
In other words, it runs all the down migrations in reverse order and then runs all the up migrations,
and it's pretty simple.
So we'll put it right here just after pop migrate down.
We have a function with the receiver of sea pointer to our and we'll call it pop, migrate, reset,
and it will just take the T.X our connection a pointer to pop dot connection, and it potentially returns
an error.
And this is dead simple.
So once again, we need this information, which I'll copy from run port migrations, migration path
and a file migrate.
Or so I'll copy that.
Come back down here, paste them in.
And now it's as simple as saying error is equal to FM dot reset, and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil return, the error otherwise turned down.
OK, so we have all of these functions now and the next step is to actually try to use them, which
means we'll have to make some modifications to the celebrities command line application and we'll get
started on that in the next lecture.