So now that we have the necessary functions all set up for pop migrations in this file migration start
go.
Let's turn our attention to the command line interface and see if we can get this working with pop migrations.
So what we'll do is go over to the Celerity folder, then the CMD folder, then the Seelye folder and
we'll look at mango.
And let's just figure out how this all works right now and what we're going to have to do.
So I'll bring up Mango, and here in the main function, we're looking for the part where you type,
make migration and then some kind of migration.
So that would be under the make right here in this case.
So we check to make sure that argument two exists.
If it doesn't, we jump out.
Otherwise, we go to do make.
So let's go over to the do make function.
So I click on that and that's in the file make don't go and we don't care about making a key.
We care about making a migration right here.
So it seems like the first thing we do is we check to see if there's a cell data type value.
We're actually not putting any error checking in there.
So we might want to put in a function here.
I'll just put in a to do comment to do make sure DB is set up and we'll take care of that a little bit
later on, but that'll remind us to do it.
So if they don't have a database set up, obviously they shouldn't be able to make a migration.
They you have to have your database configured in the dot on file before anything happens.
OK.
So something will happen there.
Then we check to make sure that they actually have a migration name.
Perfect.
OK.
So what we want to do here is we want to change the command from celebrities, make migration migration
name to actually also have a choice.
You should be able to make a PHE's migration, which of course, is a soda migration or a pop migration.
Or you should be able to make a sequel migration as we do now.
But there's no point at all in having two migrations packages installed in our code because Pop takes
care of other fees or sequel.
So what we can do here is maybe after we get all of this air checking done, wait out here.
We'll just put a bunch of blank lines in, so we knew where we are.
And what we can do here is, say, default to migration type of things.
But if they specify fees will use fees, if they specify signal that we'll use signal.
And then we have to decide what kind of migration are we doing?
So are we doing fees or sequel?
Now, if we're doing things, then we want to read a kind of default up and down template, right?
So we'll have an if statement, if sequel know if fears read default templates, otherwise use sequel.
OK.
And then we want to create the migrations up and down for either is or sequel.
Now this doesn't seem terribly complicated, but obviously we're going to want a couple of default templates
for phased migrations.
So let's go over to our Templates folder.
And of course, this is the read only file system that has all the templates we use to create things
using this command line tool.
And let's look inside the migrations folder and we'll create two files here.
So I'll create a new file, not a go file, just to file.
And I'll call this one say migration up fields and then I'll create another one the new file migration.
Underscored down the fence, so let's start with the up migration.
Now, if you look on the course resources for this lecture, you'll see a zip file that has what I'm
about to paste into this up file and also what I'm going to paste into the downfall.
And it's very simple.
We're going to just give a simple starter template for creating a table in fits, and that's often what
you have to do.
And if they don't want to use this, they can just delete it and put whatever they want in there instead.
And for the down migration, it's as simple as this.
Just dropping that table.
And again, this is the sort of thing that they'll modify for their specific needs.
The user will modify it for whatever they want to accomplish with their up and down migrations.
But now we have some something to work with.
So download the zip file with these simple migrations or just just type of man.
It's not very much text and make sure you have a file called migration underscored downed office and
a file called migration underscore update is inside the migration folder.
Inside the Templates folder seelye cmd right.
Insularity.
OK, let's go back to make Docker.
So what we can do here to default to a migration type of files is we can say we'll create a variable
migration type, assign the value of IS.
OK, so now we have a default and will declare two variables up and down both of type string.
And these will be our up and down migrations, which will hold fees content if it's for soda and it'll
just be SQL.
It's going to be simple.
Now we need to decide whether or not we're going to be using fears or sequel.
And of course, that means we're going to change the command.
It won't be any more.
Just celebrities make migration.
The migration name will also put another value in there and will default it.
If it doesn't exist, it will be fears.
And if it does exist, will choose whatever they passed.
So that will be ARG for our big three being the name of the migration.
So if ARG for which doesn't exist yet, but don't worry about that, if ARG four is equal to his
or ARG four is equal to an empty string or something, otherwise we'll do something else.
Now, where does ARG four come from?
Well, obviously run out to pass of this function, so go up to the function signature and just add
art form.
And of course, if we go back to mean, don't go.
We need to pass or for which we don't have yet, but we'll get it shortly.
Let's go right up to the top of this file and declare an urn for.
And go to validate input which actually produces this and have it send back another string, which will
be earned for and declare our four here.
And of course, these are just the command line parameters when somebody types in celebrities.
And we need to make sure that we actually have in our core here.
So let's copy this,
paste this.
You make this five, because celebrities is actually the command celebrities would be the first argument
and this becomes four or incrementing goes by one.
And make this art for.
And looks that I have an error here somewhere.
A comma.
That fixes that.
And down here, we'll just return another empty string if there's an error.
I'll take care of that problem and we'll return our four at the end of this.
OK, so now we have that taken care of.
So that should take care of the error of here when we make.
And it does.
OK, so let's go back to our make duco, and now we have our third floor and no errors with that problem.
So down here, if ERG four is equal to fizz or Argh four is empty, in other words, it wasn't specified,
then we want to create our up and down content.
So let's say up bytes and potentially an error which I'm going to ignore and you shouldn't.
But I will just to get this going.
We're going to read from the template fs, our template file system.
We're going to read the file and the file we want to read is the one we just created.
Templates, migrations, slash migration underscore up is.
Then I'll duplicate this and make this one downvotes, so it's reading the bytes from those files on
the read only file system.
And this becomes down.
So now I have those bites, and all I have to do is say up as equals a string of bites.
And down is equal to string Dumbo's.
OK.
And here I'll just say else, migration type is equal to school.
So if you specified school as your migration type, in other words, argument for is not theirs, then
what is going to be called the sequel?
OK, so we can delete this comment now, because we've taken care of that, and now we want to create
the migrations, and now we can finally call something we used or we wrote in our migrations don't go
far.
So we'll check for error.
And that's a sign the value of from sell the celebrity's variable.
We're going to call, create pop migration and we give it its necessary parameters.
So the first one is up, which has to be a slice of bite.
So we'll just cast up to a slice of bite then down, which is also a slice of bite and down.
And the next one is whatever argument three was the name of the migration three and migration type.
All right.
So we call that and we'll check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll exit gracefully and we'll handle beer.
So in theory, that should actually work, which means we don't need any of this stuff, but I'm going
to comment that out rather than deleting it.
So I might have to go back and look at it again before I'm done.
So in theory, this should actually work.
Now, we haven't actually run a migration yet, but we should be able to actually run the code and generate
a PhysX migration, and we'll give that a try in the next election.