So we have the necessary code, we think, in place to generate phase migrations or cycle migrations,
but phase for now.
So let's give this a try.
Now there's a couple of things we have to do here.
We can comment this out and we'll take care of checking to make sure the database is set up in a bit
and hopefully deleting the unnecessary imports it did.
So there's no error showing up right now.
So I should be able to open my terminal.
Make sure I'm in this hilarious folder.
Clear the screen and say make build, underscore Seelye and actually create a new celerity executable.
And I have something missing here.
So let's go get that.
I will.
Apparently, I have to go get this thing, which I will.
So let's paste right in there.
Go get it.
This is one of the problems you run into when you're working with multiple projects in a single project.
Let's try that again.
Make build, underscore Selah.
OK, so it apparently made it so now I can switch to my other tab, where I'm in my celebrity's folder
and do an last show in my My At folder and do it like special celebrities.
So that was just built moments ago.
Now let's make sure our migrations folder is currently empty, and it is.
So let's try this out, let's say.
Dot slash celebrities make migration test.
And I'll leave it with no final parameter, I could put fizz there, but I'll test it this way first.
Let's see what happens.
It says it's finished.
Let's look at our migrations folder and see what we have.
There's an up migration and that is the correct code.
And here's a down migration.
And that's the correct code as well.
So that works really well.
So let's try making another one.
Dot slash celebrities make migration test, too, and this time I'll specify Skull sequel for the last
argument.
Now, if I come up here, I should have two more.
And they're both school migrations and they should be empty, so he didn't specify anything.
Perfect.
OK.
And now let's try the last cased dot slash celebrities make migration test three is.
And if I come up here, I should have another one.
And it's a phased migration and the up is the correct content and the down is the correct content.
Perfect.
So that seemed to work really well.
So let's delete these.
So we're not going to be using them, and I don't want them messing me up later on.
And let's go back and see what we have to do next.
So back here, my to do comment.
Make sure the database is set up.
I shouldn't be able to create a migration if there is no database in place.
The only reason being that someone might create a new project and they decide all too many database
migrations without having set up their database and then migrations get created.
But every time they try to run them, they get errors.
So we may as well make sure that they do things in the correct order and set up their database before
they try to create migrations, and we'll do that in the next election.