So let's take care of this last to do item here in make don't go inside the Seelye folder, inside the
CMGI folder in the Celebrity House project, and what we want to do here is to make sure that the database
is set up.
Now that means having a valid entry or at least having some kind of entry in your own files specifying
your database.
And it also means we're going to have to have a file in a folder called config at the root level of
our application.
So a config folder inside of that's something called Database Wiimote.
And that's the configuration file that popped needs.
So we can just do it like this.
We'll say we'll call a function.
We'll just call function.
That doesn't exist yet.
Check for DB.
OK.
And if I go over to the helper file, which is inside me CMD Seelye folder right there, I'll put it
right before the help text.
I'll create a function here called func check for DV.
Now what are we going to do in here?
Well, we know our database type is read by celebrities when it reads the dot on file, so db Typekit
and that's assigned the value of year.
This is just to make it readable.
Selden DB Dot data type.
OK.
So we'll say here, we'll say if DB type is equal to an empty string.
They didn't specify anything in there on file, so we'll say exit gracefully and we'll give it an error.
Errors dot new.
And the textual pudding is simply no database connection provided in dorms.
OK, so that's our first check.
The second check is to see if the file database requirement exists in the applications config folder.
So we'll say, if not, file exists.
And the file we want to check is at the root path of the application spelled out repass plus configuration
database requirement.
So if that doesn't exist, then exit gracefully.
And the error this time is errors York-New.
Then we'll just say configuration database dot why HTML does not exist.
OK, so now we're checking for database, and that was pretty straightforward.
Now, while we're at it, let's scroll down here and update our help text because it's no longer make
migration name.
It's make migration name and then format, which means are going to hit the spacebar a bunch of times.
So things line up properly do that fast enough.
I'm sure there's a faster way to do this, but I can't recall where it is right now.
And they will change to help text creates two new up and down migrations in the migrations boulder.
Semicolon format equals, and then we'll put sequel or fused default theories.
There should be enough.
OK, so we have that out of the way.
And of course, the next step is to actually create that config slash database, start Mel file and
to actually try running some migrations once we create them and we'll get started on that in the next
election.