So at this point, we can now create pop compatible migrations, but of course, those migrations aren't
terribly useful if we can't run them.
And right now we can't.
So let's get started resolving this issue, and I'm going to start by going to the my app project celerity
us here and I'll create that database.
Why HTML file inside the config folder that PUP needs?
So I'll create a new directory at the root level of my app.
So a new directory called config all lowercase and just seal in effigy.
And inside of that, I'll create a new file.
Not to go file, it's a file named database requirement.
A Yamal file.
OK.
And if you go to the course resources for this lecture, you will see a file you can download and the
contents of it.
Are this?
And you can download it if you want to.
But it's not very much typing.
But if you do type it, make sure you get the indentations from line three to line nine exactly as they
are here.
OK.
And the values in here just describe my connection to a database.
Now, in my case, I'm using Postgres with the database name celebrities.
The username Postgres.
The password password, so on and so forth.
And of course, these have to match exactly what's in this file Docker compose.
So here I have Postgres and password insularity passport five four three two and those correspond exactly
to what's in here or nothing will work.
OK.
So I've created that.
That's very useful.
So the next step is to go back to celebrities and to look at our CMG folder.
The Seelye folder.
And let's start with Mongo and figure out how we run migrations.
So in my case, in the main function, it's this switch state that takes argument number one, whatever
comes after the word celebrities on the command line.
And of course, the one I want is right here, migrate, and that calls a function do migrate.
So let's bring that up.
And in here right now, we're calling a function called get DCIM to build our connection string in the
format that is expected by going migrate the package we're not going to be using by the time we're done,
so I'm not going to need that anymore.
So a comment that I thought what we do need and here I'll open up the migration and go file, which
is right here at the root level of salary costs.
We do need our connection.
So that means we're going to have to be able to call Pop Connect or just do this right in the code itself
in our other file.
But I'll call this, which means I probably should have exported this to start with.
So now it's export it.
So let's go back to our migrate to go file inside the Seelye folder, and let's get a connection.
So I'll get a text, a transaction, which is what they call it in the pop world, potentially an error
when I call sell dot pop connect right there.
OK.
And we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll exit gracefully with the error, OK?
And the other thing we should do here is check our database connection.
So check for DB.
So let's put that right before this check for DB, because you shouldn't be able to run migrations if
you don't have your database configured.
So now I have my my transaction might connection to my Postgres database.
Now, the other thing we'll want to do here, of course, is close that connection when we're done with
it, so we'll say defer tax Duclos.
So when this dysfunction exits, then we'll close our connection to the database, and that's always
a good thing.
Now down here at the moment when we runner up migrations, we're calling this so a comment that out
because we're not going to be using that because we don't run our pop migrations that way.
Instead, we'll call this function over here, which is run pop migrations.
So back over here, all right now, it's just a matter of doing.
This error is a sign the value of cell run pop migrations.
And we ended our connections and nothing else changes.
Now what about down migrations?
Well, right now we had an all command here, and I'm going to comment all of this.
I'll delete it momentarily.
I was going to leave it there for a moment.
All we do for our down migrations is, say, if our three is equal to all,
then do something, otherwise do something else.
And of course, if you're trying to run all migrations, then we'll say error.
It's assign the value of from the cell package port migration down with the transactions.
And we had it minus one.
And I'll get my error check here, so I'll copy this line
pasted in here, and then I'll copy the whole thing just to save some typing pasted in here and instead
of handing it minus one, I just had it one.
OK, now you could simplify that code and have fewer lines, but I think this is really readable.
So want to get rid of this comment that I line here and I'll get rid of these commented out lines?
We don't need those anymore.
And my last case is reset.
And really, to make things simpler, I'll just delete all of this and just say error is a sign the
value of cell dot, pup migrate, reset and its transaction and copy this Eric error code and paste
it in there and nothing else should change.
So this is really straightforward at this point, and it's actually less code that we had before as
well.
So in the next lecture, we'll actually give this a try and see how it works.