So let's give this a try.
And right now, I have my darker images is running, my Dr. Campos is running up, so I'm able to connect
to my celebrity's database and I am connected right here, as you can see.
So this is my favorite Postgres client, and I'm looking at the celebrity's database and it has no tables.
It's completely empty, but it exists and it's running and that's critical.
Or what I'm doing next won't work.
So let's go back to my I.D. and the first thing I have to do, obviously is in the celebrity folder
on the command line in terminal.
I need to run, make, build, underscore Seelye, to build a new version of the executable and put
it in my app folder.
Then I switch over to my other tab, where I'm in the My App folder.
And let's make a migration so that celebrities make migration.
And I'll call it test, OK, and I should make these migrations up and down.
And in my group, my migrations folder, I now have an app migration, and when I run my migrate command,
it should create a table named some table with two columns.
Well, it'll have more than two, but it will have it in some column, at least.
So let's try that celebrities migrate.
Well, that's encouraging.
It seemed to run, so let's switch to our database client and refresh this.
And there is the schema migration tables, which is automatically created by pop.
And here's some cable.
Now, if I look at it, it has the ID and the some call up, some column color, which is really hard
to say, and it automatically adds the created and updated out columns as well.
Perfect.
So let's go back.
So we're not looking at the table and I'll try migrating down that celebrities migrate down.
And that seemed to work.
So let's go back and look at our database refresh, and I should still have this schema migration table,
but this one should be gone.
And it is, so let's migrate back up again.
And now it should be back there when I come back here.
I should see that some table.
I do.
And let's try that.
Celebrities migrate reset.
And everything should be back where it was, we should have reset our database in effect, and it's
perfect.
I accidentally open the catalog, but that all seems to work really well.
So time to move on and just to make sure that other things like make us continue to work the way they're
supposed to and we'll get started on that in the next election.