So far, we can create migrations.
We can run up and down migrations, and we can do a complete reset of the database, and that's really
good.
But there are other things that interact with the database that we have to take into account.
For example, here in my terminal, in the Myat project, if I type dot slash solicitous help, one
of the things we can do is here make off.
And that creates and runs migrations for the authentication tables and creates models in a little while.
And the second part where we're creating models and middleware is no problem.
It's this first part creating and running migrations for authentication tables that we have to take
care of.
So back in my code in the file may not go inside the CMD slash seelye folder.
The one we're looking for is the make command right here.
Case make and that calls do make.
So let's look at that.
And the one we want here is make off.
We can get rid of this competitive coat now, so that's gone.
So make off, so let's call that calls do off.
Let's have a look at that.
So the first thing that does right now, and to be clear, this still works, but it's calling functions
that we want to get rid of.
Eventually, the ones that use the Golang Migrate package.
So we want to update this code to work with our pop migrations.
We can still run these simple migrations, but we want to use the functions that we just wrote earlier
in this section.
So obviously, the first thing we want to do is to get a connection after our NEBE types variable asset.
So we'll do it just like we did before T.X and error or assign values by calling Cell, which is a celebrity's
package.
The variable pop connect right there and we check for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll just exec restore with the error.
OK, once we have our connection, of course, we want to defer closing to further tech stock closed
just like we did before.
And of course, the other thing we should do here is not let them run this command unless we check for
you, unless we call that function that ensures they had their database set up.
OK, so we've checked for the database to be configured.
We've got the database type in a variable DB type there in Line 14.
We've got our connection to the database and we're deferring closing that connection.
Now do we need this file name variable?
And what that's actually doing is building their migration name with time dot now dot Unix Micro is
the leading bit.
We actually don't need that anymore, and we don't need it because Pop puts its own little numeric sequence
at the start of each migration.
So I'll just comment this one out.
We don't need it at the moment.
And that means we probably don't need these, either.
So I'll comment, these ones are we can always bring them back if we need them.
What we do need to do now here online, 28, we're actually calling that function, we wrote in the
last course copy file from Template and that reads this from the file system.
OK, so let's have a look and see what that file is.
It's off tables.
DB Typekit SQL inside the Templates Migrations folder, something will open up this alert householder.
Seemed templates, migrations.
Let's see what's inside there off tables, Postgres, look at that.
So I'm connected to Postgres right now.
So this creates or replaces a function trigger set timestamp, which is great.
Then he drops the table users, if it exists, creates a user's table, does the same thing for remember
tokens and the same thing for the tokens table.
So this sequel should be perfect.
We should be able to use that.
That's good to know.
But instead of actually copying the file from one place to another.
What we need to do.
Let's comment this one out.
Let's instead just read that contents.
Read the contents of that file into the up migration as well.
Create a file or a variable called up bytes because it's a slice of bytes and I'll check for error and
those come from calling the template EF-S.
And we'll just read that file and the file we want to read is effectively this right here.
The same thing that we have here, so it's this I can copy this code and that's what I want to read.
And paste it in here.
And now I have the contents of that up migration stored as a slice of bytes.
OK.
Now are down, downvotes will be exactly this code right here, so let's just modify this to say downvotes
is a sign the value of let me get rid of the last part here that we don't need anymore.
So now we have our up and down migrations, both stored as a slice of bytes, which means all I need
to do to create those migrations now is to check for an error when I call from the solicitor's package.
That function we wrote called Create Pop Migration, and that requires the updates, which are updates.
The down boats which are down boats.
The migration name.
I can just call it off.
And the format should be simple because that's what we're passing.
It is actual sequel.
And I will check for an air again.
So a copy of this code and paste it here, and that should be good for that.
And now we want to run the migrations.
What I'm calling here is do migrate that function we wrote a long time ago.
What I'll do instead is just delete all of this or delete that line anyway.
I'll just run my migrations.
You just call the run pop migrations function that we wrote a while ago.
So error is equal to sell dog run pop migrations, and that just requires our connection pool, which
we created right at the beginning of this function.
And if it doesn't work, then it prints out in error and dies gracefully.
Nothing else should actually change here, so that in theory should work for us.
OK.
So we'll give this a try in the next lecture and see what we got wrong.