So now that we've made these changes to the make us command, let's give them a try.
And the first thing I'll do here is just clean up some of this code.
I don't need this comment out stuff anymore.
Inside of off, don't go in this folder.
And remember that when I run this command, it's actually going to die every time.
It can't execute one of these things where I'm copying files from a template.
So, for example, I'm going to copy from the template file system templates, data user go text to
data user go in my out project.
And that means I should make sure I don't have any of the things in there already.
And basically, that's any file that's associated with making the with running we make last minute.
So, for example, I don't have a user's dongo or a token.
Don't go or remember a token, don't go in here.
So that's good.
I should also check to see what else is copied middleware.
So do I have an off Doug go and middleware Moscow looking middleware?
No, I don't.
So that's good.
So make sure that you don't have pre-existing copies of these files anywhere in your app project or
you're just going to have to go delete them and start over from scratch.
And I've had to do that several times while I was testing things, and you probably don't want to go
through that exercise.
So once you've verified that, make sure your Docker images are running so your database is running,
in other words.
And then we'll open our terminal and we'll go over to the celebrities project and we'll run that command,
make, build, see.
And if everything goes according to plan that should create a new house executable over in the My App
folder, and it looks like it did.
So now we'll go to the My Apps folder, and I'm in the correct directory and I'll run dot slash celebrities,
make off and see if it works.
And hopefully we get everything right.
We almost never do.
But let's give it a try.
So it looks like it ran properly, it open up our favorite database client and lines right here post
to come.
And connect to my Docker image right here.
And it looks like I have a remember token's table.
Some table is leftover from the last time we tested our migrations and there's tokens and there's users,
and that's very good.
I'm shocked.
I go buy a lottery ticket.
Things never work right.
The first try.
Let's make sure we have everything in the correct folders, so we have our off off token.
And remember all inside the middleware.
So that's good.
Do we have anything in our mail?
We have our password reset HTML and plain.
It looks like everything worked the way that it should.
There's my handlers and they are my data models.
Well, that was a bit shocking, but we now have that working the way that it should.
So now that we have our make up command working, let's complicate matters by moving on to social authentication
in the next section.