So in this section of the course, we're going to build the first of two different caching architectures
for our celebrity house project, and a cache is incredibly useful.
It's a storage system which could be a memory based cache.
It could be a database, it could be any kind of cache you want.
There are many, many to choose from.
But in this section, we're going to create a cache using Redis, and you might have been asking yourself
if you look at that composer file for Docker.
Why does he have Redis in there?
And you probably skipped ahead in the syllabus and saw what we're talking about.
And of course, now is when we start to use it, because Redis is a great, incredibly fast, memory
based cache caching system.
It's a key value store is what it really is.
We're going to use it as a cache, and it periodically writes the contents of its storage of its cash
or of its Redis database to disk.
So you don't lose things.
Or at least if you have a sudden power outage or whatever, you're not going to lose very much.
You'll at least have it written to disk on a regular basis.
So, of course, to use this caching system, we're going to build.
We need a driver that connects to us.
So we're going to use the one that is basically the standard in the go world.
And it's called it's a GitHub dot com slash go module slash redi-go, which is a great name and it's
really, really easy to install.
So let's do that.
Let's come down here and copy the installation string and go back to our celebrities project and make
sure it is the celebrity's project you're in.
Open your terminal and I'm going to clear the screen and paste that and go get command right in there
and that will go and get it.
Copy the necessary reference to the Go Mod file, and now we can use it.
So we're going to build the cache as its own package with insularity.
So I'm going to hide the CMT folder or close it, and I'm going to create a new directory right at the
root level of the celebrity's project.
And not surprisingly, I am going to call it cache.
And inside of that, we'll create the very first file in this and it's going to be called, you guessed
it, Kasuga package cache.
And the very first thing I'm going to do is declare an interface because we're going to build a Redis
cache in this section.
And later on, we're going to build another cache that uses this interface that stores it to not introduce.
We're not going to require a server at all, and we're not going to do it the way that they do in the
Laravel world, which is a file based cache.
We're going to use an embedded database called Badger, and we'll get to that in a while.
But right now we're worried about race.
So let's define our type and this type is an interface, and I'm going to call it cache.
It's an interface.
And all we do and here is list all of the functions that something must implement in order to satisfy
this interface.
And of course, this is Go's interface system, which I think is incredibly simple.
I love it.
It's vastly superior, I think, to Java, but that is a personal preference.
You may disagree with me, and that's just fine.
So we're going to have to have something called has.
Does my cache have some string?
OK.
And it will return a Boolean and potentially an error.
So that's a function we're going to have to have.
And it's also going to have to have get get something from the cache string.
That'll be the key to look for.
And that can be and it will return something.
We don't know what it's going to be.
So we'll just call it interface because you can store anything in a cache and potentially in error.
That's the second thing we're going to have to have set to set something in the cache string will be
the key.
The what we want to store in there is going to be an interface again because we don't know what is going
to be.
It can be literally anything and dot dot dot hint.
And this is where we're going to put the expiry for a cache because we can put something in the cache
and say this is only good for 60 seconds or this is good for eighty six thousand four hundred seconds,
which is a really long time.
Look it up.
But whatever the case may be, if we want to, we can optionally specify an expiry for something.
We set the cache and all this is going to return is an error or nil if there is no error.
So has get and set.
We're also going to want forget, get it out of the cache and just forget my key, whatever you named
it, when you threw it in there, and that just returns potentially in error.
And finally, empty by match.
This is where we can forget everything in the cache by some pattern.
Say everything that starts with the letter A. or whatever the case may be.
That's an easy one to have and are useful, and that will take one parameter string and returns an error.
Potentially.
And then just empty everything in the cash.
And that takes no parameters and it returns an error, potentially.
So that's our interface.
Now, of course, what we're going to have to do is to actually implement all of that functionality
in Redis.
And it's not that difficult.
We'll start with one function right now and we'll move on in the next lecture.
So the first thing I'm going to have to do before I actually start writing the has get set and so on
functions.
So I'm going to need a couple of types and the first one is a type called Redis cache.
OK, because that's what we're working on this time.
It's just a struct and it has a couple of members.
First of all, what's our connection to Reddit's Redis?
So I'll call that con, and that's actually a dot or a pointer to readies the package we just imported
a little while ago.
And that's it right there.
Pool a pool of connections.
OK.
And the second thing I'm going to put in there and this is purely for safety as a prefix, something
I'm going to I don't care what you call the various keys you use to store values in the cache.
I'm going to prefix them with something unique because the reality is you might have two or more applications
using Redis and they both have the cash and you put one in there called temp ID.
And then the other application puts one in there called temp ID.
You delete it from one by using the Forget function, and it's gone from both.
But if we give them a unique prefix, that problem goes away.
That's just a string.
OK.
So there's my first type.
My second type is what am I going to put in the cache?
Well, I'm going to call those entry for cache entry, and that's going to be nothing more than a map
that holds values so we can serialism because before we throw something in the cache, we might have,
well, we are going to serialize it in every case just so we can store it there, pull it back out and
then we answer, realize it, which is a really straightforward process.
So this is nothing more than a map with a key of string and a value of interface like that.
Now let's create nothing more than a simple check to see if a given key exists in our Redis cache.
In other words, the hash hash function.
We can't try it until we get a connection and all that sort of thing.
But we can write the first function just to get a sense for how this is going to work.
It's nothing more than a function with a receiver of I don't want to call it C for cash.
A pointer to read his cache and the function has to be called has as.
In order to satisfy that portion of the interface, it has to take one argument, which I'll call is
TR of type string, and it has to return the Boolean and potentially an error.
OK.
So to make this work, what we're going to do, first of all, is take that value, steer the key that
I'm looking for, and I'm going to prepend my prefix to it like this.
So I'll say key is assigned the value of format as print f and I'll give it my format string and it
will be a string followed by a colon, followed by another string.
And my substitutions are c dot prefix.
What my unique prefix that I'm going to have for this application and the string that was passed.
So that's really the key.
I'm looking forward to the end user.
They think they're looking for whatever they pass me, but I'm going to look for my prefix, followed
by a colon, followed by whatever they gave me, just for safety.
OK.
And then I'll get a connection.
Con is assigned second.
That's the connection pool.
The Reds connection cool again.
So I get one and get a connection.
And then I say, defer conduct close because I'm going to close that connection and hand it back to
the pool when I'm finished with it.
And now I do the actual work.
OK.
And error are assigned the value of red asked BOOL, which is built right into the redi-go package.
And I say use the connection con and execute this command do.
And then I execute the Reds command, which is just exists in all caps like that.
And the second parameter is the key that I'm looking for.
OK.
And of course, I have to check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then I'll return false and the error.
Otherwise I return return.
OK, which will be either true or false.
True, if I can find that key in the cache, false of the can't and nil.
So as you can see, it's actually not that difficult to work with refs.
Now, if you happen to be familiar with Redis and you're used to working with it in the command line,
you're going to have no problem at all.
But even if you don't, the commands we're going to be using over time are really, really simple.
And they're actually.
Readable, as readable as one might expect from a key value database, which is not that readable,
but not that bad.
OK, this is a good start.
Now we're going to have to implement get set, forget empty by match and empty.
And we're also going to have to get our collection pool if it exists.
And that means populating some values in the dot on file.
On the other application in my app.
And it also means connecting to Redis insularity itself.
So we'll get started on all of that in the next lecture.