Before we can do anything useful with Revis and our cash, we naturally have to connect to the right
a server and of course, we're going to do that in the Celebrity House package because we don't want
to make our end users go through all of this kind of effort to create a connection pool and so forth.
So in this hilarious project, insularity Housego, we have this type config and in there we're storing
things like our database configuration, our cookie configuration, and we actually want to store also
a Redis configuration in there.
Now this database config, for example, exists over in type start go.
So what I'm going to do is in Typekit go, I'm going to create another type and I'll call that.
Read config measures to strike, and it will hold the information we need to connect to Redis, so we'll
need a host, which is a type of type string.
We might need a password.
Certainly not in development, but in production.
You probably will.
And that will also be a string and will also put in prefix.
And that's the prefix we use to make sure that values we throw in the cache, don't conflict with some
other application that might be using Redis.
So that also will be a string.
OK.
So I'll save that for a minute.
And now we have.
I read his config, which isn't being used, but it will be momentarily.
Let's go back to celebrities.
Don't go and in our config, let's add that type redis config.
Which I'll just call read actually of type reddish config, and let's say that.
Now let's get down to the part where we actually populate that configuration.
Stay right here.
So here's where we read all of the information into our config.
And all we have to do here is, say, writers, and that will be of type reddish config and we populate
his values.
So host, we get that from our on file.
And if you look over in the My App application and you look at the icons right here, this is where
we're getting all the necessary information.
OK, so right from our dot on and we have that at this point.
So back in celebrities, we can say OS don't get on and the host is going to be is underscore host
and the password is OS.
Don't get on, read underscore password.
And the last thing we want is the prefix prefix and that is OS.
Don't get on regice underscore prefix.
So now we have this information in our configuration.
So the next step and maybe a comma here.
So the next step is actually to find a place to connect erectus, so I'm going to scroll all the way
down and I'll put it right here in its own function.
OK.
So this will be a function we call to get our connection cool, and it will be a function with the receiver
of sea, a point which is hilarious and I'm not going to export it because I'm only use it within this
package.
I'll call it create reddish cool, and it doesn't take any parameters, but it returns a pointer to
Reddit's dot pool right there from the radical package.
So we'll just have this function return, and we'll return a reference to a horrendous dark pool and
we populate its necessary values.
So how long should a connection remain idle max idle?
We'll make that 50.
That's a good number and say Max active.
What's the maximum number of active connections we can have?
And I'll make it ten thousand.
Which seems like a big number, but it's not for ratings.
And we'll give it an idle timeout and that will be equal to say 240 seconds times timed second.
And we also need a dial member or field, and that's going to be a function which returns a reddish
scone.
And potentially in error.
So we'll have that return red asked Dial.
And this is what actually makes the connection.
TCP is our format TCP like that.
And then on the next line will use from our config cedo config readies dot host.
And we might have a password, so we'll put in their red escort dial password, and if it's empty,
it doesn't matter and it's empty in my case, but it will still work.
We're going to dial password c dot config dot readies password.
And we need a comment now after that happens.
We're also going to test it.
So we'll say test on borrow, and that also is a function and inline function, and it takes our connection
con of type register.com and it takes also a parameter for T time dot time.
That's all that that is.
And it potentially returns in error, returns in error.
Now, I don't care about the first return value from the function I'm about to call.
But I do care about an error that, oh, I'm going to do is say con dot do and just ping the server.
And if there's an error, we'll get an error.
So return it return error.
And I don't need a comma here, and I should take care of that.
So this will be a function we can use to call and create a connection to readers.
Now I'm also want to create another function here, just like we did when we create to other parts of
our application, like creating a renderer, for example.
I'll throw creating a client read cash into its own function.
OK.
So I create a function here, called with the receiver of C pointer to celebrities, not config celebrities.
I'm going to call this one.
Create client.
Read his cache.
OK.
And it takes no parameters, but it returns a pointer to the cache type.
We made a while ago that read this cache there, and this is really simple.
Why is it not finding cash right at cash?
Let's try that again.
She seems to have trouble importing, that's no problem.
I'll import it.
Let's just duplicate this line and put cash in there.
There now, we come back down here.
Hopefully the air will go away and it did OK, so to create a client ready cash.
I'm going to just say my cash client is assigned the value of cash.
Dot readies his cash and we'll populate its fields and its fields are the con.
And that's going to be.
Now we're going to call that create us Pool C Dot create, write us pool that gives you my connection
pool.
And the prefix just comes from C dot config dot redis dot prefix.
And we return that return and it has to be in the form of a reference, of course.
Cash client.
OK, so now we have a means of creating a Reuters pool of creating our cash client.
The next step, of course, is to decide if we need to create a client, read as cash or open a collection
to read at all, because in some cases people will be using this application, but they're on the entries
for Redish will be empty.
They're not using Redis.
So let's go way up here.
Let's scroll up to the point just before where we create all of our conflicts.
See right here.
OK, so just like here, we're checking to see if a database type is empty.
If it's not, then we try to connect to the database.
We do the same thing for Redis right here.
So we'll say if asked, get on.
Yes.
And in this case, we're going to look for cash because if you look over in our dart on file, we have
here cash and I set mine to release.
It was might be empty in yours, but it will be ready shortly.
OK.
If it's not, you might want to change it to read this right now.
But if this is empty and we're not using Redis, so we'll say if 0s and get all cash is equal to Redis,
then we want to use Redis.
OK.
So in here, we just say my Redis cache or whatever you want to call it is assign the value of C, not
create client Redis cache.
And then we say struct cache, which doesn't exist yet.
We'll be adding that at the moment is equal to my Redis cache.
Now this court cache, of course, comes from celerity, so we need to come way up to the top here to
celebrities and just add a cache.
And we're not adding the type of Redis cache because we're going to support more than one kind of cache
instead.
We'll use that interface cache cashed out cached.
And if I save that and scroll all the way down here, we see that there's still an error here.
And of course, this is simply because we haven't created or implemented all of the methods necessary,
all of the functions necessary to support the cache type.
So if we go back to our cash, for example, cache doggo, in order to satisfy this interface cache,
we have to have a has a get set of forget an empty buy match and empty.
Well, we can put stuff methods in here for right now just to make that air go away.
So we need a func get, which takes a string.
So I'll just call it start string that has to return an interface in an error.
So interface
an error.
And it has to have the receiver of Redis cache, of course, see British cache and we just have this
return anything and nil.
OK, so that's a stub method.
Let's do some more.
We need a set.
So we'll just copy this whole thing and paste it here and call it set and set has to take a string and
interface in an it.
So a string and we'll call data interface, and it also has to have a one or more INTs.
So we'll call it whatever status or no.
Dot dot dot int.
OK.
And astroturfing return interface is an error.
So there's two.
The next one is forget to string.
It returns an error.
So func see where it is cache.
And it's called forget.
It takes one string starter string and it returns an error.
And we'll just have that return nil for now, just so we can get this thing to compile and we need an
empty by match and an empty.
So and they both return an error.
So I'll just copy this.
That will be empty by match that will be empty
and empty.
Takes no parameters.
An empty buy match takes a string and returns potentially an error, so we can just call this one empty
by match.
And when we do that, we still have an error here anyway to save.
We go back to celebrities and my red is cash.
Let's see here now.
Can I use my red as cash as cash, not cash value to sign it wrong?
Type four Methods set have func string data interface to your Int want func string interface int.
So something wrong with set?
No problem.
So set takes a string and an interface.
And an end and it returns an error.
Here's the problem.
OK, get rid of that and get rid of that and just return nil.
All right, now, if we go back to slur toss, that error is gone.
OK, so we're almost ready to try connecting to Rita's.
We have our cash type added to the celebrities.
So up here, we've added our cash type.
That's good.
Then down here, we decide whether or not we have to connect to read this at all.
If we do, then we create a client, read his cash and populate that field, and we have the two functions
necessary to make this thing work.
So if all goes well, we should be able to start building and working with the actual functions in the
cache type.
So we'll get started making the cash functions actually useful in the next election.