So we probably have reddest connecting to celebrities appropriately, and now it's time to complete
the functions in the cash, don't go far inside the cash folder in the Celebrity House project.
And one of the things we're going to have to do before we can complete these functions is write to helper
functions that serialized an item and then unseriousness them because we need to do that before we can
throw them in the cache.
Unfortunately, that's pretty easy.
So right here after the has function and before the get function, I'm going to write one called Func
and it doesn't have a receiver because I'll be using this functionality for other cache types.
So I want to be able to call it from anywhere in this package.
It's called ENCODE, and it takes one parameter which I'm going to call item and that's up type entry.
And that's what we defined back up on Line 23 of this file.
It's a map of string interface.
So that's what we take for parameters, and we're going to return a slice of bytes and potentially an
error.
OK.
So we're going to create a variable called B, which is a bytes buffered bytes start buffer from the
standard library.
And we have to put the double curly braces after it and we'll create a variable called E, which is
going to be a gob dot new encoder.
And the God package is part of the standard library.
And you have to use that any time you want to store something in the session, for example, or a cache
like this, and it's pretty straightforward.
So that is going to take as its parameter, a reference to be the bytes buffer, and we're going to
populate that before too long.
So error is equal to it in code.
That should be a new encoder, not a decoder encode.
And we're going to encode it and we'll check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we'll return nil and the error.
Otherwise we return v2 bytes and nil.
OK.
That's pretty straightforward.
That will encode things serialized in effect.
And of course, we need the corresponding func decode and that will take just a string as tier of type
string and it will return an entry and potentially an error.
And basically, we do the same thing we just did, but in reverse.
So we'll create an item of type entry and we won't populated fields.
And then we'll create a bias buffer be is assign the value of rights with the double quotes or double
curly braces and then be done right.
We're going to right to that a slice of bytes.
From here, the parameter, we pass to this function now we create a decoder.
The four decoder is assigned the value of Golborne, new decoder, new decoder and again a reference
to B and we try to decode the item.
Error is assigned the value of data decode.
A reference to item that we checked for an error if error is not equal to nil.
Then we return.
And chill in the air.
Otherwise, we return item in the air.
So there's our encoder and our decoder.
Now we'll be using those before too long.
But we may as well do these things in order.
So the first function we need to complete in order to make this functional is to get a function where
we get something from the cache.
OK.
So we want to get our key same as we did way up here.
This key is all just copy that.
And come down here and paste that in there.
And of course, what that does is put the prefix on the key that the user is looking for when they're
trying to pull something from the cache, they might be looking for an entry that has the name of some
value, but we're going to prepend the prefix and a colon to that string.
So that's the key we're going to look for.
Now we get a connection to Rita's Khan as a sign the value of from the Receiver C sitcom.
Don't get.
And I'm going to put two ends on that con just to be consistent.
So that's what I called it before, and we defer closing that connection conduct close to return it
to the pool, and now we'll create a variable called cash entry.
What we're trying to get out of the cash and we will check for an error.
And that's a sign the value of redskin bytes right there from the writers package.
And we call con and tell it to execute the following command get in all caps and a key, and we check
for an error.
The error is not equal to nil and something went wrong will return nil and the error.
But if we get it back, of course, it's of no value to us until we earn serialize.
So now we need to your lies and I'll call the result of that process decoded.
I'll check for an error.
And we just call that function.
We just wrote Decode and we handed as a string our cache entry,
and again, we check for an error.
Same idea as before.
We'll copy this and paste it here.
But if we get past that, then the item we want is actually in a map.
So item is assigned the value of decoded key decoded because an owner and we don't return an empty string.
We return item, which is now in the correct format and is usable by the end user.
So that's pretty straightforward.
So that's how you get something out of the cache.
And of course, the next step is to put something into the cache.
So we'll copy these lines began to exact the same for this function where we get our key.
We get our connection.
We defer closing the connection.
And what we want to get back, of course, is an entry so-called call value entry and it's a type entry
and we'll put the curly braces around it.
And we'll say entry key
equals value, not value lost now, value.
I'm going to change my parameters up here to something more useful.
OK?
This year will still still be the string.
I'm going to call this value because it's more useful or more intuitive, I think, than data, and
I'll change this one as well.
Two expires because when you put something in the cash, it might expire after a set number of seconds.
OK, so now this map, this entry, which is a type map, string interface, it's key is what we calculated
here.
The value of the user sent us with the pre-printed prefix in a column.
Its value is the data we want to store.
So we have that value now.
Now we need to encode it.
So encoded is assigned the value of and potentially an error in error is assigned the value of code
entry.
That serialize is checked for an error.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll return nil.
Now we're hearing the error.
There's only one return type in this.
Now we have to we actually have to do the work to put it into the cash.
But of course, there's two ways we can put things into this cash.
It might not have that final parameter and integer, they say, expire after so many seconds or it might
have it.
So we just check to see if the length of our very adequate parameter expires.
If that's greater than zero than it has an expiry time else, it does not.
OK.
So let's do the first case here, and I'll scroll up a bit if it does have that value set and expiry
time.
And then I call.
I don't care about the first return value, but I do care about the error.
Those are assigned the value of from our con, our connection to race.
We're going to execute a command due and we're going to execute Set X set with an expiry.
And the key is key.
That's how you find it in cash and the value for expiry is expires.
Zero.
How many seconds until expiry?
And what we're going to put in there is string encoded.
So we take that slice of bytes that's encoded value.
Cast it to a string and we'll check for an error.
So a copy of this code
and paste it in here.
Now, if you don't have an expiry date and it's almost the same, so I'll copy this and paste it in
here and Set X becomes just plain old set and it just takes the key.
And the encoded or the encoded turned into a string, and that puts it in there with no expiry.
So basically, it'll stay in the cache until you physically or deliberately go and remove it.
OK.
And here we return.
Nil.
So now we can get something from the cache, we can set something in the cache.
And of course, you also have to be able to forget something in the cache, and here's where you remove
something when you don't need it anymore.
So once again, we'll get our key a con, and I'll just copy this.
And paste them here.
And forgetting something is pretty straightforward.
We don't care about the first returned value.
We do care about the error and it comes from corn.
Don't do once again.
And we handed the command deal for delete and delete the key and we checked for an error.
Same logic is up here, so I'll copy and paste and paste it in that.
And that's you.
Forget something.
So the next one is called empty by match, and there's a little bit more work here, but not too much.
So once again, I need these three lines, so I'll copy those and I'll paste this in here.
And here's what we want to remove things from the cache by matching some pattern.
OK.
So to make that happen, I'm going to create a variable called editor for iteration.
I'll initialize it to be zero
and then I'll define a variable called keys.
And it has the type.
It's going to be a slice of string.
And initially, it's empty.
There's nothing in there.
OK.
And we're going to populate that slice of strings with all the things we need to get rid of.
So here I'm going to create a for loop that just executes forever.
There's no condition in the actual force statement where exits will break out when necessary.
So I'm going to create a variable called air, and I'm going to check for an error and I'm going to
execute British values, and that requires this command con due and the command we want is scan.
So we're searching the red database.
We have the variable itor, which will be updated as time goes on.
We're trying to match something and the pattern we're trying to match is just our search pattern, which
we received as a parameter to this, followed by an asterisk.
So we'll just put format s print f, which returns a string.
Give it a format string, which is just percent, as is a placeholder lowercase s, followed by an asterisk
and the substitution for percent US is just key, which we defined right there on Line 124.
OK.
So a check for an error if error is not equal to nil.
And we'll just say return the error, OK?
Otherwise, we have a value in air, which is actually in.
So here's where we update Ed Ed and we don't care about the second returned value is equal to reddest
or it.
And the parameters we're putting in there for reticent are are the first entry in array, which is zero
and no.
And I put a Mr. Bracket there and put one here.
That's better.
And now I'll define a temporary variable, which can be called anything, so I'll just call it K, and
I don't care about second return value.
Those come from lettuce dog strings.
And its parameters are array one.
That's how red it gives us the information back and no, and now keys that slice it strings we define
right up there in line 129, that's equal to append keys and then K.
But all the values we get from Kerry and Keys is spelled wrong.
So that's why that's throwing error.
That's better.
So finally, we need some condition to get out of this endless infinite for loop.
And it's pretty simple if ED is equal to zero and there's nothing more to do.
So we're done.
Great.
OK, so at this point, I now have a slice of strings with all the keys I need to get rid of.
So all I do now is, say, four, and I don't care about the index, but I do care about an individual
entry, which I'll call X and we range through keys.
And in here, all I really have to do is forget the current entry.
So I will say error is assigned the value of C to forget, which we already wrote.
And in there, we put Kate and we check for an error if error is not equal to nil, then return the
error.
And I think that should take care of it, but it's not key here.
It's X.
And that should take care of empty by March.
So the last one we have to worry about is empty, which is very similar to the one we just finished.
And again, I need those first three lines, so I'll copy those and I'll paste them in here.
Now, in this case, key is a little different because key is basically, in this case, just the prefix.
We only want to delete things in the cache to begin with our prefix and Akola.
So in this case, we get rid of this because we don't have a variable called STR and we get rid of this.
And that gives us are appropriate keys to look for.
So at this point, what I can do is pretty much the same thing.
I did an empty bar match.
Now if you think about it up here in empty by match, I'm going through all of this logic to get the
necessary keys, including this, this this variable here.
So all of that I'm going through and we think it through.
I'm going to do exactly the same thing this time around.
So why not just take all of that and cut it out of error and come down here and create a new function
with the receiver of C British cash?
And I call this one get cheese.
And it's going to take some pattern, which is a string, and it will return a slice of strings
and potentially an error.
And now I can just really I'll just paste in what I just cut out.
I'll get my connection the way that I have been doing right along Khan is a sign the value of C dot
com.
Don't get and defer conduct close.
And at this point, I can actually just modify this code so it's usable in more than one place.
So in the for loop, I'll return keys, which will be empty or only partially populated.
So keys plural and down here after the for loop, I just return keys.
No.
So now I have a means of getting all of my keys very quickly.
So back up here.
This is broken now.
I can now change this to keys in error are assigned the value of C.
Don't get keys and hand it my keys.
I check for her if error is not equal to nil.
Then I return there and I can copy this code because I'm going to need it in my empty function and paste
it right there.
And now I should be able to just call for and again, I'll call it X is equal to range and I'm going
to range through keys.
And I'll say error is equal to C.
Don't forget X and check or an error.
Copy and paste.
It.
What if I get through that for a loop, then everything should be correct.
So unless we have a typographical error, which is entirely possible, it seems likely that we're almost
ready to go here and I do see I have an error showing up somewhere.
This should be pattern.
I'm sure you noticed that because it's named pattern up here.
Not whatever I had here a moment ago.
So at this point, we have an error up here now.
Oh yes.
Somehow, I accidentally imported that.
So just get rid of it and save it.
Now finally, it seems like we're almost ready to start testing this code.
So of course, in order to do that, we'll go back to my app and make sure we have the appropriate values
in the dart on file, and we'll start trying things out and see how it all works, and we'll get started
on that in the next election.