So in order to make sure that everything works in our red is cash package, the easiest thing to do
at this point, I think, is to write some tests.
Now if we're going to be testing this, you might think that we need to read a server and we absolutely
could do that.
We could follow the same sort of approach we did when we were testing our database functionality by
spinning up inappropriate, appropriate Docker image and running tests against a temporary version of
Docker that only exists for the life of the tests themselves.
But in this case, we actually have an option to go to my Web browser.
There's a really good package and it's I should link to right from the Redi-go page.
It's it's called Alice Bob Mini it, and it creates a miniature version of Redis specifically for unit
testing, and that's the one I'm going to use.
So we'll scroll down here and find the installation bit.
Looks like this is what we want right here, so let's copy that.
Just everything in between the parentheses.
OK.
And go back to her I.D. and we'll open our terminal window in the Celebrity House project.
I'll clear the screen and type.
Go get and then paste that URL and just copied.
And again, it's slash v2.
Please stick with V2 if a later version is out by the time you take this course, so it goes and gets
for us mini readies.
And there it is.
It's all installed.
So now I can actually start writing some tests.
And as is the case for most of our tests inside the cash project, I'm going to create a new file called
set up underscore test.
Don't go.
And it will, of course, be package cash.
And this is where we'll set up our testing environment.
So I'm going to create a variable.
I'll call the variable ver test.
Red is cash and it's a type release cash, and then I'll carry the function test me to set things up.
And it takes one parameter and a pointer to testing them.
Try that again.
Test ing dot.
Yeah, that's better.
Make sure didn't import anything extra for me.
No, it did not.
So in here, what I'm going to do is start up a fake, in-memory ready server using that mini.
Read this package.
We just import it.
And that's really simple, and you can see the documentation right in the home page, but it's trivial.
So X is my variable error is what I'm checking for, and I will just call Mini Redis.
Hopefully it'll will find it.
For me, it did not run.
And if air is not equal to nil, then I will say panic.
We'll just die because something went wrong, and I don't want to run any tests at this point.
Otherwise, we'll defer Skelos and now we'll create a retest pool, which I'm going to need to run these
tests.
So Poole is assigned the value of preschool, and we follow the same kind of logic we did before.
Max idle, we'll make that 50 max active and I'll make this a thousand.
That's enough for running our test for for sure.
Not an idle timeout again, 240 times timed out.
Second, just like we did when we set up our live writers pool.
And then we're done.
And this is simply a function and dialogue has to have a colon after it.
Of course,
it's a function and it returns.
Read Scone and potentially an error.
And in here, we just return readies dial and we just hand it TCP
IP.
And here's where we call start address.
And that gives us the address of our temporary in-memory Redish server, and we need a comma here.
Now, test readies cash that variable we declare a little while ago.
Its connection is now equal to a reference to Pool, which we just got back up on Line 21 and test red
as cash dot prefix will be equal to say test dash alerts.
It doesn't matter, but that's something I know I'm not going to use anywhere else and will say Defer
test readies cash
icon that close.
Now I just run my tests on exit.
And we want to run as its prefix, and it didn't import the US package for me.
So I'll just go put it in that myself here OS.
OK.
That's our set up of tests.
Now let's create a test, so I'll create a new file inside the cash folder.
And I will call it cash underscore test, don't go.
And his package cash, and we'll write some tests.
So let's just do one right now for the cash has bit.
OK, so we're ready to function funk test cash heads.
And its test readies cash, hers is using sensible naming convention.
And that takes one parameter t a pointer to testing that T.
And what we'll do, first of all, is make sure that there's no value cold food in the cash itself,
so we'll check for an error.
And that's assuming the value of hauling test.
Red is cash and we want forget.
And we're going to forget food just to make sure there's no value called food in there.
If error is not equal to nil, then we'll say to error there.
So we know there's no value called food in there.
So we'll just say in cash a variable, I'm declaring in cash in error.
Her son, the value of and we'll call test red red at cash has and will hand hand it the key.
We're looking for food.
One we know is not in there, OK?
And again, we checked for an error, so I'll copy this and paste this.
And now we test the results.
If in cash, then Tina Error, who found in cash and it shouldn't be there or whatever you want the
error message to be.
OK, so let's just try running the test and see what happens.
So I'll open my terminal window, clear the screen, make sure I'm in the house project and then go
into the cash flow and I'll say, Go test done.
And they passed, so that's a good sign.
But we've really only tested part of the functionality, and I will say error is equal to test retest
cash.
Dot set, and I want to set the value or the key of food, and I'll put butter in there.
Doesn't matter what it is, as long as it has some value.
And again, we'll check for an error.
So a copy this and paste it here.
And now, once again, we'll come up here and say in cash and error, and I'll copy this and change
the operator, the assignment operator, to an equal sign.
Get rid of that error.
And now we'll copy this.
And paste it here and say, if not in cash.
In other words, it can't find it fu not found in cash, but it should be there.
OK, let's try running that test.
So clear my terminal window and go test.
So in effect, right now, I'm pretty much sure that forget has and set all work, but all right, test
for them to be specific, just individual tests, because I'd like to have as much coverage and be absolutely
certain that things are behaving as they should.
So I'll scroll down and close the terminal window and let's test our next function.
So here we want to test cash, get so funk test and I'm getting I want to call it red as cash red is
cash get and parameter of T point or two testing dirty.
And here I'll say I'm going to set foo and bar in the red is cash.
So I'll I already did that right here, so I'll copy this and paste it here and make that an assignment
operator.
So I've just tried to put the value of bar in the cash with the key of food.
So I'll now say X, which is the fair value.
I'm going to get back in error or assign the value of test, retest cash, get and looking for the key
of food, and I'll check for an error.
So a copy and paste and now I do my test.
If X is not equal to bar, then T error and all I have to say is.
Did not get correct value from cash, and let's try running that test so clear the screen go goats don't.
Past perfect.
OK, so that gives me get now, let's try forget, even though I'm pretty sure that works at this point,
I'm still going to write a test for it.
So funk test red is cash.
Forget testing.
No T points or two to testing dirty.
And let's get some room here to work with.
So I'll set a value in there.
So a copy this code, I'll use a different value this time, so I'll set alpha to beta.
So that puts a value in the cash and I'll try for getting it.
There is equal to test release cash.
Don't forget c h e.
Don't forget and I want to forget alpha.
And again, I want to check for an error and paste this here and now.
I'll try to see if it's in the cash in cash and error or assign a value of test red as cash has and
will look for alpha paste in my error.
Check and do my test in cash.
It shouldn't be there.
If in cash that's equal to true, then will arrow to error
alpha found in cash and it should not be there.
Let's try that test.
And you noticed that every time I write or update a test, I run them.
It just helps me keep track of what's working and what's not.
So far, so good.
OK, let's just check our coverage right now and see what that's like.
So go Test, Dash, Cover Dot.
And we're at forty eight point four percent of statements.
Not bad, we are getting there, but we're not done.
We have more things to test.
So that was forget.
Let's try empty funk test retest cash underscore empty T pointer to testing dirty.
And what am I going to do first of all?
Well, I'm going to put something in there.
I can just use this, so we'll set that value and paste it in there and then we'll call.
Empty air is equal to test red as cash dark, empty and we'll check for an error.
Copy and paste.
And we'll do her in cash check, so I'll copy all of this, and I should be able to use that with almost
no change, so we could alpha in there.
We emptied the cash.
We look for alpha.
Absolutely perfect.
Let's try running that go test dot.
And it says Alpha is found in the cache, but it shouldn't be there, so it looks like empty does in
fact not work.
So let's just try reading this again.
Go Test, be done.
And this is why we write tests.
Alpha found in cash and it should not be there.
So empty is not doing what it's supposed to do.
So let's go back to our cash functionality and find that empty bit.
There's set there's forget there's empty by match, there's empty, so I'm getting my keys.
I'm looking for the prefix of percent Escola.
So let's try something really simple.
Let's assume that it has something to do with the prefix.
OK.
So I'm going to actually comment that line out and replace it with ignore the first returned value,
try an error.
And that is a sign the value of here, I'm actually going to call directly.
Con dot do, and I want to say Deo and I'll put X there because I have a feeling that the prefix is
being added twice.
Let's just see if this does the trick.
OK, so back to our terminal.
Clear the screen.
And run that test again, and I put the Dash V flag on there just to get a verbose response.
And everything passed, so that's exactly what it is.
So that means, of course, that I can delete this line and copy this line and go back up here to where
I'm emptying by match and did the same thing here because we'll have exactly the same problem if we
don't do that.
So back to cash test and let's try empty by match.
So funk test retest cash underscore empty or match with a parameter of T pointer to testing dirty.
Give ourselves some room so it'll be similar to the one we just did.
So I'll do this little bit right here, OK?
Copy that and paste it.
So we're putting an alpha with a value of, we'll say, food just to make it a little different.
And then we'll set another one.
So we'll copy this and paste it in there and call it Alpha two and get rid of the assignment operator
or Alpha two and make that an equal sign.
OK.
And now we'll call empty by match.
Actually, before we call Empty Match, I'm going to put something else in the cache, so I'll copy
this something that doesn't start with the letter X and I'll call this beta.
OK, now I'll call empty by match because I want to make sure it only deletes the things that actually
match.
So errors assign the value of test cache, test retest cache dot empty by match, and that requires
a parameter.
And one I'll put in.
There, of course, is alpha, and I'll check for an error and paste that here.
And they'll do my checks, so I'll copy this in cash logic that we have here.
OK?
And the error message in a piece was right here.
So what I'm looking for is to see, does it have alpha?
If it does, then it shouldn't be there.
And then again, I'll copy this and look for Alpha two or change this to an equal sign instead of an
assignment operator and look for Alpha two and change the error message, then I'll copy this whole
thing in what should still be in.
There is something called beta, so I'll paste that in.
Look for better and if not in cash, we want data not found in cash.
And it should be there.
OK, let's try that and see how it's working.
Go Test Dash v Dot.
Everything passed.
Let's get our coverage go test cover, don't.
And we have eighty two point four percent of statements tested.
So the last things we need the test, of course, are encode and decode, I think.
So let's write those tests, even if they're not the last things, we definitely want them.
So we'll say funk, test, encode, decode, and that's T per point of view testing dot t.
And we'll just write simple tests for those, and they're really easy.
So we'll make an entry and a sign of the value of a blank entry like that.
And then we'll say entry foo because this is a map equals.
And it's a map string interface so we can put anything there.
So Bar will do the trick and we'll say bytes an error or assign a value of encode entry and we'll check
for an error if error is not equal to nil, then teed up error error
and then we'll say nothing.
And error is assigned the value of decode.
And we're looking for string bytes
and we'll check for an error.
And pasted in there and looks like I have a tape of similar entries or has already been defined.
I think that's it.
Yeah.
OK, let's try running the test now.
So we're we're trying to create a blank entry populating the map that it requires with food, key food
value, br encoding it into bytes.
And then we're putting those bytes into a string and decoding them.
OK.
Let's just try that and see how it works.
Go.
Test done.
Everything passed, so at this point, I think I have enough coverage that I can go and try writing
an actual web page back in my app that demonstrates the functionality of the caching package, and we'll
do that in the next lecture.