So we have our functions written for our cash, and we've written the tests for our cash, and it's
pretty much time to try this out on the front end.
And what we're going to do is we're going to create a page standard jet template that gives us a bunch
of methods of putting something into the cash, modifying its content, checking to see if it exists,
deleting it, all the core things that we've implemented.
And of course, we're going to write this as a single page, and the JavaScript on that page will call
various handlers on my app that interact with the cash.
Now we're going to be calling them using JavaScript fetch.
And one of the things that will make this ever so much easier is if we write a function in Securitas
that allows us not just to write Jason, but also to read Jason.
And that's pretty easy.
So I'm still on my salary test package and I'm going to open up.
My response utils right here.
OK, now if you recall, we already have one here called Right, Jason.
Let's add one just before it called read Jason so funk.
See a pointer to celebrities.
And we'll call it read Jason, and it will require the request, the response, some data.
That's it.
So let's start with the response HTP response writer, our pointer to that request and some kind of
data in the form of an interface so we can put whatever we want in there and it will potentially return
an error.
OK.
So we're going to, first of all, put a sanity check in here and I'm going to hardcoded, you can do
whatever you want here.
I want to make sure that the maximum number of bytes I get max bytes is a sign the value of one zero
four eight five seven six or one megabyte one megabyte.
I don't want anything more than a MEG coming as a JSON request that should be more than enough room.
OK.
And I I'm going to get the request body and body equals HDP Dot.
Max Bites Reader W and our body and 64 because it has to be in 64 megabytes.
OK, so that's just a way of reading no more than one megabyte of the request body that will create
a decoder deck.
And it's a sign the value of Jason Dud new decoder and I'm going to decode our body.
And now a check for an error when I try to decode Dekker, decode it.
If error is not equal to nil and return error
otherwise, the only thing I want to check right now is that we only allow one entry in the JSON file
just to avoid any potential nefarious users.
So again, a check for an error and that's equal to the decode and we're going to decode.
Into a reference to struct.
And then two sets of curly braces just to make sure there's only one value in there.
We'll check for an error if error is not equal to and in this case, it's not nil.
We're looking for iReport.
End of file.
Then we'll return errors.
Don't know.
And just give them a message, body must only have a single Jason value, and that's sufficient.
And I didn't import errors for me.
So let's import errors.
OK, now, if all of that passes, then we return nil.
OK, so this is now available to us to read Jason Arbitrary Jason, and that's going to be extremely
convenient.
So that's all done now.
Let's switch over to our map project and try these things out.
So the first thing I'm going to do is open my terminal and I will type go mod vendor just to get the
latest version of celebrities into the vendor directory so I can work with it without seeing errors
in my ID.
And that's done.
The second thing you need to do is to open up the dot on file and make sure that your settings are correct.
So look for the reddest config section and you'll see that it's there in line 25 on my code and in my
case, I have line twenty six Redis underscore host set to local host column sixty three eighty and
I speak as I have another copy of Redis for another project running on my system, so I had to use a
different port.
Yours should almost certainly read six three seven nine and you have no password use whatever you want
for a prefix, celebrities will work just fine, and the only other thing to worry about right now is
to ensure that cache is set to release on Line 31, in my case.
Now on the course resources for this lecture, you will find a file called Cache Dot Jet, so download
that file and you're going to put it right in your views directory.
So I don't have one in there right now, but I do have the contents of that file copy to my clipboard,
so I'll create a file called Cache Dot Git.
I'll simply paste the value of my clipboard right into there, and this is what the file is.
It's a standard template.
Just like we've used before.
It extends based on jet, which I better fix right now.
Based on jet.
It's named Cache and it has a form and the form doesn't submit anything because we're going to do everything
using JavaScript, as I said earlier.
So here are a bunch of form fields that allow us to put something in the cache to get something from
the cache, to delete something from the cache and to empty the entire cache and some buttons for each
of those actions.
And down here at the bottom, we have our JavaScript and the very first part let's see CSS, RF, Eq.
and then it gets a value from the meta tags at the top of the page.
We're not using that yet, but we will later on.
So you may as well leave that there.
Then I just get a reference to various buttons and divs on the screen, and then I have a bunch of event
listeners that listen for clicks.
So when you click, for example, on the Save button, it down here on Line eight calls a fetch statement
that calls a root that doesn't exist yet, which points to a handler that doesn't exist yet, and it
does the necessary cache operations and gives some feedback.
OK.
So get that in the right place inside The View's folder in my app.
Make sure it's named cached git.
And my next step is to go to my handler folder and I'm going to create a new file.
I'll put these handlers all in their own file, so I'm going to call this cache.
Dash handlers dot go.
And of course, that's in package handlers and lures.
And we're going to have some handlers here, sort of the first is create some stub handlers, so I'll
create a function with the receiver of a pointer to handlers
and I'll call this one save in cash.
And it's a handler.
So it has to have a response writer and a pointer to request or as a pointer to the request.
And now I'm just going to copy this and paste one stub for each of the handlers.
We're going to have to write.
So we have saving cash.
We're going to have get from cash.
We're going to have delete from cash,
and we're going to have to have empty cash.
So I'll call that empty cash.
And of course, we're going to have 10 one to display the cash rich, so funk each handlers show cash
age probably not the best title, but it'll suffice for our purposes today and hours upon request.
OK, so those are stub handlers now.
The first one show the cash.
That's pretty easy.
So we can just open up any of our other handlers and find one that renders something so right at the
top here.
Let's just go with this.
Copy that.
Go back to our cash handlers and paste that right in here and make sure it shows the cash template.
So that should be great.
OK, so let's start with the save in cash.
Now as I sit.
This handler doesn't actually show a Web page.
This handler gets called by JavaScript fetch utility and it reads some JSON file and does something
with it.
So I'm going to assume that we're going to get Jason in this format or create a variable, which I'll
call user input.
It's just a struct, and it has the following fields.
It has name which is a string and then JSON that's called right now.
Duplicate that twice.
The second one is the value.
And of course, in JSON, I call that value.
And the last one, we're not using it, but we will get there eventually.
CSR, because you want to verify that CSC SRF tokens are valid just to avoid cross-site request forgery
attacks, and this is called see SRF token in JavaScript.
OK.
Here is where I'm going to use that read JSON function we just wrote a few minutes ago.
So I'll check for an error and a sign that the value of from H.
We're going to go to app and we want to read JSON, and that requires the response writer the request,
and I'm going to pass it.
Since it's the interface, I can pass anything, including a pointer to user input.
OK.
And I'll check for an error.
Say if error is not equal to nil.
I'll just say a short error.
500 internal server error.
OK.
And that requires a W and.
I think that's all it requires.
Yep, looks good at this point.
We'll just return because we can't go any further.
But assuming we can pass that, Jason into our user input variable, read it in there.
OK, now we actually want to set a value in the cache, and that should be pretty easy at this point.
I should be able to call IRR is equal to a Dot app.
No H.
App, not creator, if not exist.
Dark cash.
That set, and that only requires two parameters, the key and the value.
Well, the key is user input, not name, and the value is user input value.
OK.
And we'll check for an error.
Again, I'm just going to do this.
This is sufficient for our purposes.
So at that point, I should have set the value in the cash.
And now I want to write some Jason.
So I'll create another variable and I'll call this one rest for a response.
And it's just a struct, and it has two two fields error, which is a Boolean.
And in JSON,
I'll call that error
and the message will be a string.
And in Jason, I'll call that message
and I'll populate that field.
Report error equals false because there is no error and respect message equals, say, saved in cash.
And now I just write that Jason out, and we can do that using silver tops.
And in this case, I'll just ignore the error.
And that's going to be equal to each dot app dot.
Right, Jason.
And that requires the following parameters w what to write to HP Typekit status created seems valid
in this case because I created something in the cache, plus my response, and that should do the trick.
Now the next step, of course, is to do this similar thing for get from cache, delete from cache and
empty cache.
But this is starting to be a pretty long lecture, so we'll move on to that in the next one.