So let's keep working on these routes for these handlers, for routes, and I'm still in cash, dash
handlers talk about start work on get from cash.
So we're going to, first of all, get our user input ver user input, and that'll be exactly the same
as what we have up here.
So let's just copy that.
Actually copy all of this system time.
So I'm going to pay set in here and that determines what we're looking for.
And in this case, I really am only going to get name and CSR if I don't care about the value.
So I'll get rid of that, say one line and I'll read the JS, and now I'll check to see if that exists
in cash.
OK?
So we'll say from cash
and potentially an error or assign the value of each app dark cash don't get.
And I'm going to get user input type name
and we'll check for an error.
So we'll copy this same sort of error code we have here and paste it in.
And now let's build our response.
So I'll come up here and copy this one, which is a good start and paste this down.
Now we may actually have an error in this case.
OK, and the error could be something like it's not in the cache, for example.
So maybe we should build a variable up here or declare one ver say, mzgee of type string.
And then down here, when we have an error, we don't do an error 500.
OK from the from Kashmir.
Instead, we'll say MSG is now equal to.
Not found in cash.
That seems to make more sense, really.
Maybe we should also declare another variable just to make things absolutely clear.
Vir encash will make that true by default.
Lowercase a here and an equal sign there, which is a lot better now, we'll say in cash equals false.
And after all of this, and we'll add a third value here, so value which is a string.
And in Jason, they'll call that value.
OK, so let's settle this.
And now once we have all this set up, so we declare user input.
We read the value from that.
I'll just move this up above that.
So these are logically grouped together, which is always good practice.
So we declared two variables we initialize message to be an empty string.
We initialize in cash to be a Boolean set true.
Then we declare our user input struct, which describes the nature of the data we're going to be receiving
from Jason.
Then we read our Jason and we check for it.
If an error occurs here, when we're trying to read Jason, we just throw an error five hundred.
Then we get past that.
We try to populate from cash with the value from.
And if we don't get that, we get an error.
We say not found in cash and false.
Then we describe the nature of our response and now we populated based upon the value of InTouch.
If in cash, we do one thing else.
We do something else.
And what we're trying to do, of course, is set the values in our RESP.
So we'll say respect error is equal to false because there is no error if we found it, if it's in the
cash respect message is equal to.
Success and in this case, we're seeing ramped up value is equal to and we'll take from cash will cast
it to a strain that's otherwise.
Something went wrong.
So respect error is equal to true.
And respect message is equal to mzgee.
And now we write that, Jason, out and up here, we kind of grab this same line.
And paste it right here.
And that should take care of getting values from the cash.
So the next one, of course, is deleting something from the cash.
And again, we're going to get this kind of information.
So let's copy that.
Our JSON file, it will be nothing more than a very simple JSON that has the name of the Kiwi wanted
wanted to delete from the cache and then the CSR token, which we're not currently using.
And then, of course, we read the JSON.
So let's reduce and paste it right below this.
And now we'll delete the value from a cache error is a sign of value or is equal to because you already
have an error variable H2 app cache.
Don't forget and we want to forget user input name and we'll check for an error.
And again, I'll just do the standard for checking, which is simple enough
and we send a response back.
So again, we'll copy all of this,
paste it down here and copy this sort of thing and paste it right here, and we'll just fix it up in
a moment.
We also need to write Jason, so I'll copy that and paste this here, and then we'll save the to format.
Everything else picks us up.
We don't need a values.
We can delete that and we can just say simply to delete it from cache.
And in this case, will end if it existed, which is actually true because if it doesn't exist, nothing
bad happens.
It just doesn't delete something because it didn't exist in the first place.
And the last thing we want to do here is basically empty the cache so we can copy all of this and also
copy this and paste it here.
In this case, we're emptying the cache.
We're not going to have a token, her name or anything like that.
So just Lucas, we're only going to have a CSR token.
So we'll read the JSON.
OK, and then down here, we may have to comment that over in a minute because we're actually not going
to do anything with it, but we'll find out.
OK.
So we read the Jason, so we've passed our file and now we say here is a sign the value of H Dot app
go up cache got empty.
And we have to check for an error, so we didn't assign a new variable so as to lead that it's better
and we'll check or check for an error and handle it appropriately and build a response.
So I'll copy this, paste it here and say.
Empty
cash, unless work, all right, so the last thing to do is to go to our roots file and set up our appropriate
routes, so we'll put it right here and we'll set a target and we'll call it say, slash cash test.
And this will show the page and that becomes a dog handlers show cache page.
OK, so that one's a get request.
The next four are a post request initiated by calling fetch in JavaScript, so eight up post.
Well, first one is in the page slash API slash save in cash, and that calls a dog handlers dot save
in cash.
No duplicate that.
We're going to call yet in cash or get from cash in that path.
Or that route is actually slash API slash, get from cache, not duplicate that and say for deleting
something from the cache.
It's delete from cache.
And that calls delete from cash, and the final one is empty cash, I believe.
And that calls empty cash, and if all went well, I should be able to open this up and say make stop
and use, it's running.
And it was make start.
Well, to put the link on our homepage for right now, we can get there manually.
So we're going to go to slash cash dash test, so we'll open up our web browser and we'll go to local
host.
There it is.
And let's add Splash Cash Dash test.
OK, so there's our cash page.
So first of all, let's try this one saving something in the cash, so I'll click on this and I'll type
in alpha and my cash value will be one to three.
Save in cash saved in cash.
Perfect.
Now let's try getting it from the cash alpha.
Mostly get from cash and go for the cash value one to three, which is exactly what I put in up here.
And that's good.
Now let's try deleting it, so I'll delete alpha delete from cash, and it's gone.
So now if I come back up here and try to get alpha from the cash not found in cash.
And if we try emptying the entire cash, everything is gone.
So I should be able to come up here and say, get from cash anything.
It doesn't matter what it is, that's not going to exist, obviously, but it seems to work exactly
as we hoped it would.
Perfect.
All right.
That's it for our cash functionality for the moment.
We'll be coming back to this later on when we implement a similar cash, but this time using a database
built right into our application called Badger.
But we have one or two things to do before we get to that.