So I'd like to keep all of this.
It's kind of like I don't know my OCD of being a teacher I like to try to keep my curriculum very modular
eyes and very consumable I call it the 38 Special where each section you break you break your your course
into sections and each section should have three day videos in each video should be three to eight minutes.
And so we just did a little bit of diving into get ahead and so I just made that it's own section.
Those are the videos we just went through and I just creating a new section here where we're gonna go
through the crawl and this is an overview of solution number one that Daniel created.
So he's going to walk us through that and he's just going to talk through what he is thinking this is
gonna go fast.
It's like the convertible ride through the countryside where you know we're just pointing it out Hey
look at that bar in there.
There's a park over there is that nice and see the river down there and you might be like Wait I want
to explore that river more and and so this is just to familiarize yourself familiarize you with the
terrain of his solution and then we'll come back and do longer stops at each of those points if you
want to you know check them out more with us so you can understand them a little bit more.
So this is an overview of solution number one.
Take it away Daniel.
Right.
So so my solution number one was to directly scrape the each team out.
So when thinking to crawl data on any given Web site.
So in this case we want to crawl all we want to get all the tweets in this conversation
with the the root the name the Twitter handle and be in the tweet itself.
That's that's basically all we were looking looking to get although we could also pull more data.
First thing to think whenever you go for something like this is is there an API that they provide that
can get this information.
So is there any Twitter API.
And yes there is a Twitter API.
No it does not actually help in this circumstance.
They don't actually have stuff to get all the replies to a tweet.
So in this case the API does not work out.
Oftentimes there is an API.
And so you can use the API that they provide and follow their instructions and it works out this case
that did not work.
That surprises me.
Yeah you have to buy it.
They only let some of their API is they have a limited number of calls.
Yeah.
And you have to know the exact I.D. numbers and you've got a limited amount you can call it day and
they've got a faster pace one but only works like the last seven days.
And so it's it's there.
Twitter's API is actually rather confusing amongst API.
I've looked at several and Twitter's is one of the more confusing ones.
So but overall they don't have an API that helps for what we're trying to do which is get all the replies
to a particular tweet so second option is to crawl the team out your Web browser needs these shemale
to actually draw the page.
So it's got all the information so you can your program can go through that A.T.M. and find everything
you're looking for.
I think this is brilliant because it's like all the data's already being sent to you.
Yeah exactly.
Thank you for sending it to me let me do something with it.
So.
So step one.
So my first actual attempt at a crawler just examines the e-mail to find the data I want.
This should be your second resort because a lot of web crawler usually doesn't respect a web page the
way a human does.
It will go way faster than a human would go through a site and go to many many pages and could overload
servers.
So you want to be careful in calling each e-mail to respect the server you're going to.
And most servers will have a little file just at the Domain at slash robots Dot T X T go to just about
any domain and we'll have this have a file here which basically defines what this Web site considers
respectful as far as crawling and so in this case.
Twitter's got a lot of list of what you or else you're allowed to access what the crawler.
Which ones you're not allowed to access.
If you go down to the bottom it's got a little list here saying don't make more than one requests per
second or wait wait one second between each request.
So just kind of general rules to follow that Twitter considers reasonable for a caller to respect to
keep their service working well for humans which is what the sites mean the for.
Quick quick disclaimer we're not attorneys this is not legal a legal advice.
So if you get yourself into hot water this is what we're going to show in court right here.
All right.
So yes do be careful some sites don't like you crawling at all.
Yes you should check that out period.
Well I don't know what the legal ramifications are.
You know violating terms of use and things like that lawyers don't always need valid reasons for launching
lawsuits.
Just know that at least in America.
So.
So Twitter's got a nice to grow robustly cheeks tea which is actually fairly generous for some sites
like this and so.
So I think you're OK.
So long as you respect that it should be OK.
Just call the team out.
So for a go there is a framework called Callie which makes crawling a shemale extremely simple and easy
and it automatically respects robots that takes so far.
That's awesome.
Don't even have to do anything if the site's got a robot that takes t..
Callie will obey what it says.
Yes this is super good to know about.
And in the in the desire to modular ize the course I am going to suggest that this is a good place to
end the first video just introducing Callie Yeah and and we'll rename overview of solution number one
or introduction introduction and I will introducing Callie but introducing.
We'll figure out the name of this video.
But we'll see the next video.
That's what we continue to see the next video.