So the video that named Daniel came up with was approaching crawling.
That's what we called the last video.
And now we're just going to move forward and you got that in your course outline.
You got a link to go college.
Let's check out some more.
Yeah so so go Carly is a rather nice go library for any kind of crawling scraping spider whatever you
want to call going over the e-mail from some Web site programmatically.
So.
So whenever I go use a new library oftentimes what I will do is I'll look for examples and go call he's
got a good amount of examples some basic advanced logging in parallel.
So I'll just find one that seems like it would have similar similar to what I'm doing.
And it's beautiful.
So here's like crawling Reddit crawling Reddit for some data.
So this is this is probably very similar to what I'm looking for it's getting a list of data off Reddit
like posts and finding individual sub data to find like the brute to it in the title and such.
This very similar to what I'm trying to do.
It's a list of data list of things it's trying to find data within the list so that's it this is the
good example to reference kind of generally what you should do in what order.
And then the go doc is the other thing I like to keep open while I'm working with a library so I can
actually see what all the options are.
So go Call me the very first thing in this Reddit example is call a new collector.
So OK.
So I go looking to go dock for new collector new collector takes in these parameters it returns a collector.
What's a collector option.
OK.
Here's a bunch of stuff I can now think about when I'm making a collector.
So for in this case for the scraping Twitter I didn't actually need any options so I was able to just
say OK create a collector once you've got a collector you're going to need data to actually what you're
actually going to be recording.
So I'm looking for a list of information.
Yes he created a data structure to hold the different information you want to pull out the different
information we wanted to pull out.
If you flip back to the tweet there we said Okay let's pull out the name.
And so you can see there's a lot Todd McCloud the top as you scroll down you see like and shool and
a cache Kosh and Hockney.
Right.
So you pull up the name and then the user name and then what they suggested.
So you're going to pull all that out.
So name username message and so that's in the data structure.
So we have a destruction that we're going to have a slice of those because there's going to be many
messages nice naming of the variables.
So very clear that that is the point of a variable name autocomplete is good enough nowadays that you
always want your variables to be clear.
So once you got messages Cawley says that works by you create the collector and you toll collector points
that you are interested in.
So with the on e-mail thing you can tell it.
I'm interested in everything with this class called this function or a time.
This clip that comes up called this function.
There's also on request every time it goes to a new page called this function.
So lots of different on things so if I go to my with I go doc you can look at on error on a shemale
on a show detach on request on response on scraped on X now except so plenty of stuff.
So in my case I was interested in whenever I see the tweet class I found this by over here.
If I open up my dev tools and I click this little button to the side of the Inspector I can now hover
over things and I can see information I found right about here I can see the entire tweet and if I could
there I can now see down here and one of the classes is tweet and that shows up on every single one.
If I click on the net if I go to the next one it's also as class tweet.
So a common class they can find for everything.
So yeah.
So what you're looking for there is something that's just really unique to the chunk of data you want
to grab.
And.
But but repeatable to each chart.
Right.
So it's like through all the code that gets sent.
You're finding that those those individual chunks and all that and all the code.
Yeah.
So.
So I'm telling you.
So here I just tell Callie I want to care.
I want every time there's a class tweet.
And so this is using just standard CSF selectors.
So if you go look if you know C assess this is just a CSF selector or if your g J.S. the query selector.
So dot means class and then the class name go.
So every time every time call he finds a dot tweet it will call this function here.
And this function will receive that element.
So in this case it's a div so this will be a div every time and so every time I find a dot tweet I will
add a new message to my list of messages with the append and create a new tweet and name and the element
has a child text which you can use to get text from a sub selected item.
So we're nice.
So within a tweet e dot child text and I can put in another selector.
So account group full name and account user name just so happened to find the name and user name and
then message was tweet text show show one of those again on Twitter just so we can see that.
Yeah.
So I'll do a so here is uh it's got tweet text.
Yeah it's going to be a class text and then show back on the code.
So tweet text.
All right.
So one thing.
No.
I've got the this separated account name and then inside that full name account.
Inside that username because of right here where it says replying to this particular replying to has
a class name of username which is the same as this one which is what I'm actually interested in is user
name.
And so you.
So.
So to make it more specific I found this username is always the username that I'm actually interested
in is always inside an anchor tag with that is always inside a.
Anchor tag with account dash group as class.
Just come over Jess dash account.
Group No account desk group account group.
So.
So I'm so I look for in four for user username specifically I need account group user name not just
any generic user name in my tweet.
So I found that out by running into it in my code directly it suddenly started telling me type iCloud
for every single one because they were all replying to Todd McLeod.
And so then I went back to my back to the H C to the H email and.
OK here's a here's a unique.
Here's a common class for the particular username I'm looking for.
So now after on H T mail I told Callie I every time a tweet happens do this.
So every time I tweet happens it will add a new message to the messages.
Then I tell Callie to visit site which I have listed out here as just a constant and it's just the URL
that you want to crawl to start off with So in this case this just.
Once tell Callie to visit Callie actually just go routines to speed up the visiting so you see that
wait to tell to wait until Callie is finished scraping so it started off when you told to visit.
Now you want to wait for it to be finished.
And so this is not that bad here because it's only visiting one page but if you're on each team l was
looking for like an anchor tag and then visiting from there to some other page and from there to some
other page.
It's very important.
You to need to wait.
So Callie will at this point call he's done.
Callie will have will have made a request to the robot start to 60 will have seen that Twitter's requests
and the robots that tweaks T and it will obey your programs respecting the robots that T.
First so in this case in this case doesn't really matter.
The page I tried to visit is allowed in the rules a t t and I'm only visiting one page so I didn't actually
make any difference at all but it was looking at the robots up to 60.
If it was a bigger crawling job that required going to multiple pages that would be something that's
really nice.
That's a really nice feature Callie and this video is getting a little long.
So maybe I'm marshall and dense very easy though we're almost done right.
Yeah.
So see our next step is I've got messages full of all the tweets so I'm just Jason marshaling it using
Marshall indent 2 to Marshall in a form that's got new lines and tabs so it's more readable and I'm
just and then I'm just printing it out to my console.
And I'm also pointing out how many tweets I got.
So if I actually run this real fast go run scraped I go it'll make the request to Twitter it will start
examining all the H it'll examine all the email it will spit out it found 19 tweets.
Cool.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I love your solution.
Great job in the next video we'll explore this a little bit more.