So now we're just gonna ask Daniel a couple of questions about his solution and my first question that
came up when I was watching him present that was the CSA as class names like I'd expect there online
twenty five twenty six and twenty seven that like it would be able to find like if you're looking like
if you're going through the tax and you're looking for like tweet tax write it's looking through the
going from tweet to tweet Yeah it's looking through the year you're your attribute is class and its
value is set to tweet text.
I say that right.
I haven't done it yet.
So classes it's all right.
One of the classes in the list of classes.
Yeah.
So so yeah their span is your tag classes that tribute and in the value values the entire list is the
is an entire list.
But within that list you have tweet text.
There's one user name.
So yeah.
For that one's usernames.
You stay there.
All right.
So there's tweet tech so it found tweet text in there and then for user name I would I would kind of
expect this to look at like okay inside user name I almost need to I almost need to put in user name
space you dashed or like maybe just put in all of that.
You will find that like it's a little surprising to me to see that it did the CSF specificity.
That's the best way I have to explain it.
So where you have like the nested stuff as a selector like this is out CSF selectors work.
You say this is a child.
Yeah.
I didn't use the child select subsets so that interest in that.
So what I'm doing is actually the child parent child thing I'm saying account name.
I'm looking for full a class full name and one of the parents has a class of account group.
So what Todd is seeking up is instead of I could use her name and then I could also do dot you'd Aster
because that's in there but is actually respecting that CSF.
So this this would add more specificity but what I'm not looking for is I'm not trying to disintegrate
between some CSX overwriting some other C assess what seat with it.
I'm just trying to find all user names.
Yeah but I don't want the user names that are out here in the message itself.
So that it may have its own.
If I inspect to this particular user name it might be the same.
I think it's got you there as well.
So yeah.
So just one thing I had noted though was that the top bar on every single tweet was account group.
Yeah.
And so that was something unique I could use to kind of narrow in on user name the particular username
I was looking for.
Yeah.
So that surprised me.
Where did that's in the documentation of how Cawley works that it does that that it's it's documentation
on a shemale it's looking for a go query selector which was.
This one.
Yeah.
And so go query when I went to it
CSF selector library.
Yeah.
And so it's the C is s select your library syntax why it's close.
Possible query.
OK that's interesting and then my next question was just a reflection on.
But like wow college is free.
That's a really well put together.
I think we use the word use the word library right.
But you can also Yes and it's an open source project.
Yeah.
And so for a terminology like first that that you know it's open source.
So so if you go over here you can actually see the license fee what you use.
This is what you have to obey to use it.
Nice and you know a question to which hundreds stars Nice to see which is this says Callie says you're
allowed to use it for just about whatever.
Just don't try to trademark it.
The creators aren't liable.
They don't give any warrant.
Yeah that's nice.
I like that summary.
I forget the other thing I was going to say and the next question was did this did this get all the
tweets because it pulled down 19.
But it seemed like there's a lot more so in this case.
No it did not.
And that's because Twitter does not actually give you all of the tweets immediately.
When I scroll down to the very bottom of the page you see it loads more infinite scrolling Kazan and
and so to do that.
That's what you did with solution number two.
So my second solution was me solved that.
We'll see that in the.
Coming up at some point we might go through this in a little bit more.
But do you have anything else you want to add any other reflections on.
No that's our colleagues Callie's very nice and I recommend you use it if you're using go and try to
make it crawl.
Do you want one of the things I like about you Sally that felt felt for her.
But like when I ask you if you have anything more you say no.
And then very often you're like however check this out.
I like that are something often more comes.
That's cool.
All right.
So that's that's it.
Anything else.
This time for real now you do the same for real.
All right.
See the next video it's five o'clock.
So we're gonna head home and then we'll be back tomorrow.
Yeah.
We'll be back tomorrow to do some more.
See you then.