Well I hope you've had a nice time since the last video.
I went home and got some sleep and that was awesome.
I can't remember anything else I did.
I was up for a couple hours in the night again and and when I was up a few of the things I reflected
on were few reflections that we could share with you about what we did in the yesterday in the previous
day and in the previous videos.
And so one of the reflections was something Daniel on to chairs were going to take a look at that.
And anyhow We're gonna go through a few reflections from yesterday and we'll start off with the two
versions of Twitter.
Why don't you tell people about that.
Yeah.
So it was not really thing I could really manage.
I don't actually have a Twitter account but a going going to this page here.
As someone who doesn't have a Twitter account it looks like this.
And then here's what it looks like if you on my computer go to Twitter and you do have an account.
It's like wait a minute.
Totally different Twitter.
And I'm logged in right.
You could see I don't know.
Well I guess I could tweet.
I have a big tweet but you can tweet when you're logged in.
And if I go down and look at that tweet that we put up so much about Twitter which is I don't know where
it is.
There it is a little bit noise outside.
That'll pass.
So here here's that tweet.
So looks really different.
And not only is a look different here but when you go into developer tools and again to get there you
they're more tools developer tools or option command high option command.
There you go.
When you go into developer tools and you check that out you have really different tags in there.
So it's different CSX.
And so it's a different version of Twitter.
Yeah.
So.
So it's important to note that your crawler will be crawling as someone who's logged out it does not
have any.
Any cookies showing that it's logged in or any other credentials.
And so to to make sure that you are looking at the same kind of page and seeing the same kind of CSX
as your crawler you should examine the page using a private or incognito browsing window which basically
gives the same effect of someone who is not logged in and has no has never visited Twitter before.
So in this case means the same thing for me.
As Twitter is just going based off whether I've walked in or not and for most web sites this does not
matter.
Usually there's not really any difference between anything but just in Twitter's case you may have a
slightly different site.
If you're logged it was not logged in with different CSF classes your crawler may may require changes
yeah.
And crawling is one of those deals where it's always you're relying upon somebody else's system and
that system could change.
You don't have control over that.
And so something that needs monitoring says the first thing we wanted to point out anything I'll say
about that one.
No.
And and then just someone that can give a little bit of an overview or maybe have a quick discussion
of an overview of your solution.
We don't have to look at the code but basically your process was you found a good library right or you
found some good code.
You can get a good package go Callie.
We're gonna do a little terminology disintegration between module package and library.
We're going to revisit that here one second.
But you found you found a good library package and then you looked at the examples and you said okay
here's an example.
And so how much of the code that you use was just kind of like you know pretty much just copy pasta
and encoding they sometimes say copy positive instead of copy paste right.
Yeah.
Kind of funny.
Yeah I've heard that but I'm just checking in to see if that's accurate because since I'm over the age
of 30 by a long ways now I fortunately I don't always understand all the lingo.
I don't get that one either.
Copy pasta.
So yeah copy paste.
Yeah.
How much of your code was copying and just pasting and then you know adjusting a little bit for the
current situation.
A lot of the archives so say it well it ends up that it ended up being very similar to how to read it
when you read it example here worked out as extremely similar but I did not actually.
I came to that kind of design kind of almost independently.
I use the example less as.
Here's how you do this and more along the lines that these are the functions you need and then looked
up with its functions were in the documentation and it turned out my design ended up being near identical
to this Reddit example.
Overall it's a nice way to do is to design it on your own.
If you have an example compare their solution and see if there's anything you can learn from it.
Like that and then the terminology terminology disambiguate and revisited.
I just want to.
For me I don't know why I really like to have precision over what words are being used and make sure
that we understand those.
Because when you're learning coding there's so many different new words and there's a language for talking
about programming and languages.
And if you don't understand those words it could just be like a sea of confusion like a foreign language
like I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't know what those words are and so I found some definitions for module package and library and
and then I put those in here and along with the resource so this is just kind of what it refers to in
computer science.
And and then this is kind of what it refers to and go.
And so in computer science module and software modules part of a program programs are composed of one
or more independently developed modules that are not combined until the program is linked.
A single module can contain one or several routines in hardware modules self-contained component and
the thing which is a little bit tricky about this terminology is I could have used the word function
there right and it would have worked just as well right.
Programs are combined of different functions and add or components even rights.
There's different words that but anyhow that's the definition came up the module but it gets back to
this general idea of the trend that software engineering and develops take him in which is to module
arise our code to take spaghetti code one big document full of code and break it up into chunks which
then can be called in and used and reused and do not repeat yourself.
Keep your code dry.
So modular izing your code gets back whether it's module component function gets back to this general
trend of breaking things up and reads usable chunks.
And so that's a module definition we came up with or I came up with here at this link and then go a
module or go module.
Either one is name spacing for your work space dependency management which includes managing direct
pendency is an indirect dependencies and versioning.
So which versions of your dependencies and you can have one or more packages in a module and usually
a module is one to one with a repo.
So that's that's module definition module and then we have package you have anything to say about module.
OK.
And then we have package and package is a namespace that organizes a set of related classes and interfaces.
This is a definition that comes from Oracle Java conceptual you can think of packages as being similar
to different folders on your computer.
You might keep H.M. pages in one folder images and another in scripts and applications and yet another.
So that's one definition we came up with for a package and in go package is a higher level grouping
of codes so if you look at the scope and go and scope if that's foreign to you.
Please go back to the earlier classes but we have the universe scope and then we have the package scope
and then we have file scope.
So the universe is the entire program.
The entire program can be made up of packages.
Packages can be made up of files and then files can be made up of code blocks and those code blocks.
I think of them as stuff between curly braces and so you have stuff between curly braces and functions
but you can also just have curly braces.
I call him curly.
You could have curly braces inside your code at various points to limit scope and so that's that's kind
of where the package falls in this and so packages we make you know to higher level grouping of codes.
We have the strings package where we have the fucked package and then so that's and I included here
from the going specification where it talks about scope.
So if you just want to read that that's from the go spec source going spec and then down here we have
library.
And so in computer science a library is a collection of non-volatile resources used by computer programs
often for software development and these may include configuration data collection of non-volatile resources
like that's used by computer programs non-volatile means that they aren't going to go away.
So it's just a resource right.
Could include configuration dad documentation helped out a message templates pre written code and subroutines
classes if we're doing classical P.
Object Oriented Programming values or type specifications and so on go.
You know like I if I if I'm typing going libraries the first result I get a Google is the programming
language packages.
But what it points to is the standard library and so I think it's nice that they call the library right
because this library is all of the different packages in the standard library so library contains all
the packages.
So that's a little bit of you know a little bit of disintegration between module.
What it kind of generally speaking is in computer science and then what it is and go package what it
generally is in computer science and what it is and go and kind of where that ties in with scope and
and then how we modular ize our code and break it up into little chunks.
He could see all these terms get confusing.
You talked about it and then a library.
Right.
Because we've been using module or library or package sometimes these words can shift back and forth
as we use them.
All right says just terminology disambiguate.
I know that's a lot about those terms but for me it's important to be precise about the language and
also if you're newer to programming and you hear people using these terms to understand that you know
there is an absolute division between those terms module component library package function right.
And depending upon the language you're working in.
They might have used different terminology to talk about very similar things in different languages.
So not to be intimidated by that when you're talking with other developers and somebody is using different
term.
You kind of understand what that means and then you can also even explain it if it's needed to be anything
you want to add.
For reals now for reals.
That's right.
We were joking about that yesterday.
All right.
So that's that's our little reflection.
We'll see you in the next section where we're going to take a look at the second crawler.
Daniel put together.